<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Airtm Blog | Get Paid Better</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.airtm.com/en/blog/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=BrowserlessCSSBridge&amp;browserless_url=http%3A%2F%2F10.0.0.124%3A3050%2F&amp;browserless_&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.airtm.com%2Fen%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_selector=.blogHome+a.linkContent&amp;url_pattern=%2Fen%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=div.body+.article&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;date_format=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=1&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=BrowserlessCSSBridge&amp;browserless_url=http%3A%2F%2F10.0.0.124%3A3050%2F&amp;browserless_token=fc703384-2d7f-46a1-b846-39102d2b7261&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.airtm.com%2Fen%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_selector=.blogHome+a.linkContent&amp;url_pattern=%2Fen%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=div.body+.article&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;date_format=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=1&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-12T20:40:55+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Why Airtm.me Is a Better Option Than PayPal For Freelances?</title>
    <published>2025-04-10T15:28:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-10T15:28:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.airtm.com/en/blog/digital-entrepreneurship/airtm-me-vs-paypal/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.airtm.com/en/blog/digital-entrepreneurship/airtm-me-vs-paypal/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Cristina Rodriguez</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">                                      Airtm.me vs Paypal?                                                                                                        Cristina Rodriguez                                                                                                                                             April, 10, 2025                                                                                                                                        3 min.                                                                                                                Freelancing continues to grow across Latin America, and with it, the need for reliable, fast, and accessible payment tools. While PayPal has long been a go-to platform, more and more freelancers are searching for a smarter, more flexible solution tailored to their region.Airtm.me stands out as a better alternative to PayPal for freelancers in Latin America, offering financial freedom and tools that adapt to the local context.                                                                                                                                                    Content Table                                                                                                                                                                                                         The Limitations of PayPal for Latin American Freelancers                                                                             Why Airtm Is a Better Alternative                                                                             Common Use Cases                                                                             Airtm vs PayPal: A Quick Comparison                                                                             Final Thoughts                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        The Limitations of PayPal for Latin American Freelancers                                     PayPal is globally recognized, but freelancers in countries like Mexico, Colombia, Peru, Venezuela, or Argentina face serious challenges when using it:   High currency conversion fees   Limited withdrawal options in local currency   Slow and restrictive transfer processes   Lack of country-specific support   Risk of account holds or frozen funds without notice   These issues make it difficult for freelancers to access and manage their income efficiently.                                                                                                                                   Why Airtm Is a Better Alternative                                     Airtm was created with Latin American users in mind. The platform connects people to the global economy, allowing freelancers and remote workers to receive payments in dollars and manage their money securely and flexibly. 1. Get paid internationally, hassle-free With Airtm’s US Virtual Account, you can receive payments just like someone with a U.S. bank account. It’s perfect for getting paid by freelance platforms or international clients, without the need for intermediaries. 2. Withdraw your funds your way Airtm lets you withdraw money through multiple local and digital methods, including local bank transfers, digital wallets, mobile payments, cash, or even crypto. You choose the option that works best for you. 3. Lower and transparent fees Unlike PayPal, Airtm offers lower, more transparent fees. You always know how much you’re receiving and paying before confirming a transaction—no hidden surprises or bad exchange rates. 4. Platform and support in your language Airtm offers support in Spanish and workflows designed for Latin American users. You’ll also find an active community sharing real-life tips and experiences.                                                                                                                                   Common Use Cases                                     Thousands of freelancers across Latin America already use Airtm to receive payments for their services, including:   Work on platforms like Upwork, Freelancer, Fiverr, or Toptal   Direct clients in the U.S., Europe, or Asia   Crypto payments converted into local currency   International wire transfers through their US Virtual Account                                                                                                                                     Airtm vs PayPal: A Quick Comparison                                          Feature Airtm PayPal     Currency conversion fees Low and transparent High and unclear   Local withdrawals Available with many options Limited or difficult   U.S. virtual bank account Yes (ACH details) Not available   Withdrawal methods Banks, wallets, crypto, cash Few options   Support in Spanish Yes, Latin America-focused General only   Flexibility High Medium                                                                                                                                        Final Thoughts                                     If you’re a freelancer in Latin America looking for a fair, fast, and flexible way to receive international payments, Airtm.me is your ideal solution.With competitive fees, multiple withdrawal methods, and a platform tailored to your region, Airtm is emerging as the best alternative to PayPal for freelancers in Latin America. &amp;nbsp; Ready to get started?Create your account at Airtm.me and start receiving payments from anywhere in the world, with ease and control.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                      </content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://www.airtm.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Paypal-1.jpg"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
