<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Raza Rizvi on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@imrazarizvi?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fimrazarizvi.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*MLz3wHqWkIZbm8JYpbnyVw.jpeg</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*MLz3wHqWkIZbm8JYpbnyVw.jpeg</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fimrazarizvi.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T21:58:23+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Answerly — Ongoing SCF Update</title>
    <published>2021-09-25T19:35:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-25T19:35:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-ongoing-scf-update-54f457ce99d1?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-ongoing-scf-update-54f457ce99d1?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Answerly — Ongoing SCF UpdateHello Stellar Community,It’s the last day of panel voting of the ongoing Stellar Community Fund (SCF) and I wanted to share some of the milestones that Answerly has achieved so far.The purpose of this post is to highlight the significance of this community fund for achieving our upcoming goals. I (Raza RIzvi) and co-founder (Zain Haider) started working on this project in early 2019. Until now, this project has been fully self-funded and we’ve managed to:Develop answerly.app along with most of its featuresGrown our social media community from 0 to 50K members (twitter+telegram+medium)Over 20K active users on AnswerlyToken listing on 5 centralized exchanges (BKEX, Probit, Hotbit, Dex-trade, and P2PB2B)100% organic volume of Stellar dex.Press release on websites like Yahoo Finance, Investing.com, and 200+ websites more to come.Scaling from 0 to 37 employees.Introduced Answerly NFTs on Litemint. We will continue adding 50 new NFTs every weekStarting a Youtube channel on some of the most searched topics on Youtube. Every video will contain a 15-second introduction to Answerly and Stellar blockchain.At this point, we have a decent marketing and development budget that would last a few months. Our Answerly revenue starts from 1st Quarter 2022 and we need the funds to continue our operations smoothly.Our upcoming steps are:Adding liquidity to the Stellar dex. Stellar dex has proved to be the best exchange for Answerly so far. We plan to integrate SDEX directly to make the withdrawal and trading process convenient for our users.Partnering up with existing Stellar projects like Litemint, Lumenswap, Lobstr wallet, etc.Setting aside a budget for SEO guest posts and influencer marketing.If we don’t make it in this round, we will try again in the next SCF. But I just wanted the Stellar judge panel to know that we’ve been through a lot of struggles in the last 3 years and still managed to achieve these milestones on a very limited budget. If we win this round, we can progress at a faster pace and would be able to achieve things that seem challenging right now. Our interests align with Stellar foundation and we are confident that we can help in growing the utility of Stellar lumens. Just looking for your support and I can promise you the results.Regards,Raza Rizvi</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">2 major announcements for Answerly</title>
    <published>2021-09-16T06:57:18+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-16T06:57:18+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/2-major-announcements-for-answerly-3f46d4471c92?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/2-major-announcements-for-answerly-3f46d4471c92?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hello Stellar Community,We prepared these announcements for 15th Sep, but due to some technical issues, we had to postpone it until today.As you all know, we recently launched our first NFT, which got sold in 2 hours. This was just a demo of what’s coming ahead because from 22nd SEP onwards, we will release the full collection of digital art on Marvel that will include another 49 characters.From now onwards, we will release 50 NFTs *every week* on a different theme. This includes superheroes-based art, travel, sports, abstract, etc.We plan to utilize these revenues to add liquidity to ANSR tokens and buying back the tokens cheap. This will stabilize Answerly token price in the long run. In the coming weeks, you will also be able to buy NFTs directly from the Answerly website by paying in Answerly tokens. That’s another amazing utility for Answerly tokens.Besides NFTs, we are also starting our YT channel where we will discuss some very interesting topics. Just to give you an idea, if you like watching videos from “What if”, you’ll love our work. We plan to create similar videos but in-depth. Every morning, we’ll release one video that will include a 20-second intro to Answerly, Answerly token, and Stellar blockchain.While video creation costs would be covered by the YT revenues, Answerly still gets to benefit from millions of impressions from all around the world.To sum it all up50 NFTs every week1 YT vid every day.This will create Answerly brand awareness and boost the demand for Answerly tokens like never before.We plan to release the first video tomorrow (17th SEP). Cheers!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">ANSWERLY X HOTBIT</title>
    <published>2021-09-08T04:19:05+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T04:19:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-x-hotbit-87b3515bfc24?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-x-hotbit-87b3515bfc24?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Thank you all for the overwhelming response to our earlier listings. We are truly humbled with the love and affection for our platform. On this note, we’d love to introduce the next big listing for Answerly Tokens: The Hotbit.This big exchange has daily trading volume upwards of $500 Million, and like our previous listings, it will offer Answerly Family with better variety and greater options. Hotbit is re-known for its customer relations, and market competitive rates. Therefore, it will indeed prove beneficial for our community.Hotbit proudly holds the record of zero loss to any of its user assets due to the platform’s security weaknesses. Besides, the security rating of the exchange is ranked same as of Binance. Most importantly, Hotbit was the first crypto-exchange in the world to offer daily current deposit interests to its users with no token locked up or frozen.Like our previous listings, Hotbit will pair $ANSR tokens with several other coins, including BTC, ETH, and USDT. So stay tuned, $ANSR will be listed on 8th of September. As mentioned earlier as well, we are coming on Reddit for AMA very soon. We would love to answer any queries you have regarding HOTBIT listing or Answerly in generalHappy Listing!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Answerly X Probit: Liquidity Like Never Before</title>
    <published>2021-09-08T03:51:50+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T03:51:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-x-probit-liquidity-like-never-before-15830b050518?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-x-probit-liquidity-like-never-before-15830b050518?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hello Stellar Family,It has been a pretty rewarding week for us, here at Answerly, and we can’t thank Stellar Family enough for making it a huge success. Thus, here we’d like to share with you all one of the biggest breakthrough for Answerly forthcoming- Probit GlobalWe know many of you had speculated our token to be listed on bigger exchanges; hence, we’re very much delighted to inform you all of this new beginning.We’re coming on Probit on 8th September (00:00 EST) and now Answerly Tokens will be listed on your beloved exchange with a mighty daily volume of $200 Million USD.High Volume, High LiquidityThis listing is the ultimate solution for all your liquidity problems, and will offer Answerly Family incredible flexibility with their tokens. Every crypto-enthusiast is undoubtedly well aware of Probit. But for those who aren’t aware let me tell you that from becoming a premier destination for DeFi tokens to offering minimalistic charges to traders, Probit is a leading player in Exchange World, which is exactly the reason for its high volume activity. With Answerly Tokens listed, we can now access better rates and greater diversity.Pairing?That not it. Answerly will be available in three pairings:Bitcoin (BTC): https://www.probit.com/app/exchange/ANSR-BTCEthereum (ETH): https://www.probit.com/app/exchange/ANSR-ETHTether (USDT): https://www.probit.com/app/exchange/ANSR-USDTLiterally, what else could one want? We truly believe that this listing is going to make it so easy for all of us, and make our Token reach greater heights.With all the love and support you guys are offering us, we just love working constantly to make Answerly Token reach above and beyond.As mentioned earlier as well, we’ve also decided to conduct an AMA on Reddit very soon. We’ll love to answer any queries that you may have in this regard or general.Last but not the leastThe best news? Probit is only the second exchange in the line! We’ve almost 4 more listings forthcoming in the month of September only, and on platforms with even higher daily volumes! We’re sure you are going to love it, so stay tuned.Happy listing!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Answerly X Dex-Trade</title>
    <published>2021-09-08T03:30:59+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T03:30:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-x-dex-trade-e1acdc25f372?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-x-dex-trade-e1acdc25f372?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are proud to announce the next big breakthrough for Answerly community: Dex-Trade. Yes, you heard it right; Answerly is coming on your beloved Dex-trade on 8th of September 2021 (00:00 EST). We know many of you are already excited about this listing, but what’s more fascinating is that Dex-Trade exchange handles mighty volumes upwards of $250 Million USD on daily basis.Unmatched LiquidityWith 50+ Cryptocurrencies listed, and with an impressive market share of 0.25%, Dex-trade is an ultimate solution for the entire Answerly and Stellar Community. Being one of the most reputable leader in De-fi World, Dex-Trade is undoubtedly preferred by every crypto enthusiast out there. This Venture will offer unmatched flexibility to $ANSR holders, and through this we can now access better rates and greater options.Answerly Tokens will be available in 5 pairings at Dex-Trade:BTC: https://dex-trade.com/spot/trading/ANSRBTCETH: https://dex-trade.com/spot/trading/ANSRETHUSDT: https://dex-trade.com/spot/trading/ANSRUSDTBUSD: https://dex-trade.com/spot/trading/ANSRBUSDUSDC: https://dex-trade.com/spot/trading/ANSRUSDCThis will allow $ANSR to reach above and beyond, and we promise that it’d be something that you all will adore. At Answerly, our primary aim is to provide our users with ultimate convenience, flexibility and profits; therefore this listing, alongside others forthcoming in the month of September, aim to achieve that goal.As mentioned earlier as well, we are coming soon on Reddit for AMA. We would love to answer any queries you have regarding Dex-Trade listing or Answerly in general.P.S. Stay tuned! There are many more, with even mightier daily volumes in the line.Happy Listing!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Answerly has advanced to the discussion phase of SCF</title>
    <published>2021-08-31T19:57:48+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T19:57:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-has-advanced-to-the-discussion-phase-of-scf-82285b890f11?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-has-advanced-to-the-discussion-phase-of-scf-82285b890f11?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hello Stellar Family,As you may know, the ongoing Stellar Community Fund has advanced to the discussion phase, and now it’s time for the interested community members to check out the core features of the projects.Since Answerly is a pretty big project that took almost 2.5 years for us to reach this point, we highly encourage the Stellar Family and the panel of judges to test Answerly and give your valuable feedback and suggestions.Since Answerly is growing by hundreds of new users every day, we understand that some of you guys may not be aware of the Stellar Community Fund. SCF is an excellent initiative by the Stellar Foundation to fund projects that are utilizing the Stellar blockchain and can help grow its ecosystem. You should definitely check out all details about the ongoing SCF round here — https://discord.gg/KuEucmUXHyWith that being said, we would really appreciate your support for Answerly. You can help us by tweeting an *honest* review about Answerly along with any suggestions that you may have. Let’s make Answerly the best and the biggest Q/A platform.Regards,Raza Rizvi</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">1/6 Listing — Probit exchange | BTC, ETH, USDT pairings</title>
    <published>2021-08-30T02:03:35+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-30T02:03:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/1-6-listing-probit-exchange-btc-eth-usdt-pairings-bd0b8b3ac147?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/1-6-listing-probit-exchange-btc-eth-usdt-pairings-bd0b8b3ac147?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">1/6 Listing — Probit exchange | BTC, ETH, USDT pairingsAnswerly X Probit: Liquidity Like Never BeforeHello Stellar Family,It has been a pretty rewarding week for us, here at Answerly, and we can’t thank Stellar Family enough for making it a huge success. Thus, here we’d like to share with you all one of the biggest breakthrough for Answerly forthcoming- Probit GlobalWe know many of you had speculated our token to be listed on bigger exchanges; hence, we’re very much delighted to inform you all of this new beginning.We’re coming on Probit on 6st September and now Answerly Tokens will be listed on your beloved exchange with a mighty daily volume of $200 Million USD.High Volume, High LiquidityThis listing is the ultimate solution for all your liquidity problems, and will offer Answerly Family incredible flexibility with their tokens. Every crypto-enthusiast is undoubtedly well aware of Probit. But for those who aren’t aware let me tell you that from becoming a premier destination for DeFi tokens to offering minimalistic charges to traders, Probit is a leading player in Exchange World, which is exactly the reason for its high volume activity. With Answerly Tokens listed, we can now access better rates and greater diversity.Pairing?That not it. Answerly will be available in three pairings, particularly with Bitcoin (BTC), Ethereum (ETH) and Tether (USDT). Literally, what else could one want? We truly believe that this listing is going to make it so easy for all of us, and make our Token reach greater heights.Frankly speaking, we can’t wait anymore for 6th of September. This would offer liquidity to all of us like never before. And with all the love and support you guys are offering us, we just love working constantly to make Answerly Token reach above and beyond.As mentioned earlier as well, we’ve also decided to conduct an AMA on Reddit on 5th September 2021. We’ll love to answer any queries that you may have in this regard or general.Last but not the leastThe best news? Probit is only the first one in the line! We’ve almost 5 listings forthcoming in the month of September only, and on platforms with even higher daily volumes! We’re sure you are going to love it, so stay tuned.Happy listing!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Major update about Answerly tokens</title>
    <published>2021-08-26T21:56:26+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T21:56:26+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/major-update-about-answerly-tokens-7cf53b47991c?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/major-update-about-answerly-tokens-7cf53b47991c?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hello Stellar Family,So finally it’s time for the **big news** — or should I say 2 big news. I know most of you guys speculated about Answerly tokens being listed on bigger exchanges and you’ll be glad to know that we also have something to share regarding it — but the actual announcement is much bigger than that. We’ll get to the listing info in a bit.Main NewsSo guys, if you’re currently holding any amount of Answerly tokens ($ANSR), you’ll be amazed to know that you’ve just x50 on your investment *literally*.Let us explain!When we first minted Answerly tokens on the Stellar blockchain, we decided to mint 30 million tokens. Over time, we realized that in order to make the circulating supply more sense, we needed to increase the circulating supply by at least 50 times.As you all know, Answerly is a Questions / Answers platform (similar to Quora) that’s built on the Stellar blockchain. If we take an example from the existing Q/A platforms, these have tens of millions of questions.As of 27th Aug 2021, Quora has over 98 million questions. Previously, Yahoo answers (now defunct) also surpassed over 250 million questions. Considering this, it’s safe to understand that 30 million Answerly tokens won’t be enough to sustain the requirements — unless we start halving the “best answer” rewards at a certain point.After carefully analyzing our options, we decided to increase the total supply of Answerly tokens from 30 million to 1.5 billion (x50 increase). We’ve planned this event for 1st September (00:00 EST) after which we’ll lock the supply so that no more tokens are minted.We will take a snapshot of ANSR token holders on (1st Sep 00:00 EST) and anyone who holds any amount of ANSR will be entitled to x50 more tokens.In simple words, if a person holds 1 ANSR, he will receive +49 more tokens. That’s an instant x50 return. Insane, right?Airdrop participantsOnce we’ve distributed the bonuses to the token holders, we’ll start with airdrop distribution the very same day. Token holders who participate in the airdrop before 1st SEP 00:00 EST will be entitled to x10 bonus. The initial airdrop was set to 10 ANSR per participant but now it’s going to be 100 ANSR.Since the airdrop is ongoing until 15th Sep, anyone who participates after 1st Sep will receive the regular 10 ANSR rewards, so make sure you set up a trustline for Answerly token by then.But wait! That’s not it…We’re proud to announce that we’re considering listing Answerly token on the following exchanges:Probit (~$200,000,000 daily volume)Dex-trade (~$200,000,000 daily volume)Vcc Exchange (~$50,000,000 daily volume)Stex (~$25,000,000 daily volume)Mercatox (~$25,000,000 daily volume)The actual listing dates will be announced in the coming few weeks.As you may know, we’ve also participated in the ongoing Stellar Community Fund. Hopefully, if we make it as one of the winners of this round, our next goal is to list Answerly token on Kucoin. For those who don’t know, Kucoin is considered to be one of the biggest and the most reputable exchanges that we have. The total daily volume ranges around $1.5 billion — $2 billion, so that’s a lot of liquidity for Answerly tokens.We understand that some of you guys may have a lot of questions and for this reason, we’ve also decided to conduct an AMA on Reddit on 5th SEP. We’ll answer any queries that you may have.That’s it for now folks. We’re truly thankful for the immense support that you’ve shown Answerly in the past few weeks. Answerly is on its way to becoming one of the biggest Q/A platforms and you’ll be proud to be a part of it.On a final note, don’t forget to snap up Answerly tokens by 1st Sep to receive an insane bonus of x50. Have a nice day!Regards,Raza Rizvi</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Answerly goals for improving the quality of online information</title>
    <published>2021-08-25T10:11:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T10:11:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-goals-for-improving-the-quality-of-online-information-1c6d87fe28da?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/answerly-goals-for-improving-the-quality-of-online-information-1c6d87fe28da?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Giant Q/A platforms like Quora are used by millions of people around the world to find relevant and accurate information. However, a large percentage of answers on existing Q/A platforms are not just inaccurate but can even be misleading. Moreover, these platforms are also known for containing plagiarized content from other websites and blogs. Finally, the answers that are not plagiarized are often biased or added by digital marketers to drive targeted traffic to their websites.At Answerly, our biggest aim is to improve the quality of information that users find online. To achieve this goal, we have integrated an algorithm on Answerly that automatically detects the quality of the answers by considering the following factors:UniquenessLengthWords countKeywordsGrammarSentence structureNumber of upvotesAlthough our algorithm is powerful enough to safeguard against any type of spam, if any spammy answer somehow bypasses this algorithm, the users can easily report such posts. We are aimed towards improving the quality of information that you find online and also compensate the users (in $ANSR tokens) for writing answers. Let us know if you have any questions regarding Answerly. Good day!Regards,Raza Rizvi</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How does Answerly plan to utilize funds from SCF</title>
    <published>2021-08-24T14:22:06+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-24T14:22:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/how-does-answerly-plan-to-utilize-funds-from-scf-d39c2b53b57c?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://imrazarizvi.medium.com/how-does-answerly-plan-to-utilize-funds-from-scf-d39c2b53b57c?source=rss-cab3d05a7fef------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hello Stellar Family,I thought that it’s important for us to be totally transparent about how we plan to utilize the funds from the ongoing Stellar Community Fund — so here it goes.We are seeking funds that would last us for the next 18 months. By that time, Answerly should self-sustain itself through revenues generated from the platform.Here are the main goals of Answerly in the coming monthsGoal 1: Complete the remaining development — Mobile app, Answerly Pro features, Integrated P2P exchange.Goal 2: Start Answerly video series on YoutubeGoal 3: Improve SEO and SMMGoal 4: Market making for Answerly token on Stellar decentralized exchangeGoal 5: Covering additional expenses: Hosting, Plagiarism check API, buying Answerly.com domain, and migrating the website from Answerly.app to Answerly.comIn-depthGoal 1: Complete the remaining development: Currently we are just a team of 2 people working on Answerly. In order to successfully complete the upcoming tasks, we need funds to hire a total of 8 employees for Social media marketing, Development, Content writing, Designing, etc. This would cost us around $5000 per month. (5000x18 = $90,000).Goal 2: Answerly videos on YT: Total 200 videos (~$125 per video) = $25000.Goal 3: SEO &amp;amp; SMM: $7,500 for guest posting on high-authority websites. This would help us to improve answerly ranking on the search engines. $7,500 for Instagram shoutouts.Goal 4: Additional expenses: Salaries for the core team, hosting costs, plagiarism API cost, buying answerly.com domain name — Everything for $10,000Goal 5: Market making for Answerly token on Sdex $10,000Regards,Raza Rizvi</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
