<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog | Axelar Network</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.axelar.network/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.axelar.network%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=%5Bdata-pf-el%3D%22true%22%5D+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.tagline.clr--grey.m--hide&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.axelar.network%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=%5Bdata-pf-el%3D%22true%22%5D+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.tagline.clr--grey.m--hide&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T21:59:01+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">XION and Axelar Integrate to Enhance Interoperability and Drive Web3 Adoption | Axelar Blog</title>
    <published>2025-04-08T21:59:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-08T21:59:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.axelar.network/blog/burnt-xion-integration</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.axelar.network/blog/burnt-xion-integration"/>
    <content type="html">XION, the first Layer 1 blockchain designed specifically for consumer adoption, has integrated with Axelar, a leading secure interchain communication protocol. This integration enables XION to connect natively with over 70 other blockchains. &amp;quot;The XION blockchain is pioneering a consumer-oriented approach to blockchain-based application platforms,&amp;quot; said Georgios Vlachos, director at Axelar Foundation and co-founder of the Axelar protocol.  “By integrating with Axelar, everyone in Web3 can access a new generation of user-friendly apps – and XION is poised to offer its users unparalleled access to a multitude of blockchain ecosystems.&amp;quot;XION is a next-generation Layer 1 blockchain that simplifies Web3 interactions through its Generalized Abstraction infrastructure. This technology removes technical barriers such as wallet management, private keys, and gas fees, enabling users to engage with blockchain applications as effortlessly as traditional web apps. &amp;quot;Integrating Axelar is an exciting milestone for the XION ecosystem, as it provides seamless interoperability and greater access. ,&amp;quot; said Burnt Banksy, founder of the XION blockchain. &amp;quot;It aligns perfectly with XION’s mission to abstract away the complexities of crypto and make Web3 accessible to everyone.&amp;quot;With the integration of Axelar, XION&amp;#x27;s interoperability extends to 70+ other ecosystems, allowing for seamless cross-chain communication. This expansion unlocks a variety of potential use cases, including:Decentralized Social Platforms: Facilitating secure identity management and content ownership across multiple blockchains.Global Commerce: Enabling borderless payments and programmable loyalty programs without the need to manage multiple wallets or currencies.Blockchain Gaming: Supporting interoperable in-game assets and cross-game progression, enhancing the gaming experience across different blockchain networks.By bridging XION with a diverse array of blockchains, the Axelar integration paves the way for innovative applications that can operate fluidly across ecosystems, driving forward the mainstream adoption of Web3 technologies.About AxelarAxelar is the Web3 interoperability platform, delivering the shortest path to scale: an open stack to connect all blockchains. Adopters include Uniswap, Microsoft and dozens of natively multichain startups with a combined total value locked (TVL) that has crossed $1 billion. Axelar supports a best-in-class developer stack on a cross-chain layer that is open, scalable and secure. Backers include Binance, Coinbase, Dragonfly, Galaxy and Polychain. Learn more: axelar.network. About Axelar FoundationAxelar Foundation is a nonprofit established to support the growth and adoption of the Axelar Network, a decentralized blockchain interoperability platform that connects multiple blockchain ecosystems. Learn more at axelar.foundation.About XIONXION is the first Layer 1 blockchain purpose built for consumer apps, and focused on making Web3 accessible to all internet users. It achieves this by making crypto disappear through its Generalized Abstraction, simplifying complexities such as wallets, private keys, multi-device usage, gas fees, and more. By removing common Web3 friction points, XION accelerates the mainstream adoption of Web3 by making blockchain technology more accessible to users and developers.Website |Blog |Discord |Telegram |Github |LinkedIn |X</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/65f28017eaba8cd1f912fa9f/67f52a63a04e38e00a7c8d76_AXELAR%20_%20Xion%20-%20Axelar%20integration%20banner%20v4%201200x600%20thumbnail.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Interop Labs Joins Linux Foundation Decentralized Trust  | Axelar Blog</title>
    <published>2025-03-18T21:59:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-18T21:59:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.axelar.network/blog/interop-labs-linux-foundation-decentralized-trust</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.axelar.network/blog/interop-labs-linux-foundation-decentralized-trust"/>
    <content type="html">LF Decentralized Trust, the open-source foundation for decentralized technologies established by the Linux Foundation, announced today that Interop Labs has joined as a member of the Trust.&amp;quot;Open-source approaches will be essential in the next phase of blockchain development, and the Axelar community has shown a strong commitment to building an open-source stack,&amp;quot; said Sergey Gorbunov, CEO of Interop Labs and co-founder of Axelar Protocol. &amp;quot;We at Interop Labs are proud to support the Linux Foundation and LF Decentralized Trust to advance transparency, reliability, security and efficiency in future iterations of the internet.&amp;quot;Interop Labs is a systems and product development company dedicated to enabling an open, interconnected Web – and is the initial developer and a core contributor to the Axelar network, a leading blockchain interoperability protocol.Recently, Interop Labs Head of Legal, Jason Rozovsky, presented to the LF Decentralized Trust community at a workshop meeting hosted by Kinexys by J.P. Morgan. The talk, &amp;quot;Connection Without Custody: Axelar and Multichain Security,&amp;quot; focused on the security and compliance advantages inherent in open-source and noncustodial blockchain interoperability. &amp;quot;Decentralization is the key attribute driving institutional interest in blockchain networks. From a business perspective, decentralization provides censorship-resistant asset storage and transfer, strengthening security,&amp;quot; Rozovsky said. &amp;quot;From a policy perspective, decentralization ensures that infrastructure remains insulated from risks associated with centralized intermediaries. We at Interop Labs are looking forward to contributing to the Linux Foundation and LF Decentralized Trust from the perspective of a decentralized interoperability builder.&amp;quot;Rozovsky and noted blockchain legal expert Lewis Rinaudo Cohen, partner at Cahill Gordon and co-chair of CahillNXT, co-authored a white paper on how decentralized blockchains can represent not a threat, but an opportunity and a paradigm shift for regulators. Download and read the white paper at axelar.network/new-regulatory-paradigm.LF Decentralized Trust has gathered a global roster of leaders and major institutions in finance and technology: Mastercard, the Depository Trust and Clearing Corporation (DTCC), Ripple, the Ethereum Foundation and several central banks – to name a few. Interop Labs joins this group at the forefront of defining the resilience and security of critical systems that will reshape markets and transform industries for a digital-first economy.About AxelarAxelar is the Web3 interoperability platform, delivering the shortest path to scale: an open stack to connect all blockchains. Adopters include Uniswap, Microsoft and dozens of natively multichain startups with a combined total value locked (TVL) that has crossed $1 billion. Axelar supports a best-in-class developer stack on a cross-chain layer that is open, scalable and secure. Backers include Binance, Coinbase, Dragonfly, Galaxy and Polychain. Learn more: axelar.network. About Interop LabsInterop Labs is a systems and product development company dedicated to enabling an open, interconnected Web. The company was founded in 2021 on the belief that open-source, heterogeneous, interconnected systems have the power to nurture innovation and creativity for the betterment of all humankind. Interop Labs builds, invests in and incubates innovative projects pushing the boundaries of blockchain interoperability, cryptography and machine learning – including as a core contributor to the Axelar network, a leading interoperability protocol. Learn more: interoplabs.io.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/65f28017eaba8cd1f912fa9f/67d96351e7916ca8fb2f35ea_AXELAR_SocialPost_Interops%2BLFD_1920x1080c_V3%20small.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Axelar Integrates Elys Blockchain | Axelar Blog</title>
    <published>2025-03-13T21:59:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-13T21:59:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.axelar.network/blog/axelar-integrates-elys-blockchain</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.axelar.network/blog/axelar-integrates-elys-blockchain"/>
    <content type="html">Elys, a DeFi platform built on the Cosmos ecosystem, is integrating with Axelar Network to scale its vision of better DeFi user experience (UX) enabled by chain abstraction and unified liquidity. Elys has created a DeFi hub across the Cosmos ecosystem, providing staking, swaps, liquidity mining and leveraged LP across top Cosmos assets. They’re also developing key features like a perp DEX, perpetual orderbook, and prediction market. The goal is simple: access every DeFi tool you need, all in one place, across every ecosystem.To date, the platform has $3.3 million in TVL and has handled $17 million in volume over the past year (source).Elys takes a holistic platform approach, featuring innovations such as account abstraction and smart-shielded pools to tackle challenges like impermanent loss, arbitrage inefficiencies, slippage, and high fees. Elys is changing the way DeFi users engage, uniting fragmented liquidity and pioneering a user experience that is smoother and more rewarding. &amp;quot;The Cosmos ecosystem provides incredible technology to enable specialized blockchains like Elys to focus on what they do best – it&amp;#x27;s the same reason we chose to build Axelar using Cosmos SDK,&amp;quot; said Georgios Vlachos, Axelar Foundation director and Axelar protocol co-founder. &amp;quot;Now that they have found product-market fit, Axelar is here to help them scale beyond the Cosmos and deliver their innovation to Web3 at large.&amp;quot; “Cosmos was designed to be the Internet of Blockchains, and Axelar is extending that vision across every ecosystem in Web3. That’s why we chose to build within the Cosmos ecosystem – it&amp;#x27;s the best place to connect with every network while allowing us to create a chain tailored to our needs using the Cosmos SDK,&amp;quot; said Hesham Aly, co-founder of Elys Network. &amp;quot;Every road will lead to the Cosmos ecosystem, and Elys Network will make it seamless for anyone to own, use and trade whatever they want.”About AxelarAxelar is the Web3 interoperability platform, delivering the shortest path to scale: an open stack to connect all blockchains. Adopters include Uniswap, Microsoft and dozens of natively multichain startups with a combined total value locked (TVL) that has crossed $1 billion. Axelar supports a best-in-class developer stack on a cross-chain layer that is open, scalable and secure. Backers include Binance, Coinbase, Dragonfly, Galaxy and Polychain. Learn more: axelar.network. About ElysElys Network is a layer 1 blockchain that brings a suite of DeFi products and features fueled by wallet and chain abstraction. It empowers both novice and pro users to easily manage their assets and put them to work across multiple chains on a single platform. Elys Network aims to open the floodgates for everyone—allowing users to buy, trade, and utilize crypto and RWAs, making their assets work for them and building their wealth on-chain, minus the complexity. Learn more: Elys.network‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/65f28017eaba8cd1f912fa9f/67d2fed7a5f5ad784d8660ca_axelar-elys-banner-12Mar2025%20small.jpg"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
