<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog | Beans App</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beansapp.com/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.beansapp.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fpost%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.cms-content-wrap&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.cms-info-block+.cms-info&amp;date_format=M+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=1&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.beansapp.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fpost%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.cms-content-wrap&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.cms-info-block+.cms-info&amp;date_format=M+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=1&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T21:59:41+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Native Bitcoin Deposits to Beans are Live!</title>
    <published>2024-03-06T21:59:41+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-03-06T21:59:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.beansapp.com/post/native-bitcoin-deposits-to-beans-are-live</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beansapp.com/post/native-bitcoin-deposits-to-beans-are-live"/>
    <content type="html">Are you tired of the hassle of explaining Bitcoin to your friends every time you want to make a payment, only to find out they prefer fiat currency? Say goodbye to the inconvenience with Beans! Our non-custodial wallet is designed for those who are new to the world of crypto. Now, you can send BTC while your non-crypto friend receives their preferred currency – all with zero fees, starting with as little as 0.01 USD worth of BTC. It&amp;#x27;s the perfect solution for seamless transactions between crypto and fiat!‍Fee-less BTC TransactionsBitcoin has done great as a store of value, but casual payments are still hard because of the lack of interoperability, high fees, and slow transaction times. Whilst there are alternatives being worked on, it&amp;#x27;s still hard to convince your non-crypto friends to receive BTC.This is what we have fixed with this update in the Beans App! Beans is a non-custodial wallet built for people who don&amp;#x27;t know anything about blockchain. In Beans, you can now deposit BTC and pay your friend who prefers fiat. The app automatically converts BTC to their preferred currency at zero fee, starting as low as 0.01 USD. Your friends can then re-send to someone else or withdraw to their bank or in cash.‍The Power of BlockchainThrough Beans, anyone who receives money converted from BTC can withdraw seamlessly to their bank or in cash. Did they choose to receive in BTC as well? You can also withdraw your Bitcoin from the Beans app directly to your Bitcoin address!‍Buy Cheap BitcoinMost direct Bitcoin buying and selling services charge large withdrawal and deposit fees when you want to buy BTC. Especially for small amounts, this can really limit your ability to buy and sell bitcoin profitably. With Beans, you can buy and sell your BTC against very low fees by first depositing EUR or USD to your account. Swap it for Bitcoin and receive the best rate available. This will save a lot of money when you want to buy or sell your $BTC!‍Beans as a Layer-2Bitcoin is a great way to store value away from any regulated currency. You are sure that a BTC is still a BTC in the future, which gives it a unique advantage over any of the other currencies out there. However, to achieve mass adoption Bitcoin still has a long way to go. Getting started with Blockchain is not very beginner-friendly, and the high fees you pay for making transactions disregard any real-world uses. By depositing BTC to Beans you can transact for free, and really put your Bitcoin to good use! No knowledge of the blockchain is required, and no fees to be paid. This is how we imagine Bitcoin will reach mass adoption!‍Try it yourself by dowloading the beansapp at https://beansapp.com/download!‍Blokchain Development</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/642fb32de87a480d2780843d/65e8649b7edbb7686c018288_whalestack.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">New deposit options with KADO!</title>
    <published>2024-01-26T21:59:41+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-01-26T21:59:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.beansapp.com/post/new-deposit-options-with-kado</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beansapp.com/post/new-deposit-options-with-kado"/>
    <content type="html">A new partnership!We are super excited to announce yet another partnership, this time with Kado! They will allow deposits through Debit, &amp;amp; creditcard,  ACH, and many more local bank options in the Beans app!‍Beans app is steadily building up a network of deposit and withdrawal partners that improve currency choices, ease of use, and deposit and withdrawal options! Beans, a non-custodial wallet built on Stellar, will work with Kado to achieve a streamlined in-app experience to deposit to your Beans account!‍New deposit options!We are super excited to start this collaboration with Kado. With Kado as a partner, we are now able to offer new deposit options in many different countries! Deposit options vary from debit- and credit card deposits available in previously unsupported countries, as well as ACH bank transfers in the United States of America and PIX bank transfer support in Brazil! ‍ACH deposits in the USA!The services from Kado improve the available deposit options in Beans for almost all our users, as well as provide the option for US users to deposit through a bank transfer with ACH. This is especially exciting for our American friends, as this means it’s now fast and cheap to send from the USA to for example Argentina, Brazil, Europe or Nigeria via bank, or almost the whole world in cash. For example, when sending 100 USD to Brazil by bank, users end up with over 4% more compared to Wise at this time.*To find a list of all supported countries and available deposit options please take a look at this list; www.beansapp.com/#countries‍Low fees, better ratesKado&amp;#x27;s strength is to provide a fast and easy deposit process, whilst also offering very competitive rates. Kado offers a competitive rate between the open market and their own offer, with only a small variable fee to process each transaction. This means that it&amp;#x27;s now even cheaper to send money internationally or on-ramp into crypto.For the actual rates please visit the Beans app and choose deposit &amp;gt; USD &amp;gt; Bank transfer &amp;gt; Kado, or visit beansapp.com.In the endWe are super excited to have Kado on Beans and be able to offer our users so many new deposit options. Having Kado as a new partner will allow you to find the best rates against the cheapest fees, and promote a healthy form of competition between our partners. That will ultimately benefit our users with lower fees and better rates! We hope that our users will start and take benefit from this new partnership, and we&amp;#x27;re excited to offer this service to users that weren&amp;#x27;t able to have these deposit options before!* Rates at 31 january 2024Blokchain Development</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/642fb32de87a480d2780843d/65ba3512e80f1395d2af84ba_kado.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Beans Joins Hands with Stellar to Support Casa Tochan&amp;#x27;s Shelter!</title>
    <published>2023-12-10T21:59:41+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-10T21:59:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.beansapp.com/post/beans-joins-hands-with-stellar-to-support-casa-tochans-shelter</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beansapp.com/post/beans-joins-hands-with-stellar-to-support-casa-tochans-shelter"/>
    <content type="html">At Beans we always strive to make a positive impact on people&amp;#x27;s lives. That is why we&amp;#x27;re thrilled to announce our participation in an extraordinary initiative hosted by the Stellar Foundation and Friends With Benefits (FWB) initiative, aimed at supporting the Casa Tochan&amp;#x27;s migrant shelter.This collaboration shows the potential of blockchain technology and the humanitarian spirit driving Stellar and the Stellar Disbursement Platform (SDP). Stellar and FWB are utilizing the capabilities of Beans to create meaningful change for Casa Tochan, a shelter that provides essential support and refuge to those facing hardship.Channeling support for Casa TochanThe Stellar Disbursement Platform, in partnership with FWB, is hosting an aid event leveraging the Beans wallet. Through this event, funds are being raised and disbursed directly to Casa Tochan&amp;#x27;s shelter. This is not just about financial aid; it&amp;#x27;s about providing safety, care, and, most importantly, love to those in need. Casa Tochan serves as a sanctuary for individuals encountering various challenges, offering not just a safe space but also crucial resources. Through this collaborative effort, Beans is leveraged to contribute to this mission of compassion and support!Making financial services accessible for allAt the core of the Beans ethos lies a commitment to making financial services universally accessible. Our platform offers a simple, user-friendly interface enabling users to access free payments and secure, high-yield savings options.For Casa Tochan, Beans plays an even bigger pivotal role. It allows the shelter to receive funds instantly, without incurring any transaction fees and without the need for a traditional bank. This direct and cost-effective method ensures that every donation goes where it&amp;#x27;s needed the most – supporting the shelter&amp;#x27;s crucial operations.A step towards global changeProviding the resources in this initiative fills us with gratitude, and being a part of this noble cause isn&amp;#x27;t just about financial transactions either; it&amp;#x27;s about being the catalysts for positive change and improving lives on a global scale.We&amp;#x27;d love to thank the Stellar Foundation, FWB, and every individual contributing to this humanitarian cause. Together, we&amp;#x27;re showcasing the incredible potential of technology as a force for good, creating meaningful impacts and hope for those who need it the most.Blockchain</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/642fb32de87a480d2780843d/65764208f769c6a9a2855b67_fwb%20partner%20v2.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
