<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog | Bitt</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bitt.com/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bitt.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.entries+a&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bitt.com%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%23content+.container&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date+p&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bitt.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.entries+a&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bitt.com%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%23content+.container&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date+p&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:00:31+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Bitt launches advisory services, drawing upon its industry-leading experience in deploying multiple CBDCs | Bitt</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:00:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:00:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.bitt.com/blog/bitt-launches-advisory-services-drawing-upon-its-industry-leading-experience-in-deploying-multiple-cbdcs</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bitt.com/blog/bitt-launches-advisory-services-drawing-upon-its-industry-leading-experience-in-deploying-multiple-cbdcs"/>
    <content type="html">                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    Bitt launches advisory services, drawing upon its industry-leading experience in deploying multiple CBDCs                                                                                                                                                                                                 The Bitt Team recently attended the CBDC Conference in Istanbul on September 12-14, as Gold Sponsors, connecting with partners, clients, and allies in the space to contribute to the advancement of CBDC technology, design, and implementation. Our COO, Imran Khan, presenting on “Adapting to the Changing Needs of Central Banks” in the plenary session noted that:  “Bitt’s experience has shown that central bank motivations and approach to CBDCs are evolving, influenced by the changing economic environment, competing central bank priorities, and learnings from other CBDC deployments. We advocate the CBDC ecosystem, and especially the innovators in this space, to broaden services and products to meet central banks where they are in their journey today. We need to get creative and find ways to answer these open questions, to help our clients forward in their CBDC journey.”  To better align with central banks’ current needs, Bitt is thrilled to officially launch its new offering: Bitt Advisory Services. Having executed digital currency rollouts in 12 countries with multiple central banks, regulators, financial institutions, payment service providers, merchants and retail users, including the largest deployment in a democratic country to date, the team at Bitt has unparalleled experience in comprehensive digital currency solutions and strategy, and are now offering Bitt Advisory Services to monetary authorities, governments, and financial institutions.   Navigating the Future of Digital Currency with Bitt  In the dynamic world of digital currency, central banks, regulators, governments, and financial institutions alike are seeking support in developing a comprehensive and multifaceted strategy for deploying and utilizing digital currencies. To effectively execute a digital currency strategy, organization-wide coordination is required in addition to the delegation of key responsibilities to existing team members and new hires. Furthermore, communications are essential to the success of a digital currency rollout and involve many stakeholder types, each with unique requirements and concerns. An impact assessment is critical to not only understand the risks associated with the introduction of digital currency, but to also understand the technical and operational requirements for risk mitigation, and integration with the legacy financial system.  At Bitt, we understand that national digital currencies – particularly in the form of Central Bank Digital Currencies (CBDCs) and stablecoins – are more than just a technological innovation; they are a transformative force with the potential to reshape economies and redefine financial ecosystems. Their success requires extensive collaboration from stakeholders within the monetary authority and regulators, as well as the many financial services entities and infrastructure providers that comprise our financial system today. As monetary authorities progress in their CBDC journey, they require expert input to ensure that lessons learned from similar deployments, and operating experience, are incorporated in their strategy. Bitt’s team of experts recognized this need and were motivated to launch Bitt Advisory Services, some of which are outlined below.   A Vision Unveiled: Identifying Use Cases and Stakeholders  Identifying the myriad of use cases that can be serviced by a CBDC or stablecoin is a critical component to any digital currency strategy. Analyzing pain points in existing payment streams, determining opportunities for increased efficacy, decreased settlement time, and other user experience advantages can help inform a successful digital currency strategy that will deliver value to both the transacting public and the system operators. Our experts will work closely with you to create detailed descriptions of each use case while meticulously identifying all stakeholders who will partake in and play a role in the payment streams.   Navigating the Terrain: Analysis of the Existing Financial System  Understanding how the existing interconnected financial system functions, especially in the context of the introduction of a new digital currency payment rail, is paramount to a successful digital currency implementation. Financial stability is core to the mandate of the monetary authority and is the primary concern when making decisions or implementing strategies that could have an impact. Financial stability risks are derived from many factors including policy, governance, technology, and more, resulting in complex scenarios that require extensive analysis and consideration. Bitt’s team has gained valuable experience from designing, developing, and deploying the Digital Currency Management System (DCMS) in multiple countries, and integrating the solution with existing financial system infrastructure and services. A core element of Bitt Advisory Services includes a comprehensive analysis, where our experts meticulously map out the landscape of your domestic financial system   Plotting the Course: Developing a Go-To-Market Strategy  Launching a CBDC is more than just creating a digital currency; it's about shaping a future where users adopt it to solve tangible problems and create new opportunities for secure, efficient, and user-friendly transactions. Collaboration with the private sector is critical to achieve the many benefits stated in digital currency research over the past ~7 years. CBDCs and stablecoins are platforms on which a multitude of payment service providers integrate to offer unique and valuable payment services to the public. Integrating with a common network reduces settlement time and cost, further freeing up liquidity that can be put to use for productive efforts. Bitt’s team of experts recognize the variety of factors present in developing and executing a collaborative strategy with the private sector, and stand ready to assist monetary authorities from advisory and technology solution perspectives.   Building Trust: Communications Strategy  In the ever-evolving digital currency landscape, trustworthiness is paramount. In a time fraught with skepticism due to difficult economic conditions, privacy concerns, abuses of power, and other issues, monetary authorities must ensure they are transparent about the nature and functionality of their digital currency system. Providing clear and concise assurances to the transacting public regarding the nature of their digital currency platform will spur users to trust the solution and bolster adoption.   Seamless Transformation: Organizational Change Management  Rolling out a digital currency platform places additional responsibilities on the monetary authority, and often demands additional personnel to fill new roles that intersect technology and policy. Bitt has a longstanding history of collaboration with central banks and financial institutions, and we recognize the substantial impact, effort, and stress associated with the implementation of a digital currency platform. New procedures will need to be developed, existing procedures will require revision, and organizational structure will change. Our team offers experienced insight into how best to address your digital currency operational requirements, and will guide your institution in implementing an effective, transparent, and functional digital currency management strategy.   Navigating the Landscape: Regulatory &amp;amp; Legal  Understanding the political environment in the context of digital currencies is complicated and crucial to ensure a comprehensive strategy. We'll help you navigate the headwinds and tailwinds, and provide insight regarding best practices for successfully launching a digital currency. Additionally, we'll conduct a rigorous legal assessment, differentiating between legislation and compliance, and addressing data protection concerns. Our legal professionals have decades of experience in governance, privacy, and international statutory assessment. They can demystify any legal quandaries associated with implementing a digital currency platform.  Bitt's Professional Advisory Services represent more than just a service offering; they signify a partnership in unlocking the future of digital currency. The future of digital currency is unfolding before us, and together, we can shape it with expertise, innovation, and dedication to high standards.  For more information on Bitt Advisory Services, please reach out to us at [email&amp;#160;protected] or visit www.bitt.com/advisory-services.      </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Bitt Shortlisted for National Bank of Georgia’s CBDC Pilot | Bitt</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:00:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:00:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.bitt.com/blog/bitt-shortlisted-for-national-bank-of-georgias-cbdc-pilot</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bitt.com/blog/bitt-shortlisted-for-national-bank-of-georgias-cbdc-pilot"/>
    <content type="html">                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    Bitt Shortlisted for National Bank of Georgia’s CBDC Pilot                                                                                                                                                                                                 Bitt has signed an MOU with the National Bank of Georgia which has led the global company to be shortlisted as the technology partner for the National Bank of Georgia’s (NBG) central bank digital currency (CBDC) pilot program. Georgia, a country with a fast-growing economy and Gross Domestic Product of over $18.6B (2021), is advancing to test critical functional components of CBDC technologies. According to the NBG, Bitt was shortlisted because the company “demonstrated sufficient technology potential, maturity, capacity, relevant experience, and desire to join our on-field exploration.” Bitt’s track record of successful development and implementation of CBDCs in other countries includes the world’s largest democratic CBDC deployment and the first for a multinational monetary union. The company has also been awarded for its ability to provide secure and reliable offline solutions that meet the needs of central banks and financial institutions. “We are thrilled to have been shortlisted as the technology partner for the NBG's CBDC pilot program,” said Brian Popelka, CEO of Bitt. “As a company that has been at the forefront of financial technology for several years, we are confident that we can help the NBG achieve its goals of modernizing the country's payment system and reducing the costs associated with cash circulation.” The NBG is exploring the possibility of introducing a CBDC to modernize the country's financial ecosystem while reducing the costs associated with cash circulation. As part of its efforts, the NBG invited proposals from companies to act as technology partners for the CBDC pilot program. If selected as a technology partner for the Pilot project, Bitt would work closely with the NBG to contribute to the development and implementation of a secure and reliable CBDC infrastructure that meets the needs of the country's central bank and citizens. See more information from the Bank of Georgia’s website here.     </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Bitt Appoints Imran Khan as Chief Operating Officer | Bitt</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:00:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:00:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.bitt.com/blog/bitt-appoints-imran-khan-as-chief-operating-officer</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bitt.com/blog/bitt-appoints-imran-khan-as-chief-operating-officer"/>
    <content type="html">                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    Bitt Appoints Imran Khan as Chief Operating Officer                                                                                                                                                                                                 Salt Lake City, July 10, 2023 — Bitt, the world's leading provider of Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC) solutions, is pleased to announce the appointment of Imran Khan as its new Chief Operating Officer (COO). With an outstanding track record in technology leadership roles, Imran Khan brings a wealth of experience and expertise that will further strengthen Bitt's position as the premier CBDC solution company globally.  Imran Khan spent a decade at Deloitte, where he chaired Deloitte's Global CBDC Committee, driving transformative advancements in digital currencies on a global scale. In his previous role as EVP of Partnerships at Bitt, he played a pivotal role in fostering strategic collaborations with leading industry players. These collaborations were particularly highlighted in global CBDC competitions, where Bitt secured the first-place ranking in 2022 in the Financial Inclusion category.  Brian Popelka, CEO of Bitt, expressed his enthusiasm regarding Imran’s appointment, stating, "We are thrilled to welcome Imran Khan as our new Chief Operating Officer. With his exceptional leadership and expertise, he has been instrumental in delivering groundbreaking solutions to our central bank clients, including the Central Bank of Nigeria. Imran’s strategic partnerships have played a crucial role in positioning Bitt as the industry leader. With him joining the senior executive team, we are confident that Bitt will continue its trajectory of success, propelling us to new heights in the world of CBDC and stablecoin solutions."  With a vision for continued innovation, Bitt remains dedicated to digitizing national currencies and fostering financial inclusion worldwide.  With his extensive experience and strategic mindset, Imran Khan is well-positioned to further elevate Bitt's market presence.  About Bitt  Bitt is a global financial technology company that provides digital currency solutions to central banks, financial institutions, and ecosystem participants worldwide. Bitt’s Digital Currency Management System (DCMS) is the secure infrastructure that monetary authorities need to deploy CBDCs, and for financial institutions to integrate digital currencies into their financial service offerings. Bitt’s DCMS has been deployed in 12 countries across Africa, Central America, Europe, and the Caribbean. Bitt is a portfolio company of Medici Ventures, L.P., a blockchain-focused fund. Overstock is a limited partner in the Medici Ventures Fund, L.P. The general partner of that fund is an entity affiliated with Pelion Venture Partners.  About Overstock  Overstock.com, Inc. (NASDAQ:OSTK) is an online furniture and home furnishings retailer and technology-focused innovator based in Salt Lake City, Utah. Its leading e-commerce website sells a broad range of new home products at low prices, including furniture, décor, area rugs, bedding and bath, home improvement, and more. The online shopping site features millions of products that tens of millions of customers visit each month. Overstock regularly posts information about the Company and other related matters on the Newsroom and Investor Relations pages on its website, Overstock.com.  O, Overstock.com, O.com, and Club O are registered trademarks of Overstock.com, Inc. Overstock and Making Dream Homes Come True are trademarks of Overstock.com, Inc. Other service marks, trademarks and trade names which may be referred to herein are the property of their respective owners.  About Pelion  Pelion Venture Partners is an early-stage venture capital firm. Currently investing out of their seventh fund, Pelion invests in Seed and Series A software companies across the United States.      </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
