<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog | Bitwave - Digital Asset Accounting Software</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bitwave.io/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bitwave.io%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bfs-toc-element%3D%22contents%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=time&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bitwave.io%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bfs-toc-element%3D%22contents%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=time&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:00:53+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Stablecoin Payments House – An Executive Event with Bitwave &amp;amp; Aleo</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:00:53+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:00:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.bitwave.io/blog/the-stablecoin-payments-house---an-executive-event-with-bitwave-aleo</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bitwave.io/blog/the-stablecoin-payments-house---an-executive-event-with-bitwave-aleo"/>
    <author>
      <name>Kaleb Leija</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">As Consensus brings the crypto community together in Toronto, Bitwave and Aleo are hosting something truly special just a few blocks away.We’re excited to announce The Stablecoin Payments House — an executive event designed to accelerate stablecoin adoption across institutional and enterprise finance. 🗓 Tuesday, May 13, 2025 📍 Toronto – The Historic Bishop’s Block neighborhood‍ ⏰ 4:45 – 8:00 PM ET‍→ Apply to Join​ (Pre-approval on Luma required for entry. Space is limited.)‍A New Standard for Enterprise PaymentsThere’s a massive disruption underway in B2B payments. Legacy systems are slow, costly, and built for a pre-digital era. Businesses are stuck with outdated rails that siphon away time, capital, and control.Stablecoin payments change that.The Stablecoin Payments House will bring together fintech founders, CFOs, and other finance leaders for a powerful evening of panels and conversations focused on real-world adoption. This is your opportunity to connect with the people building the payment infrastructure of tomorrow.→ About Bitwave Stablecoin Payments‍What to Expect We&amp;#x27;re serving up premium programming with leading voices in blockchain payments along with cocktails and bites at one of Toronto’s most iconic venues – just blocks from the Consensus event center.Registration &amp;amp; Cocktails: 4:45-5:15PM ET​Keynote &amp;amp; Panel: 5:15–6 PM ET​Happy Hour: 6–8 PM ET​Expect insight-packed panels and real conversations about:Enterprise Use-Cases for Stablecoins – How forward-thinking companies are using digital dollars today‍Legal &amp;amp; Compliance Frameworks – What CFOs and compliance leads need to know to safely adopt on-chain payments‍The Modern CFO Stack – Privacy, efficiency, and compliance in a multi-chain, programmable finance world​Speakers include Howard Wu (Founder, Aleo &amp;amp; Provable) and Pat White (CEO, Bitwave)… and more to be announced soon!‍See You In TorontoAt Bitwave, we believe stablecoin payments are the next frontier of enterprise finance. We can’t wait to share this future with you at The Stablecoin Payments House. ​This intimate event is open to fintech founders, finance leaders, and other innovators looking to accelerate the adoption of stablecoin payments. Apply now to connect with other innovators defining the future of money movement.Pre-approval on Luma required for entry. Space is limited.‍→ Apply to Join‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/64c568d103c4e2da8755c388/67f95117ea898d22b4deca10_Stablecoin-Payments-House-2025---Luma-Header-(1200x630).png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Stablecoin Invoices: The Untapped AR Superpower for Working Capital Efficiency</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:00:53+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:00:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.bitwave.io/blog/stablecoin-invoicing</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bitwave.io/blog/stablecoin-invoicing"/>
    <author>
      <name>Amy Kalnoki</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Finance leaders like you know the drill: send an invoice to a customer, wait 30, 60, maybe even 90 days to get paid, while your cash is basically held hostage. Meanwhile, you still need to pay your suppliers, make payroll, and keep the lights on. It&amp;#x27;s the age-old working capital squeeze that keeps founders and CFOs up at night.‍But there&amp;#x27;s a way to transform this cash flow nightmare. ‍Enter stablecoin invoicing – the financial innovation that can multiply your working capital efficiency by orders of magnitude.‍Sounds too good to be true? Let&amp;#x27;s break it down. ‍The Working Capital Problem for AR TeamsBefore diving into the solution, let&amp;#x27;s face the problem: traditional payment systems are painfully inefficient. ‍Your money gets stuck in multiple places:Waiting for customers to pay (average 45-day DSO)Sitting in &amp;quot;payments processing&amp;quot; limbo for daysGetting eaten up by transaction feesLocked in &amp;quot;just in case&amp;quot; reserves‍For international business, it&amp;#x27;s even worse – add forex fees, additional delays, and more uncertainty.‍→ Read: “B2B Payments Are Broken”‍What Are Stablecoins and Why Should You Care?Not all digital assets are created equal. While some crypto tokens, like Bitcoin, can have daily value fluctuations, stablecoins are a completely different class. ‍Stablecoins (like USDC or USDT) are digital currencies designed to maintain a stable 1:1 value with traditional assets like the US dollar. They are often backed by various reserves, like cash, treasuries, or gold to give business a high degree of confidence and trust. ‍Unlike traditional crypto, stablecoins give you the best of both worlds: the stability of fiat currency with the speed, efficiency, and programmability of blockchain technology.‍Show Me The NumbersLet&amp;#x27;s look at a real-world example of a mid-sized manufacturing company with $10M was able to achieve a 10X improvement to their AR efficiency. Traditional System:‍$1.23M tied up in receivables (45-day payment terms)$83K stuck in payment processing limbo$250K lost to processing fees annually$120K wasted on international payment fees$150K sitting idle in &amp;quot;safety&amp;quot; reserves‍Total annual working capital requirement: $1.65MStablecoin System:‍$411K in receivables (reduced to 15-day terms via incentives)Just $1.2K in settlement limbo (10-minute vs. 3-day settlement)Only $30K in transaction fees$0 in additional international fees$30K in safety reserves (predictable timing = smaller buffer)Plus $28K in yield earned on stablecoin holdings‍Total annual working capital requirement: $444K‍That&amp;#x27;s already a 3.7x improvement in direct capital requirements! But the story doesn&amp;#x27;t end there.‍When we factor in capital velocity – how many times you can redeploy the same capital throughout the year – we see another massive efficiency gain:‍     Working Capital Efficiency Calculation                   Base Efficiency Improvement: 3.7x (from direct capital requirement reduction)         Capital Velocity Improvement: 2.7x (from increased reinvestment cycles)     Combined Effect: 3.7 × 2.7 = 9.99x improvement               And that's not even counting additional benefits like automated contract execution, improved discount capture rates, and reduced operational costs!  ‍Stablecoins enable faster, more cost-efficient invoice payments for global businesses. ‍Breaking It All Down 1. Death to the FloatWith traditional banking, your money spends days in purgatory during the &amp;quot;settlement&amp;quot; process. That&amp;#x27;s 2-5 business days where your cash is literally nowhere – not in your account, not in your supplier&amp;#x27;s account, just... floating.‍And, traditional payment processors use this float to generate interest on these payments for themselves.. ‍Stablecoin transactions settle in minutes, not days. That time difference alone creates a 5-10x efficiency for capital in transit.2. Slash Processing CostsPopular payment processors charge 2-5% of transaction value plus fixed fees. With stablecoins, you&amp;#x27;re looking at 0.1-0.5% – that&amp;#x27;s up to 90% cost reduction, freeing up substantial capital.3. Your Money Working for You, Not the BankWhile traditional banks give you virtually 0% interest on business accounts, stablecoin holdings can be deployed in DeFi protocols earning 5-15% APY while maintaining liquidity.‍That&amp;#x27;s right – your working capital can actually generate returns instead of sitting idle.4. Smart Contracts = Smart MoneyStablecoins enable programmable money through smart contracts. This means you can automate:Early payment discounts (like “2% off” if paid within 5 days)Milestone-based partial paymentsRecurring payment schedules‍These capabilities can dramatically improve discount capture rates by 2-3x.5. Capital Velocity on SteroidsPerhaps the biggest multiplier is how quickly you can redeploy capital. ‍With traditional 45-90 day payment terms, your capital might complete 4-8 cycles per year. Stablecoin invoicing can increase this to 12-24 cycles annually – a 3x improvement in capital efficiency.6. International Business Without the International HeadachesIf you do business globally, you&amp;#x27;re losing 3-5% on forex fees and waiting 3-7 extra days for cross-border payments. Stablecoins work identically worldwide, creating a potential 15-20x efficiency boost for your international operations.‍AR Stablecoin Payments with Bitwave‍Bitwave makes onchain invoicing as easy as traditional billing – all with enterprise-grade security and compliance.‍Our platform allows you to quickly generate and send crypto invoices directly to your customers with automated tracking and compliance. Instantly match invoices to the right wallet and token, enabling fast, safe payments with complete transparency.‍The Bitwave Payment Network is being created to help you find businesses that want to get paid in crypto.‍And the best part? There’s no cost to receive payments through Bitwave. Unlike traditional rails, we don’t take a cut of your funds or delay settlement. What your customer sends is what you get. 100%.‍We know that security is important, so every transaction tracked in Bitwave is backed by SOC 1 Type 2 and SOC 2 Type 2 protocols. Know exactly when payments are sent, where they’re going, and when they arrive.‍→ Read about Stablecoin AR Payments‍How to Get StartedIf you&amp;#x27;re convinced (and you should be), here&amp;#x27;s how to begin implementing stablecoin invoicing:‍Set up a business wallet – Platforms like Circle, Coinbase, or Fireblocks offer business-grade solutionsChoose your stablecoin – USDC, USDT, and DAI are popular USD-pegged optionsIntegrate with Bitwave for accounting – Bitwave seamlessly connects your crypto transactions with traditional accounting systems, handling the complexity of digital asset bookkeeping automaticallyStart with a pilot – Test with a few trusted customers or vendorsOffer incentives – Provide discounts for customers who pay in stablecoinsDocument the savings – Track the before/after metrics‍The Bottom LineWorking capital efficiency isn&amp;#x27;t just a finance metric – it&amp;#x27;s the lifeblood of business growth. By implementing stablecoin invoicing with Bitwave, you&amp;#x27;re not making an incremental improvement; you&amp;#x27;re completely transforming your capital efficiency by an order of magnitude.‍The companies that adopt this approach early will have a significant competitive advantage – being able to grow faster, invest more in innovation, and weather financial storms better than competitors still stuck in the old banking paradigm.‍What makes Bitwave essential in this transformation is how it bridges your digital asset operations with traditional finance systems. While stablecoins provide the speed and efficiency, Bitwave ensures you can track, manage, and report on these transactions without creating an accounting nightmare.‍Major players – like Coinbase – are already leading the way and using Bitwave to improve their billing efficiency with stablecoins. This approach isn&amp;#x27;t theoretical, but actively delivering results for industry leaders.‍Ready to transform your working capital efficiency? ‍Book a demo with Bitwave today to see how your specific business could benefit from stablecoin invoicing while maintaining accounting integrity and compliance.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/64c568d103c4e2da8755c388/67f58111e25b948c64a3ec09_bitwave-stablecoin-invoicing.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Are Stablecoins the Future of B2B Payments?</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:00:53+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:00:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.bitwave.io/blog/are-stablecoins-the-future</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bitwave.io/blog/are-stablecoins-the-future"/>
    <author>
      <name>Kaleb Leija</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&amp;quot;Are stablecoins the future?&amp;quot; people ask me, which is really a way of asking &amp;quot;Why does it take three business days and a small fortune in fees to pay my overseas supplier when I can instantly send them a cat meme for free?&amp;quot; It&amp;#x27;s a reasonable question!‍The answer has something to do with the fact that while the internet revolutionized information transfer, our money still travels on rails built in the disco era.‍Stablecoins—those peculiar crypto tokens designed to be boring by maintaining a steady $1 value—sit at an interesting intersection. They&amp;#x27;re blockchain-based, which gives them all the speed and programmability crypto enthusiasts rave about, but they&amp;#x27;re explicitly designed not to make you rich overnight (or poor overnight). Their entire value proposition is stability, predictability, and utility—which, coincidentally, are exactly the qualities businesses look for in payment systems.‍So if stablecoins have so many good qualities going for them, why aren’t we living in the future today?To answer that, we need to understand both where we&amp;#x27;ve been and where we&amp;#x27;re going. The story of payment rails isn&amp;#x27;t just about technology—it&amp;#x27;s about regulation, institutional inertia, and the complex dance of infrastructure building and adoption that transforms promising technology into everyday business reality. Let&amp;#x27;s start with how we got here, and why the systems built for the telegram era are struggling to serve the needs of the digital age.From SWIFT to Blockchain: A TimelineFinancial infrastructure isn&amp;#x27;t like consumer tech—it doesn&amp;#x27;t get completely reinvented every few years. It evolves slowly, with each layer built cautiously on top of what came before.1970s: The SWIFT network emerges as the revolutionary solution to standardize international payments. Before this, banks communicated through Telex machines—essentially fancy typewriters connected to telephone lines. SWIFT was cutting-edge technology... for the era of bell bottoms and platform shoes. What&amp;#x27;s important to understand is that SWIFT isn&amp;#x27;t actually a payment system—it&amp;#x27;s a messaging system. The actual money still moves through a patchwork of correspondent banking relationships.1980s-1990s: While consumers got ATMs and credit cards, business payments saw modest improvements through electronic funds transfers and automated clearing houses (ACH). These were digitizations of existing processes rather than fundamental reimaginings of how money could move.2000s: Online banking arrives! Now you can initiate wire transfers from your computer instead of visiting a branch. But the underlying plumbing remained largely the same—like putting a shiny new faucet on rusty pipes.2009: Bitcoin introduces the world to blockchain technology. For the first time, we see how value could be transferred digitally without intermediaries. But Bitcoin&amp;#x27;s volatility makes it more like digital gold than digital cash—great for speculation, terrible for paying suppliers.2014-2018: The first stablecoins appear, initially as trading pairs on crypto exchanges. These early versions reveal a tantalizing possibility: the efficiency of blockchain without the wild price swings.2020-Present: Institutional interest in stablecoins explodes. Major payment processors begin integrating with stablecoin networks. Regulators start paying serious attention, which is both a challenge and a validation.This evolution reveals something important: we&amp;#x27;ve spent decades optimizing the user interface of payments without fundamentally changing how value actually moves. It&amp;#x27;s like we&amp;#x27;ve been putting increasingly better paint jobs on a Model T Ford instead of building a Tesla. Blockchain and specifically stablecoins represent the first real reimagining of the underlying infrastructure since the 1970s.Signs That Stablecoins Are Winning the FutureChanges in financial infrastructure move at a glacial pace because money requires trust, and trust takes time to build.But here&amp;#x27;s the thing about stablecoins: they&amp;#x27;ve been quietly gaining that trust at a speed that&amp;#x27;s surprising even the skeptics. While the crypto world has been obsessed with Bitcoin&amp;#x27;s price swings, stablecoins have been winning over the suit-and-tie crowd—the people who actually control the financial plumbing.Institutional Adoption is AcceleratingMajor financial players are no longer just observing from the sidelines. Stripe&amp;#x27;s $1.1 billion acquisition of stablecoin startup Bridge, along with Visa and PayPal&amp;#x27;s integration of stablecoins into their core services, signals that the financial establishment sees stablecoins as a strategic necessity, not just an experiment.Regulators Are Coming AroundWhen Federal Reserve Governor Christopher Waller states that &amp;quot;stablecoins are effectively &amp;#x27;synthetic&amp;#x27; dollars that can bring benefits to the financial system&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;could have a lot of potential benefits and eliminate inefficiencies,&amp;quot; it&amp;#x27;s a clear indicator that the regulatory climate is warming. This shift is crucial because regulatory clarity reduces adoption friction for businesses concerned about compliance.The Numbers Are Getting SeriousStablecoin transaction volumes have grown from billions to trillions annually in just a few years. This isn&amp;#x27;t niche activity anymore—it&amp;#x27;s mainstream financial volume.The Business Model WorksThe stablecoin formula has proven remarkably profitable: 1) Issue a regulated stablecoin, 2) partner with exchanges for distribution, and 3) earn consistent yields by investing the fiat reserves. Tether reported profits of $5.2 billion in just the first half of 2024 from placing their reserves in US Treasury bonds. This model is too attractive for traditional financial institutions to ignore, which is why we&amp;#x27;re seeing increasing institutional participation.Global Expansion Beyond the DollarWhile USD-backed stablecoins like USDT and USDC dominate the market, we&amp;#x27;re seeing expansion into other currencies. The UAE&amp;#x27;s central bank approved the dirham-backed AE Coin, and European institutions are exploring euro-based stablecoins under the new MiCA regulations. This diversification makes stablecoins relevant to an even broader global market.Real-World Use Cases Are MultiplyingCompanies like SAP are testing cross-border USDC payments, while startups like Agrotoken are enabling farmers to convert physical commodities (like soybeans) into stablecoins that can be spent with merchants. These practical applications solve real business problems around liquidity, cross-border payments, and access to stable value in volatile economies.Of course, if the future were this clear-cut, we&amp;#x27;d already be there. One of the main challenges preventing wider adoption is that using stablecoins requires bridging the gap between traditional financial systems and blockchain technology.‍The good news is that, as William Gibson put it, &amp;quot;the future is already here, it&amp;#x27;s just not evenly distributed.&amp;quot;How Companies are Bridging the Gap to the Stablecoin FutureMultiple Fortune 100 CFOs have already bridged the gap, and they&amp;#x27;re doing it with Bitwave. For businesses ready to step into the future of B2B payments, Bitwave connects your existing accounting and ERP systems with blockchain payment rails, so you don&amp;#x27;t have to rebuild your entire finance stack. Your accountants can keep using the tools they&amp;#x27;re familiar with while tapping into the benefits of stablecoins.Ready to stop sending money via systems designed when Star Wars first came out? Schedule a demo today and learn how your business can leverage stablecoins to reduce costs, increase efficiency, and expand global reach in your B2B payment operations. The future of payments is already here—it&amp;#x27;s just waiting for you to embrace it.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/64c568d103c4e2da8755c388/67f41c901623510ee1afed54_stablecoins-b2b-payments.webp"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
