<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bladelabs.io/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fbladelabs.io%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.grid-cell+.block-image+a&amp;url_pattern=%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bdata-node-view-content-inner%3D%22cardLayoutItem%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=%5Bdata-node-view-content-inner%3D%22title%22%5D&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fbladelabs.io%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.grid-cell+.block-image+a&amp;url_pattern=%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bdata-node-view-content-inner%3D%22cardLayoutItem%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=%5Bdata-node-view-content-inner%3D%22title%22%5D&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:01:02+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Blockchain-based Smart Contracts</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:01:02+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:01:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://bladelabs.io/blockchain-based-smart-contractsmic</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bladelabs.io/blockchain-based-smart-contractsmic"/>
    <content type="html">Blockchain-based smart contracts have emerged as a promising tool for modernizing Islamic financial institutions. This technology offers potential benefits in terms of efficiency, transparency, and alignment with Shariah principles. However, it also presents unique challenges that must be addressed in order to ensure compatibility with Islamic finance practices.Understanding Smart Contracts in Islamic FinanceSmart contracts are self-executing agreements stored on a blockchain network. They automatically enforce predetermined terms and conditions without the need for intermediaries.Blockchain-based smart contracts have the potential to transform Islamic financial services by significantly reducing transaction costs, enhancing accessibility, and achieving unprecedented levels of trust and transparency. [1]Some of the advantages that smart contracts can offer for Islamic financial institutions include -● Reduced operational errors – These self-executing agreements featuring smart contracts significantly reduce the risk of operational errors, ensuring that transactions are executed precisely as intended without human intervention.● Increased transparency – These automated processes enhance efficiency andincrease transparency, as all contract terms and executions are recorded immutably on the blockchain, allowing for real-time auditing and verification. Such transparency is particularly crucial in Islamic finance, where the clear tracking of asset ownership and profit-sharing arrangements is paramount.● Improved alignment with fintech innovations - Smart contracts facilitate improved alignment with broader fintech innovations, enabling Islamic financial institutions to offer advanced services that compete with conventional banking products while remaining Shariah-compliant.● Enhanced Shariah compliance through automated enforcement of rules - Smart contracts can be programmed to automatically enforce Shariah rules, such as the prohibition of interest (riba) or the requirement for asset-backed transactions, thereby enhancing overall compliance with Islamic financial principles. This automated enforcement reduces the burden on Shariah boards and minimizes the risk of non-compliant transactions slipping through.● Increased accessibility - Smart contracts can streamline complex Islamic financial products like Sukuk issuance or Mudarabah agreements, making these instruments more accessible and easier to manage. By leveraging smart contracts, Islamic financial institutions can potentially expand their customer base, offering more efficient and technologically advanced services while maintaining the ethical and religious integrity that defines Islamic finance.Potential ApplicationsBlockchain-based smart contracts have numerous potential applications in Islamic finance: [2]Sukuk Issuance: Smart contracts can streamline the issuance and management of Islamic bonds, providing greater transparency and efficiency.Zakat Management: Blockchain technology can improve the accountability and auditability of obligatory charitable giving, offering real-time visibility into fund usage and impact.Mudarabah and Murabahah Transactions: Smart contracts can automate profit-sharing and cost-plus financing arrangements, ensuring adherence to Shariah principles.Waqf Management: By leveraging smart contracts, waqf institutions can automate fund distribution, ensure transparent tracking of contributions and disbursements, and even tokenize non-liquid assets. This integration could significantly enhance efficiency, accountability, and accessibility in waqf management, potentially attracting more donors and amplifying social impact while adhering to Islamic principles.Challenges and ConsiderationsWhile promising, implementing blockchain-based smart contracts in Islamic finance faces several significant challenges. Regulatory compliance with Shariah law remains a primary concern, as the technology must align with Islamic principles and be approved by Shariah scholars.Moreover, the reputational damage caused by fraudulent digital asset issuances is a major challenge. The extreme price volatility of digital assets is also often unfairly associated with all blockchain solutions, regardless of their specific applications or merits.This is compounded by a general lack of awareness and education about blockchain technology among financial professionals and the public, hindering adoption and understanding of its potential benefits. The Islamic finance industry also struggles with a need for standardization across different jurisdictions and institutions, making it difficult to implement blockchain solutions uniformly. [3] Cybersecurity concerns pose another significant hurdle, as the immutable nature of blockchain transactions means that any security breaches could have severe and irreversible consequences.Finally, developing appropriate legal frameworks to govern blockchain-based financial transactions in Islamic finance is still in its infancy, creating uncertainty and potential legal risks for institutions adopting this technology. These challenges collectively underscore the complexity of integrating blockchain technology into Islamic finance and highlight the need for a coordinated, multifaceted approach to overcome these obstacles. [4]The Future of Islamic FinanceThe future of Islamic finance is poised for remarkable transformation through the integration of blockchain and smart contracts. As the industry, currently valued at $4.5 trillion, is projected to reach $6.67 trillion by 2027, adopting these technologies could accelerate this growth even further. [5], [6]..css-fz71is{display:-webkit-box;display:-webkit-flex;display:-ms-flexbox;display:flex;-webkit-flex-direction:column;-ms-flex-direction:column;flex-direction:column;height:100%;width:100%;-webkit-align-items:var(--flex-align);-webkit-box-align:var(--flex-align);-ms-flex-align:var(--flex-align);align-items:var(--flex-align);}.css-1kyw67{width:calc(405.3333333333333 * var(--font-size) / 16);max-width:calc(100% * var(--media-scale));position:relative;overflow:hidden;border-radius:var(--box-border-radius);-webkit-mask:none!important;mask:none!important;}.css-p4s2y9{inset:0px;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;z-index:1;cursor:-webkit-zoom-in;cursor:zoom-in;opacity:0;}.css-11lrhya{max-height:var(--media-maxH);max-width:var(--media-maxW);overflow:hidden;width:100%;display:block;}@media print{.css-11lrhya{height:unset;}}.css-zec7a{object-fit:contain;max-height:calc(var(--media-maxH) * 1);transform-origin:left top;-webkit-transform:scale(1) translate(-0%, -0%);-moz-transform:scale(1) translate(-0%, -0%);-ms-transform:scale(1) translate(-0%, -0%);transform:scale(1) translate(-0%, -0%);width:100%;}(Image source: https://www.lseg.com/en/insights/data-analytics/navigating-uncertainty-global-islamic-finance-assets-expecte d-to-exceed-67-trillion-by-2027)However, the successful integration of blockchain and smart contracts in Islamic finance will require concerted efforts from various stakeholders. Regulatory bodies must develop comprehensive frameworks that address the technological and Shariah-compliance aspects of these innovations. Islamic scholars and fintech experts will need to collaborate closely to ensure that new products and services align with Islamic principles while leveraging the full potential of blockchain technology.Furthermore, education and awareness programs will build trust and understanding among consumers and industry professionals. As the technology matures and becomes more widely adopted, Islamic financial institutions must invest in developing the necessary skills and infrastructure to support these new systems.Blade Lab&amp;#x27;s Blockchain-Powered ApproachIn this constantly evolving space, Blade Labs is one of the front runners in transforming Islamic finance with unique offerings of innovative solutions to address industry challenges. At the heart of this approach lies a modular, digital assets platform that seamlessly integrates traditional finance with digital assets.Using distributed ledger technology (DLT) and smart contracts, our flagship solution leverages digital diamonds as a commodity for Islamic financial instruments, providing a secure, transparent, and efficient ecosystem for products like Murabaha and Tawarruq.Key features of Blade Labs&amp;#x27; platform include:● AI-powered smart contracts ensuring automated Shariah compliance● Real-time settlement enhancing liquidity and reducing risk● Multi-jurisdictional framework for seamless cross-border transactions● Digital asset tokenization enabling fractional ownership● Advanced risk management tools tailored for Islamic financeCompared to traditional Islamic Finance, Blade Labs&amp;#x27; solution offers significant benefits:● Instant commodity transactions, reducing settlement times from days to seconds● Lower operational costs by eliminating physical commodity handling and storage● Enhanced transparency and traceability of commodity ownership and transfers● Improved accessibility, allowing for smaller transaction sizes and wider participation● Automated compliance checks, reducing the risk of Shariah non-complianceThis blockchain-based approach to Islamic finance represents a significant advancement in ethical banking, addressing longstanding challenges and unlocking new growth potential. Blade’s platform tackles several critical issues in Islamic finance, including transparency and compliance, smart contract automation, tokenization of Islamic assets, cross-border capabilities, and regulatory compliance.By leveraging blockchain&amp;#x27;s immutable ledger, Blade ensures full transparency of transactions and verifiable Shariah compliance, while smart contracts automate complex Islamic financial structures like Murabaha and Ijara. Our platform also enables the tokenization of Shariah-compliant assets, facilitates faster cross-border transactions, and integrates AI-powered KYC/AML processes to meet Shariah principles and international regulatory standards.At Blade, we offer a range of solutions for Islamic financial institutions, including:● Turnkey solutions for rapid market entry● Customizable white-label platforms● Seamless integration with existing systems● Ongoing compliance and technical support● Access to their Middle Eastern partner networkBlade is well-positioned to help institutions tap into the projected growth of Islamic finance efficiently and compliantly with certifications like SOC2 and ISO27001:2022, ensuring security.As the sector evolves, collaboration between fintech innovators, traditional Islamic financial institutions, regulators, and Shariah scholars will be crucial to ensure that blockchain-based solutions adhere to Shariah principles while meeting the industry&amp;#x27;s evolving needs in an increasingly digital world.The convergence of blockchain technology and Islamic finance principles holds immense promise for the industry&amp;#x27;s future. By carefully navigating the challenges and capitalizing on the opportunities presented by this technological revolution, Islamic finance can potentially offer more efficient, transparent, and inclusive financial services to a global audience. As the sector grows and evolves, blockchain-based smart contracts may become the cornerstone of a more robust, innovative, and ethically aligned Islamic financial ecosystem.References:[1] https://ijiefer.uis.edu.my/ircief/article/view/96/85[2] https://aims.education/blockchain-in-islamic-finance-and-banking/[3] https://www.mdpi.com/2674-1032/1/4/29[4] https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-blockchain-can-revolutionize-islamic-finance-system-arslan-sh ah/[5] https://www.statista.com/topics/6345/islamic-financial-sector/#topicOverview[6] https://www.lseg.com/en/insights/data-analytics/navigating-uncertainty-global-islamic-finance-assets-expected-to-exceed-67-trillion-by-2027Authored byKasturi SharmaSenior Manager – Content &amp;amp; Compliance</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="application/octet-stream" href="https://assets.api.gamma.app/1pgsrtf0dmkg5n2/screenshots/c4eyujzhkk0blv4/spgl3a6j13736tp/slide/SEHrfomSn8oEtBGCq-mfkxgL_NU"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Smart Contracts in Islamic Finance: Balancing Immutability and Flexibility</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:01:02+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:01:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://bladelabs.io/smart-contracts-in-islamic-finance</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bladelabs.io/smart-contracts-in-islamic-finance"/>
    <content type="html">Smart contracts, which are self-executing agreements coded on blockchain technology, offer remarkable transparency, efficiency, and trust by automating processes without the need for intermediaries. Their application in Islamic finance could enhance operational efficiency while adhering to core principles of Sharia-compliant financial transactions. By utilizing smart contracts, Islamic financial institutions can streamline various services, including murabaha (cost-plus financing) and ijarah (leasing), to provide quicker and more secure transactions.However, the immutability of smart contracts presents a major challenge in its application in Islamic finance, which often requires a degree of flexibility in contract terms in compliance to Shariah principles. Unlike conventional finance, where fixed contracts are standard, Islamic finance sometimes necessitates contract adjustments to account for ethical considerations like ihsan (benevolence). The unchangeable nature of smart contracts conflicts with this need for flexibility, due to which there are several approaches that have been developed in active exploration of solutions to reconcile with this challenge of immutability.Some of the approaches to address this challenge are discussed below:Flexible Code Design: This approach involves programming smart contracts with built-in flexibility, allowing for predefined modifications within Sharia-compliant parameters. Developers can incorporate conditional statements and modifiable variables that enable adjustments to contract terms without compromising the overall integrity of the agreement. This method provides a balance between immutability and adaptability, crucial for Islamic finance principles such as debt forgiveness or payment rescheduling [1]Upgradable Proxy Contracts: This technique involves creating a proxy contract that points to the main contract logic. The logic can be updated without altering the original terms, enabling adaptability while preserving the contract&amp;#x27;s core principles. [2]Oracle Integration: Oracles act as bridges between smart contracts and external data sources, allowing for dynamic updates based on real-world events or conditions. In Islamic finance, oracles can be used to trigger Sharia-compliant changes in response to market conditions, regulatory updates, or other relevant factors. This integration enables smart contracts to remain compliant with Islamic principles while adapting to changing circumstances [3]Modular Contract Systems: By breaking down contracts into modular components, specific elements can be replaced or updated without compromising the entire agreement. [4]On-Chain Governance: This method implements a decentralized decision-making process within the blockchain itself. Stakeholders can propose, vote on, and implement changes to smart contracts through a transparent and auditable process. This approach aligns with the principles of Shura (consultation) in Islamic finance, allowing for community involvement in contract modifications while maintaining the decentralized nature of blockchain technology.These innovative solutions aim to strike a balance between the immutability that makes smart contracts secure and trustworthy, and the flexibility required to adhere to Islamic financial principles.Blade Labs is uniquely positioned to revolutionize the Islamic finance industry by leveraging these innovative approaches to smart contract flexibility. Through its innovative Private Financing platform, Blade Labs combines flexible code design, upgradable proxy contracts, and modular systems to create Shariah-compliant financial products that are both secure and adaptable. By integrating AI-powered Shariah screening and compliance tools, Blade ensures that all transactions adhere to Islamic principles while still benefiting from the efficiency and transparency of blockchain technology.As a pioneer in Islamic fintech, Blade is poised to bridge the gap between traditional Islamic finance and the digital asset ecosystem, offering solutions that not only address the immutability challenge but also enhance accessibility, reduce costs, and improve overall market efficiency. With its innovative approach and deep understanding of both Shariah requirements and blockchain capabilities, Blade is set to play a transformative role in shaping the future of Islamic finance, making it more inclusive, transparent, and aligned with the ethical principles that form its foundation.As the field evolves, it is likely that new approaches will emerge, further refining the integration of blockchain technology with Sharia-compliant finance. The challenge of reconciling smart contract immutability with Islamic finance principles highlights the need for ongoing collaboration between technologists, Sharia scholars, and financial experts. By fostering this interdisciplinary dialogue, the Islamic fintech sector can develop solutions that harness the benefits of blockchain technology while remaining true to the ethical and religious foundations of Islamic finance.[1] https://ijiefer.uis.edu.my/ircief/article/download/96/85[2] https://www.talentica.com/blogs/implementing-upgradeable-smart-contracts-using-proxy-patterns/[3] https://www.amf.org.ae/sites/default/files/publications/2022-12/Guidance%20Note-Adopting%20Smart%20Contracts%20and%20their%20Legal%20Enforceability%20in%20Arab%20Countries.pdf[4] https://journal.inceif.edu.my/index.php/ijif/article/download/659/465/2136Authored byKasturi SharmaSenior Manager – Content &amp;amp; Compliance</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="application/octet-stream" href="https://assets.api.gamma.app/1pgsrtf0dmkg5n2/screenshots/s7d2oihptus0sqa/4twtouq3v8crfof/slide/1j8FvIkW1XeqOSdPbfUZDhYw28E"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Tokenization in Islamic Finance: Transforming Sukuk and Beyond</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:01:02+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:01:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://bladelabs.io/tokenization-in-islamic-finance</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bladelabs.io/tokenization-in-islamic-finance"/>
    <content type="html">The Islamic finance sector is experiencing a transformative shift riding on blockchain technology&amp;#x27;s innovative potential, guaranteeing increased efficiency, transparency and compliance to Shariah principles. In this rapidly evolving space, tokenization is opening up a lot of scope for this sector by converting real-world assets into digital tokens on blockchain networks.In sukuk (Islamic bonds), tokenization is addressing long-standing challenges and paving the way for new opportunities for investors and issuers alike. It involves converting these Shariah-compliant financial instruments into digital tokens on blockchain networks, enabling fractional ownership, increased accessibility and enhanced liquidity.The Rise of Tokenized SukukSukuk, otherwise known as Islamic bonds, have been a cornerstone of Islamic finance, allowing Muslims to invest in a Shariah-compliant manner. However, traditional sukuk faces several limitations:High entry barriers - Traditional sukuk typically have high minimum investment requirements, ranging from several thousand to several hundred thousand dollars. This high entry level prevents many retail investors from participating in the sukuk market, limiting access to only wealthy individuals or institutional investors. [1]Limited liquidity in secondary markets - The secondary market for sukuk is often weak and sluggish, making it difficult for investors to trade their holdings. This lack of liquidity is partly due to the scarcity of sukuk supply and a &amp;quot;hold-to-maturity&amp;quot; culture among investors, which hinders active trading and price discovery. [2]Predominantly regional focus - Sukuk issuances are largely concentrated in a few Muslim-majority countries, particularly Malaysia and the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) region. This regional concentration limits the global adoption of sukuk and makes it challenging for international investors to access diverse sukuk offerings from different markets. [1] [3]Tokenization addresses these issues by fractionalizing sukuk into smaller, more accessible units, which enables [1] -● Increased accessibility: Tokenization allows for fractional ownership of sukuk, enabling retail investors to participate with smaller amounts. This democratizes access to Islamic financial products, breaking down traditional barriers to entry and making sukuk investments available to a broader range of investors.● Enhanced liquidity: Tokenized sukuk can be traded more easily on blockchain platforms, improving market dynamics. This increased liquidity facilitates smoother market operations, contributes to price discovery, and offers investors greater flexibility in managing their investments.● Global reach: Investors worldwide can access digital tokens, expanding the market beyond traditional regional boundaries. This global accessibility opens up new investment opportunities for international investors and helps diversify the investor base for sukuk issuers.The scope of tokenization extends beyond sukuk to various aspects of Islamic finance:Real Estate: Tokenization allows for fractional ownership of properties, making real estate investments more accessible and liquid. This enables smaller investors to participate in the real estate market and provides property owners with a new method of raising capital [4]Commodities: Tokenization can streamline Shariah-compliant commodity trading, enhancing transparency and efficiency. This can lead to more efficient and accessible commodity markets within the Islamic finance ecosystem.Equity: Islamic equity products can be tokenized, potentially increasing their appeal to a broader investor base. This can facilitate easier trading of Shariah-compliant stocks and open new opportunities for Islamic equity investments.Blade Labs&amp;#x27; Approach for Tokenization in Islamic FinanceBlade Labs offers innovative solutions that can significantly enhance the tokenization efforts in Islamic Finance. Our DLT-based, AI-powered platform is specifically designed to cater to the unique requirements of Islamic financial institutions and investors alike, providing a bridge between traditional Shariah-compliant investments and the digital asset ecosystem.Key features of Blade Labs’ innovative tokenization offerings -Shariah-Compliant Digital Infrastructure - Blade offers an enterprise-grade financing platform that is not only technologically advanced but also Shariah-compliant.Smart Contracts for Islamic Financial Instruments - Blade’s use of smart contracts facilitates the automation of complex Islamic financial instruments. This technology can be applied to tokenize various Shariah-compliant assets, such as Sukuk (Islamic bonds), Murabahah (cost-plus financing), and Ijarah (lease) contracts, ensuring that they remain compliant throughout their lifecycle.AI-Powered Compliance Engine - One of Blade’s key features is its AI-powered compliance engine which can be instrumental in ensuring that tokenized assets remain Shariah-compliant.Multi-Jurisdictional Capabilities - Blade’s solutions are designed with multi-jurisdictional capabilities, which is crucial for the global Islamic finance market. This feature ensures that tokenized Islamic financial products can be compliant across different regulatory frameworks, facilitating cross-border transactions and investments.Blade Labs&amp;#x27; Digital Transformation of SukukThe sukuk market has shown significant growth lately, with issuance reaching $139.1 billion in the first half of 2024, equivalent to 64% of the full-year issuance of 2023. Blade is well-positioned to capitalize on this exponential growth with its tokenization offerings, potentially boosting this market further by addressing key challenges and opening new opportunities..css-fz71is{display:-webkit-box;display:-webkit-flex;display:-ms-flexbox;display:flex;-webkit-flex-direction:column;-ms-flex-direction:column;flex-direction:column;height:100%;width:100%;-webkit-align-items:var(--flex-align);-webkit-box-align:var(--flex-align);-ms-flex-align:var(--flex-align);align-items:var(--flex-align);}.css-1yfa2nu{width:calc(544.8888888888889 * var(--font-size) / 16);max-width:calc(100% * var(--media-scale));position:relative;overflow:hidden;border-radius:var(--box-border-radius);-webkit-mask:none!important;mask:none!important;}.css-p4s2y9{inset:0px;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;z-index:1;cursor:-webkit-zoom-in;cursor:zoom-in;opacity:0;}.css-11lrhya{max-height:var(--media-maxH);max-width:var(--media-maxW);overflow:hidden;width:100%;display:block;}@media print{.css-11lrhya{height:unset;}}.css-zec7a{object-fit:contain;max-height:calc(var(--media-maxH) * 1);transform-origin:left top;-webkit-transform:scale(1) translate(-0%, -0%);-moz-transform:scale(1) translate(-0%, -0%);-ms-transform:scale(1) translate(-0%, -0%);transform:scale(1) translate(-0%, -0%);width:100%;}By leveraging blockchain technology, Blade can enhance the efficiency, transparency, and accessibility of sukuk issuance and trading. This could attract a broader range of investors, including those from non-traditional Islamic finance markets and potentially increase liquidity in the secondary market. Furthermore, Blade’s focus on compliance and regulatory frameworks aligns well with the evolving landscape of Islamic finance, particularly as the industry considers adopting new standards like AAOIFI&amp;#x27;s Shariah Standard 62. [6]With the sukuk market expected to reach $160-170 billion by the end of 2024, Blade’s tokenization platform could play a crucial role in modernizing this financial instrument and potentially accelerating its growth, especially in key markets in the middle-east and the UAE, which have been driving recent sukuk issuances.With the evolution of innovative technological approaches, the Islamic finance sector is poised for significant growth and transformation. The successful implementation of tokenization could revolutionize Islamic finance and contribute to the broader adoption of ethical and sustainable financial practices globally.References –[1] https://www.zawya.com/en/opinion/markets-insights/tokenized-sukuk-islamic-bonds-made-accessib le-and-liquid-lcbo62tq[2] https://www.marmoremena.com/en/insights/secondary-market-of-sukuk-an-overview/[3] https://documents1.worldbank.org/curated/es/637041468320946094/pdf/WPS7133.pdf[4] https://www.forbes.com/councils/forbesbusinesscouncil/2023/05/15/unlocking-the-potential-of-ass et-tokenization-in-islamic-finance/[5] https://www.linkedin.com/posts/lseg-data_sukuk-islamicfinance-fixedincome-activity-722682960832 5627904-bp3b/[6] https://www.agbi.com/finance/2024/07/sharia-standard-62-may-disrupt-sukuk-market-says-sp/Authored byKasturi SharmaSenior Manager – Content &amp;amp; Compliance</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="application/octet-stream" href="https://assets.api.gamma.app/1pgsrtf0dmkg5n2/screenshots/obssqv5mi5n1h74/ga1ltzm1jin481d/slide/y3934Qum_vLwLhFYsVAXimmWxFI"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
