<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blockdaemon Blog - Latest Insights and News from the World of Blockchain</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.blockdaemon.com/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.blockdaemon.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date&amp;date_format=M+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_noproxy=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.blockdaemon.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date&amp;date_format=M+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_noproxy=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:01:30+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Blockdaemon Helps Hong Kong VATPs Meet SFC Staking Requirements</title>
    <published>2025-04-10T22:01:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-10T22:01:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.blockdaemon.com/blog/blockdaemon-helps-hong-kong-vatps-meet-sfc-staking-requirements</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.blockdaemon.com/blog/blockdaemon-helps-hong-kong-vatps-meet-sfc-staking-requirements"/>
    <content type="html">On April 7, 2025, the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) of Hong Kong published a circular outlining clear requirements for Virtual Asset Trading Platforms (VATPs) that offer staking services, recognizing the growing investor demand and importance of staking in supporting blockchain security. ‍VATPs in Hong Kong may now provide staking services if they fulfill the SFC’s standards and obtain prior SFC approval. This opens the door for regulated staking offerings that include exchange-based services, fund products, OTC deals, and ETFs for assets like ETH and SOL.‍Blockdaemon As A Trusted Partner To VATPs In Hong Kong‍Blockdaemon is well-positioned in-market to help VATPs launch staking services. Our reliable infrastructure and deep regulatory expertise enables clients to protect customer assets, disclose key information, and manage risks without compromising performance.‍Below are three key advantages Blockdaemon can bring to clients’ operations.‍1. Non-Custodial, SFC-Compliant Staking Solutions‍Full Control of Assets‍Blockdaemon enables clients to maintain full control over their customers’ virtual assets, complying with the Securities and Futures Commission’s (SFC) directive prohibiting third-party custody. Our solutions provide clients with full management of withdrawal processes, including control over private keys and pre-signed voluntary exit messages, ensuring compliance and the secure handling of client assets.‍Custom Deployment and 24/7 Support‍Blockdaemon provides flexible, customized deployment options, supporting both white-label and public validators to adapt to clients&amp;#x27; infrastructure, such as retail exchanges or institutional desks. Our 24/7 monitoring and real-time support helps clients respond to network events and remain accountable to regulators and end-users.‍OFAC Compliance and MEV Relay Integration‍​We provide flexibility to integrate either OFAC-compliant or non-compliant MEV relays into client staking operations, aligning with clients’ regulatory and operational requirements. OFAC-compliant relays block transactions involving sanctioned addresses, ensuring adherence with specific legal frameworks. Conversely, other providers may choose to only offer non-compliant relays in search for higher yields and do not impose such restrictions. ‍2. Transparency in Fees, Risks, and Reward Calculations‍Clear Fee and Risk Disclosures‍​At Blockdaemon, we ensure compliance with the Securities and Futures Commission&amp;#x27;s (SFC) mandates by providing clear disclosures on fees, protocol staking rules, and potential slashing events. Our Staking Reporting API enhances transparency by offering detailed insights into staking operations, including validator status, rewards, and performance across multiple blockchain networks. This enables clients to effectively communicate with customers and regulators. ​‍Protocol Reward Rate (PRR) Tracking‍Over the last six months, our average PRR for ETH staking has consistently outperformed the network. In March, Blockdaemon delivered an Ethereum PRR of 3.35%, compared to the network average of 3.26%. While past performance does not guarantee future results, it demonstrates our commitment to optimizing rewards.‍Higher Rewards Without Extra Risk‍Our approach optimizes compliance, security, and reward consistency. By combining industry-leading validator infrastructure with ongoing protocol analysis, we aim to maximize rewards while mitigating risks.‍3. Robust Risk Management and Internal Monitoring‍Slashing Guarantee‍We uphold our contractual guarantee to reimburse 100% of any slashing penalties resulting from double-signing or other protocol violations. To date, we have recorded zero slashing events.‍Strong Uptime and Monitoring‍We maintain 100% machine uptime and 99.9% protocol uptime, ensuring clients’ validators remain secure and online. Our robust internal controls minimize errors and downtime.‍Real-Time Risk Assessment‍We consistently evaluate network conditions, validator performance, and protocol changes. We manage any adjustments, ensuring clients meet the SFC’s standards for safeguarding client assets.Contact the Blockdaemon team today to discuss how we can help you meet the SFC’s staking requirements and ensure smooth regulatory approval. Book a call with the Blockdaemon team today. ‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/633c67ced5457aa4dec572be/67f7fb3bba24c735237a9d3e_Blockdaemon%20Helps%20Hong%20Kong%20VATPs%20Meet%20SFC%20Staking%20Requirements.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Support for Babylon Genesis</title>
    <published>2025-04-10T22:01:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-10T22:01:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.blockdaemon.com/blog/support-for-babylon-genesis</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.blockdaemon.com/blog/support-for-babylon-genesis"/>
    <content type="html">Supporting The Babylon Genesis Launch‍Blockdaemon now supports Babylon Genesis as a Finality Provider (FP), providing industry-leading infrastructure support for the first standalone Layer 1 (L1) Bitcoin Secured Network (BSN). This is the first network of its kind to derive its crypto-economic security from Bitcoin, via the Babylon Bitcoin staking protocol. In this blog, you’ll get an introduction to Babylon, Babylon Genesis, and how to stake your BTC with Blockdaemon. ‍What Is Babylon?‍Babylon is a project that bridges Bitcoin’s security into Proof-of-Stake (PoS) networks. It transforms idle Bitcoin (BTC) into an active staking asset, letting BTC holders secure rewards while boosting the security of other blockchains. Built as its own layer-1 chain using the Cosmos technology stack, Babylon introduces a unique Bitcoin staking model focused on institutional-grade security and interoperability. In essence, Babylon repurposes Bitcoin’s immense liquidity and robust security to “secure the decentralized future” by staking BTC in a trustless, self-custodial way. ‍Babylon’s Key Features‍Babylon’s approach to staking is novel, with the following notable features:‍Decentralized Bitcoin Staking: Bitcoin can be staked to secure PoS blockchains without any centralized custody or wrapped tokens. BTC never leaves the owner’s wallet control, removing the need for bridges or third-party custodians.Security as a Service: Finality Providers in Babylon regularly vote on checkpoints for connected blockchains (Bitcoin Secured Networks) and commit these votes to Bitcoin’s blockchain. Once a checkpoint is embedded in Bitcoin and confirmed, it becomes economically infeasible for the BSN’s history to be reversed without also invalidating the Bitcoin record.Fast Unbonding: Unlike traditional staking that locks assets with variable unbonding times, Babylon lets stakers unbond (withdraw) with minimal delay - typically two days. Broad Compatibility: Any PoS blockchain or rollup can become a Bitcoin Secured Network by integrating with Babylon. This means they can augment their native validator security with Bitcoin-backed finality.‍Babylon’s Staking Model‍Babylon operates a dual-quorum staking model on Babylon Genesis. It runs on CometBFT (the Cosmos SDK/Tendermint consensus engine) and uses two types of staking roles:‍Cosmos Validators (BABY Stakers): Babylon has a set of validators (initially around 100) that stake its native token (called BABY) to produce blocks and secure the Babylon chain itself. These validators perform the usual PoS duties and ensure the chain’s uptime and integrity, similar to validators on other Cosmos-based networks.Bitcoin Finality Providers (BTC Stakers): In parallel, Babylon integrates a specialized set of ~60 Finality Providers who stake BTC instead of BABY. Finality Providers (FPs) are essentially Bitcoin-backed validators. They lock up BTC in the Babylon protocol and participate in finality votes for connected networks. Each Finality Provider runs both a Babylon node and monitors Bitcoin. Babylon’s consensus incorporates these providers’ votes (a “finality round”) to finalize blocks with Bitcoin’s assurance. FPs can also stake using delegated bitcoin. ‍This architecture marries Proof-of-Stake with Bitcoin’s Proof-of-Work-based trust. The Babylon chain frequently commits its state to the Bitcoin blockchain (approximately every hour) via a timestamping mechanism. ‍By anchoring data to Bitcoin’s ledger, Babylon safeguards against long-range attacks on the PoS chain (historical attacks are thwarted because the Bitcoin record serves as an immutable checkpoint), and it enables fast unbonding. Once a Babylon checkpoint is engraved in Bitcoin, stake can be safely released much sooner than conventional PoS unbonding periods. ‍How Bitcoin Staking Works ‍To become a Bitcoin staker in Babylon, a bitcoin holder locks some BTC in a special output on the Bitcoin network using Babylon’s native staking script. This on-chain Bitcoin transaction is self-custodial, meaning the user keeps their private keys and does not hand coins to anyone else. Once locked, that BTC is recognized by the Babylon chain and converted into the ability to stake. The BTC holder can then choose to either run a Finality Provider node themselves or delegate their stake to an existing Finality Provider of their choice, such as Blockdaemon. Delegation allows those without infrastructure to participate by assigning their stake to a professional node operator.‍Babylon’s protocol enforces strict slashing-based accountability for these Bitcoin stakers. If a Finality Provider cheats or attempts to finalize conflicting histories (analogous to double-signing), the protocol can slash (forfeit) the BTC that was staked with that provider. Slashing is automatic and trust-minimized. Misbehavior triggers a pre-signed Bitcoin transaction that penalizes the offender’s locked BTC. Importantly, honest participants are protected. A BTC staker’s funds cannot be taken as long as neither the staker nor their chosen validator misbehaves. Even if the Babylon chain itself were compromised, the design ensures that an honest staker’s bitcoin remains secure under their control. ‍Conclusion ‍Babylon turns BTC from a passive “digital gold” into an active stake that secures networks, generates rewards, and acts as a root of trust for PoS blockchains. It combines the unmatched security and liquidity of Bitcoin with the growing staking economy. ‍Today, over 50,000 BTC has been staked through Babylon’s protocol, with over 200 Finality Providers. While this represents just ~0.3% of Bitcoin’s supply, it shows the appetite for Bitcoin staking products amongst BTC holders. ‍To get started with bitcoin staking today, reach out to the Blockdaemon team.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/633c67ced5457aa4dec572be/67f7dd1fe08da39760feaa63_Announcing%20Blockdaemon%E2%80%99s%20Support%20for%20Genesis%20Launch.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Blockdaemon&amp;#x27;s February 2025 Ethereum Validator Performance</title>
    <published>2025-04-08T22:01:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-08T22:01:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.blockdaemon.com/blog/blockdaemons-february-2025-ethereum-validator-performance</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.blockdaemon.com/blog/blockdaemons-february-2025-ethereum-validator-performance"/>
    <content type="html">Blockdaemon&amp;#x27;s February 2025 Ethereum Validator Performance‍Blockdaemon, an industry leading institutional staking operator, recorded strong Ethereum validator performance for the month of February, with a Protocol Reward Rate (PRR) of 3.45%. This was 5 basis points above Ethereum’s network average.‍Blockdaemon’s Ethereum’s February Analysis ‍In the first half of February, our validators achieved 3.42% PRR. However, mid-February saw a shift toward bearish conditions: ETH trading volumes dropped to around $11 billion amid uncertainty fueled by trade wars, economic insecurity, Bitcoin’s plunge from $102k to below $80k, memecoin volatility, and the Bybit hack. ‍Despite these headwinds, Blockdaemon’s validators secured strong rewards through the latter half of the month, capturing a substantial share of daily fees, rewards, and MEV, successfully mitigating volatility for our customers. ‍Where Do Blockdaemon’s ETH Protocol Rewards Come From? ‍When you stake ETH with Blockdaemon, your validators receive rewards from both the consensus layer (CL) and execution layer (EL). Most rewards come from CL for activities like attesting, proposing blocks, and participating in the sync committee. When a validator is selected to propose a block (a CL event), it triggers both CL rewards (for the proposal) and EL rewards (from fees and MEV). Because block proposals are infrequent and randomly assigned, the majority of rewards still come from CL activities, with EL rewards depending on network demand.‍ConclusionDespite the Pectra hardfork delay, new launches like Berachain’s mainnet highlight the positive, underlying sentiment around Ethereum. Blockdaemon remains committed to delivering top-tier institutional infrastructure - both in bullish phases and during market turbulence - helping our clients secure staking rewards reliably.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/633c67ced5457aa4dec572be/67f55d4b8715528c5827f90c_eth%20feb%20performance.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
