<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">BPV - Stellar Blockchain consulting and more</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bpventures.us/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bpventures.us%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=a&amp;url_pattern=.%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bdata-framer-name%3D%22Content%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bpventures.us%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=a&amp;url_pattern=.%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bdata-framer-name%3D%22Content%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:01:51+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">BPV Anchor in a box adds Stellar SEP-38 - Quotes support - BPV - Stellar Blockchain consulting and more</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:01:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:01:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.bpventures.us/blog/bpv-anchor-in-a-box-adds-stellar-sep-38-quotes-support</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bpventures.us/blog/bpv-anchor-in-a-box-adds-stellar-sep-38-quotes-support"/>
    <content type="html">BPV Pioneers First-of-Kind Integration of Stellar's Quote ProtocolBPV is excited to announce our integration of Stellar's SEP-038 Quote Protocol into our anchor-in-a-box platform, marking a significant milestone as the first implementation of its kind. This integration brings sophisticated quote-driven market capabilities to the Stellar network, particularly beneficial for emerging markets and complex trading scenarios.Why Quotes Matter: The Business PerspectiveIn many of the world's most dynamic markets, particularly in South America, quote-driven trading is the norm rather than the exception. This approach allows for more flexible and nuanced pricing strategies that can adapt to market conditions in real-time. The SEP-038 protocol provides a standardized way for wallets to request quotes, enabling seamless integration with various trading systems and protocols, including tbDEX.What makes quote-driven markets particularly powerful is their ability to provide customized pricing based on various factors:Customer relationship and trading historyTransaction volume and frequencyMarket conditions and liquidityRegional considerations and local market dynamicsThis flexibility is crucial in capital markets, where some of the largest trading venues operate on quote-driven principles. By implementing SEP-038, we're bringing this sophisticated trading capability to the Stellar ecosystem.Technical Implementation: Beyond Basic Quote GenerationOur implementation of SEP-038 goes well beyond simple quote generation, incorporating several critical features for modern financial operations:1. Comprehensive Compliance IntegrationFull support for SEP-9/12 KYC/KYB proceduresAutomated travel rule compliance checkingReal-time regulatory validation2. Automated Payment ProcessingSeamless payment tracking and reconciliationAutomatic receipt generationTransaction status monitoring3. Multi-Channel SupportIntegration with WhatsApp for quote requestsTelegram integrationEmail-based quote generation and trackingTechnical Deep Dive: SEP-038 CapabilitiesThe protocol enables anchors to accept off-chain assets in exchange for different on-chain assets, and vice versa. Key features include:Flexible Asset Support: Handles both Stellar assets and ISO 4217 fiat currenciesDelivery Method Options: Supports various payment methods including bank, ACH, and regional options like PIXQuote Types:  Indicative prices via GET /prices endpoint  Firm quotes via POST /quote endpoint  Historical quote retrieval via GET /quote/:idSecurity is paramount in the implementation, with mandatory SEP-10 authentication for critical endpoints and optional authentication for public price checking.Looking ForwardThis integration represents a significant step forward in making the Stellar network more accessible and practical for real-world financial operations. By bridging the gap between traditional quote-driven markets and blockchain technology, we're enabling more efficient, transparent, and flexible trading operations.For those interested in integrating with our platform or learning more about SEP-038 implementation, please reach out to our team. We're excited to help expand the ecosystem and bring more sophisticated trading capabilities to the Stellar network.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">BPV Whitelable Wallet adds Paypal PYUSD support - BPV - Stellar Blockchain consulting and more</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:01:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:01:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.bpventures.us/blog/bpv-whitelable-wallet-adds-paypal-pyusd-support</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bpventures.us/blog/bpv-whitelable-wallet-adds-paypal-pyusd-support"/>
    <content type="html">BPV's Retail Whitelabel Wallet has significantly expanded its services by integrating PayPal PYUSD and MoneyGram's global network, positioning itself as a uniquely versatile solution in the digital wallet market. This integration combines PayPal's ecosystem, which includes over 400 million users through services like Venmo, Xoom, and Fastlane, with MoneyGram's 150 million consumer base and 430,000 physical locations worldwide. The addition of PayPal's PYUSD stablecoin enhances BPV Retail's offering by providing a fast, low-cost option for cross-border transfers. As PayPal's President and CEO, Alex Chriss, stated, "We plan to reduce the cost of cross-border transfers and provide consumers the option to eliminate transaction fees altogether when funding with our PYUSD stablecoin." BPV Retail's expanded service now offers users access to both physical and digital financial services, including support for Bitcoin Lightning transactions. This comprehensive approach caters to a wide range of financial needs for the 1.7 billion un-banked people in the world. The wallet's functionality is further enhanced by its diverse funding options. Users can add funds using VISA and Mastercard in 180 countries, as well as through SEPA Instant in the EU and ACH in the USA. This broad range of funding methods, combined with PayPal's Xoom service enabling money transfers to over 160 countries, provides users with unparalleled flexibility in managing their finances globally. PayPal's blockchain strategy, particularly through PYUSD, aligns with BPV Retail's goal of providing practical, everyday financial tools. As Jose Fernandez da Ponte, PayPal's Senior VP of Blockchain, Cryptocurrency, and Digital Currency, explained, "Making PYUSD available on the Solana blockchain furthers our goal of enabling a digital currency with a stable value designed for commerce and payments." By leveraging the strengths of both traditional financial systems and emerging digital technologies, BPV Retail Whitelabel Wallet sets a new standard for digital wallets in terms of scope, functionality, and global accessibility.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Original: Blocks’ tbDEX: The Blockchain Remittance Solution That Isn’t - BPV - Stellar Blockchain consulting and more</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:01:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:01:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.bpventures.us/blog/original-blocks-tbdex-the-blockchain-remittance-solution-that-isnt</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bpventures.us/blog/original-blocks-tbdex-the-blockchain-remittance-solution-that-isnt"/>
    <content type="html">Cash App, the fourth most popular financial application in the US, boasts 50 million monthly active users in 2024. This represents about 17.6% of the US population, or roughly one in six consumers. Cash App's parent company, Block (formerly Square), continues to drive innovation in the financial technology space including a small startup called TBD.TBD, Unlike traditional blockchain technologies, tbDEX is an open-source, decentralized exchange protocol designed to bridge the gap between conventional financial systems and decentralized technologies like cryptocurrencies. TbDEX leverages decentralized identifiers (DIDs) and verifiable credentials (VCs) to establish trust and facilitate compliant transactions between counterparties without centralized intermediaries.TbDEX brings two key features to the table: the decentralization of Know Your Customer (KYC) data and a workflow for a Request for Quote (RFQ) system. These innovations raise important questions: Is this enough to drive adoption in the 28 Trillion dollar international payments business? Will it result in cost savings for the end customer? There are several factors indicating the project is on the right track.First, by excluding blockchain, digital assets, or stablecoins from its core solution, tbDEX alleviates concerns for remittance companies wary of jeopardizing their banking relationships, bank account access, and regulatory compliance. This strategic move makes tbDEX an attractive option for companies looking to innovate without risking their existing banking connections. Digital assets such as Stablecoins can be used - and are by US firms such as Conduit - but are not a required part of the solution.Integrating an ISO 20022 payment gateway into tbDEX would be straightforward. For our proof of concept, we used a payment in USDC, sending funds to Nigeria via Stellar. The KYC and other steps are currently mocked up, but the underlying workflow can be easily adapted for any remittance company or wallet.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
