<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Brave on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@bravepay?source=rss-77da8f520bc0------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbravepay.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*aVs1EP0gKBsStleemI6R2A.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*aVs1EP0gKBsStleemI6R2A.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbravepay.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:12+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Boosting adoption with Liquidity Rewards.</title>
    <published>2021-12-30T10:57:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-30T10:57:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://bravepay.medium.com/boosting-adoption-with-liquidity-rewards-a33e16e63d13?source=rss-77da8f520bc0------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bravepay.medium.com/boosting-adoption-with-liquidity-rewards-a33e16e63d13?source=rss-77da8f520bc0------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Brave</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The introduction of AMM has been arguable the longest awaited upgrade of Stellar Protocol 18. Designed to inject more liquidity to Stellar markets, this new feature allows holders to make deposits in pools of token pairs and get rewarded for the transactions made by the selected market maker. Nonetheless, a scarce 0.3% transaction fee distributed among the liquidity pool members, has not been an incentive to be too excited about. Well, up until now…Since the release of AMM, our holders consistently demanded bigger returns for locking their BRAVE tokens into our liquidity pools, as some other crypto players do. Purposely, we didn’t rush to this liquidity rewards party. Provided the implications of this decision, we wanted to be extra cautious. We analyzed multiple projections and scenarios to be 100% sure that the mechanics adopted would have a positive impact in the project and guarantee long term value growth. In fact, with the launch our re-designed rewards system, every new incentive in our ecosystem must comply with three guiding principles:Eliminate fraud by designReward longer term commitments whilst ensuring flexibilityFoster adoption and coin value growthToday we are pleased to introduce BRAVE liquidity rewards. This new program rewards holders providing liquidity to the market in the BRAVE-XLM liquidity Pool.Joining the liquidity rewards program is very simple:Search the BRAVE-XLM pool in the AMM section of any stellar exchange or at BravePay.net ( https://tools.bravepay.net/amm )Connect your wallet and deposit amounts in the selected pool. Bear in mind that the deposits on each pair should have equal value. For argument sake, for every dollar in BRAVEs a dollar in XLMs should be added.You will be all set.About Liquidity PoolsThink of a Liquidity Pool as Fund that operates in the crypto market, buying and selling two pairs. For every transaction made, Stellar sets a fix premium of 0.3% that goes straight to the pool. This is how the pool makes profit.But how are the rewards distributed among the pool participants? Stellar distributes those fees generated by the pool proportionally to the individual contribution to the total Pool size (individual pool share).Individual pool share = User’s contribution to the pool / Total pool sizeUnlike Tokens or Company shares, the individual pool share is dynamic, it grows or shrinks as the Pool size and or the individual contribution evolves:Individual Pool share grows if:The Total Pool size shrinks and user amount in the pool stays the same or increasesThe Total Pool size stays the same and the user amount in the pool grows.The Total Pool size grows and the user amount in the pool also grows at a higher proportion.Individual Pool share goes down if:The Total Pool size grows and user amount in the pool stays the same or decreasesThe Total Pool size stays the same and the user amount in the pool decreases.The Total Pool size decreases and the user amount in the pool decreases at a higher proportion.BRAVE Liquidity rewardsBRAVE liquidity rewards improves Stellar’s 0.3% fee baseline, adding an extra 10% of the pool size in BRAVE rewards. This additional incentive is allocated for daily distribution as per the following formula:Total daily rewards = (Total BRAVE pool size x 10%) / 30The bigger the amount in the pool, the bigger the daily rewards distribution. This approach fosters the growth of the liquidity pool which is beneficial for both coins in the pool.Remember that BRAVE liquidity rewards are paid daily via transfer to the Stellar Address of pool participants. This gives more flexibility to the holder and also opens up the possibility for smart investors to re-invest the daily rewards received, pushing the growth of the pool and thus the future earnings received.A practical example.Please find bellow a simulation of the return for a BRAVE-XLM pool with 10 million BRAVEs size, 100 members with equal shares and 10 million BRAVEs of monthly transaction volume.Get in touch.For more information about BRAVE, our products and rewards, please join us on:Official Website: https://BravePay.netTwitter: https://twitter.com/BraveCorporati1Telegram (ENG): https://t.me/bravecorporationTelegram (ESP): https://t.me/bravespainTelegram (GER): https://t.me/bravegermanyTelegram (ITA): https://t.me/braveitaly</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Need for change: Hello Brave Staking.</title>
    <published>2021-12-27T11:20:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-27T11:20:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://bravepay.medium.com/need-for-change-hello-brave-staking-8e449b2347b2?source=rss-77da8f520bc0------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bravepay.medium.com/need-for-change-hello-brave-staking-8e449b2347b2?source=rss-77da8f520bc0------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Brave</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Braves,In less than 6 months BRAVE has become a global phenomenon. Over 24k enthusiast supporters trust today the future of age controlled payments, pushing us to the very top of the Stellar network ranks. With a progressive 20x price increase since the Initial Distribution date, Brave is arguably one of the best performing Stellar tokens of 2021.Our Rewards have been an important vector for this success. They have accelerated our exposure in the Stellar Community, attracting an army of true believers in our vision. Yet, it has brought to us others, with worse intentions. People with no ethics, driven by greed and quick returns. People that abused the system with malpractices and cheats. People that use bots to dump every single token harvested through multiple accounts, sucking liquidity out of investors pools, manipulating the price…all in all, people that harmed our true, loyal investor base.Funny enough, we must thank the bad guys. If you gaze into the abyss, the abyss gazes also into you. Thanks to them, now we know what took us right here.Our Rewards were conceived to attract and retain loyal investors, giving them good incentives to keep and grow their holdings as new Corporate clients would inject more liquidity into the Market. The results of our VIP rewards exceeded our initial expectations: over 99.8% of the original VIPs keep their investments in Brave today.With the Universal and trading rewards we aimed at creating an easier entry level to Brave. The idea was simple: little commitments for big returns, that would deflate overtime as more people qualified. This seemed to be the perfect incentive for our community to expand and attract new members to our project. We were wrong.Both Trading and Universal rewards have been a call for fraud, in multiple forms and shapes. We detected users splitting their holdings among multiple accounts with the minimum qualifying balance; others, buying and selling among those accounts to also get the trading incentives; And bot accounts constantly dumping all the rewards harvested through multi accounts, sinking the coin price and compromising our growth. We witnessed how on every payroll, the dump of the extra supply in circulation offset the gains of a whole week and damaged our liquidity. We have been sitting on the lines for way too long seeing the same train coming over and over again. Now we must act.After a thorough analysis, we are happy to introduce today our completely re-designed Rewards system.1. OBJECTIVESOur new reward scheme is built on 3 guiding principles.Eliminate fraud by designReward longer term commitments whilst ensuring flexibilityFoster adoption and coin value growth2. MECHANICSWith Brave Staking our holders can now earn interest by staking their Braves for up to 12 months periods:1 month: 0.5% (compounded APY 6%)3 months: 3,2% (compounded APY 13,4%)6 months: 9% (compounded APY 18,8%)12 months: 26% (compounded APY 26%)3. BENEFITSUnlike universal and trading rewards or bank deposits, Brave Staking rewards:Do not require a minimum quantity to qualify.The payroll is customized to each user: there is not a fix pay date in the month for all users but the earned interest will be paid to each user when the chosen stacking period is over.The quantities deposited are not locked during the agreed term (1, 3, 6 or 12 months) so that the holder can withdraw them at any given time. In such cases, though, no interest will be paid.Holders will be notified in a selected e-mail address when the staking period is finished.4. PLANNED BURNING EVENTSIn order to offset the impact in the coin price of the rewards distributed, each and every month 24 million Braves will be burnt to compensate the extra supply in circulation with the Staking rewards. These planned burning events will happen the last day of every month.5. VIP REWARDSThe VIP Rewards will remain exactly the same as before.6. EFFECTIVE CHANGESBrave Stacking rewards will become effective the week of December 15th once all the necessary technical developments will be released in staking.BravePay.netThe Universal and Trading rewards will be immediately discontinued. The quantities for the Trading and Universal corresponding to November (24 Million Braves) and December 1st to 15th (12 million Braves) as well as the year end Big Prize for the Trading Rewards (20 Million Braves) will be burnt. This makes a total of 66 Million Braves that will be taken out of the Company reserves account.Staying true to Brave´s Vision and protecting our strong Community exceeds the benefits or flaws of any short term impact on our coin price.We keep working restlessly to keep growing this ambitious project with our upcoming App release, our participation in the Webit Founders Games finals, new strategic partnerships, referral program…and much more news that will be announced before year end.We are here to make history, building the very first cryptocurrency with an age-tag. Our future belongs to us.Thanks, Braves.Javier Gutierrez.Co-Founder and CEO at BraveMadrid, November 15th 2021</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
