<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">BTQ | Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.btq.com/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=BrowserlessCSSBridge&amp;browserless_url=http%3A%2F%2F10.0.0.124%3A3050%2F&amp;browserless&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.btq.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-container+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.markdown-content-wrapper&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.eyebrow&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;date_format=M+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=BrowserlessCSSBridge&amp;browserless_url=http%3A%2F%2F10.0.0.124%3A3050%2F&amp;browserless&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.btq.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-container+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.markdown-content-wrapper&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.eyebrow&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;date_format=M+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T21:44:48+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Ethereum’s Roadmap for Post-Quantum Cryptography</title>
    <published>2024-10-21T21:44:46+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-21T21:44:46+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.btq.com/blog/ethereums-roadmap-post-quantum-cryptography</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.btq.com/blog/ethereums-roadmap-post-quantum-cryptography"/>
    <author>
      <name>@BTQ_Tech</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Ethereum, a decentralized public blockchain platform created by Vitalik Buterin in 2015, enables developers to build decentralized applications (DApps) and deploy smart contracts using its native cryptocurrency, Ether (ETH). Ethereum has played a crucial role in the development of non-fungible tokens (NFTs), decentralized finance (DeFi), decentralized autonomous organizations (DAOs), and the Metaverse. Often described as "the world's most programmable blockchain," Ethereum facilitates digital asset transactions and supports a wide range of decentralized applications.The security of online communications and digital assets relies on two popular cryptographic standards: RSA and elliptic curve cryptography (ECC), both of which assume that conventional computers cannot easily solve certain complex mathematical problems. Cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin and Ethereum are built on ECC. These standards currently use public key encryption (PKE) algorithms that are considered secure because classical computers struggle to factor very large numbers or compute elliptic curve discrete logarithms.However, the development of quantum computers has introduced the "quantum threat." When large-scale quantum computers are developed, they could solve these problems and break current public-key cryptosystems, undermining the security, confidentiality, and integrity of digital communications and data on the internet.Currently, Ethereum is safe from quantum attacks because quantum computers are not yet powerful enough to break its underlying cryptographic security. However, as quantum computing advances, it could eventually compromise Ethereum's cryptographic algorithms, which protect assets and value stored on the ledger.Understanding Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC)In 1992, Peter Shor demonstrated that large-scale quantum computers could break current cryptographic systems using Shor’s algorithm. This discovery prompted cryptographers and researchers worldwide to explore post-quantum cryptography (PQC) implementation.Post-quantum cryptography, also known as quantum-proof or quantum-resistant encryption, refers to cryptographic schemes designed to protect classical computers from quantum computer attacks. PQC prepares for the quantum computing era by revising the mathematical algorithms underlying current cryptography. Importantly, PQC can be implemented on today's classical computers to safeguard them from future quantum attacks.PQC is critical to the future of digital security because data that is safe today, based on current cryptography, will become vulnerable in the quantum computing era. Implementing PQC techniques is necessary to keep data secure, both for blockchain systems and the internet as a whole.The Quantum Threat to EthereumEthereum uses common cryptographic methods to secure transactions and maintain the integrity of its distributed ledger. However, these methods may become ineffective due to potential advances in quantum computing. Ethereum's reliance on ECDSA, BLS, and KZG makes it vulnerable to quantum attacks, which could enable malicious actors to decrypt private keys, compromise smart contract integrity, and forge digital signatures—potentially giving them control over associated funds.The BLS signature scheme, which uses bilinear pairings and elliptic curve operations (BLS12-381), differs from ECDSA (secp256k1) but is still vulnerable to quantum attacks. A sufficiently powerful quantum computer running Shor's algorithm could break these elliptic curve-based cryptographic systems and expose sensitive user data on the Ethereum blockchain.Similarly, KZG (Kate-Zaverucha-Goldberg) commitment schemes, used in various parts of Ethereum for generating cryptographic secrets based on polynomial commitments, are also vulnerable to quantum computers. Trusted setups, which involve generating randomness that quantum computers cannot reverse-engineer, are currently used to mitigate this risk. However, the optimal solution is to replace these schemes with quantum-safe cryptography.Proposed Quantum-Resistant SolutionsTo prepare Ethereum for the quantum computing era, several quantum-resistant solutions have been proposed, including hash-based cryptography, lattice-based cryptography, code-based cryptography, multivariate polynomial cryptography, and STARK-based solutions. Two have gained particular attention:STARK-based solutionszk-STARKs (Zero-Knowledge Scalable Transparent Arguments of Knowledge) use a zero-knowledge proof system to enable the verification of encrypted data without revealing any underlying information. STARKs offer improvements over zk-SNARKs by relying on collision-resistant hash functions rather than elliptic curves and trusted setups. This makes them more secure and quantum-resistant. Additionally, STARKs eliminate the need for trusted setups in a blockchain network like Ethereum. To support the planned adoption of zk-STARKs in Ethereum 3.0, the Ethereum Foundation has awarded a $12 million grant to STARKware, a company focused on developing zk-STARK scaling solutions.Lattice-based cryptographyLattice-based cryptography, a post-quantum technique, is based on the computational difficulty of the nearest or shortest vector problem in lattices. Public keys are generated by encrypting an arbitrary lattice point, while private keys are derived from evaluating the shortest vector in the lattice. Many cryptographers view lattice-based algorithms as the most promising solution for securing data and providing quantum-resistant encryption due to their reliance on the hardness of solving lattice problems.However, these post-quantum cryptography methods present new challenges, including efficiency issues and compatibility with existing blockchain operations. Securing Ethereum from quantum attacks while balancing efficiency, compatibility, scalability, and performance will be crucial.Ethereum's Proactive Approach to Quantum ThreatsEthereum recognizes the quantum threat and has taken proactive steps to integrate quantum resistance into its roadmap. Current research and development efforts, especially regarding post-quantum cryptography, include the implementation of an opcode that allows users to submit zk-STARK proofs. These proofs validate a user's knowledge of a private preimage and a public key generated via approved hash functions, enabling the replacement of the user's account code with a quantum-resistant validation mechanism.Ethereum 2.0, fully launched in late 2022, replaced the Proof of Work (PoW) consensus mechanism with the Proof of Stake (PoS) system, which is believed to be more quantum-resistant. Ethereum 2.0 also offers the option to switch to quantum-resistant signature schemes like Lamport, XMSS, and SPHINCS+.Looking ahead, Ethereum 3.0, expected to launch in 2027, will introduce more robust quantum-resistant protocols such as Winternitz signatures and zk-STARKs, further protecting transactions from quantum attacks by preventing the exposure of private keys.ConclusionWhile quantum computers powerful enough to break cryptographic systems are not yet here, the ongoing development of quantum technology threatens Ethereum's security. The Ethereum community has been proactive in its efforts to safeguard the network from quantum threats by integrating quantum-resistant solutions into future upgrades. As quantum computing advances, continued innovation in blockchain security will be essential to protect Ethereum and the multi-billion-dollar assets it secures.To explore Ethereum's official roadmap documentation, see here and here.&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://btq-publication.ghost.io/content/images/2024/10/Blog---ethereum-quantum-upgrade-roadmap.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Will Quantum Computers Break Bitcoin?</title>
    <published>2024-10-08T21:44:47+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-08T21:44:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.btq.com/blog/will-quantum-computers-break-bitcoin</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.btq.com/blog/will-quantum-computers-break-bitcoin"/>
    <author>
      <name>@BTQ_Tech</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Bitcoin, the first and best-known cryptocurrency, was created in 2009 by an unknown individual or group using the pseudonym Satoshi Nakamoto. It is a decentralized digital currency that enables users to make secure, peer-to-peer transactions without needing a middleman or central authority, such as a bank or government. Due to the freedom it offers, Bitcoin's value has experienced significant volatility since its inception.Often referred to as "digital gold," Bitcoin (BTC)  is currently sitting at a value of over $60,000 (October 2024). The cryptocurrency market has also expanded significantly, with the total market value of all cryptocurrencies surpassing $1 trillion.However, quantum computing poses a potential threat to Bitcoin. This new type of computing harnesses the laws of quantum mechanics to solve problems that are too complex for classical computers. Quantum computing has advanced rapidly and aims to tackle problems of much greater complexity than even supercomputers can handle. Due to its highly sophisticated computational power, quantum computers could eventually compromise the cryptographic standards that secure Bitcoin.Understanding Bitcoin's Security FrameworkBitcoin's emergence has revolutionized the financial ecosystem. Its decentralized nature, powered by blockchain technology, has set the standard for the entire digital currency ecosystem. At the core of this revolutionary system is cryptography, which ensures its trustworthiness and resilience.Bitcoin employs Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC), a public-key cryptographic system that uses two keys: a public key for encryption, which is freely available, and a private key for decryption, kept secret by the user. These keys function as digital signatures, uniquely linked to individual Bitcoin holdings and serving as verifiable proof of ownership. Only the holder of the private key can authorize transactions, preventing unauthorized access.While no digital system is entirely immune to vulnerabilities, Bitcoin's decentralized structure and its consensus mechanism, Proof of Work (PoW), provide robust security against attacks. In this mechanism, miners compete to solve complex mathematical problems, ensuring that only valid transactions are added to the blockchain. This distributed consensus prevents any single entity from compromising Bitcoin's security and helps ensure that all transactions are recorded transparently and securely.What Makes Quantum Computing Different?Quantum computing, an entirely different approach to computing, employs the laws of quantum mechanics to solve problems beyond the reach of conventional computers. Quantum Physicist Shohini Ghose compares quantum computing to light bulbs and candles, stating, "The light bulb isn't just a better candle; it's something completely different." While quantum computers are not universally faster, they excel at solving certain highly complex problems, such as modeling atomic behavior in molecules for new drug development or detecting subtle fraud patterns in financial transactions.Quantum computing shares some features with classical computing, such as circuits and logic gates, but it relies on unique principles like:Qubits: Quantum bits, or qubits, are the fundamental units of quantum computing. Unlike binary bits, which can only be 0 or 1, qubits can exist in multiple states simultaneously.Superposition: Qubits can exist in a combination of states, called superposition, allowing quantum computers to explore complex, multidimensional computational spaces.Entanglement: Quantum entanglement links qubits so that the measurement of one affects the others, even over great distances.The Quantum Threat Timeline for BitcoinImagine a future where ultra-fast computers can break nearly all existing encryption, threatening the security of digital assets like Bitcoin. Quantum computers have the potential to crack current encryption standards, using algorithms like Shor's algorithm, which could theoretically solve the mathematical problems that underpin Bitcoin's cryptography in seconds, rather than the billion years it would take classical computers.Although quantum technology is still in its early stages, with existing systems having high error rates, researchers are working towards building fault-tolerant, error-corrected quantum computers. To protect Bitcoin from these future threats, the underlying technology will need to be upgraded to quantum-resistant algorithms. The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) has been working on identifying such algorithms since 2016, exploring options like hash-based, lattice-based, and multivariate polynomial-based cryptographic solutions that can withstand both classical and quantum attacks.The Post-Quantum Bitcoin WorldQuantum computers are a double-edged sword: they promise solutions to complex problems but also threaten current digital security. Bitcoin, which relies on ECC for its security, is vulnerable to quantum attacks. However, while the development of quantum computers capable of breaking Bitcoin is still years away, the time to upgrade Bitcoin's encryption to withstand quantum threats is now.Will quantum computers break Bitcoin? The answer is, eventually, yes—if large quantum computers are built. But as of now, Bitcoin has time to adapt. As the quantum era approaches, the crypto world will need to evolve. Rest assured, Q-Day is on the horizon, and the preparations are already underway.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://btq-publication.ghost.io/content/images/2024/10/Blog---Quantum-Computers-break-bitcoin_.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Quantum Entanglement and Computing: A Beginner's Guide</title>
    <published>2024-09-30T21:44:48+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-30T21:44:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.btq.com/blog/quantum-entanglement-computing-beginners-guide</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.btq.com/blog/quantum-entanglement-computing-beginners-guide"/>
    <author>
      <name>@BTQ_Tech</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Quantum physics, one of the major branches of modern physics, lays the foundation for our understanding of all fundamental particles, energy, and forces (except gravity). It explains how our universe works on the tiniest scales, including the very building blocks of nature: atoms, electrons, photons, and even smaller particles. Quantum physics has significantly contributed to advancements in technology in areas such as atomic energy, integrated circuits, lasers, photonics, and even quantum computing. Today, lasers and photonics alone are a $16 trillion market!Quantum entanglement is a core phenomenon in quantum physics that occurs when a pair or group of particles, such as electrons or photons, become entangled, creating a special connection between them, even when separated by an enormous distance. Where this phenomenon finds practical application is in quantum computing. Understanding quantum computing, which can help us find better materials and medicines, and solve complex problems exponentially faster, requires us to understand quantum entanglement.&amp;nbsp;Understanding Quantum EntanglementQuantum entanglement lies at the heart of quantum physics, defying our understanding of classical physics and causality. This phenomenon is shown when two or more particles become entangled, establishing a special connection or relationship between them, regardless of distance in space. Think of two objects that are connected in such a way that they are described as a single system, even when set apart by a vast distance. The state of one object cannot be described or measured without getting information about the other object's state in the system.In 1905, Albert Einstein helped to pioneer the quantum theory, from which he proposed the existence of quantum entanglement. In 1935, Einstein, alongside Boris Podolsky and Nathan Rosen, published what became known as the Einstein-Podolsky-Rosen (EPR) paradox, which inadvertently uncovered the strange concept of “entanglement.” Because of the mysterious nature of this phenomenon, especially the fact that entangled particles tend to share an inexplicable bond despite being very far apart, Einstein termed it “spooky action at a distance.” Erwin Schrödinger, one of the founding members of quantum mechanics was the first physicist to coin the term “entanglement.”This became the core concept that allowed scientists to speculate about the idea of a computer that would leverage these properties.&amp;nbsp;The Principles of Quantum ComputingFrom being considered purely speculative to becoming a rapidly emerging technology, quantum computing is a paradigm shift from classical computing. It is an entirely different approach to computing that leverages the properties of entanglement and superposition to solve highly complex problems that classical computing finds difficult to solve. Just like classical computing relies on bits for its operations, quantum computing also relies on quantum bits (or qubits) for the same purpose.Qubits are the fundamental units of information in quantum computing that are a linear combination of two distinct states. Unlike classical bits that can only be 0 or 1, qubits can simultaneously be 0 or 1 or in a superposition of both until their state is measured. Depending on the architecture of quantum systems, qubits can be made from trapped ions, photons, real or artificial atoms, or quasiparticles.If you have ever wondered how quantum computers solve complex problems that are unfeasible for classical computers, then the answer lies in the property of quantum entanglement. Quantum computing uses quantum entanglement to create networks of qubits. As more and more qubits are entangled in these networks, the ability of the system to handle calculations grows exponentially.&amp;nbsp;Quantum Entanglement in Quantum ComputingQuantum entanglement is integral to what makes quantum computing more powerful than classical computing.Quantum circuit-level implementation of entanglement is achieved through a CNOT gate. A controlled-NOT (or CNOT) gate is used to create an entangled state for two qubits. The first qubit is usually called the control qubit, while the second qubit is called the target qubit. The CNOT gate flips the target qubit only on the condition that the control qubit is in the state |1⟩. Representing this gate can take the form of the matrix [1,0,0,0], [0,1,0,0], [0,0,0,1], [0,0,1,0].&amp;nbsp;Quantum entanglement has contributed immensely to our advancements and continues to make in quantum computing, including:Quantum algorithms: Quantum algorithms are the step-by-step procedures that harness quantum properties, such as entanglement and superposition, for complex calculations at a much faster rate than classical computing. In other words, quantum algorithms are the stepwise coded instructions that leverage quantum properties to handle the intricacies of advanced computations.&amp;nbsp;Error correction: Quantum error correction (QEC) is a technique that protects quantum computers from noise. When quantum information (or qubits) are exposed to this kind of noise, they get degraded. This is known as decoherence. QEC relies on quantum entanglement to handle the encoding and protection of the logical qubits. For example, the three-qubit bit-flip code, known to be one of the simplest QEC codes, uses three entangled physical qubits to encode one logical qubit. If one of the physical qubits flips due to the influence of noise, the remaining two can detect and correct the error by measuring their entanglement.Cryptography: Quantum&amp;nbsp;cryptography&amp;nbsp;is a type of encryption technique that leverages the capabilities of entangled quantum bits (qubits). This cryptographic system takes advantage of the principles of quantum entanglement, where two qubits (or particles) remain connected even when separated by a vast distance. This system promises to be more secure than existing cryptographic methods. This is because any attempt to gain access to or intercept information causes detectable changes in the entanglement, which will instantaneously alert both the sender and receiver of interference.&amp;nbsp;Entanglement in the Next-Gen Computing Era&amp;nbsp;Quantum entanglement is a mind-bending phenomenon that occurs when two or more particles become interconnected in such a way that their quantum states are dependent on each other, regardless of the distance that separates them. This phenomenon is the key to quantum computing and algorithms.&amp;nbsp;Two quantum algorithms that leverage entanglement are Shor’s algorithm and Grover’s algorithm. The former (Shor’s algorithm) is used for integer factorization, that is, it finds the prime factors when given an integer N. It is exponentially faster at solving this problem than the best-known classical algorithm. Grover’s algorithm can search a large, unsorted database exponentially faster than the best-known classical algorithm for the same purpose. These algorithms demonstrate the transformative potential of quantum computing in areas such as cryptography and database search and leverage the power of quantum entanglement to open a new era of next-gen computing.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://btq-publication.ghost.io/content/images/2024/09/Blog---Quantum-Entanglement-and-Computing.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
