<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Cables Finance on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@cables-finance?source=rss-4634b6fb7a2e------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcables-finance.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*KQ8zCkVv9ecldeNjPVGe7w.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*KQ8zCkVv9ecldeNjPVGe7w.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcables-finance.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:21+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Why We’re Excited About the Cables Finance Launch on Stellar</title>
    <published>2024-04-12T16:12:39+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-04-12T16:12:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://cables-finance.medium.com/why-were-excited-about-the-cables-finance-launch-on-stellar-9cfa994ffc73?source=rss-4634b6fb7a2e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cables-finance.medium.com/why-were-excited-about-the-cables-finance-launch-on-stellar-9cfa994ffc73?source=rss-4634b6fb7a2e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Cables Finance</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The Cables Finance launch on the Stellar network represents a pivotal moment where traditional finance and blockchain technology converge, adding to its already strong ecosystem. This partnership embodies a shared vision to simplify cross-border payments and bring liquid FX trading to blockchain, democratizing access to financial services globally.A Shared Vision for Financial InclusionThe Stellar Development Foundation’s commitment to making financial systems more accessible worldwide perfectly complements the Cables Finance mission to revolutionize FX trading. By harnessing the Stellar blockchain, Cables is poised to transform FX trading into a more transparent, accessible, and equitable experience for all.The Dynamic Approach of Cables FinanceCables Finance stands out in the blockchain space with its semi-decentralized exchange model, a testament to our adaptability and commitment to innovation. This model blends the autonomy of self-custody with the advantages of centralized liquidity, ensuring users enjoy a trading experience that’s both secure and competitive.Quote from Tomer Weller — VP of Product at the Stellar Development Foundation:“Working with Cables Finance, we’re really pushing the envelope by bringing FX on-chain, which aligns with the Foundation’s goal to create access to the global financial system. Cables Finance is a game-changer, marrying traditional market liquidity with the security of blockchain in a way that’s seamless. Cable’s launch on Stellar paves the way for a more inclusive financial world for everyone.”Innovations and Features Setting Cables ApartCables Finance introduces a suite of unique features, including a central limit order book (CLOB), slippage-free trading, and OTC capabilities, ensuring our platform is not just another DEX but a groundbreaking financial tool that can bring stronger access to FX and high quality stablecoins to support economies where currency value and trade is more volatile.Stellar and Cables Finance: A Synergy for the FutureThe energy and collaboration within the Stellar ecosystem significantly amplify our efforts, enabling Cables Finances to explore new possibilities and contribute to the adoption of blockchain.Looking Ahead: What’s Next for Smart Contracts on Stellar?The roadmap focuses on adoption and enhancement. With smart contracts now available on Stellar, the goal now is to attract and integrate as many aligned financial services as possible. The Stellar Community Fund (SCF) plays a crucial role in encouraging further adoption, having already dispersed over $15 million from a $100 million adoption fund and supported more than 180 projects. Additionally, the work continues on technical improvements including scalability optimizations and cost model adjustments.Looking Ahead: What’s Next for Cables Finance?Cables Finance is dedicated to evolving through community feedback and innovative features post-launch. Our internal team is hard at work refining automation, enhancing system robustness, and embracing community insights to guide future developments on Soroban.In essence, the collaboration between Stellar and Cables Finance blends blockchain’s revolutionary potential with the robustness of traditional financial systems. Together, we’re not just facing the future; we’re building it.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introduction to Cables</title>
    <published>2021-11-08T14:21:59+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T14:21:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://cables-finance.medium.com/introduction-to-cables-8c770108a9d5?source=rss-4634b6fb7a2e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cables-finance.medium.com/introduction-to-cables-8c770108a9d5?source=rss-4634b6fb7a2e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Cables Finance</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Moving the world’s largest market to the blockchainMoving the world’s largest market to the blockchainCables is a decentralized exchange built on Algorand designed to integrate currency rails in TradFi and crypto seamlessly. By creating a symbiotic relationship between TradFi and crypto, Cables merges and reinforces the advantages of both financial ecosystems. We are thrilled to be tackling a long-standing disconnect between the largest market in the world (FX) and the booming space of crypto and DeFi. Read more about Cables and our mission below, and keep an eye out for more news coming soon.BackgroundCables aims to give accessibility to institutions and retailers across the TradFi, CeFi, and DeFi ecosystem through a non-custodial exchange built on Algorand. Traditional finance is guarded and restricted to select participants built on inefficient markets, favoring wholesale participants. The advancements in blockchain technology have led to significant growth across different digital protocols and the ultimate creation of DeFi. DeFi projects have made trading and borrowing/lending a barrier-less, peer-to-peer marketplace contrary to the traditional financial markets or brokers. These DeFi projects tend to be siloed across specific blockchains, but that is precisely the problem Cables addresses. We believe that all financial products will transact on-chain in the future, which is why we are building a decentralized exchange solution that will disintermediate the intermediaries at the application layer.Core Beliefs:The added layers and middlemen in FX trading make price discovery and trading complex and should be more accessible for all fiatsTrading should be accessible for all, not just select participantsFiat to crypto conversion should be efficient, secure, and easily accessibleCross-blockchain marketplaces have the ability to connect institutions and individuals to both liquidity and resources not previously available to them.A compliant DeFi network (ie. Algorand) needs to be incorporated to power these applications, while also having the ability to be cross chainCables OverviewCables are automated smart transactions and financial rails for bringing FX onto the blockchain. The innovation in traditional finance has fallen behind the digital asset industry that looks to disrupt and decentralize business models. Despite the rapid growth in the digital asset industry compared to traditional finance, there is a lack of effective risk mitigation solutions across the blockchain and digital asset ecosystem. The advancements in technology will continue to connect more and more people, industries, countries, and assets electronically, so managing and facilitating global commerce with a solution agnostic to an asset, currency, or technology is needed to protect their assets.Cables will have permissionless and permissioned pools so that every intended user can transact with optionality. that powers smart transactions to manage FX and Risk management across B2B, B2C, and Financial verticals built on Algorand and other protocols. This suite of dApps creates an automated smart contract on the blockchain so companies can take control of their fx spot, rolling spot, swaps, and risk management. Cables will allow people, companies, and industries to trade freely and automatically manage their currency and assets exposure with greater efficiency..Follow our journeyWe are working hard behind the scenes to bring Cables to the market as quickly as possible and will continue to share updates across our social media channels. So follow along with our journey across these outlets, and we look forward to connecting with you more in the near future.TwitterTelegramLinkedInMediumRedditDiscord</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Bridging the Gap Between FX and Crypto</title>
    <published>2021-06-04T14:57:07+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-04T14:57:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://cables-finance.medium.com/bridging-the-gap-between-fx-and-crypto-d9d9e3d3bab1?source=rss-4634b6fb7a2e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cables-finance.medium.com/bridging-the-gap-between-fx-and-crypto-d9d9e3d3bab1?source=rss-4634b6fb7a2e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Cables Finance</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Why it’s so important, and how CABLEs are revolutionizing the process.Crypto keeps growing, but the assumption has remained that it isn’t quite stable enough to be a safe investment. Many conservative investors still see crypto as a novelty that may one day pan out, but currently is too risky, while traditional markets are frequently deemed as more dependable and predictable. As the volatility of traditional markets continues to increase, the middle ground between them and crypto is starting to blur. Alongside this, there is a desperate need for these FX markets to be connected on a more global scale to individuals across the world.As of now, the majority of the world has no, little, or poor option for converting fiat into crypto. The current financial system is tied to only a few global cities, but moving the FX market on chain would allow for a global reach. This on-chain market would also give access to more individuals and institutions within the space.CABLEs Forward ThinkingBringing the world&amp;#39;s largest market on-chain is not an easy feat, but one that is inevitable in the future. The added layers and middlemen in FX trading make price discovery and trading complex and should be easier for all fiats. The two targeted aspects of the CABLEs project are how bringing blockchain to FX will impact the global market as well as how bringing FX to the blockchain will impact blockchain as a whole.Bringing The Blockchain to FXRisk management on FX DesksReplace archaic FX forwards industryLower friction of global tradeE-commerce ToolsBringing FX to The BlockchainFiat to DeFi On-RampsCross-asset borrowing and lendingMulti-currency auctions (NFTs)Follow our journeyWe are working hard behind the scenes to bring CABLEs to the market as quickly as possible and will continue to share updates across our social media channels. Follow along with our journey across these outlets, and we look forward to connecting with you more in the near future.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
