<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Cedar News</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.cedar.money/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cedar.money%2Fnews&amp;url_selector=a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fnews-updates%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cedar.money%2Fnews&amp;url_selector=a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fnews-updates%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:24+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Cedar.money</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:02:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.cedar.money/news-updates/how-cedar-money-protects-your-business-with-multi-factor-authentication</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.cedar.money/news-updates/how-cedar-money-protects-your-business-with-multi-factor-authentication"/>
    <content type="html">Over $1 trillion was stolen globally by scammers in 2024, according to the Global Anti-Scam Alliance (GASA) 2024 Global State of Scams Report. This figure rivals the GDP of some nations and an even more staggering insight from this report is that only 4% of the victims of these scams were able to recover their losses.‍Cyber threats are on a constant rise globally and businesses dealing with high value international payments are prime targets. Fraudsters are getting more sophisticated and a single breach could be devastating, both financially and reputation-wise.‍This is why at Cedar Money, security isn’t a filler word. It’s a cumulation of intentional processes aimed at safeguarding your funds against fraud and other cyber threats. One of these processes is Multi-Factor Authentication.‍What is Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) and Why Does It Matter?‍Multi-factor Authentication (MFA) is a security enhancement system that involves users providing more than one verification factor to confirm their identity before they’re granted access to an application or account. By adding this additional security measure that goes beyond simply entering a password, MFA significantly reduces the risk of security threats like phishing and password breaches—making it harder for unauthorized persons to gain access to a user’s account.‍MFA models typically combine several factors which break down authentication into:Something the user knows: A password, pin or the answer to a pre-set security question.Something the user has: A physical device like your smartphone, security key or hardware token.Something the user is: Biometrics like fingerprints, voice patterns, facial recognition or iris scans.‍Why does MFA matter?‍In only the first half of 2023, the European Central Bank (ECB) and European Banking Authority (EBA) recorded that 71% of card payment fraud in the European Economic Area (EEA) involved cross-border transactions. That’s a huge indicator of the heightened vulnerability of international transactions can be if stronger security protocols like MFA are treated as just a nice-to-have instead of an essential measure for protecting your business.‍How Cedar Money’s Multi-Factor Authentication Works‍At Cedar Money, your account security is our utmost priority which is why we make it easy for you to add an additional layer of protection on your account with Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA).‍Once you’ve enabled MFA on your account, it helps ensure that only you or someone you have authorized can access your account, even if your password somehow falls into the wrong hands. Here&amp;#x27;s how it works:Log into your Cedar Money account and head to settings on the left navigation bar.Select security and add two-step verification.Scan the QR code provided using a trusted authenticator app like Google Authenticator.‍If you’re using your mobile, copy the setup key into your trusted authentication app like Google Authenticator.‍Each time you log into your account, you’ll be asked to enter a unique code generated by the authenticator app you used.‍As quick and easy as this process is, it adds a robust security checkpoint to your account and keeps your information and money safe.‍Benefits of Using MFA for Your Business‍MFA is a significantly more secure system than single-authentication (passwords or pins alone):Enhanced Security: With MFA, you prevent unauthorized access to your account. This way, even if someone steals your password, they would be unable to log in without the second factor.Protection Against Fraud: If unauthorized persons are unable to gain access into your account, it significantly reduces the risk of fraudulent activities.Peace of Mind: MFA gives users greater peace of mind knowing that their funds and sensitive information are protected by an additional layer of security.Why Cedar Money is the Trusted Choice for Secure Cross-Border Payments‍While paying out up to $30,000,000 in 24 hours to over 130 countries is an awesome benefit of making cross-border payments with Cedar, we pride ourselves more in the fact that security is at the core of how we operate. If businesses cannot count on their cross-border payment platform to protect their transactions, data and reputation, all that speed and efficiency becomes redundant.‍Beyond MFA, we’ve built multiple layers infrastructural security to ensure you never have to lose a night’s sleep over the security of your funds. This includes real-time monitoring to detect and prevent any and all suspicious activities, end-to-end encryption to protect your data while in transit, and a secure API integration that allows you connect your systems with confidence.‍Furthermore, to stay ahead of ever-changing regulations and threats, we strictly adhere to compliance standards and regularly review our systems‍With Cedar Money, the only thing you ever have to worry about is how to keep up with the vast opportunities for business expansion.‍Next Steps‍If you are already a Cedar Money user, take a couple of seconds to enable Multi-Factor Authentication in your account settings. It’s a simple step that requires minimal effort but gives maximum rewards— an extra layer of protection to your transactions.‍New here? Now is the perfect time to experience secure, seamless cross-border payments with a partner you can trust. Sign up today and choose safety and security for your business transactions!‍</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Cedar.money</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:02:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.cedar.money/news-updates/the-hidden-costs-of-collecting-payments-from-africa-and-how-to-avoid-them</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.cedar.money/news-updates/the-hidden-costs-of-collecting-payments-from-africa-and-how-to-avoid-them"/>
    <content type="html">On paper, getting paid from Africa should be simple—send an invoice, get paid. But if you’ve done business on the continent, you know it’s rarely that straightforward. In reality, businesses often encounter unexpected obstacles that chip away at their revenue, disrupt their operations, and create unnecessary friction in cash flow.‍One of our clients—a wholesale supplier based in Europe who frequently exports goods to buyers in Nigeria and Ghana— learned this the hard way. When she first expanded into these markets, she assumed international payments would be as seamless as in her home country. But soon, she found herself battling unexpected deductions on every transaction, long settlement delays, and unpredictable currency fluctuations. In one instance, a delayed payment cost her a lucrative deal because she couldn’t restock inventory in time.‍She’s not alone. Many global businesses eager to tap into Africa’s fast-growing economies find themselves battling hidden costs that eat into their margins.‍So, what exactly are these hidden costs, and how can you avoid them? Let’s break it down.‍1. Expensive Transaction Fees That Add Up‍Cross-border payments often come with multiple layers of fees that significantly reduce the final amount received. These costs typically include:Bank transfer fees: Banks charge exorbitant fees for processing international transactions. If intermediary banks are involved, these fees multiply.Correspondent bank fees: Payments routed through multiple financial institutions can incur additional charges, sometimes without the payer or recipient even being aware.Third-party payment provider fees: Many online payment platforms charge commission-based fees, especially for high-value transactions.‍To bring this home more, a $10,000 transaction could quickly shrink to $9,200 after multiple deductions. That’s $800 that could have been invested into your business, gone.‍While some of these fees are necessary for the services provided, you can avoid some unnecessary ones by choosing a provider like Cedar Money, which offers transparent pricing and competitive rates with no hidden fees, ensuring you retain more of your earnings.‍2. FX Losses from Poor Exchange Rates‍When making FX collections, currency conversion is a silent profit killer especially when dealing with countries in Africa with currencies that have lower value. Many exporters and other businesses unknowingly lose money due to:Unfavorable exchange rates: Banks and payment providers often add a markup on top of the mid-market exchange rate, which can cost businesses thousands over time.Settlement rate fluctuations: By the time payments clear, currency volatility may have further eroded the value of the funds received.‍For instance, if a business in Europe receives payments in Nigerian Naira (NGN) instead of USD, currency fluctuations could lead to significant losses. The Naira has historically been volatile, with devaluations happening multiple times over the past decade. Without a reliable FX strategy, businesses risk losing a significant portion of their expected revenue.‍How to Avoid It:‍Opt for a payment provider like Cedar Money, which offers competitive FX rates and allows you choose what currency to receive payments in, even when your client sends funds in their own local currency. This way, you avoid exposure to unstable local currencies and everyone walks away happy.‍3. Payment Delays That Disrupt Cash Flow‍One of the most frustrating challenges businesses face is slow payment processing times. This can be caused by:Lengthy bank clearance processes, which may take several weeks.Regulatory checks and compliance requirements, which vary from country to country.Intermediary banks holding funds, sometimes without clear communication.‍How to Avoid it: ‍With Cedar Collections, you benefit from T+1 settlements, ensuring your payments (which can be up to $30,000,000 per day) clear within one business day, rather than weeks.‍4. Limited Payment Options for African Buyers‍Many African businesses operate in markets where international payment methods like credit cards are not widely used. If your payment collection system doesn’t support local bank transfers, mobile money, or regional payment rails, you may lose customers to competitors who offer more accessible options.‍How to Avoid It:‍Cedar Money supports collections from Nigeria, Ghana, Kenya, South Africa, Tanzania, Rwanda, Uganda, Zimbabwe, and Ivory Coast, allowing buyers to pay in their local currency while you receive funds in your preferred currency.‍5. Compliance and Regulatory Hurdles‍Every country has its own cross-border payment regulations, and failing to comply can lead to payment rejections, frozen accounts, or even legal issues. Common regulatory challenges include:Restricted currencies: Some African countries have capital controls that limit how much money can be sent abroad.KYC (Know Your Customer) and AML (Anti-Money Laundering) requirements: Failure to provide the right documentation can result in delayed or blocked payments.Inconsistent regulatory updates: Governments frequently change policies, making it difficult for businesses to keep up.‍If you’re looking to do business in multiple African countries, it can be even more daunting trying to adhere to these regulatory requirements which may differ per country.‍How to Avoid It:‍With Cedar Money, compliance is automated and built-in, so you don’t have to navigate complex regulatory landscapes.‍Make Cross-Border Collections Simple‍Countries in Africa offer immense business opportunities, but outdated banking infrastructure, excessive costs, and unpredictable regulations can slow you down. The good news? There’s a better way.‍With Cedar Money, you can:Receive payments faster with T+1 settlementsEliminate excessive fees and unfavorable FX lossesOffer your customers easy, secure payment optionsStay compliant without the headaches‍Stop losing money to hidden fees and delays. Switch to Cedar Money today and get paid faster, for less. Get started now!‍</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Cedar.money</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:02:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.cedar.money/news-updates/leading-the-charge-women-at-cedar-money-driving-change-in-fintech</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.cedar.money/news-updates/leading-the-charge-women-at-cedar-money-driving-change-in-fintech"/>
    <content type="html">In fintech, where innovation moves at breakneck speed, progress toward gender equality still lags behind. Women remain underrepresented in leadership roles, funding opportunities continue to favor male-led ventures, and systemic barriers persist. The theme of this year’s International Women’s Day, Accelerate Action, calls for bold, immediate measures to bridge these gaps and create a more inclusive future.‍At Cedar Money, women are not just participating in fintech, they’re leading the charge. From product innovation to marketing strategy, they are breaking barriers, challenging norms, and shaping the financial landscape for the better. We spoke to four remarkable women at Cedar about what Accelerate Action means to them and their advice for the next generation of women in fintech.‍Breaking Barriers and Driving Inclusion‍For many women in fintech, accelerating action isn’t just about moving fast, it’s about moving with purpose. “Since entering the industry in 2005, I’ve learned that success comes from taking decisive steps, adapting quickly, and not waiting for permission to lead,” says Maya Har Noy, Cedar Money’s VP for Financial Strategy. “It’s about identifying opportunities, making strategic moves, and pushing through challenges without hesitation.”Despite progress, fintech leadership remains largely male-dominated. Titilayo Oluwatosin, Director of Marketing at Cedar Money, believes that accelerating action means “amplifying women’s voices, driving inclusion, and proving through results that women belong at the forefront of innovation.” It’s not just about getting a seat at the table, it’s about ensuring equal representation and leadership.‍Innovation Through Bold Action‍Fintech thrives on innovation, and real change happens when women step up and take charge. Julianah Omosehin, Product Manager at Cedar Money, emphasizes the importance of bold action. “Accelerate Action means boldly stepping up to solve real problems and driving innovation that creates meaningful change. It’s about being proactive—addressing deep customer pain points and pushing boundaries to build solutions that matter.”‍For Sharon Yishai, who has spent nearly two decades in fintech, and leading Financial Operations at Cedar Money, accelerating action means embracing every challenge with energy and creativity. “We’re in an industry that’s all about acceleration—turning ideas into reality, solving problems at lightning speed, and making financial transactions smoother, faster, and smarter. If we want more women leading in fintech, we need to remove friction, whether in payments, innovation, or decision-making.”‍Paving the Way for the Next Generation‍Progress in fintech isn’t just about the present, it’s about creating opportunities for the future. That’s why women who have broken barriers must now help others do the same. “Success isn’t just about you—it’s about lifting others up too,” says Maya. “Mentor, encourage, and create space for other women to thrive.”‍Julianah agrees, highlighting the importance of self-investment. “The more you grow, the more confident and prepared you’ll be to lead and drive change. Seek out mentors and allies, but also back yourself and take risks when opportunities arise.”‍Sharon keeps it simple: “Be bold. Find your tribe. Keep learning. Own your journey.”‍The Time for Change is Now‍The call to Accelerate Action is urgent. It’s not enough to acknowledge the gender gap in fintech, we must actively work to close it. That means pushing for more women in leadership, advocating for equal opportunities, and fostering an environment where women can thrive. As Titilayo puts it, “If you see a gap, don’t just acknowledge it, be the one to fill it.”‍At Cedar Money, we’re committed to doing just that - breaking barriers, creating opportunities, and ensuring that women continue to shape the future of fintech.‍The future of fintech is diverse, dynamic, and inclusive. And women are leading the charge.‍</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
