<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Announcements</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.chainsatlas.com/announcements"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chainsatlas.com%2Fannouncements&amp;url_selector=a&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chainsatlas.com%2Fannouncements%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bclass%5E%3D%22PAGE_SECTIONS%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=h3&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chainsatlas.com%2Fannouncements&amp;url_selector=a&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chainsatlas.com%2Fannouncements%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bclass%5E%3D%22PAGE_SECTIONS%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=h3&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:31+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">ChainsAtlas Partners with COTI to Enable Privacy-Preserving Cross-Chain AI Agents</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:02:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.chainsatlas.com/announcements/chainsatlas-and-coti-partner-to-enable-privacy-preserving%2C-cross-chain-ai-agents</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.chainsatlas.com/announcements/chainsatlas-and-coti-partner-to-enable-privacy-preserving%2C-cross-chain-ai-agents"/>
    <content type="html">#comp-m14mbn0w {aspect-ratio: 3.5999999999999996;}10 April 2025ChainsAtlas  is excited to announce a strategic partnership with COTI. This collaboration will combine COTI’s privacy-on-demand with ChainsAtlas’ on-chain agents, enabling AI agents to operate securely, autonomously, and across multiple chains.Privacy-Preserving AI Agents: ChainsAtlas provides on-chain AI agents, while COTI ensures secure data processing with its confidentiality layer.Autonomous Smart Contracts: AI agents on AtlasAI interact with smart contracts across chains, with COTI protecting sensitive user data.Cross-Chain Interoperability:  AI agents move seamlessly between blockchains, with COTI enhancing privacy and security.This partnership marks a significant step toward the future of decentralized intelligence, where AI-powered agents operate securely and autonomously across chains.ChainsAtlas is a blockchain platform designed for seamless cross-chain interoperability, making it possible for developers or AI to work effortlessly across multiple blockchain networks without the need to rewrite or restructure their code. As the first agentic AI blockchain, ChainsAtlas lets you create and deploy your own AI agents that live on-chain and interact effortlessly and independently, across all other chains.JOIN TELEGRAM                                                                The COTI Network is the fastest and lightest confidentiality layer on Ethereum. Powered by the breakthrough cryptographic protocol Garbled Circuits and secured by Ethereum, COTI introduces the most advanced and compliant solution for data protection on the public blockchain, paving the way for the next wave of Web3 innovation and adoption. COTI unlocks a whole new world of use cases, including confidential transactions, Artificial Intelligence, DeFi, decentralized identification, and more.Back to Announcements                                Share                       LinkedIn                       X (Twitter)                                WhatsApp                       Facebook                       Copy link</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Atlas Activate</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:02:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.chainsatlas.com/announcements/atlas-activate-</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.chainsatlas.com/announcements/atlas-activate-"/>
    <content type="html">#comp-m14mbn0w {aspect-ratio: 3.5999999999999996;}11 April 2025ATLAS ACTIVATEBuilding on the success of Atlas Connect, we’re launching the next phase: Atlas Activate.The campaign is officially live today, April 11th at 4PM UTC+7, and will run until May 9th at 4 PM UTC+7. This is your chance to gain early access, unlock exclusive rewards, and secure your position ahead of the curve before Devnet opens to the public.WHAT IS ATLAS ACTIVATE? It’s a high-energy questline for explorers, builders, and early movers.There’s a $500 prize pool for top participants, and TGE rewards for everyone involved!You complete quests.You climb the leaderboard.You unlock your place in the next phase of ChainsAtlas, including early access to our upcoming Devnet.Prize Breakdown1st Place: $702nd Place: $503rd Place: $40Places 4–20 (17 winners): $20 eachHow to join:  Start now on Zealy: https://zealy.io/cw/atlasactivate/questboardFollow &amp;amp; engage  Complete quests  Refer friends for extra XP  Win rewards + secure early accessBe early. Be active. Be seen.  Our community has been at the heart of every step forward, and now it’s your turn to be part of what we’re building. Together, we’re shaping the future, and Atlas Activate is your opportunity to contribute, lead, and thrive in the next phase of ChainsAtlas.Follow ChainsAtlas to stay up to date:Website: https://www.chainsatlas.com/X: https://x.com/ChainsAtlasLinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/chainsatlasYouTube: https://www.youtube.com/@ChainsAtlasDiscord: https://discord.com/invite/Deqmcp4SB8Telegram: https://t.me/chainsatlasofficialJOIN TELEGRAM                                                                Back to Announcements                                Share                       LinkedIn                       X (Twitter)                                WhatsApp                       Facebook                       Copy link</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">AtlasAI Hackathon</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:02:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.chainsatlas.com/announcements/atlasai-hackathon</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.chainsatlas.com/announcements/atlasai-hackathon"/>
    <content type="html">#comp-m14mbn0w {aspect-ratio: 3.5999999999999996;}26 February 2025What’s Your Vision for AI Agents?ChainsAtlas is excited to present the AtlasAI Hackathon – an open invitation to innovators, developers, and AI enthusiasts to push the boundaries of AI agent technology. Whether you’re interested in artificial intelligence, blockchain, or solving practical challenges, this hackathon is a chance to present and refine AI agent concepts.Selected projects will have the opportunity to receive sponsorships for further development, with top winners moving to Phase 2 (Development), where they will receive team support and waived fees.Develop AI Agents for Real-World ApplicationsExplore Blockchain and AI IntegrationsReceive sponsorship &amp;amp; Development SupportGain Visibility in AI &amp;amp; Web3 CommunitiesThe hackathon is open to all individuals of any level of expertise and AI knowledge. Whether you&amp;#x27;re a beginner exploring AI for the first time or an experienced developer pushing the boundaries of innovation, you’re encouraged to join. For compliance reasons we will not be able to accept participants from OFAC-sanctioned nations.Online Registration Opens: 26 February 2025Submission Deadline: 14 March 2025Project Evaluation: 14-20 March 2025Winner Announcement: 26 March 2025Top Winners Move to Phase 2!Up to 20% of projects (max 10) will advance to Phase 2 with sponsorship &amp;amp; support.Winners will be featured on our social media &amp;amp; official website.Each submission will be evaluated based on the following criteria, with a total score of 100 points:Technological Implementation (30 points): Assess whether the project demonstrates quality software development, thoroughly leverages generative AI agents, and utilizes sophisticated prompting techniques to improve the performance of the Agents in the context of blockchain. Innovation and Originality (25 points): Evaluate the uniqueness of the AI agent and its approach to addressing the identified problem, as well as the originality in problem-solving and the application of innovative ideas.Potential Impact (25 points): Consider the scalability of the solution, its potential for expansion or adaptation to broader applications, and its sustainability, including the long-term viability and resource efficiency of the solution.Presentation and Communication (20 points): Assess how well the idea and implementation are articulated and documentedThe AtlasAI Hackathon is an opportunity to explore new AI-driven solutions and collaborate with a forward-thinking community. How will AI agents transform the way we interact with technology in the coming years?Bring your AI agent concept to life!JOIN TELEGRAM                                                                Back to Announcements                                Share                       LinkedIn                       X (Twitter)                                WhatsApp                       Facebook                       Copy link</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
