<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Changera Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.changera.co"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.changera.co%2Ffeed%2F&amp;content_selector=.content-inner&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;remove_styles=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.changera.co%2Ffeed%2F&amp;content_selector=.content-inner&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;remove_styles=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:32+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How to Get a Free Virtual and Physical Dollar Card</title>
    <published>2025-02-13T06:54:26+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-13T06:54:26+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.changera.co/how-to-get-a-free-virtual-and-physical-dollar-card/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.changera.co/how-to-get-a-free-virtual-and-physical-dollar-card/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Adeola</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In today’s digital economy, having a reliable dollar card is no longer a luxury—it’s a necessity. Whether you need to shop internationally, pay for subscriptions, or withdraw cash abroad, a dollar card simplifies these transactions. However, many financial institutions charge high issuance fees, impose strict spending limits, and offer cards that may not work for all global payments.
    
Fortunately, Changera’s newly improved subscription plans now allow users to get a free virtual and physical dollar card with seamless access to international payments. Therefore, if you’re looking for a secure, convenient, and cost-effective way to manage your global transactions, this guide will show you how to get your free Changera dollar card in just a few easy steps.
    
Ready to get a free virtual and physical dollar card with Changera? Sign up now and enjoy seamless global transactions!
        Why You Need a Changera Dollar Card    
Before going into the process, it’s important to understand why a Changera dollar card stands out. Although many platforms offer dollar cards, not all provide the same level of convenience, flexibility, and affordability. Therefore, here are some key benefits of choosing Changera’s virtual and physical dollar cards:
                         
                 
 					
                      Handpickedfor you                                        
 					
                                          
                     
                                              
                                                      How to Choose the Right Changera Card for Your Needs                                                                       
                                      
                                                      How to Earn Rewards Using Your Changera Card                                                                       
                                      
                 
                     
 				    
 				        
 				             				        
 				        
 				            
 				                
 				            
 				        
 				        
 				            
 				                
 				            
 				        
 				    
 				
                 
                 
                     
                     
                                                           
                                      
 					 					var jnews_module_3245_0_67f876e7124ea = {"header_icon":"","first_title":"Handpicked","second_title":"for you","url":"","header_type":"heading_7","header_background":"","header_secondary_background":"","header_text_color":"","header_line_color":"","header_accent_color":"","header_filter_category":"","header_filter_author":"","header_filter_tag":"","header_filter_text":"All","post_type":"post","content_type":"all","number_post":"2","post_offset":0,"unique_content":"disable","include_post":"","exclude_post":3245,"include_category":"1","exclude_category":"","include_author":"","include_tag":"","exclude_tag":"","sort_by":"latest","show_date":"","date_format":"default","date_format_custom":"Y\/m\/d","pagination_mode":"nextprev","pagination_nextprev_showtext":"","pagination_number_post":"2","pagination_scroll_limit":0,"ads_type":"disable","ads_position":1,"ads_random":"","ads_image":"","ads_image_tablet":"","ads_image_phone":"","ads_image_link":"","ads_image_alt":"","ads_image_new_tab":"","google_publisher_id":"","google_slot_id":"","google_desktop":"auto","google_tab":"auto","google_phone":"auto","content":"","ads_bottom_text":"","show_border":"","el_id":"","el_class":"","scheme":"","column_width":"auto","title_color":"","accent_color":"","alt_color":"","excerpt_color":"","css":"","paged":1,"column_class":"jeg_col_1o3","class":"jnews_block_29"}; 				
             
                     
    
Zero Issuance Fees – Unlike traditional banks, Changera offers free virtual and physical dollar cards with no hidden charges.
Multi-Currency Wallet – You can fund your card in USD and other foreign currencies, making it easy to transact globally.
Secure and Reliable Transactions – Changera’s dollar card is designed to work seamlessly on international platforms, preventing payment failures.
High Spending Limits – Depending on your plan, you can spend up to $50,000 monthly with the Blue Plan and $100,000 monthly with the Gold Plan.
Exclusive Cashback and Rewards – You can enjoy exciting perks when using your Changera card for payments.
Global Acceptance – You can use your Changera dollar card for online and in-store purchases, as well as ATM withdrawals worldwide.
    
Most importantly, getting a Changera card is quick and hassle-free. Now, let’s walk you through the steps to obtain your free virtual and physical dollar card today.&amp;nbsp;
    Step-by-Step Guide to Getting Your Free Changera Dollar Card    Step 1: Download and Sign Up on Changera    
First, you need to download the Changera app from the Google Play Store or Apple App Store. After installing the app, proceed to create an account by providing your email, phone number, and password.
    
To enhance security, Changera will send you a verification code via SMS or email. Enter the code to confirm your registration and access your Changera dashboard.
    Step 2: Upgrade to a Subscription Plan That Offers a Free Dollar Card    
Although Changera offers different plans, only the Blue Plan and Gold Plan come with a free virtual and physical dollar card. Therefore, you must upgrade to one of these plans to enjoy this benefit.
    
Blue Plan – Best for freelancers, remote workers, and travelers who need a reliable dollar card for moderate transactions.
Gold Plan – Ideal for high-spending individuals and businesses that require higher limits and premium features.
    
To upgrade, go to the subscription section in the Changera app and select the plan that suits your needs.
    Step 3: Complete Your KYC Verification    
Since Changera prioritizes security and compliance, all users must complete Know Your Customer (KYC) verification before obtaining a dollar card.
    
To verify your identity, you will need to:
    
Upload a valid government-issued ID (e.g., passport, national ID card, or driver’s license).
Provide proof of address (utility bill or bank statement).
Take a live selfie for facial verification.
    
Once you submit these details, Changera will review your information. The verification process usually takes a short time, and as soon as you’re approved, you can proceed to request your free card.
    Step 4: Request Your Free Virtual or Physical Dollar Card        
After upgrading your plan and completing KYC verification, the next step is to request your free dollar card.
    
Simply navigate to the Cards section in the Changera app and click Request Card. You will have two options:
    
Virtual Dollar Card – Best for online payments, digital subscriptions, and e-commerce transactions.
Physical Dollar Card – Ideal for POS purchases, ATM withdrawals, and travel expenses.
    
Your virtual card will be instantly available in the app, while your physical card will be processed and delivered to your registered address.
    Step 5: Fund Your Dollar Card and Start Using It    
Now that you have your Changera dollar card, it’s time to fund it and start making transactions. You can easily add funds to your card from your Changera wallet using various funding options available in the app.
    
Once your card is loaded, you can use it for:
        
Paying for global subscriptions (Netflix, Spotify, Apple Music, Amazon Prime, etc.).
Booking flights and hotels at discounted rates.
Shopping on e-commerce platforms (Amazon, eBay, AliExpress, etc.).
Withdrawing cash from ATMs when traveling abroad.
Making POS payments at stores worldwide.
    
As a result of Changera’s improved card features, you can now enjoy smooth transactions with zero restrictions on major international platforms.
    Why Changera’s Dollar Card Is the Best Choice for You    
Although several platforms offer dollar cards, Changera stands out because of its unique features. Unlike traditional banks that charge high fees and impose strict limits, Changera provides a cost-effective and seamless solution for individuals and businesses.
    
Here’s why Changera’s dollar card is the best option for international payments:
    
No Issuance Fees – You get a free virtual and physical dollar card without extra costs.
High Spending Limits – Enjoy up to $100,000 in monthly transactions, depending on your plan.
Seamless Global Transactions – Use your card on any platform, including PayPal, Google Ads, and Facebook Ads.
Quick and Secure Transactions – Your payments are processed instantly and securely.
    
Most importantly, Changera is trusted by thousands of users across the globe who rely on its services for hassle-free international transactions.
    Final Thoughts    
In summary, getting a free virtual and physical dollar card with Changera is simple, fast, and rewarding. Whether you’re a freelancer, traveler, business owner, or remote worker, this card gives you the financial freedom to make global payments without limitations.
    
So, why wait? Sign up on Changera today, upgrade to the right plan, and enjoy the convenience of a free dollar card for all your international transactions!
    
You can download the Changera mobile app from the Google Play Store or App Store to begin.&amp;nbsp;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://blog.changera.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/virt.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How to Choose the Right Changera Card for Your Needs</title>
    <published>2025-01-21T07:04:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-21T07:04:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.changera.co/how-to-choose-the-right-changera-card-for-your-needs/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.changera.co/how-to-choose-the-right-changera-card-for-your-needs/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Adeola</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Choosing the right payment card can be overwhelming, especially with various options available. Changera simplifies this process by offering a range of cards tailored to different user needs. Whether you’re a traveler, freelancer, or someone managing global transactions, there’s a Changera card for you. This guide will help you identify which card best suits your needs.
    
Discover how to choose the right Changera card for your needs. Learn about White, Black, Blue, and Gold cards and their benefits.
        Understanding the Changera Card Options    
Changera offers both virtual and physical cards, with four card types: White, Black, Blue, and Gold. Each card comes with specific benefits based on your subscription plan. Let’s explore the options:
    
Changera White Card
    
For: Freemium users
Type: Virtual only
Best For: Basic transactions and users new to Changera.
Key Features:
    
No card creation fee.
Suitable for online payments.
Consider This Card If:
You want a no-frills virtual card for occasional use.
    
Changera Black Card
    
For: Freemium users
Type: Virtual and physical
Best For: Users needing a physical card for in-store transactions.
Key Features:
    
Works for both online and physical payments.
Affordable with basic features.
Consider This Card If:
You want a versatile card but don’t need advanced benefits.
    
Changera Blue Card
    
For: Freelancer/Travel subscribers
Type: Virtual and physical
Best For: Frequent travelers and freelancers managing global payments.
Key Features:
    
5% cashback on spending, capped at $300.
Travel points for Changera Travel.
Includes all benefits of the Blue subscription plan.
Consider This Card If:
    
You want cashback rewards and travel perks.
You need both virtual and physical payment options.
    
Changera Gold Card
    
For: Premium subscribers
Type: Virtual and physical
Best For: High-spending users seeking maximum rewards and exclusive benefits.
Key Features:
    
10% cashback on spending, capped at $800.
Travel points for Changera Travel.
Includes all benefits of the Gold subscription plan.
Consider This Card If:
    
You prioritize luxury benefits and higher cashback limits.
You are a frequent traveler or premium user.
    Key Factors to Consider When Choosing Your Changera Card    
Your Subscription Plan
    
Your Changera subscription directly impacts your card choice.
                         
                 
 					
                      Handpickedfor you                                        
 					
                                          
                     
                                              
                                                      How to Get a Free Virtual and Physical Dollar Card                                                                       
                                      
                                                      How to Earn Rewards Using Your Changera Card                                                                       
                                      
                 
                     
 				    
 				        
 				             				        
 				        
 				            
 				                
 				            
 				        
 				        
 				            
 				                
 				            
 				        
 				    
 				
                 
                 
                     
                     
                                                           
                                      
 					 					var jnews_module_3239_0_67f876e8aed01 = {"header_icon":"","first_title":"Handpicked","second_title":"for you","url":"","header_type":"heading_7","header_background":"","header_secondary_background":"","header_text_color":"","header_line_color":"","header_accent_color":"","header_filter_category":"","header_filter_author":"","header_filter_tag":"","header_filter_text":"All","post_type":"post","content_type":"all","number_post":"2","post_offset":0,"unique_content":"disable","include_post":"","exclude_post":3239,"include_category":"1","exclude_category":"","include_author":"","include_tag":"","exclude_tag":"","sort_by":"latest","show_date":"","date_format":"default","date_format_custom":"Y\/m\/d","pagination_mode":"nextprev","pagination_nextprev_showtext":"","pagination_number_post":"2","pagination_scroll_limit":0,"ads_type":"disable","ads_position":1,"ads_random":"","ads_image":"","ads_image_tablet":"","ads_image_phone":"","ads_image_link":"","ads_image_alt":"","ads_image_new_tab":"","google_publisher_id":"","google_slot_id":"","google_desktop":"auto","google_tab":"auto","google_phone":"auto","content":"","ads_bottom_text":"","show_border":"","el_id":"","el_class":"","scheme":"","column_width":"auto","title_color":"","accent_color":"","alt_color":"","excerpt_color":"","css":"","paged":1,"column_class":"jeg_col_1o3","class":"jnews_block_29"}; 				
             
                     
    
Freemium users: Access to White and Black cards.
Freelancers/Travelers: Blue card offers enhanced benefits.
Premium users: Gold card unlocks maximum perks.
    
Your Spending Habits
        
If you spend regularly and want cashback, opt for Blue or Gold cards.
For occasional spending, White or Black cards may suffice.
    
Travel Needs
    
If you travel often, Blue and Gold cards offer travel points and rewards.
Black and White cards are better for local transactions.
    
Physical vs. Virtual Cards
    
Virtual cards are ideal for secure online shopping.
Physical cards are better for in-store purchases and ATMs.
    
Funding and Transaction Fees
    
Understand the funding fees for each card.
$1 for funding below $100.
2% for funding above $100.
Choose a card that aligns with your budget and transaction frequency.
    Why Choose a Changera Card?    
Changera cards are designed to simplify global transactions. They combine convenience, affordability, and rewards in a single platform. Here are some standout features:
    
Compatibility: Works with Apple Pay and Google Pay.
Flexibility: Upgrade or downgrade cards based on your subscription.
Global Use: Seamless international payments with transparent FX fees.
Rewards: Cashback and travel points for Blue and Gold cardholders.
    Step-by-Step Guide to Choosing the Right Changera Card    
Assess Your Needs:
    
Identify your primary purpose for the card—travel, business, or personal transactions.
    
Review Your Subscription Plan:
    
Check your current Changera plan and determine if an upgrade is necessary.
    
Compare Card Benefits:
    
Use the table below to compare the features:
    CashPlanTypeCashbackTravel PointsBest ForWhite&amp;nbsp;FreemiumVirtual onlyNoneNoneOccasional transactions.BlackFreemiumVirtual/PhysicalNoneNoneVersatile spending.BlueFreelancerVirtual/Physical5% (max $300)YesTravel and rewards.&amp;nbsp;GoldPremiumVirtual/Physical10% (max $800)YesHigh spenders.    
Make Your Choice:
    
Choose a card that matches your lifestyle, then activate it through the Changera app.
    
Ready to choose your ideal card? Sign up or log in to the Changera app today to explore your options and enjoy global convenience with ease!
    
Download the mobile app from Google Play Store or Apple App Store to get started!</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://blog.changera.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/virt.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How to Earn Rewards Using Your Changera Card</title>
    <published>2025-01-15T01:33:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-15T01:33:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.changera.co/how-to-earn-rewards-using-your-changera-card/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.changera.co/how-to-earn-rewards-using-your-changera-card/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Adeola</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In today’s world, a debit card is more than just a payment tool. It can also help you unlock incredible rewards. The Changera Card takes this a step further by offering a wide range of reward opportunities tailored for users who value both convenience and savings. Here’s how you can make the most of your Changera Card to earn valuable rewards.
    
Discover how to earn rewards using your Changera Card. Learn tips to maximize cashback, points, and exclusive partner offers. Let’s go!
        What Makes the Changera Card Special?    
The Changera Card is a global dollar card that combines secure payment features with exceptional reward programs. Whether you’re paying for subscriptions, booking travel, or shopping online, the Changera Card ensures you earn points or cashback while you spend.
    
Most importantly, it allows users to transact in multiple currencies, making it perfect for global citizens. As a result, you not only save on conversion fees but also get rewarded for every transaction.
                         
                 
 					
                      Handpickedfor you                                        
 					
                                          
                     
                                              
                                                      How to Get a Free Virtual and Physical Dollar Card                                                                       
                                      
                                                      How to Choose the Right Changera Card for Your Needs                                                                       
                                      
                 
                     
 				    
 				        
 				             				        
 				        
 				            
 				                
 				            
 				        
 				        
 				            
 				                
 				            
 				        
 				    
 				
                 
                 
                     
                     
                                                           
                                      
 					 					var jnews_module_3232_0_67f876ea79987 = {"header_icon":"","first_title":"Handpicked","second_title":"for you","url":"","header_type":"heading_7","header_background":"","header_secondary_background":"","header_text_color":"","header_line_color":"","header_accent_color":"","header_filter_category":"","header_filter_author":"","header_filter_tag":"","header_filter_text":"All","post_type":"post","content_type":"all","number_post":"2","post_offset":0,"unique_content":"disable","include_post":"","exclude_post":3232,"include_category":"1","exclude_category":"","include_author":"","include_tag":"","exclude_tag":"","sort_by":"latest","show_date":"","date_format":"default","date_format_custom":"Y\/m\/d","pagination_mode":"nextprev","pagination_nextprev_showtext":"","pagination_number_post":"2","pagination_scroll_limit":0,"ads_type":"disable","ads_position":1,"ads_random":"","ads_image":"","ads_image_tablet":"","ads_image_phone":"","ads_image_link":"","ads_image_alt":"","ads_image_new_tab":"","google_publisher_id":"","google_slot_id":"","google_desktop":"auto","google_tab":"auto","google_phone":"auto","content":"","ads_bottom_text":"","show_border":"","el_id":"","el_class":"","scheme":"","column_width":"auto","title_color":"","accent_color":"","alt_color":"","excerpt_color":"","css":"","paged":1,"column_class":"jeg_col_1o3","class":"jnews_block_29"}; 				
             
                     
    Ways to Earn Rewards with Your Changera Card    
Use Your Card for Everyday Expenses
    
One of the simplest ways to earn rewards is by using your Changera Card for daily purchases. From groceries to online subscriptions, every transaction adds up. The more you spend, the more points or cashback you earn.
    
Pro Tip: Use your card for recurring payments, such as streaming services or utility bills, to rack up rewards automatically.
    
Take Advantage of Partner Offers
    
Changera collaborates with numerous merchants and brands to provide exclusive deals for cardholders. By shopping with these partners, you earn extra rewards, such as bonus points or discounts.
    
Example: Look out for promotions offering higher rewards when you shop with specific e-commerce platforms or travel agencies.
    
Pay for International Transactions
    
The Changera Card is designed for seamless international
    
payments. It minimizes conversion fees while rewarding you for transactions in foreign currencies. Whether you’re purchasing from global brands or paying for overseas services, you’re always earning.
        
Refer Friends and Family
    
Referrals are an easy and effective way to earn rewards. By introducing your friends and family to Changera, you can earn bonus points or cashback when they activate and use their cards.
    
Pro Tip: Share your referral link on social media to reach a wider audience.
    
Participate in Changera Promotions
    
Changera frequently runs promotions for cardholders. These may include challenges like spending a specific amount within a given timeframe or using your card for particular categories of transactions.
    
Example: Spend $500 in a month to earn double the points or qualify for a raffle draw.
    
Redeem Your Points for Discounts
    
Your accumulated rewards points can be redeemed for discounts on various products or services. This ensures you’re constantly saving money while enjoying premium benefits.
    Maximizing Your Rewards: Tips and Tricks    
To earn the most rewards, you need a clear strategy. Here are a few tips to help you get started:
    
Track Your Spending: Monitor your spending patterns to understand where you can earn the most rewards. Focus on high-reward categories like travel or partner merchants.
Set Payment Alerts: Use reminders to pay recurring bills with your Changera Card. This helps you earn rewards consistently.
Plan Ahead: Align your big purchases with Changera promotions to maximize points or cashback.
Explore Reward Tiers: Some cards offer higher rewards as you spend more. Check if your Changera Card has a tiered program for better benefits.
    Why Choose the Changera Card for Rewards?    
Although many cards offer rewards, Changera stands out for its unique benefits tailored to international users. These include:
    
Low Conversion Fees: Unlike traditional cards, Changera minimizes hidden charges for international payments.
Accessibility: It’s easy to manage your card through the Changera app, where you can also track rewards in real-time.
Flexibility: Redeem your points for a wide range of benefits, including cashback, discounts, or exclusive offers.
    
As a result of these features, you get to enjoy global spending power while earning rewards that align with your lifestyle.
    
Ready to unlock the full potential of your spending? Sign up for the Changera Card today and start earning rewards with every transaction! Download the Changera mobile app from Google Play Store or App Store to learn more.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://blog.changera.co/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/invest-1.jpg"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
