<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Chipper Central - Official Chipper Cash Community Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.chippercash.com/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chippercash.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.blog-metadata-large&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chippercash.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.blog-metadata-large&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:39+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Ripple and Chipper Cash join forces to unlock faster and more cost-effective crypto-enabled payments across Africa - Chipper Central</title>
    <published>2025-03-27T22:02:39+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-27T22:02:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.chippercash.com/blog/ripple-and-chipper-cash-join-forces-to-unlock-faster-and-more-cost-effective-crypto-enabled-payments-across-africa</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.chippercash.com/blog/ripple-and-chipper-cash-join-forces-to-unlock-faster-and-more-cost-effective-crypto-enabled-payments-across-africa"/>
    <content type="html">San Francisco/Lagos March 27, 2025 – Ripple, the leading provider of digital asset infrastructure for financial institutions, and payments provider Chipper Cash have today announced a new partnership to support cross-border payments into Africa using Ripple Payments, which leverages digital assets for faster, cheaper, more efficient cross-border payments.By leveraging Ripple’s crypto-enabled payments solution Chipper Cash, which has five million customers in nine countries across Africa, will enable consumers to receive funds from around the world 24/7/365 - reducing the time and friction to make moving value into Africa dramatically more efficient.“Our partnership with Chipper Cash marks a key milestone in the expansion of Ripple’s business in Africa. Consumers and businesses across the continent are increasingly recognizing the potential of blockchain technology, and we are excited to bring our crypto-enabled payments solution to our partners in the region,” said Reece Merrick, Managing Director, Middle East and Africa, at Ripple. “By integrating our technology into Chipper Cash’s platform, we’re enabling faster, more affordable cross-border payments while driving economic growth and innovation across the markets they serve. With over a decade of experience in tokenizing real-world assets, Ripple’s journey began by bringing fiat currencies on-chain to simplify international money transfers. As the global cross-border payments market grows, more institutions like Chipper Cash are tapping into the transformative power of blockchain technology to drive efficiency and innovation.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;Crypto-enabled payments have the potential to enable greater financial inclusion, accelerate access to global markets, and empower businesses and individuals across Africa,” said Ham Serunjogi, Co-Founder &amp;amp; CEO at Chipper Cash. “Through integrating with Ripple’s global payments network, we are excited to be able to harness the transformative potential of blockchain technology to enable consumers to receive payments faster and at lower cost.”Ripple’s simple, secure, compliant digital asset infrastructure means it is well positioned to provide the core services that financial institutions need to tokenize, store, exchange and move digital assets. Ripple Payments has near-global coverage with 90+ payout markets representing more than 90% coverage of the daily FX markets, processing more than $70 billion in volume. Ripple has over a decade of experience in the digital asset space and holds 60+ regulatory licenses and registrations in various jurisdictions.‍‍About Ripple Ripple is the leading provider of digital asset infrastructure for financial institutions—delivering simple, compliant, reliable software that unlocks efficiencies, reduces friction, and enhances innovation in global finance. Ripple’s solutions leverage the XRP Ledger and its native digital asset, XRP, which was purpose-built to enable fast, low-cost, highly scalable transactions across developer and financial use cases. With a proven track record working with regulators and policymakers around the world, Ripple’s payments, custody and stablecoin solutions are pioneering the digital asset economy—building credibility and trust in enterprise blockchain. Together with customers, partners and the developer community, we are transforming the way the world tokenizes, stores, exchanges, and moves value.About Chipper CashChipper Cash is a financial technology company serving more than five million customers across the African continent. In 2018, Chipper Cash revolutionized moving money in Africa by providing a frictionless way to send and receive money cross-border. Since then, Chipper has increased its product suite by offering personal investments and digital business transactions and expanded its reach into the US. Led by co-founders Ham Serunjogi and Maijid Moujaled, Chipper Cash is focused on its mission to provide the most trusted and accessible financial services for people living in Africa and beyond.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/63c81b0c3ad92959b9062d4b/67e50cb1b750033ed5a9c210_Ripple%20x%20Chipper.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Find Your Adventure: Win an All-Expense-Paid Kenyan Safari with Visa and Chipper Cash - Chipper Central</title>
    <published>2025-02-17T22:02:39+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-17T22:02:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.chippercash.com/blog/find-your-adventure-win-an-all-expense-paid-kenyan-safari-with-visa-and-chipper-cash</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.chippercash.com/blog/find-your-adventure-win-an-all-expense-paid-kenyan-safari-with-visa-and-chipper-cash"/>
    <content type="html">Find Your Adventure: Win an All-Expense-Paid Kenyan Safari with Visa and Chipper CashVisa and Chipper Cash are thrilled to bring you an extraordinary opportunity—a chance to win an unforgettable Kenyan Safari that captures the magic and wonder of The Lion King. Following our exclusive screening of Disney’s Mufasa: The Lion King for our amazing customers, we’re going even bigger. This campaign celebrates our commitment to rewarding you, and it’s time for you to take part in this once-in-a-lifetime adventure.Your Path to AdventureBring the magic of The Lion King to life as you explore the breathtaking landscapes of Kenya. Witness the iconic savannahs and majestic wildlife that inspired Disney’s timeless storytelling. With Visa and Chipper Cash, three lucky winners will enjoy an all-expense-paid safari for themselves and three companions.Here’s what’s included:	•	Flight Tickets: Round-trip flights from Lagos to Nairobi.	•	Luxury Accommodation: Enjoy 4 days and 3 nights in premium lodgings.	•	All Meals: Indulge in delicious meals throughout your stay.	•	Exclusive Tours: Experience guided safaris in Kenya’s stunning national parks.	•	On-Ground Transportation: Seamless travel for all scheduled activities.	•	Gift Packs: Special surprises to make your trip even more memorable.How to Win?Ready to join the adventure? Here’s how you can qualify for this incredible experience:	1.	Use Your USD Visa Chipper Card: Spend a minimum of $500 across at least three transactions each month.	2.	Make a Deposit: Ensure you make at least one deposit within the month of review.	3.	Be Verified: Only verified Chipper Cash users are eligible.Winners are selected on a first-come, first-served basis, so start spending early to secure your spot!Open to Nigerian residents who are verified Chipper Cash users aged 18 or older.‍Don’t Miss Out on This AdventureThis is your chance to turn everyday spending into extraordinary rewards. Use your USD Visa Chipper Card today and stand a chance to win the ultimate Lion King Safari Experience in Kenya.Start spending now and take the first step toward creating memories that will last a lifetime!‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/63c81b0c3ad92959b9062d4b/67b357f12cc93dc663383a02_Find-your-adventure-blog%20(1).jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">10 Amazing Black Friday Deals You Can Unlock with the Chipper USD Card - Chipper Central</title>
    <published>2024-11-27T22:02:39+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-27T22:02:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.chippercash.com/blog/10-amazing-black-friday-deals-you-can-unlock-with-the-chipper-usd-card</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.chippercash.com/blog/10-amazing-black-friday-deals-you-can-unlock-with-the-chipper-usd-card"/>
    <content type="html">Black Friday is here, and the USD Chipper Card is your ultimate shopping companion. With global acceptance and seamless payments, you can score incredible deals from top brands worldwide. Here are the best Black Friday deals to make the most of this shopping season:1. PrettyLittleThing: Fashion Frenzy with Up to 80% Off Upgrade your wardrobe with PrettyLittleThing’s jaw-dropping sale. From casual wear to party-ready outfits, enjoy up to 80% off when you shop with your USD Chipper Card.📍 Deal Link: PrettyLittleThing Black Friday2. Jumia: Up to 80% Off Across CategoriesJumia is offering unbeatable discounts on electronics, fashion, and home appliances. Look out for daily flash sales and exclusive deals during Black Friday month.📍 Deal Link: Jumia Black Friday Deals3. Amazon: Shop Everything with Up to 70% Off Get the best gadgets, home essentials, and more deals during Amazon’s Black Friday event. Shop with your USD Chipper Card for seamless transactions.📍 Deal Link: Amazon Black Friday4. BCode: Up to 50% Off Adidas and Premium Fashion Refresh your wardrobe with stylish clothing and shoes at BCode. Enjoy up to 50% off on top brands like Adidas during Black Friday.📍 Deal Link: BCode Black Friday5. IHG Hotels &amp;amp; Resorts: Save 15% on Global Stays Turn Black Friday into the beginning of your next adventure. Book with IHG Hotels using your USD Chipper Card and enjoy 15% off luxurious stays across Africa and beyond.📍 Deal Link: IHG Black Friday Deals6. Xiaomi: Discounts on Redmi Phones and More Save big on gadgets with Xiaomi’s Black Friday offers. From smartphones to tablets, enjoy significant discounts and free accessories at select retailers.📍 Deal Link: Xiaomi Black Friday7. Apple Music: 6 Months Free for New Users Music lovers can enjoy six months of free Apple Music when signing up with the USD Chipper Card. Start your holiday soundtrack on a high note.📍 Deal Link: Apple Music8. Nike: Up to 50% Off Footwear and Apparel Stay ahead in style and performance. Use your USD Chipper Card to shop Nike’s Black Friday sale and save up to 50% on sneakers and activewear.📍 Deal Link: Nike Black Friday9. Netflix: First Month Free for New Subscriptions Stream your favorite movies and shows this season. New Netflix users can enjoy their first month free when signing up with the USD Chipper Card.📍 Deal Link: Netflix10. Shein: Trendy Looks Up to 60% Off Shop the latest trends on a budget with Shein’s Black Friday event. Use your USD Chipper Card for easy payments and discounts of up to 60%.📍 Deal Link: Shein Black FridayWhy Shop with the USD Chipper Card?The USD Chipper Card makes global shopping effortless. Say goodbye to hustle and hello to incredible savings this Black Friday. Don’t have your card yet? Sign up today and shop smarter.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/63c81b0c3ad92959b9062d4b/6747919f603ebbb7ac6033b6_Black%20Friday%202024-blog-05.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
