<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">CityStates - Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fcitystates%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fcitystates%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:43+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">CityStates/addirktive First Steps for a Potential Reboot</title>
    <published>2023-07-18T07:52:53+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-07-18T07:52:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/citystates-addirktive-first-steps-for-a-potential-reboot-98d5c181c2?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/citystates-addirktive-first-steps-for-a-potential-reboot-98d5c181c2?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>addirktive</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Foreword:Upon the dissolution of “Addirktive Games Development Services, Philippines,” it has come to our attention that the CSM token has become defunct and rendered untradeable on the Stellar platform. As a result, the CSM token holds no remaining monetary value and lacks any legal standing or representation whatsoever.The entity responsible for the initial issuance of the CSM token has been formally dissolved due to its inability to sustain business operations and fulfill associated obligations. In a voluntary and non-obligatory manner, Dirk Pollmann Consulting, Germany, has assumed and fulfilled the liabilities associated with the tokens issued by “Addirktive Games Development Services, Philippines,” namely HEX, aBTC, aETH, USDA, and yAQUA. In consideration of this transfer, assets including the domain addirktive.com, the ‘Dashboard’ code base, the domain citystatesm.com, the CityStates: Medieval and CityStates: Domination game code, NFTs, and all other assets pertaining to these projects have been transferred to Dirk Pollmann Consulting, Germany.It is important to note that “Dirk Pollmann Consulting” has also undergone dissolution as of March 2023. Therefore, all rights, assets, and obligations that were previously held by “Dirk Pollmann Consulting” have now been transferred in their entirety to Dirk Pollmann, a private individual. Dirk Pollmann now assumes full ownership and control over these rights and assets.As previously communicated, the stipulated cutoff date for the swap or exchange of assets bearing their previous names was scheduled for the end of June 2023. An extension was subsequently granted, extending the deadline until July 15th, 2023. However, we regret to inform you that the aforementioned extended deadline has now lapsed.To unequivocally clarify the matter at hand, it is imperative to recognize that in the event a new entity is established for the purpose of continuing development, the CSM token shall not possess any legal standing or be subject to liability. Under no circumstances shall the CSM token be revived, employed for future endeavors, generate royalties, undergo repurchase, or be subjected to burning. This definitive course of action is primarily due to the legal uncertainties that the token would encounter under the purview of German regulations and jurisdiction. Consequently, with the dissolution of its issuing entity, “Addirktive Games Development Services, Philippines,” the CSM token has ceased to be operational.Proposal for Resumption of CityStates Development:As the proprietor of the CityStates intellectual property, code bases, and an 88% majority share of the now-defunct CSM token, I hereby propose the resumption of CityStates development and the Addirktive Dashboard under a newly formed entity that complies with the legal framework established under German law.The opportunity to participate in the establishment of the new entity shall be exclusively extended to current token holders who have demonstrated unwavering support for the project. Each prospective founder shall be required to fulfill the necessary legal formalities to register as a shareholder. In order to facilitate this process, dedicated Know Your Customer (KYC)/Anti-Money Laundering (AML) information has to be submitted to dirkpollmann123@gmail.com.The precise details pertaining to the documentation and information necessary to fulfill the KYC and AML requirements shall be disclosed once a sufficient number of interested users have expressed their willingness to participate and their intention to pledge sufficient capital towards the establishment of the new company.Each founder shall have the option to pledge a minimum amount of $1,000 (~950 €). Consequently, the founders collectively shall receive an equitable allocation of 10% of the shares in the new entity. Moreover, based on the quantity of CSM tokens deposited into the Dashboard, each founder shall be entitled to a proportional bonus in the form of an additional 5% of shares.In recognition of the substantial contributions made by Michael Hollingsworth, widely known as FruitGuru, it has been decided to allocate 10% of the company shares to him as an expression of gratitude.In contrast to the prior allocation, which comprised a lower percentage specifically attributed to the CityStates intellectual property, a significantly higher proportion of the overall entity shall be distributed among the founders.In the event that the minimum requirements necessary to initiate the development process, as outlined below, are not met, the establishment process shall be deemed unsuccessful. In such an event, all pledged amounts shall be subject to refund.Please be aware that I am not a legal professional. Consequently, the first crucial step shall entail seeking legal counsel to provide guidance on the establishment of the entity and the associated legal framework. Should it become apparent at any stage that the endeavor is infeasible or legally questionable under German law, the entire process shall be terminated, and any remaining funds shall be returned to the founding members.Alternatively, the existing state of dormancy can be perpetuated. Any objections to this proposed plan may be directly communicated within the former CityStates Discord server. In the event of an excessive number of objections raised against the outlined process, I reserve the right to potentially resume development independently or in collaboration with select partners at a future juncture.The Proposed Process:Following the acquisition of favorable legal advice concerning the proposed plan, a subsequent round of establishment shall be conducted. During this phase, both previously registered founders and new interested investors (subject to KYC/AML procedures) shall have the opportunity to pledge funds toward acquiring shares in the newly formed entity. The requisite amount shall be contingent upon the outcome of the initial funding round and the estimated budgetary requirements for the impending tasks.To facilitate the trading of shares, a token shall be issued to represent ownership in the new entity. However, such trading shall be strictly limited to verified shareholders. To this end, each shareholder shall be afforded the opportunity to verify a Stellar account on the Dashboard, thereby enabling them to hold and trade the token on the Stellar Decentralized Exchange (DEX). Regular updates and reports regarding the token holdings of each shareholder shall be provided to German authorities, as mandated by legal obligations.In order to fulfill the initial registration of the entity as a ‘Gesellschaft mit beschränkter Haftung’ (GmbH), a temporary deposit of €13,000 and an estimated upfront cost of €2,000 for legal advice and notarial setup shall be required. Consequently, a minimum of 15 dedicated supporters, each pledging €1,000, shall be necessary to proceed.The temporary deposit of €13,000 shall be allocated for immediate operational requirements following the establishment and shall form an integral part of the ongoing operating budget.Minimum Development Budget Requirements for the First Three Months:The defunct stable in-game currency, the ‘HEX token,’ shall be replaced by a new speculative in-game currency whose valuation shall be determined by market demand and supply dynamics.An approximate sum of €10,000 shall be allocated for web, game, and blockchain development pertaining to CityStates: Domination, leading up to its release. The necessary features and associated budgetary considerations will be thoroughly discussed with the developers, who shall be contractually obligated to complete the development within the allocated budget.A sum of €x,000 (TBD) shall be allocated for Michael Hollingsworth (FruitGuru).A sum of €x,000 (TBD) shall be allocated for Dirk Pollmann.An estimated €17,000 shall be allocated for marketing efforts and exchange listings.Objectives of the New Entity:Development of CityStates: Domination for the WAX blockchain within a three-month timeframe.Issuance and support of a speculative in-game currency on multiple blockchains.Development of NFT support for Ethereum Virtual Machines (EVMs) in CS:DO (Ethereum, Binance Smart Chain, Polygon, etc.).Ongoing enhancement of the Dashboard, transforming it into a hub for web3 and other games, complete with its own launcher.Development of a private fork/sidechain of the Stellar Network, aimed at reducing player account setup costs, transaction fees, and addressing congestion and Horizon API issues (e.g., in-game latency). Additionally, direct bridges to and from Stellar, as well as bridges facilitating connectivity with other supported blockchains in the game(s), shall be established.For discussion, please join the Addirktive Discord server: [Discord Link]For direct contact, please write to dirkpollmann123@gmail.com or send a DM to user citystates on Discord.What to do with the defunct CSM token on Stellar:The unlock process for the currently locked CSM tokens on Stellar will be announced in the near future. This announcement will include comprehensive instructions on how token holders can transfer their tokens back to the issuing account, participate in the new founding round via the addirktive Dashboard, or proceed with the swap-out process. Kindly await the forthcoming announcement concerning the unlock procedure.It is important to note that attempting to buy or sell defunct CSM tokens with the intention of leveraging them in the new round is strictly prohibited. Any accounts found engaging in such activities after the unlock will be subject to indefinite locking.If unsure: don’t. If still unsure, contact me first.CityStates/addirktive First Steps for a Potential Reboot was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">addirktive/CityStates Dashboard: Swap and Withdraw remaining Funds</title>
    <published>2023-06-01T08:52:38+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-01T08:52:38+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/addirktive-citystates-dashboard-swap-and-withdraw-remaining-funds-f1ee0745476e?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/addirktive-citystates-dashboard-swap-and-withdraw-remaining-funds-f1ee0745476e?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>addirktive</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">addirktive Games Development Services, PH (initial issuer of CSM, HEX etc) has been dissolved. Balances on the dashboard have been made available for swap to one of the currencies supported for withdrawal (XLM, USDC, BNB, WAX). Please swap and withdraw before the end of June 2023.For assets held on the SDEX, please set sell orders for HEX at $0,00225. For the old yield assets, please set sell orders at 1:1 to the corresponding asset (e.G. yAQUA/AQUA, aBTC/BTC etc).The CSM token is defunct and is neither swappable nor transferrable.The addirktive dashboard and CityStates website may go offline by June 30th. A database backup will be made in the (currently unlikely) case that development can continue in the future.For further information or questions please join the CityStates Discord server: https://discord.gg/jb8EMUt8Neaddirktive/CityStates Dashboard: Swap and Withdraw remaining Funds was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How to top up your addirktive account and buy HEX in-game currency for CityStates</title>
    <published>2023-04-29T14:14:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-04-29T14:14:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/how-to-top-up-your-addirktive-account-and-buy-hex-in-game-currency-for-citystates-953f92cc7f45?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/how-to-top-up-your-addirktive-account-and-buy-hex-in-game-currency-for-citystates-953f92cc7f45?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>addirktive</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">If you are unfamiliar with the Stellar Network, the easiest way to get HEX is to top up your addirktive dashboard account with any of the supported cryptocurrencies and swap it to HEX using our integrated tool.After creating your account on addirktive head to Balance -&amp;gt; Deposit, select the currency you want to deposit and the blockchain you want to send from:For lowest fees we suggest using XLM or if supported Stellar USDC. In case of using Stellar, you can also send from exchanges but don’t forget the memo!After the deposit was credited to your account (fastest and cheapest using Stellar), you can now swap your balance directly in the game to HEX:Do note that you need to research ‘Purchase Power’ in the game before you can use this feature.How to top up your addirktive account and buy HEX in-game currency for CityStates was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">General Balance Updates in CS:M</title>
    <published>2023-03-09T17:24:19+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T17:24:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/general-balance-updates-in-cs-m-41af6eb59d29?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/general-balance-updates-in-cs-m-41af6eb59d29?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>FruitGuru</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hey folks, it’s time for another CS:M update article, today we’re going to be talking about resources and balance in the game and the recent changes we have been working on.Before we jump right into some of the issues and how we addressed them, we would like to preface that we have taken all player feedback on board and studied it meticulously. Quite often, it is common that feedback or suggestions might target a specific feature in the game and while this feature might be under or over preforming, there are times where the solution may not be with the aforementioned mechanic directly, but with something else. For this reason, if you made a suggestion that made a lot of sense but isn’t directly featured here, it’s most likely because we addressed it through bringing other features up to par with it.So once again, buckle in because much like our last development update article, this is a big one.EconomyRight now, it’s very clear that players are able to stockpile key resources once they reach somewhere around castle level 6–8 depending on how they play. While it initially feels great living in a somewhat perpetual golden age, this greatly hampers a player’s ability to play to earn - a key feature of the game. The fact of the matter is that if everyone has too many resources then there’s no buyers at market.Fixing this isn’t as simple as just nerfing resource income, it’s something we had to approach on multiple levels which of course we will go into more detail below.Player income scalingSo when we say “income scaling” in CS:M, we’re referencing how many resources a high level player can earn in the game compared to a lower level player and how much progress they can supply to these lower level players on a daily basis via the resources they put up on the market.Currently, this snowballs far too quickly. While a level 10 player should (and still will) produce more resources than a level 6 player, we want to reign in the building power their daily market sales provide other players.Although we have addressed this on many levels, one of the core fixes was to introduce a base system of diminishing returns when upgrading your production buildings. This means that while upgrading a resource building will still give you more resources per level, the increase will also diminish each level.Forester Example (simplified values)Current Scaling:Level 1: 100 WoodLevel 2: 110 WoodLevel 3: 125 WoodLevel 4: 145 WoodNew Scaling with diminishing returns:Level 1: 100 WoodLevel 2: 110 WoodLevel 3: 119 WoodLevel 4: 127 WoodRight away from this simplified example, you can see that this alone greatly reduces the power (income) creep. This means we were able to adjust building and upgrade costs across the board meaning that although your income will be reduced, so will your building costs.POPS/Housing:Next up on the list is POPS. The team had developed a great system where assigning more POPS to a building increased its productivity which makes sense as well as giving players agency over how their city is run.While on paper, this was a really unique feature our game offered, the reality is that players currently don’t really have to interact with this mechanic as housing and POPs are too easy to access right now. You would be hard pushed to find players in the test server who don’t have all their production buildings maxed out with workers.With this in mind, we have reduced the amount of houses that can be built as well as the amount of POPs each house level up grants.This now puts all players in a position where they must make decisions as to which resources they want to focus on, this should also help stimulate market activity.To be clear, this doesn’t mean that players will need to pay money in order to sustain their city, but rather encourage market trading while giving attentive players more earning potential.Research and SpecializationPreviously we had to be very careful with what we added to the research tree in terms of giving a player more power. This mechanic was only recently developed, meaning we were quite restricted in terms of what we could add to it.Due to going back to square one in terms of production, POPS, etc, we were able to keep the research tree in mind and now have a lot more freedom to make it more diverse and most importantly of all, give players more agency.One big change we made to resources in general is that wood and stone now have the same value in terms of what they build. This allows us to create specialization in the research tree allowing players to take a one or the other research option. For example, a player may choose a 10% increase to wood production while another player would choose the 10% to stone production.This change means that while a player can still develop and maintain their city by themselves, it will be much faster to sell off the excess resource you have specialized in and buy resources your city is producing at a lower rate.This should create a bit of a market minigame where attentive and patient players can profit off the wood and stone trading difference on a day to day basis as the value changes.Due to the nerfs to housing and POPS we can also give some of this power back to players through the research tree at certain levels.These are just a couple of examples, but the bottom line is we are making research more exciting and rewarding.Land and Bandit CampsAnother issue that currently exists is the amount of land players have access to. We have covered some of our ideas here before in terms of slowing down progression on this front.The previously proposed idea was to make the fights very difficult meaning a player would have to learn the fights, fail a number of times, and inevitably sink a lot of resources into making squads to retry the encounter.We got some very mixed feedback on this, some player loved the idea of the challenge while others raised concern that this may be too oppressive.Feedback like this is fantastic because it allows us to go back to the drawing board and study the situation and come up with a solution that meets somewhere in the middle ground.So while we will still buff bandit camp difficulty and introduce the reinforcements mechanic, we won’t make it overwhelmingly difficult to beat and will instead gate bandit progression behind castle level — something that had also been suggested by multiple players.Personally, I (Fruitguru) really do like the idea of extremely difficult fights but I agree that mainline progression shouldn’t be gated by this, however it’s something to consider for a later update as optional content.Castle Upgrading and PacingPreviously, upgrading a castle was far too cheap and quick to preform. We are greatly increasing the amount of resources and time it takes to upgrade the castle.In return for the increased cost and build time, we have changed up the pacing of the game, right now, castle levels 5 is a massive spike in terms of what a player can do in the game while other levels at times feel lacklustre.With our pacing changes, we have made it so each castle level offers a player more than just an extra level to their buildings, be it in the form of new research, mechanics, buildings or bandit camp progression on a level by level basis.In ClosingThere’s a lot more to cover in terms of the Global Map, however this has multiple features and will require an article of its own so stay tuned.Once again, a huge thanks to the community for the feedback provided, which really is invaluable. We’re looking forward to introducing these changes and seeing how they play out. As always if you have any questions or suggestions please send them our way on Discord.General Balance Updates in CS:M was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">PVP Ranked Ladder Opening on 21/02/23</title>
    <published>2023-02-18T16:17:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-02-18T16:17:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/pvp-ranked-ladder-opening-on-21-02-23-4b2cb6f823a3?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/pvp-ranked-ladder-opening-on-21-02-23-4b2cb6f823a3?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>FruitGuru</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Basic Information:Typically, these ranked ladders will have a set run time, but seeing as we are in a test phase, in this instance the competition will run till the end of the test.The concept is simple, defeat other players (PVE does not count) and win points.Due to how the ladder system is designed, players who defeat opponents much higher ranked than them will receive significantly more points than players who challenge those ranked far below them. The same holds true for losses, if a player is defeated by an opponent ranked much higher than then, the points loss will be reduced.This system rewards players who punch upwards as opposed to attempting to farm those less skilled or experienced than them and gives newer aspirants a fighting chance to compete.How To Enter?You will need military squads to play. In order to be competitive, aspirants will want to make sure their city is producing enough food through their farms and to reach castle level 6 in order to have access to the barracks, camp and archery range buildings to produce all four troop types.Once you have five squads built, you can challenge other players by clicking into the PVP arena menu.You will want to select your hero NFTs for battle. Each player can bring 5 different heroes for their active abilities and set one hero as their main which will use that heroes passive.You will also want to select which squads you wish to use for your next battle, in this menu, you can also equip each squad with gear if you have crafted any, common gear is easily accessible and can be built in the level 5+ forge providing you have researched “Blacksmith Mastery I”.And finally, once content with your load out you can click “battle” in order to host or join other players games. Due to the relatively low amount of players in the test server, if you can’t get a game going here, feel free to use our Discord to find opponents.Rules:No win trading. Win trading is when players intentionally allow other players to win battles. All battles are recorded and can be reviewed. Anyone caught trying to game the system will not only be removed from this competition, but also banned from future PVP events.Be courteous. I know we probably don’t need to mention this as you guys are great but sometimes competitive gaming brings out the worst in people. Be humble in victory and graceful in defeat, banter amongst friends is of course fine.Ladder points gained now will not count, the ladder will be reset in time for the competition, but please use the next few days as a chance to hone your skills.Prizes:The top 10 players at the end of the season will receive prizes which will be announced later. Any player that finishes with at least 1 point on the ladder will receive one of our collectable NFTs — these have no use in game but as Freya puts it:Best of luck to everyone who enters!If you have stumbled across this article and are not familiar with our project but like what you see, you too can join in the fun, all you need to do is hop on our Discord and apply for a whitelist!PVP Ranked Ladder Opening on 21/02/23 was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">General Development Updates in CS:M</title>
    <published>2023-02-16T19:38:06+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-02-16T19:38:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/general-development-updates-in-cs-m-acabec61e67a?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/general-development-updates-in-cs-m-acabec61e67a?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>FruitGuru</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Right folks, we’re well overdue one of these but with so much going on with the test and development in general it’s a little delayed, but buckle in because we’ve got a lot to cover.All in all, we’re really happy with how things are going in our current test. We typically don’t share internal roadmaps but there’s a few key components that we have on high priority and are actively working on or have recently solved.Memory Leak (Status — Solved)Although in general, performance this time around has been much better than previous tests, there was one lingering issue, the memory leak. As of Feb 15th 2023, this issue has been resolved, it’s been around a day since the fix has been implemented and we haven’t seen a single spike when it comes to performance issues.Other smaller issues such as scouts being stuck finalizing or consumption issues have been linked to our forced server restarts to combat the leak, going forward, these should be far less prevalent, if occurring at all.City and Battle map visual rework (Status — In progress)While this update doesn’t directly impact the actual gameplay in CS:M, it is something that we as a team are very keen on implementing. This however isn’t something as simple as replacing older models with new versions as we’ve taken some extra steps to make things feel more realistic.One of the most common feedbacks received during our mid year testing in 2022 was that players really wanted their buildings to visually change as they were updated, and so, when we redesigned our models, we made sure to implement this feature. Our new buildings now have three different models associated with them that will change once they hit certain levels. Since the castle is so integral to player development and the heart of the city, we added some extra models here as you can see below:We’ve also added depth to the city map, allowing for hills and rivers which makes it feel much more realistic then our previous flat mono tennis court style:There’s even more subtle changes such as the land the buildings sit on upgrading over time, going from dirt to proper paved roads and small flowers growing on the grass.UI Changes (Status — In progress)This is another key feature of our game that we really want and need to get right. Some of these changes are for no other reason than to make the interface nicer, but there are some menus, that in their current iteration are difficult or unintuitive to navigate (we’re calling you out personally crafting menu!).It would take a little too long to go through each of these individually, so with that in mind we will showcase a couple of the newer updates. The first is our research tree which although currently is fine in terms of functionality, it wasn’t looking as good as it could do and so our UI designers have given it a much needed face lift.Note — The sword icons on each research will be replaced with something more on theme.Going back to perhaps our most guilty offender when it comes to difficulty to use, let’s talk about the Forge. This menu has been completely reworked and now shows key information that was previously omitted, such as rarity, stats and a far more intuitive sorting system.All in all, we’re very confident that the new UI should make gameplay far easier and eliminate a lot of the unnecessary mystery behind certain functions.PVP (Status — In progress)To preface this, we’re happy with PVP right now in terms of how it plays. Having said that, we are aware of the issue with manual PVP and the disconnect from the rest of the game. The main concern here is that the risk/reward is heavily weighted on the risk side in that you stand to lose everything but gain nothing, with the exception of bragging rights, but sadly that won’t pay your POPs.This is something we’re going to be addressing over time through both short and long term solutions.One of the solutions we will be bringing in on the sooner side of things is actually rewarding those who place at the top of the in game ladder. We will need to decide on things like prizes and how often each ladder lasts for but you can expect a separate post on that on the horizon. We are looking to make rewards a mix between both prizes with monetary value (NFTs) and exclusive cosmetics.Another option, as we’ve previously mentioned is to consider bringing in items that can drop at the end of a battle which will help with the development of your city. This would require a lot of care as to not knock the game out of balance but to still make the risk desirable.I’ll briefly mention automated player raids here too as it comes up quite a bit. These are not balanced yet, putting these into the game was more so to test the mechanic and to make sure it functioned as intended. Through multiple player feedback, we’ve identified some core issues with the mechanic such as it being too oppressive to an unprepared defender, potentially destroying their progress. It’s on our radar though and once we have a solid adjustment plan in place we will follow up with more information.Hero Ability Update (Status — Completed pending minor changes.)As mentioned in previous articles, we really wanted to go back and work on our Heroes. There was a clear power imbalance and we wanted to make the abilities more mechanically interesting. We’ve also changed hero ability values to scale with the rarity of the card.We can probably expect to see some small tweaks with some of the % modifiers. Magnus however will be updated to a new passive.Bandit Camps (Status — in progress)We’re aware that the progression to unlock new land to build on is too easy. We are currently reworking this mechanic to be much harder, to the point where players should expect to fail attempts to down these, particularly when it comes to later camps. Right now, beating a camp is an empty feeling as all you have to do is show up. Ideally these camps should be a struggle to defeat, unlocking that land should feel like an achievement.We’re taking a two pronged approach here. The first part is to greatly buff enemies. At the end of the day, a player is always going to outplay the AI in CS:M and so we need to even the playing field a little bit.The second part will be the reinforcement mechanic. You will need to partake in multiple battles to capture a single camp, so if you get lucky with a cheesy map layout in your first battle, you won’t win the land from that alone.There’s a couple of other details we’re going to leave out for now but you should expect this to be a difficult challenge.In closingBesides everything mentioned, we’ve also worked on a lot of other aspects of the game such as craftable equipment having unique names and named after actual weapons and armour that existed in the middle ages. There’s a little bit of cross over, but for the most part you will unlock and upgrade to these in the chronological order they were used in the Middle Ages. We’ve also renamed military squads to be clearer and are addressing other localization changes.If you made it this far, well done! As always if you want to learn more join us on Discord, you can actually play CS:M right now if you apply to our whitelist channel!General Development Updates in CS:M was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">CityStates: Medieval Test Event</title>
    <published>2023-01-09T21:03:02+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T21:03:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/citystates-medieval-test-event-9a0b2d4a2953?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/citystates-medieval-test-event-9a0b2d4a2953?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>FruitGuru</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We’ve added and changed quite a lot since our last small scale community test and we’re ready to open the servers again for further testing and feedback.Before we go into detail about what the test will feature, there’s a few key points that we want to make clear in order to temper expectations.The game is still in development. While there&amp;#39;s been improvement in terms of performance and the elimination of bugs, as well as new and exciting features to play with, we still expect that an increased tester base will uncover new issues that the team will be able to resolve.The current build is still using a lot of placeholder visuals, including the city buildings and UI. These are still being worked on. A lot of care has gone into making these just right - just today the team added some details to the grass for example, it’s little touches like this that make a big difference. The good news is that these new visuals will be deployed as testing goes on so while they won’t be available from the start, you will get to see them in game.New Grass TilesMuch like the above point, Clans are also still being finished. We have chosen to disable the function initially, but will include it during the test at a later stage.With that said, let’s take a look at some of the new things you can now do in CS:M.Manual Combat:Players will have access to the following new combat mode:Gladiator Arena (PVE) — A test mode that will allow players to borrow units and equipment for no cost to test builds and strategies.Research Tree:Players will have access to the research tree covering research up to castle level 20.Global Map:Players will be able to unlock and use the global map, including the following features.Scouting — Reveal the Global Map.Missions — Compete with players to farm resources from map missions.Global Map Bandit Camps — Players can defeat and gain resources from bandit camps on the Global Map.Player Raids — Players can set a defensive garrison and attack other players cities to steal their resources.We have also added more functionality to previous features such as trading as well as combat in general which now includes squad abilities — see you on the battlefield!Who’s eligible to play during the test?Gold VIP pass holders will be granted access first, on the 16th. Community Testers are also eligible for access on the 16th.Silver VIP pass holders will be granted access shortly after once we’re happy to increase numbers.Bronze VIP pass holders will be next in line, once again when we’re happy to increase numbers.Public/Early Access — Yup, we’ll even be taking in none passholders into this test, while we hope to keep the passholder entry fairly close together, none passholders should expect access at a later stage in the test compared to passholders. We will announce a date for this at a later stage.Rollbacks and Resets:We’re at the point now where we shouldn’t need to rollback or reset progression. While we will hope to avoid this, please be prepared for the possibility of this happening should anything major occur. For now this is not planned.You can and should expect changes being made in terms of balance and values as we take player feedback on board throughout the test.Competition:We will have competitive events in the later stages of the test, these will be separately announced at a later stage — Rain of Arrows is back on the menu folks.Play to Earn?:Partially. We will still be using the test tokens as resources, but real HEX will be usable. HEX lost and gained during the test will be real.Platforms:This test client will be available Windows OS. Other builds are on the horizon but this will be at a later stage.CityStates: Medieval Test Event was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">CS:M Global Map Reveal</title>
    <published>2023-01-01T18:30:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-01-01T18:30:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/cs-m-global-map-reveal-6320ba51e214?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/cs-m-global-map-reveal-6320ba51e214?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>FruitGuru</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">If you missed it on our YouTube, we recently posted a video showcasing the Global Map in CS:M.https://medium.com/media/42222c4dbf88e34c87ab12d0b3d5942b/hrefThe Map allows players to explore the world of CS:M, uncovering not only other player locations but also missions which can be completed in order to secure more resources to help build your city.Make sure to check out the video above to see the map in action, but for those of you who just want to read, continue down this article for a breakdown of mechanics.There are currently 4 different mechanics on the Global Map alone, these are:Scouting:Players can research scouts and use these to reveal the map. Initially, a player will only be able to see the immediate area around their city. As a player advances their city, they will be able to research additional scouts as well as increasing scouting speed to make uncovering further distances less time consuming.Missions:Players will also be able to find areas on the map such as abandoned mines and send squads to these to loot their resources. These are designed to allow multiple players to farm them.Bandit Camps:Similarly to missions, players will also discover random bandit camps on the map. These can be attacked (combat is auto resolved for these). Players will need to be careful they have and send the right squads to defeat these or they may possibly be defeated and come home empty handed.Player Raids:And finally (for now), player can establish a defensive garrison in their city and also attack other players on the map. Like bandit camps, the combat for these is automatically resolved. While this can be very profitable, you are essentially declaring war on another player, so do so with caution and be prepared for retaliation!CS:M Global Map Reveal was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Advent Calendar Announcement &amp; Giveaway Event</title>
    <published>2022-12-03T17:06:47+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-12-03T17:06:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/advent-calendar-announcement-giveaway-event-13a896e87b70?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/advent-calendar-announcement-giveaway-event-13a896e87b70?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>FruitGuru</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Currently we are hosting an Advent Calendar Event on our Twitter.Each day, we will be opening up a door for 24 days and not only are we giving away free NFTs that will be usable in our game, but we’re also revealing something new and exciting that’s recently been developed for CityStates: Medieval.At the time of writing this we’re only on day #3, so there’s plenty of chances to win more prizes and learn about some of the amazing work that’s gone into the project recently.Due to Twitters limits on word count, we won’t be going into huge detail on these mechanics during the event but we will be taking a more in depth look at these new mechanics in the new year, which we cannot wait to share with you.You can check out our Twitter here: https://twitter.com/CityStatesMWe also always encourage people interested in the project to join up on our Discord where both team and our community welcome any questions you may have about CS:MAdvent Calendar Announcement &amp;amp; Giveaway Event was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">New 3D models for CityStates: Medieval Heroes.</title>
    <published>2022-10-05T19:10:09+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-05T19:10:09+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/citystates/new-3d-modes-for-citystates-medieval-heroes-3341c64f0c9d?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/citystates/new-3d-modes-for-citystates-medieval-heroes-3341c64f0c9d?source=rss----d6008c85d51b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>FruitGuru</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">If you missed the recent post on Telegram. We unveiled 7 of our 3D hero models with their correct poses. Previously we’ve teased some of these but they hadn’t been rigged and had been in the standard T-pose. Currently we have three tiers of hero card rarity, these are to be used for the fourth tier.We’re really happy with how these have come together and are pleased to show them off to those of you who may have missed them the first time around. So, without any further ado let’s get started!MagnusWe actually had a battle pose for Magnus a while back as many long terms fans might remember. We recently had him remodelled and he’s looking fiercer than ever! We did show him off in a previous post but he’d probably kill us if we didn’t put him back in the limelight.FreyaSpeaking of fierce, here’s another hero you certainly don’t want to cross. Freya is as always, ready to slay those misfortunate enough to find themselves her enemy.AtienaWe all were extremely impressed when we saw Atiena’s base T-Pose model, she is a personal favourite of mine and this action pose delivers in spades capturing both her grace when delivering arrows fired with what we can assure you is deadly precision.KonradA classic crowd favourite when it comes to our community. Perhaps one day we may see him without his helmet, but for now he is easily recognised by the burning sun emblem engraved on his armour as well as his massive blood red sword he wields. The colouring is just dye though… Right?IzelAlthough we already have a varied cast of heroes, Izel’s aesthetic really stands out for all the right reasons. The character rigger (person who sets the poses) really knocked this one out of the park as it perfectly captures our shaman friend in mid dance, perhaps preforming some sort of ritual.NiobeWhen you think of a ninja, this is the pose that comes to mind, looking as deadly as her current +1 action point ability, we’re just glad she’s on our side, for now.AmaruqAnd finally, last but not least, the grey wolf himself. Not much is known about this hero to date but if there’s one thing for certain, we can tell he’s ready to fight. Don’t let his bone spear find a soft spot in your troop armour or it’s all over.And that’s all for now folks. We hope you like them as much as we do and as always we welcome any feedback (even if you just want to let us know who your favourite is — in fact please do, we’re curious!) on Discord.New 3D models for CityStates: Medieval Heroes. was originally published in CityStates on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
