<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog Home | Code4rena Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://code4rena.com/blog/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=SitemapBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fcode4rena.com%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fcode4rena.com%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.post__body&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;site_map=https%3A%2F%2Fcode4rena.com%2Fsitemap.xml&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=SitemapBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fcode4rena.com%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fcode4rena.com%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.post__body&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;site_map=https%3A%2F%2Fcode4rena.com%2Fsitemap.xml&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:02:49+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Ones in the Arena: Krystal | Code4rena Blog</title>
    <published>2024-06-27T04:29:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-27T04:29:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://code4rena.com/blog/the-ones-in-the-arena-krystal</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://code4rena.com/blog/the-ones-in-the-arena-krystal"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="post__body"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;#x27;re talking to the Krystal team about their mission, how they tackle the biggest challenges in liquidity provisioning, and how the industry can achieve better security outcomes across web3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Talk to us about Krystal&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Krystal offers advanced automated liquidity management, featuring a comprehensive all-in-one dashboard and mobile wallet, equipped with automated strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is it so important?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We simplify and enhance liquidity provisioning on Decentralized Exchanges (DEXes), especially those using the Concentrated Liquidity Market Maker (CLMM) model. While this can offer high passive income, it also presents challenges like impermanent loss and unstable yields. Our mission is to make liquidity provisioning profitable, convenient, and accessible for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We provide various tools to help users navigate and optimize their strategies in the DeFi space:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated strategies:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can follow and copy top strategies from a community of liquidity providers, or customize their own.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced dashboard:&lt;/strong&gt; Our comprehensive dashboard consolidates fragmented liquidity across multiple DEXes and chains, providing detailed analysis in a single interface.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficient tools:&lt;/strong&gt; We offer a suite of tools like zap-in, zap-out, readjust-range, collect-fee, auto-compound, and auto-readjust, making liquidity management effortless and effective.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Krystal makes it easier for users to earn passive income in Web3, combining simplicity with powerful features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What prompted you to get an audit with Code4rena?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our decision to audit with Code4rena was driven by several key objectives. First, we aim to finalize a robust, long-term version of our smart contract to ensure the highest level of security for both our users and Krystal as a platform. We also recognize the importance of public awareness and a solid go-to-market (GTM) strategy. Ensuring our smart contract&amp;#x27;s security through a reputable audit is crucial in building trust and credibility within the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After exploring multiple audit options, we found Code4rena to be the best fit for our needs due to their strong reputation, extensive community of skilled auditors, competitive costs, and favorable timeline. This combination makes Code4rena the ideal partner to help us achieve our security and public awareness goals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apart from running an audit with us, what does your security roadmap look like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Krystal, we take security seriously. Key initiatives in our security roadmap include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regular audits:&lt;/strong&gt; We commit to conducting regular audits with reputable firms to continuously assess and improve our smart contract security.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-time monitoring:&lt;/strong&gt; We monitor our platform in real-time to identify suspicious activities and potential threats, allowing us to respond swiftly to any issues.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparent communication:&lt;/strong&gt; Transparency is crucial for us. We openly share our security practices and updates with our users. Detailed information about our security measures can be found in our &lt;a href="https://docs.krystal.app/technical-docs/security" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Technical Docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;By combining these efforts with our audit partnership with Code4rena, we aim to create a secure and reliable platform for our users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can our industry level up security practices across the web3 ecosystem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Krystal&amp;#x27;s point of view, our community can enhance security together with 5 key actions:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foster open communication:&lt;/strong&gt; Encourage transparent and open communication about security practices, potential vulnerabilities, and incident reports. Sharing knowledge and experiences helps everyone stay informed and vigilant.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaborate on audits:&lt;/strong&gt; Engage in collaborative audits and peer reviews. By pooling resources and expertise, we can identify and address security issues more effectively.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promote security best practices:&lt;/strong&gt; Regularly educate community members on security best practices, such as safe handling of private keys, recognizing phishing attempts, and using two-factor authentication.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encourage responsible disclosure:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a supportive environment for responsible disclosure of vulnerabilities. Ensure there are clear, respectful, and rewarding processes for reporting and addressing security issues.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop and share tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Collaborate on the development and sharing of security tools and resources. Open-source tools can benefit the entire community and help standardize security measures.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where is the best place for wardens to learn about Krystal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wardens can visit our documentation site: &lt;a href="https://docs.krystal.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;docs.krystal.app&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find detailed information about our platform, including technical documentation, security practices, and user guides. This resource will provide a thorough understanding of Krystal&amp;#x27;s features, functionalities, and security measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn more about Krystal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href="https://www.krystal.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.krystal.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KrystalDeFi" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://twitter.com/KrystalDeFi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Discord: &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/krystaldefi" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://discord.gg/krystaldefi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Docs: &lt;a href="https://docs.krystal.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://docs.krystal.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ones in the Arena spotlights emerging and established DeFi projects and their founders, with an eye to celebrating and learning from them. The series’ name is inspired in part by Teddy Roosevelt’s famous quote, which has a central place in &lt;a href="https://docs.code4rena.com/philosophy/security-is-about-people#we-can-do-better" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Code4rena’s philosophy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/zfwgl80c/c4-blog/8a85c1a2a0e888480abd2d55ce6d17168cae7321-1200x680.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing Code4rena Pro League: all-star auditors, assembled | Code4rena Blog</title>
    <published>2024-04-25T16:09:16+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-04-25T16:09:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://code4rena.com/blog/introducing-code4rena-pro-league-all-star-auditors-assembled</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://code4rena.com/blog/introducing-code4rena-pro-league-all-star-auditors-assembled"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="post__body"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pro League is here. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code4rena has assembled the world’s most expert security researchers, on-demand to meet your project’s most challenging and critical releases. Welcome to &lt;a href="https://code4rena.com/pro?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=wardens" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the next level&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What is Code4rena Pro League?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code4rena Pro League is the elite tier of Code4rena professional security researchers who compete, consult, and provide a range of services to projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, projects can:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gain exclusive access to top security talent&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Engage with the talent in one marketplace&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Employ the talent through all of their development lifecycle phases&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, Wardens can:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build a full, lucrative career path within Code4rena&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Graduate from competitive audits to solo or team engagements, high-impact consulting, technical leadership, management, or security entrepreneurship&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Oh, and you weren’t seeing things. &lt;a href="https://code4rena.com/@cmichel" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;cmichel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://code4rena.com/@samczsun" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;samczsun&lt;/a&gt; (among other big names) are a part of the exclusive Code4rena Pro League roster. You can check out the full list &lt;a href="https://code4rena.com/pro?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=wardens" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Taking a deeper look at the playbook.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For projects:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to engage Code4rena Pro League talent, there are multiple ways to do so:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Work with Code4rena to curate a custom team: Our team will hand-pick the best talent from our pool of industry-leading security researchers to suit your project’s needs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choose a captained team: You can sort through existing Pro League teams to see which best suits your project’s needs based on proficiencies, budget, and timing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s more is that, in typical Code4rena style, we’ve designed Pro League to incentivize participants to perform at the top of their game. Security researchers included in the Pro League roster have to consistently prove their skills in a competitive environment or face relegation. This means you can have access to incentivized, industry-leading security researchers at any (or every!) stage of your development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interested in learning more? &lt;a href="https://tally.so/r/w5dxMv" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Reach out to our team here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Wardens:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A full, lucrative career path within Code4rena? Sounds pretty good, doesn’t it. Let’s get into the nitty-gritty of how that works for you as a Warden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in &lt;a href="https://code4rena.com/blog/code4rena-spring-update-2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;yesterday’s Spring update&lt;/a&gt;, we’re making the meritocratic professional hierarchy of Code4rena official with the launch of &lt;strong&gt;Security Researcher levels.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To achieve a level-up, you’ll need to improve your ranking, by attaining specific performance milestones and quality metrics. Your ranking improves by participating in &lt;a href="https://code4rena.com/audits#active-audits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;open competitive audits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each level up brings increasing opportunities for compensation, role flexibility, and professional growth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting May 1st, SR will replace “backstage” as the criteria for earning the role currently called “backstage”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As your level increases, so does your ability to participate in lucrative earning opportunities via Pro League engagements. So, what are you waiting for? &lt;a href="https://code4rena.com/are-you-pro?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=wardens" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Check your Pro League eligibility now&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Let’s score big, together.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that, security-minded peers, is how we’re applying the same ‘let’s take this good thing and elevate it to the next level’ mentality to working with individual security researchers, just as we did with open competitive audits. We’re looking forward to this next era with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/zfwgl80c/c4-blog/5488515e1ae6149c94e76744db16118f57a35166-1200x675.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Top Wardens Take Note: New Rules, Bigger Rewards | Code4rena Blog</title>
    <published>2024-04-24T17:00:47+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-04-24T17:00:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://code4rena.com/blog/code4rena-spring-update-2024</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://code4rena.com/blog/code4rena-spring-update-2024"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="post__body"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximize your earnings with the Code4rena Spring Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re introducing some exciting new rules and roles that will increase rewards for top Wardens looking to establish themselves as the best security researchers in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These changes include a major update to C4’s submission flow and award structure, which will improve the value that projects get from sponsoring a competitive audit, while bringing more earnings to the Wardens who contribute the most meaningful submissions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read on for the full details of the update, and get ready to earn rewards to match your reputation when the changes go live on or after May 1st, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR Takeaways:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;💰 More lucrative awards for Wardens finding HM awards, for both uniqueness AND breadth of coverage&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;➕ Increasing % of pool allocated to excellent QA reports – and introducing new Governance section&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;👋 Introducing SR (Security Researcher) levels&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;⚖️ New Validator role to speed up the judging process&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Increased focus (and rewards) on &lt;strong&gt;HMs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serious risks matter the most so we’re allocating a greater percentage of awards to HM findings. This stronger overall emphasis on HM awards in award calculations will make audits more lucrative for the top performing Wardens on C4.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And as further incentive, we’re introducing &lt;strong&gt;two new bonuses&lt;/strong&gt; within the HM pool:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hunter bonus:&lt;/strong&gt; 10% of the HM pool will be awarded to the warden or team who identities the greatest number of &lt;em&gt;unique&lt;/em&gt; HMs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gatherer bonus:&lt;/strong&gt; 10% of the HM pool will be awarded to the warden or team who identifies the greatest number of valid **HMs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Both bonuses weigh Highs more heavily than Mediums, similarly to C4’s typical awarding mechanism.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes to QA Reports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;These QA changes will reward the highest value QA and Gas reports, making them more beneficial for sponsors and the top Wardens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;QA pools are increasing to 4% of the overall award pool.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Introducing Governance section in the QA report for centralization risk and admin privileged functions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Non-critical findings are discouraged.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pausing bot races for the time being.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pausing Analysis for the time being.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gas optimization pools are opt out by default; sponsors who wish to include a Gas pool may choose to do so.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Only the top 3 submissions in each of the QA and Gas categories will be awarded.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Researcher levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;From our very first competitive audit, Code4rena has been the place for talented security minds to get in their reps, earn a name for themselves, and make a career in web3 security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we’re making that process more official with the launch of &lt;strong&gt;Security Researcher levels.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To achieve a level-up, you’ll need to improve your ranking, by attaining specific performance milestones and quality metrics. Your ranking improves by participating in &lt;a href="https://code4rena.com/audits#active-audits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;open competitive audits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each level up brings increasing opportunities for compensation, role flexibility, and professional growth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“SR” will replace “backstage” as the criteria for earning the role currently called “backstage”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have a lot more coming on this front soon. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Validator role&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Validators are a new role that decentralizes triage, eliminates spam for customers, and speeds up the judging process. It will also mean that wardens&amp;#x27; past performance in Code4rena will be a factor in how their submissions are reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Each competition has a qualifying threshold that allows wardens to bypass validators. This threshold is based on your accuracy score.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Qualified wardens’ submissions go directly to the usual findings repo.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All other wardens’ submissions are routed to a Validation repo.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;3-5 Validators review submissions immediately after the audit closes:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Satisfactory submissions are forwarded to the findings repo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unsatisfactory submissions are closed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Validators may also enhance submissions (add PoC, increase quality of report, etc.) in exchange for a % of the finding’s payout.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The judge reviews all submissions in the findings repo.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra spring cleaning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Updated awardcalc formula that better accounts for partials based on community feedback&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;New audit readme format for clearer scope definition&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these changes, please visit the &lt;a href="https://discord.com/channels/810916927919620096/810931711609143326" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;#questions channel&lt;/a&gt; in the Code4rena Discord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/zfwgl80c/c4-blog/dac9afa7bbce84f47d4ecd0f4bd3fa10d88a47a6-1200x675.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
