<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">CodeLn - Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fcodeln&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fcodeln&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:08:29+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">AI vs. Recruiters: Who Really Makes the Best Tech Hiring Decisions?</title>
    <published>2025-04-10T15:40:12+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-10T15:40:12+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/ai-vs-recruiters-who-really-makes-the-best-tech-hiring-decisions-21109c12ee22?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/ai-vs-recruiters-who-really-makes-the-best-tech-hiring-decisions-21109c12ee22?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Táíwò Majeks</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">“Would you trust a robot to hire your next software engineer?”That’s no longer a hypothetical question. Across the globe, artificial intelligence is quietly taking over hiring processes — screening CVs, scheduling interviews, and assessing technical skills. A recent report by Codeaid reveals that nearly 80% of companies are already using AI in some form for recruitment. As AI evolves, a pertinent question arises: Can AI outperform human recruiters in making the best tech hiring decisions?The Rise of AI in RecruitmentThe adoption of AI in recruitment has accelerated in recent years. A survey by ResumeBuilder indicates that 51% of companies currently utilize AI in their hiring processes, with projections suggesting this figure will reach 68% by the end of 2025.AI applications in recruitment are becoming mainstream globally with 79% of companies worldwide now using AI-powered tools to streamline hiring processes. These tools support various stages — from resume screening and candidate assessments to conducting interviews and even onboarding. The data highlighted by the Demandsage report revealed that notably, 82% of employers leverage AI to parse resumes efficiently, while 43% use chatbots to enhance candidate communication. What is also quite undeniable is that the benefits are compelling: AI has been shown to reduce recruitment costs by up to 30% and cut down time-to-hire by nearly 50%. Additionally, companies report up to a 40% improvement in hiring accuracy when using AI-driven interview analytics.Human Recruiters: The Irreplaceable Element?Despite AI’s impressive capabilities, human recruiters bring unique qualities to the hiring process. They possess the ability to assess cultural fit, interpret nuanced candidate responses, and build relationships that foster trust and engagement. Moreover, human intuition and empathy play crucial roles in evaluating soft skills and potential, aspects that AI may not fully capture.However, the rise of AI has introduced new challenges for human recruiters. The increasing use of generative AI tools by candidates to assist with coding problems has led to a surge in cheating during tech interviews, complicating the assessment of genuine talent. That’s why companies like Google and Amazon are considering a return to in-person interviews to mitigate this issue.Striking the Right BalanceThe optimal approach may lie in a synergistic collaboration between AI and human recruiters. For example, AI is better suited to handle time-consuming tasks such as resume screening and initial assessments, allowing human recruiters to focus on deeper evaluations and relationship-building. This partnership can enhance efficiency while ensuring that the human elements of judgment and intuition are preserved. Ethical considerations are paramount in this integration. Ensuring that AI systems are transparent, unbiased, and regularly audited is essential to maintain fairness in hiring decisions. Companies like CodeLn are addressing recruitment bias by implementing AI technologies that serve as a &amp;#39;coach&amp;#39; to recruiters, aiming to streamline processes and reduce time burdens while ensuring fairness.ConclusionWhile AI offers remarkable efficiencies and data-driven insights in tech recruitment, it is not a panacea. The nuanced understanding, empathy, and ethical judgment of human recruiters remain indispensable. A balanced integration of AI and human expertise promises a recruitment process that is both efficient and deeply attuned to the complexities of human potential.Follow us on social media for more tips on Hiring &amp;amp; Payroll: Linkedin, Twitter, IG, and Facebook.AI vs. Recruiters: Who Really Makes the Best Tech Hiring Decisions? was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Invisible Costs of Paying Global Teams: How to Avoid Hidden Fees</title>
    <published>2025-03-25T23:34:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-25T23:34:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/the-invisible-costs-of-paying-global-teams-how-to-avoid-hidden-fees-c23b2884bb1d?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/the-invisible-costs-of-paying-global-teams-how-to-avoid-hidden-fees-c23b2884bb1d?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Táíwò Majeks</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Before now, hiring international talent was a luxury reserved for multinational giants with deep pockets. Today, it’s the norm. A startup in Lagos can have a designer in São Paulo, a developer in Kyiv, and a customer success team in Manila. But while companies are celebrating the ease of building global teams, they often overlook a silent drain on their finances: hidden fees in cross-border payroll.At first glance, paying remote employees seems straightforward. Just send the money, and they receive it, right? If only. In reality, global payroll is a tangled web of currency conversions, intermediary bank charges, compliance costs, and unpredictable transaction fees. These hidden expenses add up quickly, eating into company profits and causing headaches for finance teams.Where Does the Money Go? Let’s uncover the fees lurking in the shadows:1. Currency Conversion Markups — The Silent Tax on PaymentsBanks and payment providers often inflate exchange rates to squeeze out extra profit. Instead of converting money at the mid-market rate (the real rate you see on Google), they apply a hidden markup. This practice, as explained here by Papaya Global, means companies unknowingly pay more than they should. Over time, these small markups become significant costs.2. Intermediary Bank Charges — The Money That Disappears in TransitHave you ever sent money internationally and noticed the recipient got less than expected? That’s because international payments often pass through multiple banks before reaching their destination. Each of these banks takes a small fee for “processing” the payment, resulting in unexpected reductions.3. Compliance &amp;amp; Regulatory Expenses — The Hidden Costs of Following the RulesGlobal payroll isn’t just about sending money; it’s about navigating tax laws, social security contributions, and employment regulations in multiple countries. Governments worldwide are cracking down on non-compliance, and companies that don’t follow local payroll laws risk hefty fines. According to Multiplier, businesses often underestimate the cost of ensuring compliance.How to Avoid These Hidden Fees and Pay Smarter1. Pick a Platform with a Transparent Fee StructureMost companies accept fees as inevitable, but they don’t have to be. Find payment providers with clear pricing. Some platforms offer transparent fee structures, helping businesses predict and control costs rather than dealing with unexpected deductions. CodeLn Pay is one of the platforms that offers the most affordable and transparent payroll pricing for cross-border payment, helping businesses save thousands of dollars annually in hidden charges.2. Leverage Fintech Solutions — The New Age of Cross-Border PaymentsFintech has revolutionized global payroll. Services like multi-currency accounts, blockchain-based transfers, and automated payment systems allow companies to move money across borders with minimal fees. An example is Nilos, a modern fintech platform is helping customers cut out traditional banking fees and provide businesses with real-time exchange rates.3. Use a Single Payment Platform — To Reduce FeesOne of the easiest ways to cut costs is to stop relying on multiple banks and payment providers. Instead, use a single, centralized payroll system designed for global teams.4. Stay Ahead of Regulatory Changes — Know the Rules Before They ChangeInternational tax laws constantly evolve, what worked last year might not be compliant today. Staying informed about global payroll regulations can prevent fines and extra compliance costs. Companies proactively tracking regulatory changes are less likely to face unexpected financial penalties.Final Thoughts: Pay Smarter, Not MoreThe allure of building a global team is undeniable, but hidden fees in international payroll can quietly drain company resources. By understanding where the money goes, using smarter payment solutions, and staying ahead of regulatory changes, businesses can pay their teams fairly without overpaying banks and middlemen.Ultimately, paying global teams shouldn’t feel like navigating a minefield. With the right strategy and fintech tools, it’s possible to cut unnecessary costs and keep more money where it belongs — supporting the people who make businesses thrive.Follow us on social media for more tips on Hiring &amp;amp; Payroll: Linkedin, Twitter, IG, and Facebook.The Invisible Costs of Paying Global Teams: How to Avoid Hidden Fees was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Are AI Agents the New Employees?</title>
    <published>2025-03-14T14:45:25+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-14T14:45:25+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/are-ai-agents-the-new-employees-9106d1df94e7?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/are-ai-agents-the-new-employees-9106d1df94e7?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Táíwò Majeks</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">A recent job post by Firecrawl went viral. They listed a job for an AI agent, offering a salary of $15,000 a year. “Please apply only if you are an AI agent, or if you created an AI agent that can fill this job,” the job post read. The founders of Firecrawl claimed that it was a PR stunt/experiment, but it sparked a lot of interest on X, with people wondering if this is truly what the future of hiring will look like.The Emergence of AI Agents in the WorkplaceLet&amp;#39;s face it, we&amp;#39;re getting used to the new normal of AI agents rapidly reshaping modern workplaces by handling a wide range of tasks, from administrative duties to complex decision-making processes. According to Business Insider, leading companies such as ServiceNow, Salesforce, and SAP have already begun integrating AI-driven systems to enhance productivity. ServiceNow&amp;#39;s AI agents, for instance, have been credited with reducing the time required to handle complex cases by 52%, demonstrating the significant value they bring to businesses.The fast-food industry has also embraced AI as a tool for improving efficiency. A report from Reuters revealed how Taco Bell has implemented its &amp;#39;Byte by Yum&amp;#39; AI system to assist managers with scheduling and inventory management, reducing workload stress. Meanwhile, McDonald&amp;#39;s is rolling out AI-enabled drive-throughs and smart kitchen equipment across its 43,000 locations to accelerate service and improve customer experience, as gathered by the New York Post.Beyond operational tasks, AI is making a strong impact in recruitment and hiring. TechCrunch reported that Klarna&amp;#39;s CEO revealed that AI has reduced the company&amp;#39;s need for human hiring, yet it still advertises open roles, signalling a hybrid approach. While AI can streamline hiring and remove human bias, concerns about transparency and fairness persist.But, What Are The Challenges and ConsiderationsWhile the benefits of AI agents are substantial, their integration into the workforce presents challenges:1. Job Displacement: With AI automating tasks traditionally performed by humans, concerns about job loss and economic displacement are on the rise. Many workers may find themselves needing to re-skill to remain competitive in the job market.2. Erosion of Autonomy: As AI assumes more decision-making responsibilities, employees might experience a diminished sense of control over their work, potentially leading to reduced job satisfaction and engagement.3. Privacy and Surveillance: AI-driven workplace monitoring tools collect vast amounts of data, raising concerns about employee privacy and workplace surveillance. A recent case saw Y Combinator deleting a demo posts about one of their startups (Optifye.ai) after people raised ethical concerns about the product. Ethical deployment of AI must balance efficiency with respect for workers&amp;#39; rights.4. Bias and Discrimination: AI systems trained on biased datasets risk perpetuating discrimination, particularly in hiring and performance evaluations. Ensuring ethical AI practices is crucial to prevent unintended biases from influencing decisions.It All Comes Down to The Human-AI CollaborationDespite these challenges, the future of work is likely to be characterized by collaboration between humans and AI agents. AI can efficiently manage repetitive and data-driven tasks, freeing up human employees to focus on strategic thinking, creativity, and interpersonal interactions. Companies that successfully integrate AI as a supportive tool rather than a replacement for human workers will likely see the best outcomes in terms of productivity and job satisfaction.In conclusion, what is quite evident is that AI agents are transforming the workforce, taking on roles that were once the exclusive domain of human employees. While they offer significant advantages, such as efficiency and innovation, organizations must navigate the accompanying challenges carefully. By fostering a workplace where AI and human workers complement each other, businesses can ensure a future where technology enhances rather than disrupts employment.Follow us on social media for more tips on Hiring &amp;amp; Payroll: Linkedin, Twitter, IG, and Facebook.Are AI Agents the New Employees? was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Will PayFi Outshine TradFi for Cross-Border Payroll?</title>
    <published>2025-02-26T15:18:07+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-26T15:18:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/will-payfi-outshine-tradfi-for-cross-border-payroll-f2d13c48917f?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/will-payfi-outshine-tradfi-for-cross-border-payroll-f2d13c48917f?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Táíwò Majeks</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Will PayFi Outshine TradFi for Cross-Border Payroll?Imagine you’re a Startup Founder based in New York, managing a team of developers spread across Africa and LATAM. When payday comes, you issue payments via your bank account but 1 week later your team has still not received their salaries. They keep asking to confirm if you have sent the payment. Does this sound familiar?For global businesses, cross-border payroll has long been a headache. Also, what is quite evident as it concerns Traditional finance (TradFi) systems is that, while reliable, they are slow, expensive, and riddled with compliance hurdles. But what if there was a faster, cheaper, and more efficient way? This is where PayFi comes in.PayFi (short for Payment Finance) is like the new kid on the block because of its offerings - A blockchain-powered alternative that promises to revolutionise cross-border payroll. But the question is, can it truly outshine TradFi which has been around for much longer?Understanding TradFi in Cross-Border PayrollTradFi systems rely on banks and regulators to facilitate payment across borders. While they provide structure and trust, they come with significant drawbacks:Slow Processing Times: Payments can take days, or even weeks due to multiple intermediary banks, processors, and custodian platforms.High Transaction Fees: Each middleman takes a cut - charges from customer banks, SWIFT/SEPA, beneficiary banks, foreign exchanges, and other external processors. Your employees are always short-changed once the money hits their account.Compliance Complexities: Every country has different tax laws, banking regulations, and reporting requirements and this increases the administrative burden.These issues make TradFi a frustrating choice for employers and remote employees who need instant, low-cost, and transparent payment solutions.Are the setbacks of TradFi The Reason Why PayFi is Gaining Momentum?Since PayFi is done on-chain and relies less on multiple external third parties, it is beginning to give TradFi a run for its money, and here’s why it’s becoming a game-changer:Faster Settlements: Unlike TradFi, which relies on banking hours, PayFi enables real-time payments, 24/7. According to an article by Stellar Network, blockchain-powered solutions can process near-instant settlements.Lower Fees: One of the biggest advantages of PayFi is lower charges. By eliminating intermediaries, both employers and employees can save significantly on charges, this is what platforms like CodeLnPay offer its customers.Transparency and Security: Every transaction on a PayFi system is recorded on an immutable blockchain ledger, reducing fraud risks and ensuring accountability.No Pre-Funding Requirements: Unlike traditional payroll systems that require companies to hold funds in advance, PayFi allows for more flexibility. Huma Finance explains how this provides an advantage here.What Are The Real-world Applications of PayFi in Payroll?Several platforms are pioneering PayFi solutions to simplify payroll:CodeLn Pay: A web-3 powered payroll solution that enables global employers to pay African-based remote talent securely with speed.Remittix: This platform converts crypto payments into fiat, allowing businesses to pay employees directly into their bank accounts.Rise: A decentralized payroll system that provides an alternative to the expensive traditional banking methods.Challenges and ConsiderationsWhile PayFi has enormous potential, some hurdles remain:Regulatory Uncertainty: Different countries have varying stances on crypto payroll, and businesses must remain tax-compliant and obey labor laws.Crypto Volatility: Paying employees in crypto means exposure to price swings unless stablecoins like USDC are used.Adoption Barriers: Many businesses and employees are still unfamiliar with blockchain-based payroll, requiring education during onboarding.So, will PayFi outshine TradFi in cross-border payroll? The signs are promising. Faster payments, lower costs, and greater transparency make it an attractive alternative. For companies navigating global payroll challenges, the big question remains: will they be willing to fully embrace the switch from TradFi to PayFi?Follow us on social media for more tips on Hiring &amp;amp; Payroll: Linkedin, Medium, Twitter, IG, and Facebook.Will PayFi Outshine TradFi for Cross-Border Payroll? was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Future of Tech Recruitment: Trends to Watch in 2025</title>
    <published>2025-02-17T20:44:58+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-17T20:44:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/the-future-of-tech-recruitment-trends-to-watch-in-2025-7b5af47d237b?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/the-future-of-tech-recruitment-trends-to-watch-in-2025-7b5af47d237b?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Táíwò Majeks</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Previously, landing a tech job often meant polishing a CV, applying online, and hoping for a recruiter’s call. Fast-forward to today, and the landscape has drastically shifted. Advanced tech-powered platforms are reshaping the industry. With these swift changes and evolutions in the recruitment process, hiring is no longer just about filling vacancies - it’s a strategic game where companies compete for the best minds in an ever-evolving digital economy.For recruiters, hiring managers, and job seekers, staying ahead means understanding the trends that will define the future. From AI-driven recruitment to the rise of decentralized hiring models, this article explores the key changes shaping tech recruitment in 2025.1. AI and Automation Dominating Talent AcquisitionArtificial Intelligence is no longer a futuristic concept in hiring—it’s becoming the backbone of modern recruitment. Now, AI will not only automate repetitive tasks like resume screening and interview scheduling but might also play a role in decision-making. CodeLn, HireVue, and Humanly are examples of AI-powered recruitment platforms. In 2025, expect AI-driven tools to refine how companies source, assess, and onboard talent, reducing hiring time by as much as 50%.2. Skills Over Degrees: The Rise of Competency-Based HiringFor decades, a degree from a prestigious university was the golden ticket to a tech career. However as big tech companies began to embrace skills-based hiring, the traditional degree requirement is losing relevance. The shift towards competency-based hiring sees tech recruiters focusing on coding challenges, project-based assessments, and proof of practical skills. Platforms like Clide, HackerRank, and LeetCode are already at the forefront of this movement, enabling companies to evaluate real-world abilities. In 2025, this trend will be even more pronounced, with companies investing in skill verification platforms and upskilling programs.3. Remote Work and Global Talent PoolThe remote work revolution that started in 2020 has only gained momentum. The reality in 2025 is that companies that resist remote hiring might risk losing top talent to more flexible employers. A study by McKinsey revealed that 87% of tech professionals prefer hybrid or fully remote work. Companies can now hire across borders, using global payroll solutions like CodeLnPay, Riseworks, and Rippling to onboard international talent seamlessly. This trend allows companies to tap into a diverse talent pool. As a result, the tech job market is becoming borderless, with location no longer a constraint for employment.4. The Growing Importance of Employer BrandingIn a competitive job market, companies must position themselves as desirable workplaces. Employer branding is no longer a “nice-to-have”—it’s a necessity for attracting top talent. A report by LinkedIn stated that 75% of job seekers research a company’s brand before applying. In 2025, strong employer branding will involve more than just a well-designed career page—it will require companies to showcase culture, employee testimonials, diversity initiatives, and career growth opportunities across multiple platforms. Companies like Microsoft, Netflix, and Shopify have mastered this art, using social media, podcasts, and blogs to create compelling employer brands that attract the best minds.5. The Rise of Decentralized and Blockchain-Based HiringLately, blockchain is making its way into recruitment, particularly in credential and identity verification. In 2025, blockchain-based resumes and decentralized job marketplaces will eliminate fraudulent claims on CVs, making hiring more transparent. Platforms like Joba and SpringWorks already use blockchain to verify candidates’ skills and work history, reducing the need for tedious background checks and speeding up the hiring process. Companies adopting this technology will have a competitive edge.6. Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (DEI) in HiringDiversity hiring is no longer just a corporate checkbox—it’s a business necessity. A Research by McKinsey shows that diverse teams outperform homogeneous ones by 35% in profitability. In 2025, companies will adopt the use of AI-driven tools to remove biases from job descriptions and hiring processes. Software like Textio helps organizations craft inclusive job postings and identify bias in recruitment. Additionally, companies will move beyond traditional DEI metrics and focus on fostering inclusive work environments that retain diverse talent long-term.7. The Integration of Gamification in RecruitmentGamified hiring is transforming candidate assessment. Companies like Google and Amazon already use interactive challenges and coding games to evaluate problem-solving skills. In 2025, expect gamification to become mainstream, with AI-driven simulations and virtual reality (VR) assessments giving recruiters deeper insights into candidates&amp;#39; abilities and decision-making skills. Platforms like CodeSignal and CodinGame are leading this trend, making hiring more engaging and data-driven.8. The Shift to Continuous Learning and Internal Talent MobilityCompanies are realizing that upskilling existing employees is becoming a priority. According to a Report by Linkedin, 94% of employees would stay at a company longer if it invested in their careers. In 2025, organizations will implement learning management systems (LMS) and in-house boot camps to reskill their workforce. Tech giants like Amazon and Microsoft are already offering paid reskilling programs to retain talent and fill skill gaps internally. This trend will only grow, as companies find that fostering internal mobility is more cost-effective.Which of these trends will you be adopting for your company?Follow us on social media for more tips on Hiring &amp;amp; Payroll: Linkedin, Twitter, IG, and Facebook.The Future of Tech Recruitment: Trends to Watch in 2025 was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">CodeLn Launches CodeLnPay for Cross-Border Salary Payment to Africa</title>
    <published>2023-07-04T15:21:04+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-07-04T15:21:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/codeln-launches-codelnpay-for-cross-border-salary-payment-to-africa-8ba4b73d98b7?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/codeln-launches-codelnpay-for-cross-border-salary-payment-to-africa-8ba4b73d98b7?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ladyroselineorji</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In today’s interconnected world, businesses are increasingly aiming for a global scale. As companies expand their operations across borders, paying salaries to employees in different countries can become complex. This is particularly true regarding paying remote employees based in Africa. Companies face challenges around restrictions, compliance, currency conversion complexities, fluctuating exchange rates, and the high cost of remittances.African-based remote employees are also experiencing challenges around salary delays, deduction on earnings, and county work restrictions. According to a 2021 report by Google, 38% of African Software Engineers work for at least one company based outside of the continent. These are some of the challenges cited by remote employees/freelancers working across country with employers in Africa or across the continent with employers overseas.Our CEO, Elohor Thomas announced the launch of CodeLn Pay on stage at the recently concluded Collision Conference in Canada. This new product was built to mitigate the challenges and friction experienced by both employers and employees/freelancers. CodeLn Pay streamlines the salary payment process, making it efficient, secure, and hassle-free.At the time of this launch, CodeLnPay is available for employers based in Canada, the United States, the United Kingdom, and Europe to process salary payments seamlessly and compliantly to their remote employees/contractors in Africa. And employees based anywhere in Africa can invoice their employers abroad and receive payments from any of the specified regions.Benefits of CodeLn Pay for EmployersMulti-Currency Payout: without bothering about currency conversion rates, you can send salaries in USD, Euro, or GBP while the receiver chooses if they want to collect it in the same currency or their local currency.Payroll Scheduling: you can easily schedule salary disbursements based on your preferred frequency (monthly, biweekly, or customized) in order to ensure timely and consistent payments.Transparent Pricing: there are no hidden charges, our charges are fixed based on the amount per transaction. This transparency helps you minimize associated costs and complexities.Multi-Payment Option: we support multiple payment options, you can choose to pay using any of your preferred payment options or partner.Benefits of CodeLn Pay for Employees/FreelancersInvoice Employers: Whether you need an invoice for a one-time payment or recurring payment, we have got you covered. Seamlessly generate and share invoices on CodeLn Pay to help you track your earnings.Multi-Currency Payout: you can choose to receive your salary in USD, Euro, GBP, or any local African currency.Fast Disbursements: salary drops on your payday, no more long wait times. You receive your earnings without delays according to the timelines communicated.Cost-effective Rate: receive your complete salary without unnecessary deductions. CodeLn Pay offers you price transparency and affordable rates.Sign up on CodeLnPay today for a seamless payment experience.You can find a short demo of the product here, reach us via chat or email (INFO@CODELN.COM) if you have questions.We are still committed to supporting the growth of innovative companies by providing them with a simple platform to find, test, hire and pay top-quality talent from the African continent.Follow us on social media for more updates: IG, Linkedin, Twitter, and Facebook.CodeLn Launches CodeLnPay for Cross-Border Salary Payment to Africa was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">CodeLn Launches Insight, a FREE Applicant Tracking System to Help Startups Digitize their Hiring…</title>
    <published>2022-03-19T13:40:59+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-19T13:40:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/codeln-launches-insight-a-free-applicant-tracking-system-to-help-startups-digitize-their-hiring-5eeeed8bf787?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/codeln-launches-insight-a-free-applicant-tracking-system-to-help-startups-digitize-their-hiring-5eeeed8bf787?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Elohor Thomas</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">CodeLn Launches Insight, a FREE Applicant Tracking System to Help Startups Digitize their Hiring ProcessCodeLn, an online tech talent marketplace has launched Insight, a smart Applicant Tracking System (ATS) to help startups manage job applicants and monitor their job vacancies.One of the biggest challenges for startups as they scale up is the hiring process. This complex process is often done using emails and spreadsheets which is time-consuming and prone to error. If this process is not properly conducted, companies risk having productivity loss, a bad hire, and high employee turnover.The Insight platformCodeLn’s new platform, Insight is a smart, easy-to-use ATS where recruiters can post jobs, share jobs, receive job applications, manage job applications, and collaborate with team members to rate and hire candidates from any field. Some of the key features of the products include: a company dedicated job board, drag and drop kanban to manage applications, and a team collaboration feature. Insight is a platform that helps recruiters manage all their job applications in one platform. They do not have to pay to use Insight, it is completely free.“We noticed a problem that can be solved by simplicity and automation so we jumped on it. Being engineers, my team loves building so this time, we decided to build one for the Startup community as our way of giving back. Having noticed a lot of startups struggle during hiring season, we built Insight to help them ease that stress” stated Elohor, CEO and Co-founder.Start using Insight today: https://insight.codeln.com/CodeLn Launches Insight, a FREE Applicant Tracking System to Help Startups Digitize their Hiring… was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Classifying the Various Levels of Developers (Junior, Mid &amp; Senior)</title>
    <published>2021-07-01T15:17:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T15:17:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/classifying-the-various-levels-of-developers-junior-mid-senior-78bdc0a15c79?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/classifying-the-various-levels-of-developers-junior-mid-senior-78bdc0a15c79?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>D.R CHIBS</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">It feels fulfilling to be at the very top of the hierarchy of any ranking system. Like in Naruto (a childhood anime), a Ninja is either a Genin (beginner), a Chunin (mid), or a Jounin (advanced). Being a developer can feel like this, there’s a name for your skill level at any point in time: Junior, Mid, or Senior and then, there is also Lead (this is like the Hokage of software development).Firstly, we ought to establish that the “years of experience” is not the only yardstick to measure the various levels of developers, there are varying standards and measurements for this which will be our focus. We noticed that some recruiters and developers have a vague idea of this classification, it is evident in the tech ads that we see on media spaces and in resumes that developers wave in the faces of recruiters regularly.In this article, we will be sharing our opinions on the topic that will hopefully save you the time, stress, and confusion concerning this classification.Some questions we will be answering include:What are the differences between the 3 different levels highlighted?How do you know when you need a junior, mid or senior developer?What expectations should you have when you hire a certain level of developers?JuniorsThe role of a junior developer is an entry-level position. This does not imply complete ignorance but a junior can be a greenhorn to the workflows and the full lifecycle of software development. They require supervision, instruction, and guidance. They are expected to be able to strike a balance between asking for help and finding solutions.At the least, they should be familiar with one programming language, one IDE, frequently used APIs, simple select statements for databases, and they should know platforms where they can get quick answers e.g Stack Overflow.This level of developers is quite affordable, they can be hired by Startups to build an MVP or by Corporates to join a bigger team. They quickly adjust to your company culture and can easily learn and grow with your team. We do advise that there is at least someone senior to supervise them, there was a case of a junior engineer that deleted the entire database of a company unknowingly. If there was no backup, this would have been a very costly mistake.Mid-levelThis group is somewhere in-between junior and senior-level but it is safe to say it is more inclined towards the senior level. Mid-level developers have probably been through the whole development cycle at least once. They have made many simple mistakes and have learned enough from them to be fairly competent. Unlike juniors, they can take up fairly difficult tasks with little supervision and can handle major bug fixes. They can break down major tasks into smaller sub-tasks and even coordinate juniors.At this level, they should be familiar with coding best standards and practices, coding documentation, and some project management tools e.g Jira. They care about the readability of code, design patterns, automated testing, proper documentation, and know the ins and outs of code collaboration.They are a worthwhile investment for employers who do not have the time and budget to train juniors or the huge salaries to keep seniors satisfied.SeniorA senior developer is skilled enough to handle the complexities of a product from initialization through development to production, they write with maintainability and scalability in mind.They can work both independently and manage teams, they have technical direction and can quickly spot and fix bugs because of their professional years of experience doing the same. Familiarity with multiple languages and the ability to multi-task is also part of their selling point.They can set and decide code design and architecture and break down the entire task into simple and mid-level tasks for junior and mid-level teams under their supervision.They are always a great investment to lead your team and handle complex products as long as you can sell them your vision or pay a really good salary.The bottom line of this article is to give you an idea of the classes of developers and what to know about their skill sets and their efficiency as it pertains to your product. This is not set in stone, you should be creative with your choices and skill combination but we hope this article informs your choices better.We are always excited to help, while you focus on other areas of productivity. CodeLn is your foremost platform for recruiting tech talents, with a pool of over 14,000 developers, you can build the most diverse development team with just the click of your mouse. Speak with us today! info@codeln.com or visit https://www.codeln.comClassifying the Various Levels of Developers (Junior, Mid &amp;amp; Senior) was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing Remote Codeln</title>
    <published>2021-04-08T11:58:50+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-08T11:58:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/introducing-remote-codeln-4dc9b569cdc0?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/introducing-remote-codeln-4dc9b569cdc0?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>D.R CHIBS</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">When Codeln launched a few years ago with initial offices in Lagos, Accra, and Nairobi, we aimed to become the global go-to marketplace for verified African tech talent. A technical recruiter who already knows his job requirement can hire a developer in under 15 minutes because the entire tech recruitment process is automated end-to-end. You can post a job, receive recommended candidates based on the skills shared, conduct an online test to vet expertise, schedule an interview, and present a job offer, all without leaving the platform.When the COVID-19 global pandemic rocked the world in 2020, it crippled many businesses and organizations, so much that a lot of industries ran in the red for many months; it was a new, harsh, and seemingly inoperable circumstance for many as it spurred multiple lockdowns, compulsory stay-at-home and economy shutdowns in so many countries.There had to be another way for businesses to operate outside the physical, in-office work model. This is why the not-so-liked remote work model became mainstream and saved many businesses, and today, many recruiters and workers alike have quickly adapted to remote work.Like every other thing in the universe, remote work, even with its many advantages and perks, there are particular challenges too when compared with the normal work model, like security, effectively managing a remote workforce, etc. This is one of the reasons at Codeln, we decided to step up to the challenge and build an additional new product, Remote Codeln.There has been a heightened demand for freelancers since 2020, especially with the massive retrenchment of staff in many redundant companies. This was even more pronounced in the tech space where tech organisations went fully remote and this opened up so many opportunities, like tech organisations setting their eyes on tech talent outside their locality and even outsourcing some aspects of their product development.Remote Codeln stands as an intermediary between companies and freelance developers and guarantees that milestones are completed before payment is done and that developers get paid for all work done.Remote Codeln is an innovative platform that helps companies and individuals to manage projects and track product development tasks throughout the product development process.It makes the Gig workforce adoption very seamless for companies as it allows you to start a new tech project, receive bids from freelancers, pick from a pool of verified bidders, draft product development contract, assign/manage product development tasks, and even automate payment based on milestones completed using escrow, all without leaving the platform!CEO and Co-founder, Elohor ThomasOur CEO and Co-founder, Elohor Thomas has this to say about our exciting new product, “We saw the need to enlighten companies on how to manage programmers working remotely as it was not the norm in Africa before COVID hit. But we soon realised the additional need for a tool to help them manage this process seamlessly that is why we built Remote CodeLn. This platform ensures a smooth process for both the company and the programmer”.Why is Remote Codeln worth it?Verified Talent Pool — Codeln already boasts of a talent pool of over 13,000 developers across Africa, what this means is that we did not build from nothing. Remote Codeln gives you access to receiving bids from only verified developers who have gone through our technical assessment tests such that the issue of trust is already taken care of, rest assured you are recruiting a qualified developer.Project Tracking — Now you do not have to be in the dark about your own project, waiting and praying that the freelancer is really working, you can collaborate with freelancers working on your project and track product development effectively from start to finish.Escrow Payment — An escrow is a financial arrangement where a third party holds and regulates payment of the funds required for two parties involved in a given transaction. With Remote Codeln, you can seamlessly manage your payment based on your milestones using escrow.Arbitration — standing as an intermediary between the freelancer and the client, the platform manages all forms of dispute resolution that may arise ensuring both parties have a smooth working experience.Convinced about giving Remote Codeln a try? Let us know, you can contact us at codeLn@codeLn.com if you have more questions about our platform.We are really excited to see what you build and how you will use this tool!Introducing Remote Codeln was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Why Global Companies should Hire African Software Engineers in 2021</title>
    <published>2021-02-02T06:44:05+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T06:44:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/codeln/why-global-companies-should-hire-african-software-engineers-in-2021-32053d7eea02?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/codeln/why-global-companies-should-hire-african-software-engineers-in-2021-32053d7eea02?source=rss----14c60c27fdd0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>D.R CHIBS</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">According to Microsoft, the digital transformation that happened during the global pandemic lockdown last year was expected to happen in 2 years. As such, they estimated that there will be 149 million new tech jobs in 2025. The fact is, more and more jobs requiring digital skills are being created daily, do you have enough talent in your market to handle this?Source: Financial MarketsSome stats about Africa:Africa is currently the world’s youngest continent with a population of over 1.9 billion and 60% of it being below 35 years of age, so the youth population is large.According to this article by Forbes, Africa is a continent of the future and she can leapfrog the rest of the world with innovation.There are currently over 618 active tech hubs in Africa which include Facebook Hub, Google Hub, and many more.The year 2020 was a record-breaking one for African tech startups, with 397 companies securing US$701.5 million worth of investment.According to a report by IFC &amp;amp; Google, tech talent in Africa is at a historical peak and continues to rise annually.Source: IFCWhy hire African Software Engineers?In 2019, Google opened its first Artificial Intelligence Lab in Africa. Microsoft also opened its first Africa Development Centers which currently hires local African Software Engineers to build their products. If these giants have seen the potential and are currently hiring African engineers, why shouldn’t you?Language is not a barrier: I bet you will agree that programming language is the only global language. An African Javascript programmer writes the same js code as a programmer in any part of the world as the structure has been defined globally by Javascript’s best standards and practices. African programmers can compete with their peers from anywhere in the world. Literally stating languages, most Africans have their first language being either English or French due to the colonization. So communication is never an issue if you have them in your team.Time Zone differences? Most African countries have similar times as Europe and adaptable times with the US and other continents allowing them to work seamlessly remotely during the day or at night. Timezone has never been an issue for engineers working remotely with clients because they are naturally proactive, resilient, and very flexible.How about Soft Skills? As long as you are hiring from a trusted recruitment firm, you should have nothing to worry about. Renowned recruitment firms like CodeLn trains programmers on the necessary soft skills needed for the workplace and tools/skills required for remote work, e.g Scrum, Slack, Jira, etc.Value for money: you are also guaranteed value for your money. Due to the currency exchange rate, you can get highly qualified senior software engineers at a really good rate from whatever country you are hiring from in Africa. Unlike other markets where the standard of living is quite high, the African talent market can be considered quite affordable even for startups.CodeLn currently has a pool of over 13,000 qualified African Software Engineers available for hire. Contact us at codeLn@codeLn.com if you are interested in creating global impact from local tech talent.Why Global Companies should Hire African Software Engineers in 2021 was originally published in CodeLn on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
