<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Coins Blog | Coins.ph</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://coins.ph/blog/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fcoins.ph%2Fblog%2Frss%2F&amp;content_selector=.post-content&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;remove_styles=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fcoins.ph%2Fblog%2Frss%2F&amp;content_selector=.post-content&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;remove_styles=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:04:33+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Trump Strikes Down IRS Crypto Rule, Bitcoin Fuels China-Russia Trade, and ETH Options Trading Approved</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T03:21:28+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T03:21:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://coins.ph/blog/crypto-news-atbp-april-11/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://coins.ph/blog/crypto-news-atbp-april-11/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Coins Blog</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Trump Repeals IRS Crypto Rule
U.S. President Donald Trump has signed a repeal of a controversial IRS rule enacted under the Biden administration. The rule had required businesses to report crypto transactions over $10,000 along with personal information, a move critics said was overly invasive. Its repeal is seen as a win for crypto privacy advocates and signals the continued political battle over digital asset regulation. (The Block)
China and Russia Settle Energy Trade in Bitcoin
China and Russia are reportedly settling some cross-border energy trades using Bitcoin. This marks a significant shift from traditional reliance on the U.S. dollar and signals deeper financial collaboration between the two nations. Analysts say the move may challenge U.S. sanctions and accelerate the global use of crypto in international commerce. (Yahoo Finance)
SEC Approves Options Trading for Spot Ethereum ETFs
The U.S. SEC has greenlit options trading for spot Ethereum ETFs, including products from BlackRock, Bitwise, and Grayscale. The approval could enhance liquidity and attract more institutional investors to Ethereum. Analysts say this signals growing regulatory comfort with Ethereum-based financial instruments, though some caution that volatility may increase with options trading. (The Block)
DOJ Disbands Crypto Crime Unit in Major Policy Shift
The U.S. Department of Justice is shutting down the National Cryptocurrency Enforcement Team, signaling a retreat from aggressive crypto enforcement. Deputy Attorney General Todd Blanche emphasized that the DOJ “is not a digital assets regulator,” criticizing the previous administration’s “regulation by prosecution” approach. Instead, crypto enforcement will narrow its focus—targeting scams and criminal misuse like drug trafficking or terrorism financing—while stepping back from prosecuting developers and platforms for their users’ actions. (AP News)
Saylor’s Bitcoin Bet Down $5.9B — But He’s Not Selling
Strategy founder Michael Saylor is sitting on a $5.9 billion unrealized loss on Bitcoin, but he remains committed to holding. The company recently acquired more BTC, reinforcing its long-term bullish stance. Analysts note that while Saylor’s strategy is high-risk, it reflects a deep belief in Bitcoin as digital gold — even in the face of volatility and drawdowns. (The Street)
Hong Kong Approves Crypto Staking ETFs
Hong Kong regulators have approved a new wave of crypto staking ETFs, marking a significant regulatory milestone in Asia. These products will offer exposure to staking rewards while allowing traditional investors to access crypto yield without directly holding tokens. This move positions Hong Kong as a more crypto-friendly jurisdiction amid global regulatory uncertainty. (The Block)</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://static.blog.coins.xyz/coins-landing-blog-ph-en/2025/04/Crypto-ATBP_11-Apr-2025_Blog-Banner.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">P2P VIP Express: Unlock VIP Perks Today!</title>
    <published>2025-04-10T06:43:49+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-10T06:43:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://coins.ph/blog/p2p-vip-express-mechanics/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://coins.ph/blog/p2p-vip-express-mechanics/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Coins Blog</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Are you a P2P merchant looking to level up your trading? Now’s your chance!
With Coins’ P2P VIP Express Campaign, we’re offering VIP upgrades to eligible P2P merchants, giving you two-month access to lower trading fees, higher transaction limits, and priority support on Coins.ph.
How it Works
If you don’t have it yet, create a Coins.ph account and get identity verified. For a quick guide, click here.
Sign up by filling out the VIP Upgrade application form: link
Submit proof of your active P2P merchant status on another platform (e.g., screenshots of recent trades, merchant profile, or verified trader status).
Enjoy VIP benefits for 2 months upon approval!
Who Can Join?
P2P merchants who don’t have a Coins.ph account yet&amp;nbsp;
Inactive P2P merchants on Coins.ph who haven’t made a trade in the last 60 days
Why Upgrade to VIP?
As a Coins VIP, you’ll enjoy two months of:
Lower trading fees to maximize your profits
Higher transaction limits and trade at a higher volume
Dedicated customer support for seamless transactions
Sign up today and experience VIP trading perks at Coins.ph!
Terms and Conditions
The Program is ongoing and is open exclusively to either inactive P2P merchants on Coins.ph (no trades in the last 60 days) or new P2P merchants registering on Coins.ph.
To join, participants must register via the VIP Upgrade application form and provide a proof of active P2P merchant status on another platform. Only verified users who meet the criteria will be eligible for the VIP upgrade.
Successful participants will receive VIP 6 status for two (2) months upon approval.
Coins.ph reserves the right to review and validate all submissions before approval.
Coins.ph reserves the right to approve, deny, or revoke VIP status at its discretion.
Participants found engaging in fraudulent transactions, providing false information, or misusing the promotion will be disqualified.
Employees of Coins.ph and their relatives (up to the second degree of consanguinity or affinity) are not eligible for this campaign.
By participating, merchants agree to comply with these Terms &amp;amp; Conditions.
Coins.ph may amend, extend, or discontinue this promotion at any time without prior notice.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://static.blog.coins.xyz/coins-landing-blog-ph-en/2025/04/P2P-VIP_Blog.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">$CARV Convert Competition!</title>
    <published>2025-04-08T08:42:45+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-08T08:42:45+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://coins.ph/blog/carv-convert-competition-mechanics/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://coins.ph/blog/carv-convert-competition-mechanics/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Coins Blog</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Win your share of the 4,000 $CARV prize pool! Trade CARV on Coins Convert and join the competition today!
How to Join:
Buy and/or sell at least P2,500 worth of $CARV on Coins Convert
Rank among the Top 200 in convert trading volume to win rewards
To learn more about how to use Coins Convert to trade $CARV, see this guide: link
Promo lasts from April 8 to May 8, 2025 only.
Rewards:  
Rank
Reward (in $CARV)
1-5
1,500
6-50
1,500
51-200
1,000
  
What are you waiting for? Buy and/or Sell $CARV to secure your rewards in the Convert Competition! 
Terms and Conditions
The Program is open to individuals aged 18 or older with a KYC account that is Identity Verified. Participation is limited to users based in the Philippines.
Both buy and sell on Coins Convert of the eligible token/s will be tallied.
Rewards will be disbursed to users’ accounts and are non-transferable and must be accepted as awarded.
Winners will be notified via email within ten (10) working days after the end of the promo period.&amp;nbsp;
Rewards will be credited to the winners’ Coins.ph wallet within fifteen (15) working days after the end of the promo period.&amp;nbsp;
Any disputes concerning the conduct of this Promotion will be resolved by Coins.ph at its sole discretion.
By participating in this Promotion, participants agree to abide by these Terms and Conditions.
Coins.ph reserves the rights to disqualify and exclude users who are involved in any dishonest or fraudulent behaviors (i.e. wash trading, illegally bulk registered accounts, market manipulation).
Coins.ph reserves the right to amend these Terms and Conditions, including but not limited to the eligibility criteria, program period, and reward distribution, at its sole discretion.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://static.blog.coins.xyz/coins-landing-blog-ph-en/2025/04/Carv-Convert-Competition_Blog.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
