<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Introducing Virtual US Bank Accounts - Copperx</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://copperx.io/blog/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fcopperx.io%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_selector=a.block&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fcopperx.io%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.content.blog.prose&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;thumbnail_as_header=on&amp;date_selector=.text-md.leading-snug.text-gray-500&amp;date_format=M+d+Y&amp;author_selector=.text-md.leading-snug.text-gray-700&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fcopperx.io%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_selector=a.block&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fcopperx.io%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.content.blog.prose&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;thumbnail_as_header=on&amp;date_selector=.text-md.leading-snug.text-gray-500&amp;date_format=M+d+Y&amp;author_selector=.text-md.leading-snug.text-gray-700&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:04:53+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing Virtual US Bank Accounts - Copperx</title>
    <published>2025-03-06T22:04:53+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-06T22:04:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://copperx.io/blog/introducing-virtual-us-bank-accounts</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://copperx.io/blog/introducing-virtual-us-bank-accounts"/>
    <author>
      <name>Dalpat Prajapati</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://copperx.io/og/home.png?v=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="content blog prose"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copperx has launched Virtual US Bank Accounts, powered by Bridge. This feature allows users to create a virtual US bank account, receive USD payments from US customers, and automatically convert USD to USDC in their Copperx wallet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Virtual US Bank account with your legal name&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Receive USD via local payment rails like ACH and Wire&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Automatic conversion of USD to USDC&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="challenges-in-onchain-payments"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges in Onchain Payments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For global freelancers, businesses, and individuals, receiving &lt;strong&gt;USDC payments&lt;/strong&gt; has often been difficult due to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited access to US banking services &lt;/strong&gt;–&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Opening a bank account in the US can be a complicated process.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. High fees and long settlement times with traditional methods &lt;/strong&gt;–&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Traditional methods often incur high fees and longer settlement times. SWIFT transactions typically take 2-3 business days to process payments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Complicated blockchain transactions for senders &lt;/strong&gt;– Senders need to understand blockchain technology and USDC, leading to a longer learning curve and higher effort for a single transaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copperx addresses these challenges with Virtual US Bank Accounts, enabling a &lt;strong&gt;direct USD-to-USDC conversion&lt;/strong&gt;, reducing reliance on multiple platforms and expensive intermediaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="who-can-benefit-from-virtual-us-bank-accounts"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Can Benefit from Virtual US Bank Accounts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.copperx.io/blog/2025/03/image-1.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="1756" height="951"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;🔹 &lt;strong&gt;Freelancers &amp;amp; Remote Workers&lt;/strong&gt; – Receive payments from US clients in USD and get USDC directly in your wallet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🔹 &lt;strong&gt;Global Businesses&lt;/strong&gt; – Accept payments from US customers via ACH and wire transfers without requiring a US entity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🔹 &lt;strong&gt;Individuals&lt;/strong&gt; – Receive personal payments, remittances, or transfers from the US with automatic USDC conversion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="how-it-works"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How It Works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up on Copperx&lt;/strong&gt; and complete KYC/KYB verification.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create Your Virtual US Bank Account&lt;/strong&gt;—no US residency required.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Receive USD Payments&lt;/strong&gt; via ACH or wire transfers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic USDC Conversion&lt;/strong&gt;—funds are credited to your Copperx wallet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id="why-use-copperx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Use Copperx?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.copperx.io/blog/2025/03/image.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="1756" height="988"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Simple Account Setup&lt;/strong&gt; – No US residency or extensive paperwork required.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Low Conversion Fee&lt;/strong&gt; – A cost-effective alternative to traditional on-ramp services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Faster Transactions&lt;/strong&gt; – Receive and convert USD to USDC without long delays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Integrated Onchain Banking Solution&lt;/strong&gt; – Use your virtual bank account alongside features like USDC-to-local currency conversion, &lt;strong&gt;Copperx Debit Card&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;8% yield on USDC savings&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="copperx-bridging-traditional-and-onchain-banking"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copperx: Bridging Traditional and Onchain Banking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copperx Virtual US Bank Accounts provide a practical solution for global users to access US banking services, allowing them to manage stablecoin finance alongside features like local off-ramping, a stablecoin debit card, and a savings feature. Copperx offers a complete onchain financial solution, empowering users with financial independence and control over their assets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get started today!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sign up on Copperx, complete verification, and start receiving payments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="kg-card kg-button-card kg-align-left"&gt;&lt;a href="https://payout.copperx.io/auth/login" class="kg-btn kg-btn-accent"&gt;Get Started &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.me/+DsdpSUtrospjZDFl"&gt;💬 Join our Telegram community&lt;/a&gt; and visit the Copperx Support Center for assistance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://copperx.io/og/home.png?v=1"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Copperx x Circle: Redefining Onchain Payments and Payouts - Copperx</title>
    <published>2025-01-13T22:04:53+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-13T22:04:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://copperx.io/blog/copperx-x-circle-programmable-wallets-redefining-onchain-payments-and-payouts</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://copperx.io/blog/copperx-x-circle-programmable-wallets-redefining-onchain-payments-and-payouts"/>
    <author>
      <name>Tarun Mangukiya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.copperx.io/blog/2025/01/Circle-x-Copperx-1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="content blog prose"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Managing crypto wallets should be simple and secure for businesses. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's why we're excited to announce that Copperx is leveraging the&lt;a href="https://www.circle.com/wallets" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt; Circle’s Programmable Wallets&lt;/a&gt; to enhance our payout platform. By integrating Copperx's payout system with Programmable Wallets, we aim to make managing crypto payments and payouts faster, more secure, and safer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="about-circle-programmable-wallets"&gt;About Circle Programmable Wallets&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.circle.com/"&gt;Circle&lt;/a&gt;'s Programmable Wallets offer a flexible, secure wallet infrastructure tailored for blockchain applications. Developers can create in-app wallets for global users, facilitating commerce at an enterprise scale. The platform provides APIs and SDKs in various programming languages, enabling rapid deployment without the need to learn new languages like Solidity or Rust. Additionally, it enhances security through multi-party computation (MPC) wallets and allows for real-time compliance checks to meet regulatory requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="copperx"&gt;Copperx &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://copperx.io/"&gt;Copperx&lt;/a&gt; is a global payment solution designed for businesses and individuals, enabling real-time fund transfers to own bank account, vendors, contractors, and employees across over 50 countries. It supports deposits in USDC and offers features like bulk payments, scheduled transactions, and automated off-ramps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="the-problem-why-crypto-wallets-need-a-better-solution"&gt;The Problem: Why Crypto Wallets Need a Better Solution&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today's businesses face a critical challenge: managing crypto wallets securely and efficiently. The current landscape forces companies to deal with significant wallet-related complexities that slow down their operations:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complex key management systems that require technical expertise&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Security risks from managing private keys&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lack of enterprise-grade wallet solutions that scale&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complicated wallet infrastructure that's difficult to maintain&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poor user experience that makes wallet operations cumbersome&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many existing wallet solutions force businesses to make difficult tradeoffs between security and usability. They either choose highly secure systems that are complex to operate, or user-friendly solutions that may compromise on security features. This creates particular challenges for companies needing robust security and operational simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The market needs a unified wallet infrastructure that provides enterprise-grade security while maintaining an intuitive user experience. This is exactly what Copperx achieves by leveraging Circle's Programmable Wallets and CCTP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="the-importance-of-wallet-infrastructure"&gt;The Importance of Wallet Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Onchain economy, having a secure and scalable wallet infrastructure is essential for success. As businesses grow and manage more crypto assets, the complexity of wallet management increases exponentially. Traditional wallet solutions often force companies to choose between security and usability, creating operational bottlenecks and increasing risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With features like advanced encryption and multi-party computation (MPC), every aspect of wallet management stays protected while remaining flexible and scalable. Whether you're a small startup or a growing enterprise, your wallet infrastructure needs to evolve with your business while maintaining the highest security standards. Circle's Programmable Wallet provides exactly this balance, keeping your assets secure while making operations intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="why-circle-programmable-wallets-is-the-ideal-solution"&gt;Why Circle Programmable Wallets is the Ideal Solution&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Circle's Programmable Wallets excel in several critical areas that make them perfect for any size business. Their implementation process is remarkably swift, with ready-to-use APIs and SDKs that support multiple programming languages. This means businesses can get up and running quickly, without lengthy development cycles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the security front, Circle's multi-party computation technology and distributed key management ensure your crypto assets are always protected. The system is built to handle enterprise-scale operations, supporting high-volume transactions with 24/7 reliability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What truly sets Circle's Programmable Wallets apart is its approach to user experience. They've managed to hide all the technical complexity behind an intuitive interface, making crypto transactions simpler than ever. Their comprehensive system allows businesses to focus on growth while the technical details take care of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="copperx-x-circle-enhancing-payment-features-with-programmable-wallets"&gt;Copperx  x Circle: Enhancing Payment Features with Programmable Wallets&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The integration of Copperx Payout with Programmable Wallets expands functionality and provides users with efficient and secure payment solutions. By utilizing Circle’s wallet infrastructure, Copperx is introducing features that improve user experience and operational efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="current-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deposit from Multiple Chains&lt;/strong&gt;: Users can deposit funds across multiple chains using CCTP, simplifying the payment process.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faster Settlement of USDC&lt;/strong&gt;: Settlement times are significantly reduced, enabling quicker fund transfers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple Wallet Support&lt;/strong&gt;: Facilitate payouts across multiple wallets, offering flexibility for different use cases.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="upcoming-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upcoming Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multichain Wallets&lt;/strong&gt;: Enable wallet operations across various blockchain networks, improving accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Offramp&lt;/strong&gt;: Streamline the process of converting digital assets to fiat currency.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payout APIs&lt;/strong&gt;: Provide APIs for automated, programmable payouts tailored to business workflows.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Asset Support&lt;/strong&gt;: Add support for various digital assets beyond USDC.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Wallet with Team Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Introduce collaborative wallet management features for team fund handling.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Circle Programmable Wallets, Copperx is focused on delivering practical and scalable payment solutions to meet the needs of growing businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copperx Payout’s integration with Circle Programmable Wallet is making payments faster, safer, and more flexible. With features like multi-chain wallets, automated offramps, and multi-asset support, it’s all about giving users a smoother experience while handling payments. This collaboration is setting the stage for better tools and more ways to manage transactions effortlessly, keeping things simple and efficient for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: For the most up-to-date information about features and capabilities, always refer to the official documentation of Circle and Copperx.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.copperx.io/blog/2025/01/Circle-x-Copperx-1.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Ultimate Guide to Crypto Taxes in India: Everything You Need to Know (2024) - Copperx</title>
    <published>2024-11-25T22:04:53+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-25T22:04:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://copperx.io/blog/the-ultimate-guide-to-crypto-taxes-in-india-everything-you-need-to-know-2024</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://copperx.io/blog/the-ultimate-guide-to-crypto-taxes-in-india-everything-you-need-to-know-2024"/>
    <author>
      <name>Tarun Mangukiya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://copperx.io/og/home.png?v=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="content blog prose"&gt;&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;₹180 crore (~$21M)&lt;/strong&gt; was collected as TDS from crypto transactions in India last year. This highlights the growing adoption of cryptocurrencies in the country—but also underscores the confusion and uncertainty surrounding crypto taxation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With evolving regulations and complex rules, many Indian crypto users are still unclear about when and how taxes apply to their crypto activities. From trading and staking to NFTs and airdrops, there’s a lot to unpack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog simplifies the &lt;strong&gt;state of crypto taxes in India&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;10 key points&lt;/strong&gt;, real-life examples, and actionable insights to help every Indian crypto user stay compliant. Let’s dive in!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="1-when-does-the-flat-30-tax-apply"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. When Does the Flat 30% Tax Apply?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In India, Section 115BBH of the Income Tax Act mandates a flat &lt;strong&gt;30% tax&lt;/strong&gt; on any profits earned from the transfer of cryptocurrency or Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs). This tax applies uniformly, regardless of your income tax slab, making it a critical consideration for crypto traders and investors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What constitutes a transfer?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;A transfer includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Selling cryptocurrency or NFTs for fiat currency.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exchanging one cryptocurrency for another.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Surrendering crypto assets in any other way.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="how-are-profits-calculated"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Are Profits Calculated?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Profits are calculated as:&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profit = Sale Price - Purchase Cost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="example"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you purchased 1 Bitcoin for ₹1 lakh and later sold it for ₹1.5 lakh, your profit is ₹50,000.&lt;br&gt;Tax = 30% of ₹50,000 = ₹15,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.indiafilings.com/learn/crypto-tax-in-india-taxation-on-cryptocurrency/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="2-when-does-1-tds-apply"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. When Does 1% TDS Apply?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Section 194S, &lt;strong&gt;1% TDS (Tax Deducted at Source)&lt;/strong&gt; is applicable on crypto transactions involving the purchase of Virtual Digital Assets (VDAs) from a resident seller. This TDS ensures the government tracks crypto transactions and collects taxes upfront.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exceptions to the TDS Rule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;No TDS is deducted for trades on &lt;strong&gt;international exchanges&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;decentralized exchanges (DEXs)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;TDS is mandatory for &lt;strong&gt;P2P transactions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Transfers between your own wallets are not subject to TDS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="effective-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effective Date:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rule came into effect on &lt;strong&gt;July 1, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="example-1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you buy 1 ETH via a P2P transaction for ₹1 lakh, the buyer must deduct ₹1,000 as TDS (1%) and pay ₹99,000 to the seller.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://tax2win.in/guide/tds-section-194s-income-tax-act"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.copperx.io/blog/2024/11/image.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="2072" height="896"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="3-how-are-crypto-payouts-taxed"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. How Are Crypto Payouts Taxed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crypto payouts, such as salaries paid in cryptocurrency, are taxable under &lt;strong&gt;two events&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="1-receipt-of-salary"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Receipt of Salary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The market value (MV) of the cryptocurrency on the date of receipt is taxed as &lt;strong&gt;salary income&lt;/strong&gt;, according to your income tax slab rate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="2-sale-of-crypto"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Sale of Crypto:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the received crypto is sold, a &lt;strong&gt;30% tax&lt;/strong&gt; is applicable on profits (Sale Price - MV). Additionally, &lt;strong&gt;1% TDS&lt;/strong&gt; is deducted by the buyer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="example-2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Received BTC as salary worth ₹1 lakh.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Later sold BTC for ₹1.5 lakh.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salary Tax:&lt;/strong&gt; ₹1 lakh taxed as per your slab rate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sale Tax:&lt;/strong&gt; Profit = ₹1.5 lakh - ₹1 lakh = ₹50,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;30% of ₹50,000 = ₹15,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;1% TDS = ₹500.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Tax on Sale:&lt;/strong&gt; ₹15,500 (excluding slab tax).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cleartax.in/s/cryptocurrency-taxation-guide"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="4-how-are-airdrops-taxed"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. How Are Airdrops Taxed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Airdrops are classified as taxable events and are taxed &lt;strong&gt;twice&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Receipt:&lt;/strong&gt; The market value (MV) of the tokens at the time of receipt is taxed as &lt;strong&gt;Other Income&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Sale:&lt;/strong&gt; A flat &lt;strong&gt;30% tax&lt;/strong&gt; applies to profits (Sale Price - MV).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If no market value is available when the airdrop is received, the tax applies to the &lt;strong&gt;entire sale amount&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="example-3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Received an airdrop worth ₹10,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sold it later for ₹20,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Profit = ₹20,000 - ₹10,000 = ₹10,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tax = ₹3,000 (30% of ₹10,000).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.koinx.com/tax-guides/tax-on-airdrops-in-india"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="5-how-are-crypto-gifts-taxed"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. How Are Crypto Gifts Taxed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gifting cryptocurrency may seem straightforward, but it has specific tax implications. Gifts are taxed under &lt;strong&gt;two events&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="1-on-receipt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. On Receipt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gifts received from &lt;strong&gt;relatives&lt;/strong&gt; are &lt;strong&gt;tax-free&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gifts from &lt;strong&gt;others&lt;/strong&gt; are exempt up to ₹50,000 annually. Any amount exceeding ₹50,000 is taxed as per slab rates.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="2-on-sale"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. On Sale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When the gifted crypto is sold, a &lt;strong&gt;30% tax&lt;/strong&gt; applies to the profit, calculated as:&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profit = Sale Price - (Cost to the previous owner or taxed Gift Income).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="example-4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gift worth ₹60,000 received → ₹10,000 taxable.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sold the gift for ₹80,000 → Profit = ₹20,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tax = ₹6,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.koinx.com/tax-guides/tax-on-crypto-gifts-in-india"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="6-are-crypto-mining-rewards-taxable"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Are Crypto Mining Rewards Taxable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crypto mining rewards are taxed during &lt;strong&gt;two events&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="1-receipt-of-reward"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Receipt of Reward:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The market value (MV) of the mined cryptocurrency at the time of receipt is taxed as &lt;strong&gt;Business Income&lt;/strong&gt; under your income tax slab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="2-sale-of-crypto-1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Sale of Crypto:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A flat &lt;strong&gt;30% tax&lt;/strong&gt; is applicable on profits (Sale Price - MV), and &lt;strong&gt;1% TDS&lt;/strong&gt; is deducted by the buyer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="example-5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mined crypto worth ₹1 lakh → Sold later for ₹1.5 lakh.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Profit = ₹50,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tax = ₹15,000 (30% of ₹50,000) + ₹500 TDS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.koinx.com/tax-guides/tax-on-mining-income-in-india"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="7-is-income-from-staking-or-yield-farming-taxable"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Is Income from Staking or Yield Farming Taxable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Staking and yield farming income are also taxed during &lt;strong&gt;two events&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward Claimed:&lt;/strong&gt; The market value of the reward at the time of claiming is taxed as &lt;strong&gt;Other Income&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sale of Crypto:&lt;/strong&gt; A flat &lt;strong&gt;30% tax&lt;/strong&gt; is applied to profits (Sale Price - MV).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id="example-6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Claimed staking rewards worth ₹1 lakh → Taxed as Other Income.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sold later for ₹1.5 lakh → Profit = ₹50,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tax = ₹15,000 (30% of ₹50,000).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.koinx.com/tax-guides/tax-on-crypto-staking-in-india"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="8-how-is-crypto-trading-or-investing-taxed"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. How Is Crypto Trading or Investing Taxed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trading and investing in cryptocurrencies attract a &lt;strong&gt;flat 30% tax&lt;/strong&gt; on profits, plus applicable surcharge and cess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="key-rules"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Rules:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The tax applies only to &lt;strong&gt;profits&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;No deductions for brokerage, fees, or other expenses.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="example-7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bought ETH for ₹1 lakh → Sold for ₹2 lakh.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Profit = ₹1 lakh.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tax = ₹30,000 (30% of ₹1 lakh).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.indiafilings.com/learn/crypto-tax-in-india-taxation-on-cryptocurrency/#:~:text=In%20India%2C%20you'll%20pay,within%20a%20single%20financial%20year."&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="9-are-crypto-borrowing-and-repayments-taxable"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Are Crypto Borrowing and Repayments Taxable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Borrowing crypto or repaying a loan in crypto is &lt;strong&gt;not taxable&lt;/strong&gt;. However, profits made from trading with borrowed funds are taxed at a flat &lt;strong&gt;30% rate&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="example-8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Borrowed 1 ETH worth ₹1 lakh → Traded and earned ₹50,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tax = ₹15,000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cleartax.in/s/cryptocurrency-lending-and-borrowing"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2 id="10-how-are-nfts-taxed"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. How Are NFTs Taxed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs) are treated as Virtual Digital Assets (VDAs) and are taxed at a flat &lt;strong&gt;30% rate&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="example-9"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bought an NFT for ₹1 lakh → Sold for ₹2 lakh.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Profit = ₹1 lakh.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tax = ₹30,000 (30% of ₹1 lakh).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cleartax.in/s/taxation-on-nfts-and-cryptocurrencies"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h3 id="faqs-your-questions-about-crypto-taxes-answered"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FAQs: Your Questions About Crypto Taxes Answered&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="1%EF%B8%8F%E2%83%A3-if-my-wallet-is-hacked-after-making-profits-do-i-still-pay-tax"&gt;1️⃣ &lt;strong&gt;If my wallet is hacked after making profits, do I still pay tax?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, taxes must be paid on profits earned &lt;strong&gt;before the hack&lt;/strong&gt;. The unfortunate loss of funds does not exempt you from tax liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id="2%EF%B8%8F%E2%83%A3-what-if-i-receive-usdc-as-a-salary"&gt;2️⃣ &lt;strong&gt;What if I receive USDC as a salary?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Receiving USDC as salary is treated as regular salary income. It is taxed based on the &lt;strong&gt;market value&lt;/strong&gt; of the USDC at the time of receipt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id="3%EF%B8%8F%E2%83%A3-can-the-government-track-trades-on-a-dex"&gt;3️⃣ &lt;strong&gt;Can the government track trades on a DEX?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, authorities can trace transactions on decentralized exchanges (DEX) using blockchain analytics tools. Staying compliant and reporting these trades is essential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id="4%EF%B8%8F%E2%83%A3-is-there-tax-or-tds-on-wallet-transfers"&gt;4️⃣ &lt;strong&gt;Is there tax or TDS on wallet transfers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, transfers between your &lt;strong&gt;personal wallets&lt;/strong&gt; are neither taxed nor subject to TDS. These are considered non-taxable events.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id="5%EF%B8%8F%E2%83%A3-do-losses-from-one-crypto-trade-offset-gains-from-another"&gt;5️⃣ &lt;strong&gt;Do losses from one crypto trade offset gains from another?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, losses from one trade cannot be deducted from gains in another. Each profitable trade is taxed &lt;strong&gt;individually&lt;/strong&gt; at the applicable rates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id="6%EF%B8%8F%E2%83%A3-are-airdrops-fully-taxed-when-sold"&gt;6️⃣ &lt;strong&gt;Are airdrops fully taxed when sold?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Airdrops are taxed twice:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On receipt as &lt;strong&gt;"Other Income"&lt;/strong&gt;, based on market value.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;On profits earned when the airdrop is sold, taxed at &lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h3 id="final-note"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://x.com/TheWeb3CA"&gt;Web3CA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, for simplifying crypto tax regulations in India. Your clear insights on TDS, 30% tax rules, and NFT taxation have been invaluable for helping the crypto community stay compliant and confident. For personalized guidance on crypto taxes, reach out to &lt;a href="https://x.com/TheWeb3CA"&gt;Web3CA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your efforts make navigating crypto taxes much easier. 🙌&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://copperx.io/og/home.png?v=1"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
