<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stay Up-to-date on Web3 Security Trends | Cyvers.ai Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cyvers.ai/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fcyvers.ai%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.blog-card+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.post-details&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=5&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fcyvers.ai%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.blog-card+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.post-details&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=5&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Next Mega-Hack Won’t Be Stopped by Fixing Bybit’s Mistakes - But by Protecting Against the Unknown | Cyvers.ai</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>urn:sha1:38f873c6363e2969a642ea02da6fd32f0aad011c</id>
    <content type="html">While these reactions are necessary, they expose a dangerous flaw in cybersecurity thinking: preparing for the last attack rather than the next one.The reality is stark: The next breach won’t look like the last one. Every major exploit introduces new tactics, bypasses existing safeguards, and exposes vulnerabilities that were previously unknown. Cybercriminals evolve faster than defenses, and nowhere is this more evident than in the sophisticated hacks we’ve seen in 2024.The Lazarus Group: A State-Backed Cyber MenaceThe FBI has confirmed that North Korea’s Lazarus Group orchestrated the Bybit hack. This isn’t just another cybercriminal syndicate - this is an advanced persistent threat (APT) group backed by a nation-state, leveraging military-grade hacking tactics to steal billions and fund illicit state operations.As Keri Pearlson from MIT’s Cybersecurity Research Consortium put it:&amp;quot;The good guys must protect against every possible vulnerability, while the bad guys only need one small crack in a company’s armor to get in.&amp;quot;This couldn’t be more relevant in Web3, where a single compromised wallet, a slight UI manipulation, or a blind signature can lead to catastrophic losses.Anatomy of the Bybit Hack: A Multi-Layered AttackUnderstanding what happened at Bybit reveals how advanced hackers are exploiting human and technical vulnerabilities in tandem.1️. Initial CompromiseThe attackers infiltrated the computer of a Safe wallet developer through a supply chain attack.This allowed them to introduce a malicious transaction during the wallet’s deployment.2️. UI ManipulationThe hackers altered the Safe wallet frontend, tricking signers into approving fraudulent transactions that looked legitimate.This exploit made it impossible for signers to distinguish between a real and malicious transaction.3️. Blind SigningSince cold wallets don’t display human-readable transaction details, signers blindly approved the fraudulent transaction.This method bypassed security checks that rely on manual verification.4️. Instant DrainWithin seconds, the attack was executed across four simultaneous transactions, draining funds before security teams could react.This was not a brute force attack - it was a surgical, premeditated strike. And it could have been prevented.The methods used in the Bybit hack were not new - even though the implementation was slightly different. Previous mega-hacks like WazirX ($235M) and Radiant Capital ($50M) also exploited compromised wallet signers, blind transaction approvals, and multisig vulnerabilities, allowing attackers to bypass security measures and drain funds undetected.Source: CyversHow This Could Have Been StoppedMost security solutions focus on reactive measures, identifying breaches after they occur. But what if you could stop an attack before it happens? This is exactly what Cyvers Interceptor does.🔍 How Cyvers’ Pre-Transaction Threat Simulation Works1️. Analyzes transaction parameters in real-time, detecting malicious payloads before execution.2️. Simulates the final state of the transaction, ensuring it matches the expected outcome.3️. Uses real-time threat intelligence to classify blockchain interactions and flag high-risk delegation calls.Source: Cyvers💡 Key Insight: The malicious smart contract used in this attack was detected by Cyvers two days prior to the hack. Had Bybit implemented Pre-Chain Interceptor, it would have flagged:⚠️ “High-risk delegation call detected - fund loss imminent!”This early warning would have halted the attack before execution, preventing Bybit’s losses and preserving user trust.‍Cyvers interceptor’s analysis of the Bybit hackSource: Cyvers‍Cyvers interceptor’s analysis of the WazirX hackSource: Cyvers‍‍The Future of Web3 Security: Preparing for the UnknownThe Bybit attack isn’t an anomaly - it’s a blueprint for what’s coming next.🔹 900% increase in CeFi exchange hacks in 2024.🔹 $2.3 billion lost in Web3 security breaches in 2024.The battle for Web3 security isn’t about fixing past mistakes - it’s about preventing what we don’t yet know.That requires AI-driven preemptive prevention that prevents threats before they execute.🔒 Don’t train for yesterday’s battle - equip yourself for all future threats, known and unknown.➡️ Schedule a demo with Cyvers today‍‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/636a75aa90ee580b0a16bbbb/67c5ca338dccb45e8fff688d_IMG_4106.JPG"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The State of Web3 Security in 2024:A Year of Escalating Threats and Hard Lessons | Cyvers.ai</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>urn:sha1:c5146aa84ee0b70c460fad7802dd6538f888b388</id>
    <content type="html">If you thought Web3 security was finally turning a corner, 2024 might have given you a rude awakening. This year has been a relentless battlefield for blockchain projects, exchanges, and DeFi platforms, with cyber threats evolving at an alarming pace. The numbers? Nothing short of staggering. A whopping $6+ billion was lost to attacks, exploits, hacks and other cyber incidents in 2024—marking a 40% exploits increase from 2023. If one thing has become painfully clear: hackers are not just keeping up; they’re staying ahead. From access control failures to smart contract exploits, the attack surface is only expanding. But despite the mounting losses, there’s still hope. With the right security strategies, organizations can fight back and outsmart cybercriminals. Let’s break down the biggest security trends of 2024, the most devastating attacks, and what this means for the future of Web3.‍2024: The Year of Soaring Web3 Losses Web3 was built on the promise of decentralization, transparency, and security. But in reality, attackers are getting more sophisticated, and projects that fail to prioritize security are paying the price—literally. By the end of Q4 2024, $2.3 billion had been drained from Web3 projects. And quarter by quarter, the numbers climbed. Q1: $517 million Q2: $587 million Q3: $669 million Q4: $130 million  ‍@Cyvers AiTo put this into perspective, Web3-related losses in 2023 totaled $1.69 billion. While 2024’s losses are still lower than 2022’s record-breaking $3.78 billion, the upward trend is undeniable—and concerning.So, where is all this money going?  Straight into the hands of hackers exploiting smart contract flaws, bypassing access controls, and targeting high-value digital assets. How Hackers Stole $2.3 Billion in 2024 Not all attacks are created equal. Some exploit weak security policies, while others take advantage of poor coding practices. However, two major attack types dominated in 2024: Access Control Violations – 81% of Total Losses The overwhelming majority of funds were stolen due to weak authentication and permission mechanisms. This highlights a critical issue: many Web3 projects still aren’t implementing proper security protocols to protect user assets. Smart Contract Exploits – 19% of Total Losses Even a single flaw in a smart contract can be catastrophic, and 2024 was proof of that. Poorly written code resulted in millions of dollars being siphoned from DeFi platforms. When we analyze the types of incidents, the breakdown is even more alarming: 98 attacks (59%) stemmed from smart contract vulnerabilities 67 incidents (41%) were due to access control failures This isn’t about minor security oversights—these were major vulnerabilities that led to some of the biggest hacks of the year. ‍Think your favorite platform is immune to hacks? So did these projects—until they lost millions. Let’s dive into the biggest Web3 heists of the year and see who got hit the hardest ‍‍The Biggest Web3 Hacks of 2024 Some of the biggest names in the industry suffered multi-million-dollar exploits. Here are the top 10 largest hacks of the year by funds lost: 1️⃣ DMM Bitcoin – $305M 2️⃣ PlayDapp – $290M 3️⃣ WazirX – $235M 4️⃣ Muchables – $97M 5️⃣ Address Poisoning Attack (Cyvers Exclusive) – $68M 6️⃣ Radiant Capital – $55M 7️⃣ DeFi Saver – $54M 8️⃣ BtcTurk – $52M 9️⃣ BingX (Cyvers Exclusive) – $44.7M 🔟 Hedgey Finance – $39M @Cyvers AiThese incidents are a stark reminder that even the most well-established platforms can be vulnerable. Without continuous security monitoring and proactive defenses, hackers will always find a way in.‍Which Blockchains Were Targeted the Most? If you’re wondering which blockchains suffered the biggest losses, one name stands out: Ethereum.  📉 51% of all stolen funds in 2024 came from Ethereum. 📉 BNB Chain followed with 24%, while Bitcoin (5%), XRP (4%), and Arbitrum (3%) also took heavy hits. Ethereum’s dominance in DeFi makes it a prime target. More users, more liquidity, and—unfortunately—more opportunities for attackers. @Cyvers AiCan Stolen Funds Be Recovered?  Not all hope is lost—some recovery efforts have been successful, but the results have been mixed. The first half of the year saw the most significant recoveries, with $620 million reclaimed in Q1 and $562 million in Q2. However, by Q3, that number had dropped dramatically to $93 million, and by Q4, recoveries had nearly vanished, totaling just $25 million. This decline highlights a critical challenge: while early intervention can help recover stolen assets, delays often allow funds to disappear before authorities and security teams can act. ‍Lessons from 2024 &amp;amp; Predictions for 2025  ✅ Smart Contract Audits Are No Longer Optional One-time audits before launch aren’t enough. Continuous monitoring and real-time vulnerability testing should be standard practice. ✅ AI-Powered Threat Detection is the Future Cybercriminals are using AI, so security teams need to fight fire with fire. AI-driven security solutions can detect threats before they escalate. ✅ Stronger Authentication &amp;amp; Access Controls Are a Must Since 81% of losses were due to access control failures, Web3 projects must adopt multi-factor authentication, better key management, and robust permissions systems. ✅ Regulations Are Coming Governments are paying closer attention to Web3 security, and 2025 will likely bring tighter compliance measures. ‍Conclusion  2024 proved that Web3 security is in a constant arms race—hackers innovate, and defenders must evolve even faster. With over $6 billion lost, the message is clear: security cannot be an afterthought. The good news? Proactive security measures work. Platforms that invest in continuous smart contract monitoring, AI-powered threat detection, and strong access control mechanisms stand the best chance at avoiding the fate of this year’s biggest victims. As we step into 2025, one question remains: Will the industry finally prioritize security before the next billion is lost? ‍Check out our full Cyvers 2024 Web3 Security Report for exclusive insights, key attack patterns, and what’s next in crypto security: https://cyvers.ai/report‍Book a call with our security experts today and stay ahead of the next attack: https://calendly.com/d/cqjd-77h-r6x/cyvers-first-call?month=2025-01</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/636a75aa90ee580b0a16bbbb/6788fd0b663c729d25e86586_2025-01-16%2013.27.34.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Secure Signer: A New Era of Transaction Security by Cyvers and Station70 | Cyvers.ai</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>urn:sha1:3d37e6a1aa40fce7099a8bf8414ce72ba2dd0229</id>
    <content type="html">In an industry-first collaboration, Cyversand Station70 are launching &amp;quot;Secure Signer,&amp;quot; an institutional-gradetransaction security solution to confront access control threats in Web3. Giventhe alarming rise in access control breaches, which have resulted in over $4billion in losses across the crypto ecosystem, this tool aims to bolsterinstitutional protection for digital asset transactions.Understanding the Challenge of AccessControl BreachesAccess control has emerged as one of thebiggest challenges in Web3 security, as reported in Cyvers&amp;#x27; recent studies,which highlight a significant increase in centralized attacks targeting walletand transaction signing systems​​. In 2024, centralizedentities experienced a 1,000% spike in such breaches, including major incidentsat BtcTurk and BingX, revealing vulnerabilities in current systems​.Introducing Secure Signer: ADual-Layered Approach to Transaction SecuritySecure Signer combines Cyvers&amp;#x27; advancedAI-powered real-time threat detection engine with Station70&amp;#x27;s hosted co-signertechnology, creating a dual-layered security shield for institutional users.This integration provides an innovative pre-transaction simulation andvalidation layer, making sure every transaction is vetted for risks beforereaching the blockchain. The technology aligns seamlessly with Fireblockswallet infrastructure, extending security to a global user base and helpinginstitutions avoid fraudulent transactions without added complexity​​.Rebuilding Trust in Web3 TransactionsAdam Healy, CEO of Station70, emphasizedthe importance of this partnership for the security ecosystem: “By combiningCyvers&amp;#x27; threat intelligence with our co-signer technology, we provideinstitutions with a streamlined path to advanced transaction security.” Thisstatement is echoed by Cyvers&amp;#x27; CEO, Deddy Lavid, who describes thecollaboration as a transformative approach to Web3 security, addressingcritical security gaps in wallet access and signing processes.Why Secure Signer Is a Game-ChangerCounterparty risk remains a top concernamong institutional investors and risk managers. Following the custody failuresin recent years, firms have more and more been moving operations toself-custody services such as Fireblocks. While this approach is centered moreon the fundamentals of cryptocurrencies in general and gives the institutionsmore control of their assets, it creates centralization and “black box” risk.This risk can only be addressed by Secure Signer. Secure Signer’s -as-a-servicemodel removes the “black box” of MPC wallet services and does so withoutinstitutions having to staff dedicated engineering teams responsible forrunning co-signer services.  With Secure Signer, Cyvers and Station70are setting a new standard for transaction security, empowering institutionswith proactive solutions to safeguard their assets in an increasingly volatiledigital landscape. ‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/636a75aa90ee580b0a16bbbb/673c59ac92b750039e93a658_Partnership.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How Relm Insurance Found the Ideal Web3 Security Partner in CyVers | Cyvers.ai</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>urn:sha1:635f2290c166d48bea49f0097905d3b2acc4a10c</id>
    <content type="html">In the rapidly evolving world of Web3, where digital assets and blockchain technology are becoming increasingly integral to global commerce, the need for robust security solutions is more critical than ever. Recognizing this, Relm Insurance, a leader in innovative insurance solutions, sought a partner who could offer advanced, real-time security capabilities to protect their clients from the sophisticated cyber threats endemic to the Web3 ecosystem. This search led them to CyVers, a company whose cutting-edge technology and seamless integration made them the perfect match for Relm&amp;#x27;s VistaWEB3 crime insurance product. Together, we are setting a new standard in digital asset protection.‍About Relm InsuranceRelm Insurance has built a reputation as a global leader in providing commercial insurance solutions for some of the most forward-thinking industries, including digital assets and Web3, AI, biotech, and the space economy. With a Financial Stability Rating of A from Demotech, Relm is trusted by companies pushing the boundaries of innovation for its reliability and deep industry expertise.‍The Need for Real-Time SecurityIn the digital age, the risk of cyber threats has never been higher. For companies dealing with digital assets, threats such as suspicious funding activities, malicious contract deployments, smart contract vulnerabilities, flash loan attacks, and private key leakages pose significant risks. To mitigate these threats, Relm Insurance sought a partner capable of providing real-time, advanced solutions to secure their clients&amp;#x27; digital assets.‍Why CyVers?Market-Leading TechnologyCyVers stands out for its post-deployment monitoring of smart contracts, utilizing advanced algorithms that detect and prevent security issues in real-time, both on-chain and off-chain. This capability is crucial for maintaining the integrity and security of digital assets.‍Perfect Fit for VistaWEB3CyVers’ VigiLens platform integrates seamlessly with Relm’s VistaWEB3 product, providing enhanced digital asset protection and reducing risk profiles for clients. This synergy ensures that clients benefit from the most comprehensive security measures available.‍Proactive Threat PreventionBeyond simple monitoring, CyVers excels in proactive threat prevention, identifying threats and triggering response playbooks to provide robust defence against sophisticated cyber-attacks. This proactive approach is a game-changer in the Web3 insurance landscape.‍Custom SolutionsCyVers&amp;#x27; commitment to client satisfaction is evident in its ability to develop custom solutions swiftly. For example, we recently added a bulk address upload feature to accommodate the complex needs of Relm&amp;#x27;s clients. This adaptability and responsiveness make CyVers an outstanding partner for Relm.‍The Impact on Relm’s ClientsRelm’s partnership with CyVers delivers tangible benefits for its clients, including reduced risk profiles and potentially lower premium costs. The enhanced security measures have been well-received, with clients expressing peace of mind and increased confidence in their digital asset protection.‍Testimonial from Relm&amp;quot;Securing access to real-time wallet and smart contract monitoring, among other threats, creates a tangible value add for our partners and ultimately lowers the insured&amp;#x27;s risk profile,&amp;quot; said Christian Davies, Global Head of Distribution and Innovation at Relm. &amp;quot;By melding VistaWEB3, our market-leading crime insurance product, with Cyvers&amp;#x27; best-in-breed technology, we continue to deliver best-in-class products for our Web3 clients.&amp;quot;‍ConclusionRelm Insurance’s strategic partnership with CyVers is more than just a collaboration; it’s a significant advancement in the protection of digital assets within the Web3 space. By combining their strengths, Relm and CyVers are not only enhancing client security but also setting a new benchmark for proactive threat detection and prevention in the industry.For more information, visit Cyvers.ai and RelmInsurance.com</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/636a75aa90ee580b0a16bbbb/66c49554636e759a0390c122_5341453902240932411.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">UwU Lend $23M Exploit: Oracle Vulnerabilities Exposed | Cyvers.ai</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>urn:sha1:c32eaea7ce3074533dffedcae96e2f9115a9c487</id>
    <content type="html">On June 10, 2024, UwU Lend, a non-custodial liquidity market protocol, fell victim to a sophisticated multi-transaction exploit on the Ethereum mainnet, resulting in a staggering $23 million loss.The root cause? A vulnerability in the protocol&amp;#x27;s price oracle system, which relied on the median of 11 price sources, five of which could be manipulated using Curve Finance pools, we take immense pride in the fact that Cyvers&amp;#x27; state-of-the-art Security Operations Centre (SOC) was the first to detect the UwU Lend exploit in real-time. Our vigilant threat monitoring systems raised the alarm bells when the stolen amount was a mere $14 million, prompting our team to swiftly disclose the ongoing attack to the wider Web3 community. This proactive approach not only garnered recognition for our early detection capabilities but also played a crucial role in mitigating the risk of additional losses for investors and stakeholders in the UwU Lend protocol.https://x.com/Cyvers_/status/1802674928950432097‍Let’s understand the attacker’s strategyThe attacker&amp;#x27;s strategy was very clever. They initiated by taking a massive $3.796 billion flash loan from various DeFi protocols, one of the largest ever borrowed for a single trade. Roughly half of these borrowed assets were used to create a leveraged position with substantial sUSDE debt.https://x.com/CyversAlerts/status/1800139071857316328The remaining assets were then strategically deployed to manipulate the price of sUSDE across the five vulnerable price sources on UwU Lend&amp;#x27;s oracle, artificially inflating its value. This rendered the attacker&amp;#x27;s leveraged position insolvent, triggering liquidations. Through calculated manoeuvres, the exploiter repeatedly liquidated their position, acquiring significant amounts of uWETH. Finally, they reversed the manipulated asset prices, repaid the flash loan, and secured their ill-gotten profits.‍The Aftermath and Cyvers&amp;#x27; Early DetectionThe stolen funds encompassed assets like USDT, FRAX, bLUSD, and DAI, totaling over $23 million. The attacker swiftly converted these to ETH and distributed them across two addresses under their control.Notably, we at Cyvers, a leading provider of Web3 real-time security solutions, were the first to detect and responsibly disclose the ongoing exploit to the wider community when the stolen amount was $14 million, garnering praise for their early detection capabilities.In the wake of the attack, the UwU Lend team acknowledged the exploit and paused the protocol. However, the attacker struck again three days later, exploiting the remaining vulnerabilities and syphoning an additional $3.72 million.https://x.com/CyversAlerts/status/1801160124033093748‍Lessons Learned and Preventive MeasuresThe UwU Lend exploit underscores the criticality of robust Oracle security in DeFi. While using multiple price feeds appeared robust, the lack of liquidity and price smoothing in half of these feeds proved exploitable.Furthermore, implementing monitoring systems that trigger alerts or enforce limits on unusually large transactions or flash loans could provide an additional layer of security.‍ConclusionThe UwU Lend exploit serves as a stark reminder that in the DeFi landscape, innovation must go hand in hand with an unwavering commitment to security. As the ecosystem continues to evolve, robust Oracle implementations, comprehensive auditing, and proactive monitoring will be paramount to safeguarding user funds and fostering trust.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/636a75aa90ee580b0a16bbbb/667c1b220303441d6cd497c7_Picture200.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
