<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by DEXTools on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@dextools?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdextools.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*loY0qZhyg6gdUogKj9HhOg.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*loY0qZhyg6gdUogKj9HhOg.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdextools.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:14+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The biggest Token Burn in the History of DEXTools (by now)</title>
    <published>2023-03-10T14:13:12+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-10T14:13:12+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/the-biggest-token-burn-in-the-history-of-dextools-by-now-ef109516020b?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/the-biggest-token-burn-in-the-history-of-dextools-by-now-ef109516020b?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are very proud to announce that DEXTools just burned 3M token more (3% of our circulating supply) thanks to our great tokenomics and we are celebrating it with a gift to our community, the Burn DashboardThe deflationary modelThe utility token of our platform, $DEXT, has been described by many as one of the most deflationary and sustainable tokens in the Defi market (here and there). But how come?This is 100% due to the continuous buybacks and burns made possible by the on-platform aggregator and the updated social fee services.Given that the day-to-day operations are already funded by advertising and other activities, we decided to dedicate most of the other revenues to $DEXT token.More precisely:100% of the aggregator fees in any chain will be used to buyback and burn $DEXT.100% of the update social fees paid in $DEXT (around 40% of the grand total) will be burnt.For a more detailed overview you can check this analysis made by our friends of Blockchain Army.The Burn DASHBOARDOur community asked for it, and we delivered.We are proud to announce that the Burn Dashboard is officially live thanks to our partner Blockchain Army too.Starting today, you won’t need to scan dozens of different pages anymore to check Dextools revenues and burns — you’ll just need to open burn.dextools.io.But let’s get into the details.By giving a quick look at the dashboard you’ll immediately notice why $DEXT has one of the strongest tokenomics out there.Let’s describe the metrics line by line.In the first row, you have two graphs:The first one indicates the speed at which $DEXT is reducing supply, showing how the burn is performing over time.The second one shows the supply shrinkage: just in the last 30 days the circulating supply reduced by 102.2m to 101.5m!In the second row, you have three panels showing in detail how much $DEXT has been burnt in the last day, week, and month, in the amount of $DEXT, percentage of supply, and estimated percentage of supply burnt per year.The estimations range from 7.72% to 18.21% per year!The third shows further information about $DEXT token, statistics, and projections. In particular, you can find:The number of unique token holders and last 24h growth (around 14.8k!)The price in $DEXT to update the social network in the Dextools platform, and the discount with respect to the $ETH priceThe total $DEXT burnt — and the estimated annual burn based on last month’s burnThe estimation of buy pressure and resultant price if the burn continues at the last month’s speedThe last row, instead, gives a complete panoramic of the aggregator and social fee wallets, showing their change in the last 24h and how much eth/bnb/dext they hold.ConclusionsThe Burn Dashboard is a powerful tool, that allows our holders to be informed day by day on how Dextools burns are performing.This is just one of the numerous news that Dextools has planned for 2023.We’ll keep you posted on our official channels!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">DEXTools x KLON AMA RECAP</title>
    <published>2022-12-21T20:21:41+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-12-21T20:21:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/dextools-x-klon-ama-recap-a5b53beaf615?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/dextools-x-klon-ama-recap-a5b53beaf615?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We were honored to host an AMA with KLON on December 16th in the DEXTools community telegram! It was jam packed with info and we were impressed with the progress and the honesty and integrity Philipp, CEO of KLON conveyed! We summarized the amazing conversation below and also rewarded $20 to 4 people who had the best questions at the end!Below is the conversation between Wael Rajab from DEXT Force Ventures (DFV) and Philipp, CEO of KLON.DFV: Hey DEXTools and the KLON community we have a huge AMA today. Joining us is Philipp, CEO of KLON! Can you please introduce yourself and your background?Philipp: Glad to be here and thanks for having me let’s get it on. I have more than 20 years of experience in advertising and marketing. I have operated an independent media agency and I founded an advertising technology company with combined more than 100 employees and a yearly ad-spend of more than 250m dollars. We have used data driven attribution models to get campaign data which reflects the best possible impact of different channels on the total ROI and we were specialists in programmatic advertising. I was awarded as digital agency of the year in Switzerland. After that I stepped into the blockchain game and advised international companies and celebrities regarding social tokens and NFT Projects including famous stars and brands like Post Malone, West Coast Customs and Universal Music. After that in my brain I formed a vision of KLON and my dream was to build something with a positive impact in a future world. That’s why I founded KLON. DEXTools is one of the very early supporters of KLON and I really appreciate it.DFV: Appreciate the trust in us, and we are looking forward to the long and successful partnership! So can you explain what KLON is and what you are hoping to achieve?Philipp: There’s multiple layers to dig into, but I will summarize it with four bulletsCombining Avatars with a true decentralized identity LayerMaking you a trusted (but trust-less) partner in the metaversePerfect copy of yourselfEasy access to all the metaversesThat means, we see ourselves as a combination as a provider of Identity, avatars and make it usable in a very practical way.DFV: Wow, very ambitious! Would love to see myself in the metaverse! Amazing work, I’ve seen the KLON examples on the website and I urge everybody to go take a look! Can you introduce the team and who is behind all the great work at KLON?Philipp: I think many projects in the ID space are cool. Many projects in the avatar space are cool. But not many of them find a way to combine it to a real user-beneficial and easy to use product. My team is a highly motivated and skilled small group of people I really trust. Including some of my best friends. Everyone with a specific skill set. From Branding to UX design to blockchain dev.My CTO Sandro is a long time partner of mine. He was leading the dev team in my advertising technology company and is deeply rooted in crypto and blockchain since 2015. Senior Dev Jake has worked for Unreal Engine as a Dev and also contributed important elements to Pancake Swap.The outer layer of my core team is advisory based. Here I have people who are working hard for the project regarding network, tech sustainability and implementation. And the 3rd layer of the team is completely outsourced to selected and trustful partners, who are really committed to the project on the one hand, but also have the flexibility to scale up the workforce fast if needed and scale down if needed as-well. This keeps this project fast and flexible and ensures the financial health by not having too much overhead. Especially in these times I’m so happy to have chosen this kind of setup.DFV: Sounds like you got a tight ship and crew! Love to see that, as you mentioned KLON brings out our personal representation in the virtual space. Some folks in the crypto scene want to enter the metaverse as an anonymous character, potentially to keep their identity safe or to simply live a new identity, does KLON accommodate this?Philipp: KLON will become an open platform and the beauty of Web3 is that you can combine anonymity with trust. This means that as a user you will be able to use dozens of avatars. Those from KLON, but also others. Ready Player me, Adidas or Nike avatars. The important thing is that you can use the KLON ID to verify all your avatars and appear as a trustworthy partner. So if you want to be a dragon. Be a dragon =) but think of KLON as the umbrella and I guess if you want to have a virtual meeting with your boss… you could choose your high end 3D KLON and not the dragon =)DFV: Makes sense, so you can switch from avatar to avatar and I saw you can hop from metaverse to metaverse. What metaverses have KLON collaborated with so far? Do you guys plan to release your stand-alone metaverse or is the goal to have KLON integrated in the most popular platforms?Philipp: Yes! Definitely, we will not launch our own Metaverse project. We are focusing on users being able to move around the metaverse and on users actually being able to do useful things with their KLON identity. We see ourselves as an enabler, for both the users and the metaverses. To underline this: it will be possible that you can equip your avatar with university certificates, further education certificates, credit rating information. which is beyond the game-like use-cases we see now.We have many partners in the background, we work with the guys from Bloktopia, Netvrk, Metaarrow, Metavision and many many more… But the thing is, that the focus is straight to the use-cases for the users from day one. Independent from all the existing metaverse projects.DFV: Awesome! What network is KLON being launched on as the goal is for everybody at some point to have their own KLON, it would need to be affordable and will it be multi-chain?Philipp: Our home chain will be Polygon, but we will be multi chain from the beginning. The most important thing is security in this game, and we have developed a great way to bridge between the chains without being too vulnerable regarding attacks to the centralized elements of traditional bridging. But still, this needs a lot of eyeballs and effort.DFV: Definitely, you guys are taking on a lot! Will you be able to transfer your KLON or sell the KLON? Have you ever thought about somebody selling their identity and that being used for either good or bad?Philipp: No, that will not be possible. One KLON identity per person. Not transferable. Otherwise our use-case is not given. Of course, every single scam you can think of has been done. but to unlock the full potential of a KLON you need to verify your identity and your liveness. Otherwise it wont work.DFV: Great, can you go into some of the added utility for KLON holders and what incentives they may see for holding the token when released?Philipp: Regarding the token utility, KLON will be used as transaction currency. You will need to stake KLON tokens to actually use the product. You can buy and sell items on our marketplace and buy premium features with KLON tokens. Interesting is that we are building on a lot of B2B partnerships and we will use KLON also for these partnerships. A part of this is used for deflationary mechanisms in the eco. We will release more utilities with the release of versions and lastly governance features will follow further down the timeline.DFV: Looking forward to it, a ton of utility off the bat as well! I saw that KLON reinvests 49% of all assets directly into KLON’s associated Metaverse projects. Can you go into more detail of what the funds are being allocated towards (Land, NFTs, Coins, ect)?Philipp: That’s a great question and I’d have answered this question a little different half a year ago. But let’s get it on: We talk about a more or less traditional structured product that minimizes investment risks for users and is managed via algorithms.This means that based on various qualitative and quantitative signals, the share of a certain coin in the portfolio is increased or decreased. The FTX case has shown us, however, that we have to be extremely careful and have an absolutely integrity based system that is as safe in bear market situations as it is in bull market times. We can’t afford to play ever At the same time, on the legal side, we have to be absolutely perfect in many markets. We have a very good concept, but we will only launch this part of the product when we have clearly assessable signals with regard to regulation, auditing, etc.We don’t want to take a risk on a “nice to have” part of the product — and that’s this feature — that we can’t assess. So, don’t expect this feature to be launched in 2023. but in 24… I’m really confident!DFV: Rebalancing is important, and I love that you are very serious about minimizing huge risks and keeping it on the safe side. Makes total sense, you wouldn’t want to rush this! I believe this is going to be huge!!Now a question you probably get asked everyday! Do you guys have a TGE date in mind?Philipp: I love the question =) Look at the markets. We are almost ready to launch the MVP. But in these markets. No way a launch will be successful. We’re financially stable and have enough runtime to wait until markets turn green. That’s what I said in the beginning. I’m happy that we did not blow money in the first half of the year. So we are safe, and have at least 18 months of dev time And that’s what we have agreed on with all our investors and partners… if possible Q1 2023.DFV: Im a huge believer! Very impressed with everything so far!We talked about market conditions right now, so how does KLON plan to stay ahead of the competition with the excessive launch of Metaverse/NFT related projects and being in a bear market?Philipp: I hope my opinion is not unpopular, but let’s get it on. What’s happening in the market is a clearing of the land and, from my perspective, a long overdue correction. It cannot be that projects that really just suck, allocate so much money and rip off the next ponzi scheme. I think we have all seen that enough. And quite honestly, I’m happy about the current situation. It gives us, as a serious project, time to develop a serious product that is also effectively useful and solves a problem. And it takes attention away from crap projects and makes it harder for scammers to get money. So we’ll see how it goes, but I think the time for scam projects is running out.As far as KLON is concerned, I can only say that we are very careful with our investor’s money and have our burn rate under control, so that we have enough runtime to develop and then launch when everyone is a bit happier again.DFV: Agreed, I believe only strong projects and teams build out in these market times. Most scams/ponzis don’t survive markets like this.I definitely learned a lot here, and I think everybody watching did as well. I have to ask for everybody watching that wants to get involved with KLON, can they still support the project, are there more IDO opportunities?Philipp: Here I have to refer to our other very esteemed partners like Enjinstarter, Blokpad etc. You can participate through them. We have become very conservative in our launchpad strategy, because currently even the big players in the industry cannot keep their commitments. That’s why we don’t intend to expose ourselves more. But you’ll be the first community that gets informed about updates regarding the IDODFV: Awesome, our community would love that! Sounds like you guys are committed to only working with loyal and trustworthy companies instead of anybody who wants to just give you money! I like the integrityYou have answered everything amazingly today and I’ve sincerely enjoyed this AMA. I have to ask what you think about DEXTools? And the future of DeFi?Philipp: I can’t say too much about this without drifting into philosophy. What I do know is that DEXTools has been an honest, loyal and truly serious partner of KLON from the very beginning. and I really mean it. I can only speak highly of DEXTools. From the very first call with Tom, I had a very good feeling, and I am proud to have such a competent partner on board.Regarding DeFi? I am a romantic and believe in great potential. Overall, DeFi has the potential to significantly improve financial inclusion and bring financial services to people in unbanked countries who may not have access to these services through traditional means and I think ultimately this case will bring DeFi the success it deserves.DFV: I truly believe so as well, coming from an unbanked country my self. I understand the mission and it will succeed! Could have not answered it any better myself That was an exciting and info packed AMA! Let’s check in with the community and see if they have any questions!?The community had tons of questions for KLON, they seemed to love the product and we had a huge inflow of messages, support, and questions! Below are the 5 questions that qualified and each user won $20 for asking! Make sure to join us on our next AMA! Community questions below!@Sojib00038: So many projects just like to speak about the “long term vision and mission” but what are your short term objectives? What are you focusing on right now?Philipp: The short term objective is, that our MVP, which will be available when we launch the token, brings an immediate use-case for an everyday user. That’s the goal, I don’t say by now, what exactly, but we want to generate the feeling, that you really are missing something if you don’t make your own KLON@Julius_guerrero_92: We do understand that increasing your KLON-Score unleashes your KLON’s full potential. Can you enlighten us on what some of these potentials are?Philipp: The KLON Score is a way to have exclusive access and premium features and so on, thousands of options. If you have a great KLON score, you may get front row seats on a virtual fashion show, or you are capable of attending a specific event or you can enter rooms that are not available for people with a lower score!@Railgun10032: How will KLON bridge the gap which users from web2 experience when they transition to web3 world? How will you explain Decentralized Identification to web2 users?Philipp: The avatar design is not the key, the ID is the key, and you are only verified. If you are verified as a person.@PepayaCC: How are avatars in the metaverse being used for identity, business or marketing purposes, and what are some examples of innovative or successful applications of this technology?Philipp: Think of this: you deal everyday with AIs of companies, chatbots and so on. It’s time to scale yourself, right? Your KLON will be the scalable version of you. You will be able to let your KLON make the first 1000 job interviews and this is the future of a scalable me.About KLONKlon.ai makes lifelike avatars called KLONs so users can access the metaverse. Using several chains, KLON securely joins various metaverses. By enabling users to switch between metaverses with a single click, it consequently offers a seamless metaverse experience.https://www.klon.ai/https://www.dextools.io/app/https://dextforce.net/</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">DEXTools 2022 RECAP</title>
    <published>2022-11-24T11:01:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-11-24T11:01:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/dextools-2022-recap-1dca684cc14b?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/dextools-2022-recap-1dca684cc14b?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hello DEXTools Community!Since DEXTools was launched as a public beta in June 2020, as a test, but also ambitious and exciting project, it was immediately confirmed as the leading DeFi platform for trading analytics worldwide, with a vertiginous growth since its origin, and becoming exponential during this year 2022.Both the large number of different blockchains visible and easily accessible through the application’s own Pair Explorer (there are already more than 60 chains, and growing), and the huge number of traders who benefit from its wide and useful range of information and trading tools from anywhere on the planet (the record is 50 million users per month), have skyrocketed.Its functionality has also been expanded and enhanced, with constant technical improvements on the app in order to make it more versatile to meet the demands of a growing and more complex saturated crypto market, but also with the intention of adapting it to the requirements and direct needs of a growing community of loyal users, who, from the very beginning, have been and are the main support and the greatest asset of DEXTools.The already well-cohesive DEXTools team also forms a close-knit group with those who enjoy the app and because of that, this contributes to its improvement: alerting of technical bugs and suggesting useful changes in the usability of the platform, especially through the DEXT Force and main Telegram channels, which are always very active, such feedback explains part of DEXTools’ resounding success, no doubt. But there is much more, actually….Security, power, versatility, innovation and trust are the key words here. Pool Explorer, Pair Explorer, Big Swap Explorer, Multiswap and Wallet Info are the main and powerful tools. From the DEXTools app, and both in its desktop and mobile version (Android &amp;amp; IOS), you can check live token prices, follow market movements, track favorite pairs and set useful alarms. The users have plenty of helpful resources at their disposal, such as a useful price and alerts bot and also DEXTscore for the different tokens, which gives the user an idea about their reliability as a guideline to prevent scams. In fact, security is a vital factor for DEXTools, both for the app itself and for those who benefit daily from its use, either for free or through the holding of $DEXT token, that extends the advantages.This year 2022, as we say, has meant a huge boom for DEXTools, and this despite the obvious current crisis affecting the entire crypto world, in the midst of the bear market. This is parallel to the general crisis of fiat money and the stock market, to which the crypto ecosystem itself is no stranger, as it has suffered it on the rebound. Bad credit tokens have fallen, but also other theoretically stable such as UST from Terra/Luna, even leading companies like FTX or BlockFi have also been affected (sometimes because its bad practices) . For its part, the DEXTools native token ($DEXT) has weathered the storm well with some rises even, such as the most recent one in November. At the beginning of the Project 200 million $DEXT tokens were created, after burning 50 Million from the team, our deflationary system mechanism with a monthly burn by the team it’s working better than ever so its current circulation is lowering everyday.Despite the inevitable ups and downs of the market in 2022, DEXTools has continued its investment projects through its satellite platform Dext Force Ventures. It has also emphasized its educational and informative work through DEXTools Academy on YouTube. It has participated in public talks and live conferences, but also in various online meetings to raise awareness of the platform and establish ties with the most important players in the crypto ecosystem. In addition, and with an eye on the future, DEXTools has also been involved in broadening the range of its strategic presence in the metaverse, by partnering with ambitious projects such as Outer Ring, a promising Spanish play-to-earn.Below, we add a basic chronology with some of the innovations in DEXTools, always in a process of growth and improvement. Briefly, without much emphasis on detailing the multitude of new chains, whose work we will deal with in future articles.2022 MilestonesAs always, if you want to connect with us, our public group at Telegram is the best choice: https://t.me/DEXToolsCommunityThank you!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">1ST DEXTools Token Burn from aggregator Fees</title>
    <published>2021-12-06T21:30:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-06T21:30:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/1st-dextools-token-burn-from-aggregator-fees-edb936e545ad?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/1st-dextools-token-burn-from-aggregator-fees-edb936e545ad?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hi DEXTools Community, As we shared in a previous medium article, we decided to remove DEXTShare and move to a burn-it-all model, where we don’t increase the circulating supply sharing team’s tokens, and also we use the profit generated by our aggregator buying tokens from the market and burning it.The D day has arrivedWe are proud to share that the initiative was far more successful than expected, this month we bought more than 900k DEXT into the markets at Uniswap and Pancakeswap, and also we received more than 200k DEXT from subscriptions to the app. OOur growth was especially big on the BSC side where the fees are lower and the performance of the aggregator is much better. The expectations for the next months are to continue growing and increasing at least to 2x of the current income, as the trading volume of DEFI keeps growing.The BurnWe burned 900k DEXT tokens in 2 transactions, reducing our total supply in that amount.TX1 &amp;amp; TX2We expect to exceed our expectation of burning 5M per year in the next 6 months.Aggregator fees revenue based on number of TXAdding Liquidity to Pancakeswap PoolWe have the main part of our liquidity at Uniswap at this moment, with a pool of over 6M liquidity. DEXToolsAs we shared also in the previous medium we reserved part of the funds bought and received in subs to increase liquidity in Pancakeswap, a thing that was already done. We added 150BNB + 172k DEXT to the pool, almost doubling our current liquidity. DEXtoolsCommunity Rewards and AdminsThe rest of the remaining DEXT Tokens will be saved into the DEXT Force Community Chest and used for Contests or future rewards, also to reward people in the community that helps and supports the DEXTools growth.This is all by now. See you at our Telegram group for any questions or feedback: https://t.me/DEXToolsCommunityEnjoy Trading!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">DEXTSHARE UPDATE</title>
    <published>2021-11-06T17:30:59+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-06T17:30:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/dextshare-update-6c2a2b87c73b?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/dextshare-update-6c2a2b87c73b?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">BURN IT ALL EDITIONOver the past year, DEXTShare has been our way of rewarding our community and the people who believed in us from the beginning. As you already know, 12 million DEXT tokens have been shared from the team itself as well as 90% of all subscriptions to the application. This has generated for the Premium holders more than 5M dollars in monthly airdrops.This initiative has proved to be very successful and has ensured the creation of a very expert and cohesive community of traders and followers, for this, the DEXTools team would like to thank you.However, there have also been disadvantages:During the last 12 months 1M more tokens have been added to the market each month. This has generated an inflation of around 15% over the total supply, but taking into account that the main pool of DEXT in Uniswap has around 6M DEXT currently, releasing more than 12M has caused a huge damage to the price of the token in this past year.Although it has grown in an optimal way due to the great success of the app, from the team we believe that it has been a much more limited growth than it could have been given our volume and constant buying pressure, we can easily check that DEXT vs ETH price remained constant in the last year.DEXT Pool Beginning of DEXTShare vs NowIt is estimated that at least 60% of the tokens distributed in DEXTShare are sold to the market. This results in significant monthly sell pressure.More barriers to the current Model :In the Premium community, it was decided a few months ago to incentivize token holding, reducing the Standard Tier to 1000 DEXT, which has brought greater price stability and a significant increase in holders, but has largely dismantled the forecasts for DEXTShare that had been made following the subscription pattern.The model has continued to work due to the team’s incentives, but this has ended and DEXTShare will be reduced by almost 90% if this initiative continues.The estimate is less than 100 usd per month per 100,000 DEXT, despite the record number of subscriptions this October 2021.Therefore, the DEXTools team, after checking and evaluating all the options, has decided to pause DEXTShare indefinitely in favor of other options proposed by the community, with burn as the main option.WHAT’S NEXT?Aggregator Fees:The part you’ve all been waiting for.The DEXTools aggregator launched just over 3 months ago has been a complete success, generating more than 500k usd in fees and with an amazing growth in the last month, especially in the BSC part due to its low network fees. We expect to continue this growth in the coming months, with forecasts to generate at least 1M per month.The amounts are flexible due to the fact that most of the commissions are received in tokens and can vary greatly in price from one moment to another. We will be converting to ETH, BNB or stablecoins as far as possible.As you know we have always taken into account the benefits for our community, so we have decided that 100% of the aggregator’s profits will be used to buy and burn DEXT. The DEXT received through the aggregator as fees will also be burned.This will, we hope, greatly increase the burning rate of DEXT and its 100% deflationary character. Not only do we not increase inflation with that 1M from the DEXTShare but we buy into the market and burn everything received.Our goal is to try to burn at least 5M DEXT in the first year, out of a pool of 6M and continue to incentivize our holder community to ensure price stability. Token purchases will be random during the month, trying to maximize the benefits for the community (e.g. after a big sale) and to avoid gaming.Note: The first month the aggregator commissions from the BSC side will be used in part to add liquidity and not just buy. Because the DEXT traffic in BSC is growing a lot, we find it necessary to increase the liquidity in PancakeSwap to ensure that our BSC holders also have enough liquidity to buy and sell DEXT comfortably with low commissions.DEXT Force VenturesThe jewel in the crown, the Ventures model with our DEXT Force Ventures has turned out to be much more successful than expected at the beginning and has generated much more profit for our Premium Holders in just one month than the DEXTShare has in the entire past year.Therefore we are going to incentivize, expand and put all our effort in the ventures that will be the core of the DEXT Force Premium, something we have already been doing in the past month, as you have already seen with star launches such as Dreamsquest, Decentraweb or Kusamastarter.Ultimately our goal is to have our own Launchpad under the DEXT ecosystem. Something we hope to accomplish during the next year.Special thanks to all Committee members that work hard to make this possible.Fees from app subscriptions:Even despite incentivizing the holding, there will be a remaining of DEXT fees from monthly app subscriptions. We have decided that for now a portion will be used to incentivize people who support DEXTools , including telegram admins and people who we feel deserve it for their contributions to the community.The rest will be kept in a Community Chest and used in incentives for the community, such as contests, marketing, staking etc, for which the opinion and proposals of the DEXT Force itself will be taken into account. Ultimately it could also be burned if no agreement is reached.The amounts that are being considered are 20% for supporters and 80% for the community chest. But this could change depending on the number of subscriptions.For all this, DEXTools will continue to receive no profit from the DEXT token, and will continue to be financed by the ads in the app, giving all the token benefits to the community.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">DEXT Force is NOW OPEN</title>
    <published>2021-11-04T18:32:04+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T18:32:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/dext-force-is-now-open-a6dc966966b5?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/dext-force-is-now-open-a6dc966966b5?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">For all Standard HoldersFor those that still don’t know DEXT Force, you can read our foundational medium hereSince last year our goal was to create a strong community of traders and investors who benefit from our application and help each other and DEXTools to support our ecosystem.This initiative was successful and our premium group was the core of our community for many months, but as the market is growing and also our traffic, we feel it’s the moment to increase our reach.DEXT Force Community UpdateTo continue our growth and support our community as a family of traders within the DEXTools ecosystem, we are opening the DEXT Force to all holders of 1000 DEXT, the Standard Tier.This is nominative only and does not include any of the current DEXT Force Ventures benefits.We are going to a transition and we created a community on Discord for the whole DEXT Force that is more manageable and easy to follow due to its system that allows us to create different channels, roles, pin info (so you don’t miss the latest announcements) and many other things.100k Tier now is called DEXT Force Premium.300k Tier remains as DEXT Force Stealth.ALL DEXT Force Premium current benefits remain exclusive but we will create new incentives for our Standard community in which the Premium will also be able to participate.What to do nowIf you are a Standard holder with at least 1000 DEXT tokens, you can join our new community in the following link:Join the DEXT Force HQ Discord Server!IMPORTANT STEPSAfter you click the Discord join link you need to verify being a human by clicking the button “Prove human” within 60 seconds. After this, you will see the main rules. If you agree with the rules you can type in the “Welcome” channel.Type the command “/provewallet” and you will get a DM from the DEXT Force HQ bot to prove the wallet. You can choose the network and get a link where you can connect your wallet (best to connect with MetaMask).When you have enough DEXT in this wallet you will get a DM from the bot again and you get access to the channels you have rights to, depending on the amount of DEXT you have.Attention: if you connect your wallet on mobile please use the build-in browser (dapp browser) of the wallet app.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing the DEXTools telegram price bot</title>
    <published>2021-08-12T19:51:48+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T19:51:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/introducing-the-dextools-telegram-price-bot-21fdae07bb78?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/introducing-the-dextools-telegram-price-bot-21fdae07bb78?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Today we are pleased to introduce a new tool that you have been asking us for a long time during the last weeks, the price bot for telegram.After receiving a lot of your comments and feedback about bots like uncbot or the poo price bot, we have decided to launch our version, with it, all projects and groups will be able to install the bot and have instant information about prices, liquidity and the chart of your token. It also includes the DEXTools link to the pair.The steps are very simple, you just have to send a message to our bot @DexTools_Pricebot at Telegram and start it by typing /start.It will show you the steps to follow to set it up that are:1- Please add the bot @DexTools_Pricebot as admin to the desired Telegram group/supergroup/channel (for the best experience give the bot the right to delete messages to delete the /price message after sending the chart). Then go to the Telegram channel (you must be an admin) and register the token with /set_pair.2- After /set_pair you first specify the chart number and then you specify the AMM network (ethereum / bsc / polygon) and the pair contract.Example:/set_pair 1 ethereum 0xa29fe6ef9592b5d408cca961d0fb9b1faf497d6dA maximum of 4 chart numbers is allowed3- (Optional) You can also set the desired chart type by typing the following syntax: /set_chart &amp;lt;chart number&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chart type&amp;gt;Chart types: line / ha (Heikin Ashi)Example:/set_chart 1 ha4- (Optional) You can also set the desired chart cool-down period (time before a new chart request can be done) by typing the following syntax: /set_cooldown &amp;lt;chart number&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cooldown minutes&amp;gt;The cool-down period is in minutes, the minimum is 3Example:/set_cooldown 1 55- (Optional) You can also delete a chart using the command:/delete_pair &amp;lt;chart_num&amp;gt;Example: /delete_pair 16-(Optional) You can set an custom button description for the charts by typing the following syntax: /set_chartname &amp;lt;chart number&amp;gt; &amp;lt;button name&amp;gt;The button name has a max length of 80 charactersExample:/set_chartname 1 DEXT/WETH uniV2Members in this Telegram channel can request the price by sending:/price &amp;lt;chart number&amp;gt;.If now a chart number is given and multiple charts are defined a button choose list will show. You can find all pair addresses on the Dextools app (https://dextools.io/app).As always for any feedback or questions, you can reach us at the DEXTools official telegram group: https://t.me/DEXToolsCommunity</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Tiers update and listing of DEXT at BSC Network.</title>
    <published>2021-06-09T23:02:17+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T23:02:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/tiers-update-and-listing-of-dext-at-bsc-network-af36285b8adb?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/tiers-update-and-listing-of-dext-at-bsc-network-af36285b8adb?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hello community! we hope you are enjoying trading, today we bring you a great update on the operation of the platform with many good news:1- DEXTools Listing at PancakeSwapAs many of you expected DEXTools has just been officially listed on Pancakeswap. This opens the door to other markets and makes it much easier for traders on the Binance network to use the advanced features of our platform.Our BSC Smart contract is :0xe91a8d2c584ca93c7405f15c22cdfe53c29896e3IMPORTANT: make sure you double-check before buying, as with every project, there may be fake ones.You can find here the official DEXT Pair at Pancake hereINFO: If you are already a DEXT holder from ETH network, you can very easily convert your erc20 tokens to bep20 using ANYSWAP Bridge, the process is very simple and only takes a couple of minutes depending on the network speed.https://anyswap.exchange/bridge2-Accepting subscriptions and holding for Standard Tier in DEXT BEP-20 (Binance Smart Chain).Now you can access all the advanced features of DEXTools with the tokens you buy on Pancake, the procedure for paying the monthly subscription is the same as on the ETH network, and the holding is much simpler, just buy, hold and connect your wallet to DEXTools to enjoy the STANDARD TIER.3- Reducing the Standard TIER of holding from 20,000 to 1000 DEXT.This is one of the most important things that we are going to bring out regarding user management and that has been widely requested by our community.After seeing our incredible growth in users last month, we want to make the standard tier accessible to all people who wish to access it by purchasing our token, making the Standard Tier accessible by holding only 1000 DEXT, we offer all investors the opportunity to be part of our DEXT family and accessing all the features that DEXTools have to improve your day trading just holding our token.So from now:STANDARD TIER: Hold 1000 DEXT or pay 100 USD of monthly sub in DEXT (BSC or ETH network)PREMIUM TIER: Hold 100,000 DEXT ( to receive all benefits only DEXT ERC20 by now)And that’s all for today. As always, thank you very much for your support and remember you can reach us in our Telegram group for support or any questions or doubts.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">CTDSEC, The New DEXTools Ally Against Scams.</title>
    <published>2021-06-04T11:38:18+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-04T11:38:18+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/ctdsec-the-new-dextools-ally-against-scams-12336d7fffbc?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/ctdsec-the-new-dextools-ally-against-scams-12336d7fffbc?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">As many of you know, DEX are full of scams, most of them very low effort ones and based on tricking people by including malicious features in the contract, not being able to sell, being able to mint infinite tokens, are some of the most common and we can see dozens of projects using them trying to abuse uneducated or new investors. DEXTools’ battle against scams has been continuous since our birth, we have always tried to provide as much information as we can to our community and to all investors who bet on the future of DEFI to try to avoid them.Fortunately, apart from our community, we have had many allies along the way, projects that are also based on trying to help people avoid scams, some of them have fallen, but today we are stronger because we have found a new one, CTDSEC.WHAT IS CTDSEC?CTDSEC is a platform that provides blockchain project owners with instant access to our expert smart contract auditors and product designers, making it simple for them to verify the security and code integrity of their smart contracts and build their blockchain products.Smart contract security auditing is a thorough analysis of blockchain applications’ smart contracts in order to correct design issues, errors in the code, or security vulnerabilities.CTDSEC is one of the most well-known auditor firms in the crypto space and we are proud to partner with them.DEXTools SMART CONTRACT ANALYZERThanks to the amazing technology that CTDSEC provided to us, we were able to integrate the new DEXTools Feature, the contract analyzer, this feature is able to analyze all the contracts of the pairs listed at our supported DEX and check for the most common types of scams or malicious functions within the contract giving our users another layer of security before investing.Contract Details at Pool ExplorerYou can check all contract details on every token pair explorer page and also at the pool explorer for every new pair. If the contract is not even verified, that means the code is not public and it is usually a big red flag, you should research a lot before investing. Keep in mind that we are still analyzing all the old pairs and it may take some time to have everything.Of course, this is still the first version and it’s not infallible, many scams can rug or sell tokens even with good quality smart contracts, Check always if liquidity is locked, the DEXT Score and DYOR.For any doubts or feedback about this feature please contact us at DEXTools or CTDSEC Telegram groups.CTDSEC Links and contact:Website: https://ctdsec.com/Twitter: https://www.twitter.com/ctdsecTelegram: https://t.me/ctdsec</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Comments and tips about DEXT Score</title>
    <published>2021-05-14T09:29:20+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-14T09:29:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dextools.medium.com/comments-and-tips-about-dext-score-7f6cfd628ee2?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dextools.medium.com/comments-and-tips-about-dext-score-7f6cfd628ee2?source=rss-ff1059b78ddd------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>DEXTools</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">One of the best tools we have in DEXTools and that differentiates us from other projects is the DEXT Score, we have noticed that despite having this tool, unfortunately, many people still fall into the typical scams that we see in DEXes every day and that could be avoided in many cases with a simple review of the DEXT Score and a little research.Therefore, we would like to shed some light on HOW to use this tool to avoid most of the scams in the DEXes we have integrated at the moment, Uniswap, Sushi and Pancake.THE DEXT SCOREThe DEXT Score is an algorithm created by DEXTools that measures all the information we get from the blockchain and some external information sources to measure the confidence of a project. The score obtained ranges from 99 (Maximum) to 1 (Minimum).PERFECT DEXT SCOREThe parameters measured in the DEXT Score are among others: Social Information, Pair Liquidity, Number of Transactions, Number of Token Holders and Contract Creation.FOR TEAMS: Social information is obtained from the Etherscan and Bscscan platforms, when it’s updated there it will automatically appear in DEXTools.Description of the score ranges, (this estimate is approximate and may vary depending on the project).High DEXT Score (80 or more)These are the tokens that have a higher probability of being legitimate projects, most will have all or most of the social information in order and a good amount of the other parameters, transactions, holders and liquidity. You should be able to invest and buy and sell without a problem, however, always do your research, as the DEXT Score does not measure the quality of the project.Average DEXT Score (from 50 to 80)These are usually tokens that fail in some of the parameters described above, they may lack social information, have a low creation score or low liquidity, it is up to you to investigate why, in some cases they are new projects that have not had time to update and in others they are simply more elaborate scams.Some scams can have up to 200 ETH of liquidity, but still scams.Low DEXT Score (Less than 50)A token with a score of less than 50 is usually a new token on the market that fails in many of the parameters described above. This is where the gems and scams are usually found in equal parts, many of the projects that end up with a higher score start here. There are many opportunities in low Score, but invest only if you are willing to take a very high risk.TIP: Check always the tx history to see if there are sales, if you only see buys, it’s very likely that is a scam and you won’t be able to sell after buying.Minimum DEXT Score ( Less than 10) The projects with a score of 1, are in 99% of the cases scams, and lack all the parameters described above, usually have little or no liquidity, in many cases have already made a rug pull, and have no social information, a quality contract or transactions. Please avoid investing in this type of projects or you will lose all your money in a very high percentage of cases.Minimum ScoreTHE SCORE IS DYNAMICNow that we have described the scoring system and the main cases of scores that a project can receive, we must add the characteristic of dynamism. The Score score tends to adapt very quickly to market conditions, and in those quality projects that have all the information updated, it usually reaches a consolidated score in the first 24 hours after listing. In those cases where information is missing, it will be updated as soon as the information is available.The opposite case may also occur, projects that previously had a good score and usually due to TEAM actions (Teams selling, Rug Pulls in large projects) may lower their score, even going from 99 to 1 in case of scam. The Score cannot predict the future, that’s why it is always DYOR.After this little explanation, we hope that your trading with DEXTools will be much safer.If you have more questions or info you can reach us in our Telegram group:DEXTools CommunityThank you</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
