<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Dfns — Welcome to our blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dfns.co%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-list+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Farticle%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.blog-body&amp;content_cleanup=nav%2C.list-4&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.blog-post-author-date&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=.blog-post-author-name&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dfns.co%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-list+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Farticle%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.blog-body&amp;content_cleanup=nav%2C.list-4&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.blog-post-author-date&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=.blog-post-author-name&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Dfns Secures Series A Funding</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dfns.co/article/dfns-secures-series-a-funding</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.dfns.co/article/dfns-secures-series-a-funding"/>
    <content type="html">Dfns has closed its Series A led by Further Ventures, with support from previous backers. In this blog post, we share our thoughts on this milestone, our journey so far, and how our wallet infrastructure is helping over 130 fintechs enable secure blockchain adoption worldwide.Today, we’re delighted to announce a major milestone in the journey of Dfns:  the successful completion of our $16 million Series A funding round. Led by our new lead investor, Further Ventures, the venture capital arm backed by Abu Dhabi’s largest sovereign wealth fund, ADQ, this round also welcomed new investors, including Motive Ventures, Wintermute, and Motier Ventures (Galeries Lafayette Group), alongside existing backers like White Star Capital, Hashed, Semantic, Techstars, and others.First, we want to thank our investors for their continued trust in Dfns, our team, and our vision for the future of finance. We see this achievement as more than just securing funds; it’s a validation of our technology and the strategy we committed to amidst fast-changing, unpredictable crypto markets. The last two years have been a turbulent time for crypto, and making it through while continuing to grow is no small feat. Today, we&amp;#x27;re excited to share our roadmap, our priorities and how we plan to continue developing the industry’s most secure and scalable wallet infrastructure.Here’s a brief overview of the 2024 metrics we’re most proud of:130+ clients: Trusted by leaders in banking, custody, payments, tokenization, and trading.10 million wallets: Supporting both custodial and non-custodial models for treasury management and end-user onboarding experiences.$1 billion in monthly transactions: Securing and processing critical payment volumes, globally.Foundational infrastructure for blockchain financeWhen we founded Dfns in 2020, the concept of wallets-as-a-service (WaaS) built on zero trust security architecture was met with cautious optimism, and also outright skepticism. Wallets, this very central yet misunderstood little piece of blockchain technology, have long been plagued by security flaws, poor user experiences, and a lack of institutional-grade infrastructure, hindering mass adoption across the board.We saw an opportunity to change that, to create something foundational. From the outset and at its core, Dfns has been an infrastructure and cybersecurity company. We’ve avoided chasing trends or superficial growth, choosing instead to focus on what fintechs and financial institutions truly need: a secure, reliable way to hold, trade, and manage digital assets.Nearly five years later, our platform supports over 130 fintechs across every continent, including industry leaders like Fidelity, Bridge (acquired by Stripe), Zodia Custody (backed by Standard Chartered Bank), Tungsten Custody (backed by ADQ), and many others. Achieving this has required building a dungeon of trust, as clients now entrust us with mission-critical parts of their infrastructure, a responsibility we take deeply seriously. With their trust, we have unlocked invaluable insight. Institutional clients (think: banks, governments, large-scale apps, etc.) share with us their trade secrets, security architectures, regulatory challenges, technical debt and other sensitive elements. These conversations empower us to design tailored solutions that enable seamless, secure blockchain adoption. Starting Q2 2025, with the release of our new Data Integrity Framework, we’re confident no vendor will be able to match our security model. Wallets are the new subterranean rails of financeWe often say that wallets are to cryptocurrencies what bank accounts are to fiat currencies. But the reality runs deeper: wallets are the linchpins of trust in the new decentralized internet. They enable people and businesses to interact with assets, validate ownership, and execute transfers in a way that traditional bank accounts never could. Although we think wallets don’t receive the attention they deserve, they undoubtedly form the simplest and most foundational primitives of blockchain finance.However, we believe the wallet space is currently undergoing a quiet renaissance. Analyst Robbie Petersen from Delphi Digital captures this in his &amp;quot;Fat Wallet Thesis.&amp;quot; He argues that as blockchains and applications become commoditized, wallets are emerging as the primary interface for users (read: retail customers or business employees) within the crypto financial ecosystem. With diminishing differentiation at the protocol and application layers, and as the limits of onchain capabilities become clearer, wallets are taking center stage. They now serve as the critical access point for managing, authenticating, and securing user interactions and transaction flows, much of which happens offchain.Over the past two years, wallets have undergone profound transformations. For instance, we see that the distinction between keys and wallets is becoming clearer. Key management services focus on generating and securing digital signatures, while wallet infrastructures handle the full transaction lifecycle—creating, broadcasting, and managing multichain interactions independently. Also, the industry-wide perception of wallets have evolved far beyond simple cryptocurrency storage. They’re now dynamic operating systems for managing digital assets across multiple networks, facilitating seamless transactions, and integrating with third-party applications in a fluid, uninterrupted workflow.With that said, much work still lies ahead. To unlock the full potential of digital asset finance, wallets tooling must become more accessible, secure, and interoperable. Admittedly, today, many wallets and digital asset infrastructures remain siloed, burdened by clunky interfaces, poor transaction management, complex key processes, high costs, and limited interoperability among other bottlenecks. These issues are even more magnified for institutions, which demand scalability, compliance, and resilience at the organization level. How can banks, neobanks, and other fintechs confidently integrate blockchain technology and tokenized instruments when the infrastructure remains fragmented and insecure?As a wallets-as-a-service platform, our mission is clear: to enable any platform, app, or service to integrate crypto capabilities and launch wallets in days. We don’t believe in the notion of “a wallet to rule them all.” Instead, we think diversity will drive the evolution of global financial services with uncompromising security, proven cryptography, and modular infrastructure. By rethinking wallets from the ground up as secure, compliant, scalable, and flexible gateways, we’re making sure blockchain can integrate into existing financial systems. Our API-driven infrastructure equips institutions to deploy wallets with:Ease: Simple interfaces make integration easy, helping fintechs bring solutions to market faster.Functionality: Core financial features like secure transaction handling, activity logs, identity management, and approval workflows.Interoperability: Full compatibility with all blockchains and digital asset types.Security: Robust safeguards protect users, transactions, APIs, keys, and credentials from weak security practices or single points of failure.Compliance: Comprehensive tools ensure operations meet regulatory standards, with support for access controls, entitlements, policies, quorums, and more.The Dfns strategic vision for 2025 and beyondSince 2020, Dfns has forged its path through the early stages of product development and the evolutions of crypto. The past two years have tested our resilience, particularly in the aftermath of FTX’s collapse, which redefined the industry. While economic, operational, and regulatory challenges led to some client turnover, Dfns has maintained an impressive 300% year-over-year growth since 2021. This momentum is now fueled by a new wave of fintech innovators—spanning trading, banking, payments, lending, investing, asset management, treasury, and more—focused on delivering real economic value and tangible utility.Two years ago, we made a strategic upmarket move focusing on institutional clients, a decision based on a deeply rooted thesis that has proven successful. Our vision remains steadfast: institutional investors are the key to crypto adoption as they control the lion’s share of global liquidity. To meet their standards, we built our foundation on uncompromising security and zero trust principles, abiding by the rigor of traditional finance while leveraging state-of-the-art technology to exceed expectations. As blockchain assets grow in value, so do the risks and regulatory scrutiny surrounding them. From the outset, Dfns positioned itself as the most secure blockchain wallet infrastructure to earn the trust of the leading institutions navigating the complexities of crypto and integrating it into the financial system. Today, the institutionalization of the crypto is undeniable, with players like BlackRock embracing Bitcoin.Dfns stands as a benchmark for transparency, reliability, and security, underpinned by a robust foundation of trust-building measures: industry-leading certifications, regulatory licenses, comprehensive insurance, independent audits, and collaborations with global leaders. Trusted by Tier-1 banks and licensed financial services, Dfns has established itself as the go-to wallet-as-a-service platform. In 2024, Dfns consistently outperformed competitors in active RFPs from banks and crypto custodians, cementing its leadership for fintechs and institutions managing digital assets with security, efficiency, and scalability.Following our $13 million seed round in 2022, this Series A funding positions Dfns to accelerate the global adoption of its multichain wallet APIs and infrastructure throughout 2025 and beyond. Our focus is clear: driving adoption across banks, neobanks, payment services, trading platforms, investment applications, tokenization projects, government and corporate treasuries, as well as fund administrators, with a strategic emphasis on the EU, UK, UAE, and the US markets ready to soar.We have a clear plan. In this volatile crypto market, sustainable growth is more important than rapid expansion. Instead of growing our team too quickly, we want to increase from 25 to 35 employees by year-end, depending on our progress and market conditions. Our focus is on providing top-notch infrastructure for fintech clients. They need bank-level security, smart transaction tooling, smooth third-party integrations, excellent developer APIs, and user-friendly interfaces. That’s where we excel, and it’s what we will continue to deliver.AuthorsClarisse HagègeCEO &amp;amp; Co-founderClarisse Hagège is the CEO and Cofounder of Dfns. She has an extensive background as a Board Member of the MPC Alliance, Mentor at Techstars Web3 Launchpad, and crypto startup Advisor at Station F. With BSc and MSc degrees in Finance, Economics and Political Science from Sorbonne University, Sciences Po, and Dauphine University, her career spans a decade in investment banking and corporate treasury in Paris and New York, including roles at Goldman Sachs, Merrill Lynch, and Crédit Agricole CIB.Christopher Grilhault des FontainesCo-CEO &amp;amp; Co-founderChristopher Grilhault des Fontaines is the co-CEO and co-founder of Dfns. He’s also Chairman of the Supervisory Board of Super Capital and investor at Wagmi Ventures. Chris is a serial founder who’s worked across HR Tech, Sports, Food and Social media industries before joining the world of cybersecurity and blockchain finance at Dfns. He holds a BSc degree in Liberal Arts and Philosophy from the Bordeaux University as well as an MSc degree in Management and Organizational Behavior Studies from Dauphine University.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/6787820afb65021f01ebac8a_Annoucement%20Serie%20A-min%20(1).jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Custodial or Non-Custodial Under MICAR</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfns.co/article/custodial-or-non-custodial-under-micar</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/article/custodial-or-non-custodial-under-micar"/>
    <content type="html">What EU law actually says about digital asset custody, and why it matters more than ever.Over the past year, we’ve heard the same question raised in nearly every serious institutional conversation about digital assets: “What does custody actually mean under MiCAR?” It is a fair question. The regulatory landscape in Europe is moving fast. The Markets in Crypto-Assets Regulation (MiCAR) and the Digital Operational Resilience Act (DORA) are reshaping the way institutions engage with digital assets. Yet, even as &amp;quot;compliance explainers&amp;quot; flood LinkedIn and vendors promise plug-and-play solutions, many banks, trading platforms, and custodians still feel like they are navigating in a fog.Last week, we wrote about this lack of clarity. We explained why DORA, in particular, remains largely undefined. We highlighted key takeaways from the closed-door roundtable organized by Siedler Legal in Brussels, where Dfns was the only wallet infrastructure provider in the room. There, the question of how to classify DeFi under MiCAR and DORA sparked lively debate. The consensus was that we are still early. But MiCAR’s approach to custody is different. The clarity is already here.It matters because understanding whether a service is custodial or non-custodial under MiCAR is not just a legal exercise; it defines the obligations, licenses, liability, and compliance exposure of nearly every single digital asset operation in the European Union. It shapes whether your company needs to become a regulated Crypto-Asset Service Provider (CASP), whether your infrastructure partner drags you into the scope of MiCAR, and whether your user relations are considered financial services or software services.To help bring this clarity into focus, we commissioned a legal memorandum from Morgan Lewis. The objective was to assess whether our “delegated signing” configuration constitutes a custody service under MiCAR and French law, or not. The result is a 20-page analysis, issued by Hubert de Vauplane on March 31, 2025, that dissects MiCAR’s legal definitions, explores the legacy French approach under the PACTE Act, and applies those principles directly to MPC-based infrastructure. Here is what we learned.MiCAR’s definition of custody of digital assetsMiCAR defines custody as “the safekeeping or controlling, on behalf of clients, of crypto-assets or of the means of access to such crypto-assets, where applicable in the form of private cryptographic keys.” At first glance, this seems very expansive, but this definition borrows directly from earlier French law, notably the PACTE Act of 2019 and the AMF’s guidance issued in 2020, which focused custody around a single legal concept: control.“Control” should be understood here as the capacity to move digital assets without anyone else’s involvement or dependency. It’s not about theoretical access, physical storage, or who designed the software. Rather it’s about the real-world ability to trigger a blockchain transaction without the approval or participation of the end-user.Recital 83 of MiCAR makes the scope even clearer: providers of non-custodial hardware or software wallets are not considered custodians. This exemption was intentionally added during the legislative process to ensure that technology providers, who merely enable others to manage keys, are not regulated as financial intermediaries. Control, in this context, is not a technical feature – it is a legal threshold.The role of French law and AMF guidanceAlthough MiCAR is now fully applicable across the EU, France remains an important interpretative reference point. The French Financial Market Authorities (AMF) was among the first regulators in Europe to define crypto-asset custody in law and to distinguish technology service providers from financial custodians. According to AMF guidelines, custody requires not only access to the private keys but also a contractual relationship that authorizes the service provider to act on behalf of the user. These guidelines outlined four indicators of custody: the ability to transfer assets, possession of wallets containing private keys, control of the public address, and the receipt of user assets into a wallet owned by the provider.These elements are illustrative, not exhaustive. More importantly, they are not met by software solutions where the end-user retains the exclusive ability to authorize transactions. The AMF further clarified that technology providers whose solutions store cryptographic keys under the sole control and responsibility of the client do not offer custody services. That language has since been echoed almost verbatim by MiCAR’s own drafters.How MiCAR views our “delegated signing” schemeDfns provides digital asset infrastructure based on Threshold Signature Schemes (TSS) and Multi-Party Computation (MPC). These cryptographic techniques ensure that private keys are never created, stored, or held in full. Instead, keys are actually generated in the form of encrypted partial keys and distributed across multiple secure environments. The patent-pending innovation of Dfns’ “delegated signing” solution is that signing a valid transaction requires first an API call authenticated by the end-user. Without this step, no signature can be generated. And without a signature, there is no transaction.Morgan Lewis’ assessment hinges on this point. Under both MiCAR and French law, Dfns satisfies the first two elements required for a regulated service, aka professional activity and a contractual relationship with its customers. But the third element, control, is where the distinction is made. In the non-custodial version of the architecture reviewed by Morgan Lewis, neither Dfns nor its clients (read: platforms) can trigger a blockchain transaction without the end-user’s authentication credential in use. Even if the infrastructure runs in Dfns-managed data centers or includes trusted execution environments, what matters is not the location of the MPC key shares, but the fact that Dfns has no access or ability to use them in the normal course of business. This authentication step, secured through WebAuthn and other alternative key-based protocols, places control in the hands of the end-user. It is the legal equivalent of custody, and since Dfns lacks that control, it is not a custodian per MiCAR.And what about sub-custody, does Dfns qualify?MiCAR requires regulated custodians to only rely on authorized sub-custodians when outsourcing custody functions. This clause initially raised questions about whether MPC providers like Dfns could be seen as sub-custodians. Morgan Lewis addresses this directly. According to the interpretation developed through AMF precedent, sub-custody exists only when the delegate has actual control over the assets. A technology provider that cannot move assets, even if it manages key orchestration or storage, does not meet this test. Hence, Dfns does not act as a sub-custodian. It does not hold or control digital assets. It operates infrastructure that prevents it from doing so. The legal structure mirrors the operational design.The substance of control in the context of MPCThe memorandum also goes deeper and challenges the notion that the mere possibility of access—even in edge cases like cyberattacks or software bugs—should be treated as control. The law, it argues, should be grounded in the normal course of business, not in theoretical failure modes. Just as we do not consider a traditional custodian liable for a natural disaster unless negligence is involved, we should not define control based on speculative risks.This is particularly important in the context of MPC. Unlike multi-signature wallets, where control is shared across multiple key holders, MPC systems never generate or store a full key. Even if one party acts maliciously, it cannot reconstruct the private key or sign alone. Assuming that the architecture ensures that user authentication is always cryptographically required to trigger a signing process, then the control rests with the user, and no custody service exists.Infrastructure ≠ Custody: Tech is tech, finance is financeOne of the more profound takeaways from this legal assessment is that MiCAR continues the evolution that began with the AMF’s early guidance: a clean separation between financial intermediation and infrastructure provision. Custody is not defined by how software works, but by who uses it and how. A platform that holds the signing secret and initiates API calls on behalf of users is a custodian. A platform that delegates that control to users, and cannot act without them, is not. The legal classification depends on the contractual and operational structure, not the existence of an API or the presence of an MPC algorithm for example. This distinction enables builders to decouple technical infrastructure from regulatory liability. It allows wallet platforms to offer user-controlled configurations. It enables institutions to build services with clarity on where the regulatory perimeter begins and ends.The MiCAR framework is still evolving, however. Many questions remain about DeFi, staking, governance tokens, and token issuance among other items. But when it comes to custody, the law is already clear, and the analysis of Dfns’ delegated signing solution helps illuminate that clarity. Control is the legal crux. Not key generation. Not storage. Not software design. What matters is who can move the assets. In the case of Dfns, that answer is simple: the user. Which means that for those who rely on Dfns to build infrastructure, the regulatory perimeter stops at the edge of your system—not at the center of ours.If you would like to access the full legal memorandum by Morgan Lewis, you can request it by contacting: sales@dfns.co.‍AuthorsChristopher Grilhault des FontainesCo-CEO &amp;amp; Co-founderChristopher Grilhault des Fontaines is the co-CEO and co-founder of Dfns. He’s also Chairman of the Supervisory Board of Super Capital and investor at Wagmi Ventures. Chris is a serial founder who’s worked across HR Tech, Sports, Food and Social media industries before joining the world of cybersecurity and blockchain finance at Dfns. He holds a BSc degree in Liberal Arts and Philosophy from the Bordeaux University as well as an MSc degree in Management and Organizational Behavior Studies from Dauphine University.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/67f4df7d01cd9ac048816512_Dfns%27%20Custodial%20Status%20under%20MiCAR-min.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Announcing Midas</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfns.co/article/announcing-midas</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/article/announcing-midas"/>
    <content type="html">Dfns and Midas have joined forces to bring institutional-grade yield strategies onchain, securely, seamlessly, and at scale. This partnership unlocks access to tokenized U.S. Treasuries, crypto basis trades, and Bitcoin yield products, directly within Dfns wallets.Imagine accessing institutional-grade yields onchain via exposure to the U.S. Treasury Bills, crypto basis trades, or Bitcoin yield strategies, with zero wallet friction and no compromise on security. That future is now a reality, thanks to the partnership between Dfns and Midas. This collaboration brings together two industry leaders with complementary visions:Midas has selected Dfns to power its secure custody and treasury infrastructure—including support for Telegram’s TON blockchain and Jetton tokens.Dfns is integrating Midas&amp;#x27; tokenized yield products, such as mTBILL, to help clients seamlessly tap into transparent, onchain income streams.The next step is to embed Dfns-powered multichain wallets into the Midas platform, so new users can easily access onchain financial services without any hassle.Together, we’re building a secure bridge between traditional finance and decentralized investing.Midas: Internet-native investing, institutionally engineeredMidas is on a mission to reimagine how financial products are structured, accessed, and distributed in the internet era. The company offers Liquid Yield Tokens (LYTs),fully-compliant ERC-20 tokens that bring performance from real-world and crypto-native strategies onto the blockchain.Flagship Yield Strategies:mTBILL – Tokenized short-term U.S. Treasuries with ~4% stable APY.mBASIS – Crypto market-neutral strategy capturing basis trade spreads.mBTC – Bitcoin-backed token generating passive BTC-based yield.mEDGE, mMEV, mRe7YIELD – High-yield stablecoin strategies powered by institutional partners like Re7 Capital, MEV Capital, and Edge Capital.All Midas tokens are freely composable across DeFi, built with atomic redemption, real-time pricing, and backed by institutional-grade structuring. Importantly, they are issued under ring-fenced, regulatory compliant structures in Europe under the German BaFin framework with transparency reports, legal disclosures, and external audits available at all times. Led by Fabrice Grinda, a world-class team (alumni from Goldman Sachs, Anchorage Digital, Capital Group, Solaris Group SE, and Ondo Finance) and backed by top investors like Framework, BlockTower, HV Capital, and Coinbase Ventures, Midas is bringing onchain finance into a new era of accessibility and trust.“Integrating Dfns’ wallet infrastructure has allowed us to focus on building the best yield-generating products without compromising on user security or experience. Our users can now invest with confidence and ease.” — Dennis Dinkelmeyer, CEO &amp;amp; co-Founder, MidasDfns: secure wallet infrastructure without the frictionWhile Midas builds the yield-generating engine, Dfns removes all the wallet complexity under the hood. As the wallets-as-a-service (WaaS) provider trusted by financial institutions like Standard Chartered-backed crypto custodian Zodia Custody, ADQ-backed Tungsten Custody, Fidelity International, ABN AMRO, Bridge (acquired by Stripe), Iron (acquired by MoonPay), and 160+ other fintechs and financial institutions, Dfns offers secure, programmable, and embedded wallets that abstract away blockchain complexities, key management, transaction lifecycle management and other critical features for digital asset custody. What Dfns brings to Midas:Embedded wallets with zero seed phrases: Wallets are generated instantly via API and accessed with biometrics, passkeys, or PINs, creating no single points of failure.Multichain compatibility: Full support for TON, Ethereum, and over 100 other blockchains including Polygon, Base, Solana, and Arbitrum.Ultra-secure custody: Powered by advanced MPC (Multi-Party Computation) or HSM (Hardware Security Modules), backed by FIPS 140-2/3 compliant infrastructure. Built-in transaction reliability: Dfns automates queuing, retries, and fee optimization across chains, enabling seamless execution, even during network congestion.Regulatory alignment: Deploy keys and policies in chosen jurisdictions. Dfns is ISO 27001 certified, SOC 2 Type II compliant, and aligned with frameworks like US FISMA and EU DORA.&amp;quot;At Dfns, our mission is to remove complexity from digital asset management so that visionary companies like Midas can push blockchain finance forward and give access to yield-generating instruments to a wider audience. Together, we’re making institutional-grade yields accessible to everyone, which makes us very proud.&amp;quot; — Clarisse Hagège, CEO, DfnsReal yield, real security, now available onchainMidas and Dfns share a long-term vision: giving users access to high-quality, yield-bearing financial products without sacrificing security, UX, or regulatory clarity. This partnership is more than just an integration; it’s a model for how institutional finance and DeFi can come together, responsibly and securely. With Dfns powering custody and Midas delivering yield, users can now access the future of fund management through a clean, compliant, and composable experience.To learn more, visit midas.app or dfns.co.‍AuthorsClarisse HagègeCEO &amp;amp; Co-founderClarisse Hagège is the CEO and Cofounder of Dfns. She has an extensive background as a Board Member of the MPC Alliance, Mentor at Techstars Web3 Launchpad, and crypto startup Advisor at Station F. With BSc and MSc degrees in Finance, Economics and Political Science from Sorbonne University, Sciences Po, and Dauphine University, her career spans a decade in investment banking and corporate treasury in Paris and New York, including roles at Goldman Sachs, Merrill Lynch, and Crédit Agricole CIB.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/67ee406a1177ce0f7d98daae_midas.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Onchain Transaction Reliability, Solved</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfns.co/article/onchain-transaction-reliability-solved</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/article/onchain-transaction-reliability-solved"/>
    <content type="html">Lessons from Dfns’ work on onchain transaction success and improving blockchain reliabilityAs blockchain becomes more central to finance, reliable onchain transactions are now highly critical. An onchain transaction isn’t just a message, it’s a promise. When a user signs and sends a transaction, they expect a result: a transfer to go through, a position to update, a contract to execute. That promise sets off a chain of expectations, both for users and for systems around them. When that promise is broken—when a transaction fails—it doesn’t just cause a delay. It breaks user flows, interrupts automation, and erodes trust. For platforms processing thousands of transfers per day, such as payment providers, trading firms, or bridge protocols, even a one percent failure rate means hundreds of issues daily.Over the past year, we set out to rebuild our transaction delivery stack from the ground up. We combined strong infrastructure, smart retry mechanisms, and developer-friendly reliability tools. The result is that our clients such as Bridge, now part of Stripe, Iron, now part of MoonPay, and circa 10% of the stablecoin payments industry run on Dfns with failure rates close to zero across Solana, Ethereum, Base, Tron, Polygon, and other major blockchains. This is the story of what we built and why it works.Why transaction reliability is hard (and important)At first glance, sending a blockchain transaction seems easy. A user signs a payload, it gets broadcasted to the network, and eventually it gets confirmed. But in practice, making sure this process works every time, at scale, is anything but simple. Every blockchain behaves differently. Some prioritize speed and offer near-instant finality, but come with volatile gas fees that spike without warning. Others keep costs low but introduce complex signing procedures or require extra steps before a transaction is considered valid. That variability makes it hard to build a universal transaction engine.Then come the infrastructure challenges. Blockchain transactions can only get executed through nodes (whether your own or from third-party providers) whose only job is to register the event into the state of the entire chain. But these nodes can be unreliable. Sometimes they are slow to respond. Sometimes they drop requests. Sometimes they give conflicting data about the same transaction. RPC endpoints might say a transaction was submitted, but it never reaches the mempool. Or worse, it gets stuck in limbo, neither confirmed nor failed, leaving developers unsure whether to retry or wait. This uncertainty becomes even more painful at scale. When you are running a wallet platform, payment system, or trading engine that sends thousands of transactions per day across chains like Ethereum, Solana, or Polygon, every gap in reliability can turn into an operational nightmare. Support tickets pile up, automated workflows fail, funds go temporarily missing, traders miss positions, and users lose trust.Reliable transactions are not just about moving money; they are about trust in the system. They ensure that every operation, whether sending ten dollars or ten million in stablecoins, is submitted, confirmed, and tracked with clarity. That level of reliability is what separates a hobby project from production-grade infrastructure. This is the core challenge we’ve focused on at Dfns: how to make blockchain transactions behave with the same consistency and predictability people expect from traditional finance. Solving it means going beyond simply broadcasting a transaction, it means building for financial resilience, recovery, and confidence at every step.The Dfns recipe to ensuring transaction reliability(1) From delegating to owning the blockchain node layerOne of the most impactful changes we made was taking control of our blockchain node infrastructure. We now operate our own dedicated blockchain nodes across the major networks we support. This gives us three key advantages.First, security. By hosting our own nodes, we eliminate dependencies on third-party providers that can introduce blind spots, errors, or even manipulated data. We continuously cross-validate our node data with external endpoints, ensuring that discrepancies are caught immediately.Second, observability. With full access to node logs, mempools, and transaction queues, we can investigate failures in real time. We no longer have to rely on opaque external RPC services or slow vendor support. If a transaction fails, we know why—and we can fix it in record time.Third, redundancy. Our infrastructure is designed to reroute requests automatically if a node is slow or temporarily unreachable. Whether the issue is load, connectivity, or sync lag, traffic is seamlessly redirected to a healthy node, ensuring uninterrupted service.(2) Automatic failure recovery with reindexing and rebroadcastingDespite best efforts, even the most carefully crafted transactions can get stuck or lost in the network. That’s why we built automated systems for transaction reindexing and rebroadcasting. When a transaction is submitted, our backend continuously monitors its status. If a transaction fails to confirm within a given window, the system triggers a reindexing flow. This involves rescanning the blockchain for that transaction, comparing block data, and checking for matches based on hash, payload, and expected signature.If the transaction is confirmed, we update our internal records accordingly. If not, we rebroadcast it programmatically and without developer intervention. Our infrastructure handles signature reordering (for chains like Solana), fee recalculations, and signature reconstruction as needed. This is especially crucial during periods of high congestion, such as we saw with Solana during the TRUMP token surge earlier this year. These flows have helped clients like Bridge reduce manual recovery work dramatically. Transactions that would have once required support tickets or replays now complete automatically in the background—keeping money flowing and customers happy.(3) Eliminating accidental double-spending and duplicate transfersEven if the blockchain protects against double-spending at the protocol level, many issues originate offchain where most systems still fall short. Network hiccups, retries from mobile clients, and misunderstood error codes can cause users to unknowingly resubmit the same transaction multiple times. Without proper safeguards, this can result in multiple transactions being initiated, leading to confusion or even double charges. To address this, Dfns introduced API-level idempotency. Developers can assign a unique externalId to each transaction request. When a request is received, our system checks if this ID has already been seen:If it has, and the payload is identical, we return the original response.If it has, but the payload differs, we return a 409 Conflict—preventing accidental duplicates.If it’s new, we store the ID and process the transaction normally.We support both transient storage (using fast-access memory like Redis) and permanent storage (via databases like DynamoDB), allowing developers to choose between speed and retention based on their needs. This simple feature has had a massive impact—especially for high-volume or latency-sensitive applications like Iron, where retries are common and safety is paramount. By offloading retry handling to Dfns, developers can simplify their logic, reduce edge cases, and ensure consistent behavior across all chains.(4) Performance optimization at the infrastructure layerTransaction reliability isn&amp;#x27;t just about preventing failures—it’s about doing so at scale.Our infrastructure has been tuned to process thousands of requests per second, across dozens of chains, without slowing down. We do this through:Parallel processing which allows us to handle high transaction volume without queue buildup.Smart queuing where high-priority transactions are surfaced and processed ahead of less critical ones.Advanced load balancing, which distributes requests intelligently across servers and nodes to avoid overloads.Caching, to prevent redundant lookups and speed up access to frequently used transaction data.These improvements have shaved milliseconds off transaction pipelines and allowed clients to scale aggressively without running into bottlenecks.Takeaways for developers tempted to build in-houseThe best validation of any system is how it performs in the wild. And over the past year, we’ve seen real-world impact across some of our most demanding partners. Before adopting Dfns’ full reliability stack, clients like Bridge and Iron were seeing transaction failure rates close to 10% due to a mix of network congestion, inconsistent node data, RPC errors and UI-centric, legacy vendors that were not focused on solving these core issues. Since implementing node redundancy, API idempotency, reindexing, rebroadcasting, and data consistency features, that number has dropped to nearly zero. This improvement isn’t just a technical win, it’s a business enabler. Faster settlements, fewer errors, and reduced support tickets have allowed these teams to scale faster, maintain SLAs, and offer a better user experience. If you’re building in crypto, reliability should be non-negotiable. With Dfns, you get infrastructure that’s designed for:Resilience: Near-zero failure rates, even across high-volume workloads.Recoverability: Automatic reindexing and rebroadcasting to ensure transactions don’t get lost.Safety: Idempotency handling that prevents user-side errors from becoming financial mistakes.Visibility: Real-time tracking and monitoring of transaction status, retries, and node performance.These systems are deeply integrated into our Wallet-as-a-Service platform, so you can get started with minimal setup—no need for external relayers, custom smart contracts, or complex monitoring stacks.Transaction reliability on blockchains is a hard problem. We’ve seen first-hand how even small inconsistencies can lead to failed payments, frustrated users, and operational chaos. That’s why we’ve made it our mission to reduce that uncertainty to the lowest odds possible. By bringing node infrastructure in-house, building resilient retry systems, implementing offchain idempotency, and tuning our backend for performance, Dfns now powers onchain transactions with the kind of reliability that institutions demand. We’re proud of what we’ve built together with our clients and deeply grateful for their trust and support.Try Dfns today or get in touch for early access to upcoming features.AuthorsNoah CornwellChief Technology OfficerAs Chief Technology Officer, Noah heads the engineers team at Dfns. Before joining Dfns, Noah spent over 15 years of his life in technical and engineering leadership roles at crypto exchange and bank Gemini as well as trading firms like MIK Funds and Boston Technologies. He holds an MSc in finance from Northeastern and BSc degree in Economics from the University of Oregon.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/67ee7cd3f74bc46733407187_Cover.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing Fee Sponsors</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfns.co/article/introducing-fee-sponsors</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/article/introducing-fee-sponsors"/>
    <content type="html">Dfns now supports fee sponsorship, allowing our clients to pay transaction fees on behalf of their users directly through our API. At Dfns, we are always working to make building with wallets easier, safer, and more flexible. Today, we&amp;#x27;re excited to launch Fee Sponsor Wallets, a new feature that removes friction in user experience for onchain applications and makes automated transaction workflows easier, especially for use cases like payments and trading. Initially available on Solana, our Fee Sponsor Wallets will expand to other major blockchains in the coming weeks. Ethereum/EVM and Tron are next on our roadmap.Why fee sponsorship matters on blockchainsFees are the price of trust on blockchains. They exist to prevent spam, reward validators, and anchor transactions in a shared execution layer. But in practice, they also introduce friction.Users often struggle with fee-related issues, such as needing to hold SOL to complete a transfer or understanding why a transaction fails due to insufficient gas. Developers building user-friendly applications face additional challenges around token management, wallet funding, and maintaining faucets or top-up systems.Fee Sponsor Wallets remove this complexity. Developers can now sponsor transaction fees for their users through Dfns’ secure API, enabling:Onboarding new users without needing to airdrop native tokensManaging employee wallets or automation systems from a centralized treasuryAbstracting away gas from end-users entirelyThis feature is part of our broader mission: making digital assets secure, but more importantly, operationally usable.Fee sponsorship starts on SolanaSolana is the first supported blockchain. Solana natively supports fee delegation: one wallet can initiate a transaction, while another pays for it. Dfns builds on this with a secure, audit-friendly API flow that integrates directly into our Wallets-as-a-Service platform.With Dfns, a sponsored Solana transfer includes two custodial wallets within the same organization:Org or user wallet: Initiates the token transfer. It signs the transaction payload but holds no SOL.Fee sponsor wallet: Pays the transaction fees. It provides the second signature and is debited onchain.Step-by-step flowCreate a fee sponsor based on a custodial wallet: https://docs.dfns.co/d/api-docs/fee-sponsors/create-fee-sponsorCollect user intent The user initiates a standard SPL or native transfer from a custodial wallet.Include the feeSponsorId in the API call when creating the transfer request: https://docs.dfns.co/d/api-docs/wallets/transfer-asset-from-wallet#spl-request-bodyDfns automatically handles both signatures: The user wallet signs the transactionThe sponsor wallet signs the feeRelevant metadata and cryptographic signatures are recorded in our systems.BroadcastDfns broadcasts the transaction. The Solana network deducts the fee from the sponsor wallet and executes the transfer.Each sponsorship action is traceable, with audit logs and permission enforcement built in.Quick look at the API integrationTo perform a sponsored transfer, simply use the following:POST /wallets/:walletId/transfers {   &amp;quot;kind&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Native&amp;quot; | &amp;quot;Spl&amp;quot; | &amp;quot;Spl2022&amp;quot;,   &amp;quot;network&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Solana&amp;quot;,   &amp;quot;...&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;other required fields&amp;quot;,   &amp;quot;feeSponsorId&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;fs-xxx&amp;quot; }The user must have Wallets:Transfer permission for both the sending wallet and the sponsor wallet. The fee sponsor must be on the same chain and correctly flagged as a sponsor wallet.This requires no external relayers or custom smart contracts. All logic is handled natively within the Dfns infrastructure.Built for control with policies and permissionsSponsorship flows are fully customizable and governed through each client’s own logic and permissions. All relevant metadata and cryptographic signatures are recorded in our systems, ensuring transparency and compliance. Each sponsored transaction includes an audit trail that clearly shows who signed, what was signed, and when, making it easy to enforce policies and trace activity. Clients can start using fee sponsorship with minimal code changes while maintaining full visibility and security.Expanding fee sponsors to all blockchainsSolana is just the beginning. We&amp;#x27;re expanding Fee Sponsors to a wide set of chains, whether they support sponsorship natively or not. Here&amp;#x27;s what to expect:        BLOCKCHAIN     MECHANISM           Algorand     No native support. Must fund a wallet beforehand to opt-in to assets.           Aptos     Sponsored transactions. Asset owner signs, then fee payer signs.             Bitcoin     Possible via UTXOs.           Cosmos     Fee grant module. Sponsorship via on-chain grants.             Ethereum/EVM     Pending EIP-7702. Post-implementation, could support flexible fee sponsorship.           Solana     Native fee payer.            Stellar     Fee bump transactions. Sponsor wraps and signs fee bump. Double fee cost.              Substrate     No native support.            Sui     Sponsored transactions. Fee payer adds gas info and signs.            TON     v5 only. Pay for gas with Jettons via gas proxy API.            Tron     No native support. Possible with energy delegation.    In the near future, we&amp;#x27;ll support periodic invoicing for sponsored fees, policy-based fee delegation, and automated sponsor wallet budget management.Next stop: AI-powered fee managementA core challenge in sponsoring transactions is predicting the correct fee to ensure a transaction goes through, especially when networks are congested. To address this, we’re planning on integrating AI-based fee prediction directly into the Fee Sponsors flow. This system would dynamically calculate the optimal fee based on real-time network conditions, historical data, and transaction context.In February 2025, Solana was severely congested due to a surge in transactions involving the TRUMP token. Many transactions failed due to underpriced fees, affecting user experience and reliability. Our AI system is designed to detect these shifts early, adjusting sponsored fee levels proactively to prevent similar failures. This intelligent fee calibration will ensure fewer failed transactions during network congestion, predictable cost controls for fee sponsor accounts, and a better UX with consistent transaction finality. We want this feature to be chain-agnostic and will evolve with each supported network.Available today for all Dfns clientsFee Sponsors are native to our Wallets-as-a-Service (WaaS) product. It works with existing org-managed (custodial) wallet, integrates with existing permissions and policy frameworks, and requires no external smart contracts, relayers, or dependencies. The next step is to enable fee sponsorship for user-managed (non-custodial) wallet configurations. Security remains intact: all transactions require multiple signatures and pass through the audit trail engine.Fee Sponsors are available now on Solana. You try it today from your Dfns account. Support for more blockchains—starting with Ethereum/EVM and Tron—is coming in Q2 2025. To get started, visit app.dfns.io. If you want early access to upcoming networks, reach out to our team.AuthorsChris SuttonChief Product OfficerAs Chief Product Officer, Chris runs all things product and developer experience at Dfns. With a powerhouse background spanning Mastercard, Zerohash, IBM, Cisco, BlackRock, and Oasis Pro Markets, Chris has been at the edge of stablecoin payments, tokenized securities, and blockchain finance since 2016.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/67ed4de1b4bc8a71133beefc_Fee.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Our New Dashboard</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfns.co/article/our-new-dashboard</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/article/our-new-dashboard"/>
    <content type="html">Dfns unveils new dashboard, bringing institutional-grade control to digital asset operations.For five years, Dfns has been on a mission to build the most secure, API-first bank-grade custody and wallet infrastructure for fintechs, banks, and enterprises. Our technology powers some of the most trusted digital asset platforms, and today, we’re making it even more accessible.The new Dfns dashboard is here. Fast, intuitive, and secure. It’s the perfect admin companion to our once upon API-first technology, empowering operational actors in financial industries to move at the speed of the market without sacrificing control. Built from the ground up by our dedicated frontend team, this dashboard is designed to help organizations manage complexity with ease, combining flexibility and security with clear visibility and governance.‍What you can do with the new dashboard‍Instantly create wallets across multiple chains - Deploy wallets on Solana, Base, Polygon, Bitcoin, and over 50 additional blockchains in just a few clicks. Whether setting up operational accounts, treasury wallets, issuance wallets, custody wallets or onboarding new clients, the process is simple, with automatic address generation, real-time asset detection, and ready-to-use deposit addresses.‍Execute transactions with fee optimization, logging, and tracking - Broadcast onchain transactions confidently with recommended gas settings and automated fee estimations. Pre-execution checks and transaction lifecycle management features ensure peace of mind, while real-time tracking and detailed logs provide complete transparency.Get real-time approvals with secure key-based authenticationFor large and sensitive transfers, set multi-step approval policies. Approvals happen instantly, supported by passkey-based authentication and full audit trails that keep teams secure and accountable. We also recommend creating a quorum of admins for policy editing to avoid singlehanded actions inside your organization. Set up role-based access controls and compliance rulesDefine granular roles and role-based permissions that fit your organization’s workflows. There are more than 100 different read and write capabilities you can turn on or off for each role you create and assign to a user. From there, automate policies like daily transfer limits or whitelist-only transactions, all enforced directly in the platform.Manage users, keys, credentials, and automations in one placeCentralize your operations with a single command center. Onboard users, import, expect and archive keys, manage and revoke credentials, and oversee automations with complete oversight and change history.Built for every admin within financial institutionsFor CFOs and finance teams: gain real-time oversight of treasury activity and wallet balances.For compliance officers: automate policy enforcement and access detailed audit trails.For CISOs and security teams: control user access, approve transactions securely, and manage keys with confidence.For treasury managers: initiate and monitor high-value transactions with full control.Coming soon: more powerful featuresThis release is just the beginning. Soon, users will benefit from asset flow visual maps, drag-and-drop policy builders, and customizable dashboards for tailored oversight. These enhancements will bring even more clarity, efficiency, and confidence to digital asset operations.With Dfns’ new dashboard, we’re making institutional-grade security and operational simplicity available to every stakeholder—from financial operators to compliance teams and security officers. The Dfns dashboard is your new control tower: robust, secure, and designed for real-world institutional use.Start now: app.dfns.io/get-started ‍AuthorsNoah CornwellChief Technology OfficerAs Chief Technology Officer, Noah heads the engineers team at Dfns. Before joining Dfns, Noah spent over 15 years of his life in technical and engineering leadership roles at crypto exchange and bank Gemini as well as trading firms like MIK Funds and Boston Technologies. He holds an MSc in finance from Northeastern and BSc degree in Economics from the University of Oregon.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/67d98d82eb7ebaae42354a70_New%20dashboard%20(1).jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Welcome, Maud Tezenas du Montcel</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfns.co/article/welcome-maud-tezenas-du-montcel</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/article/welcome-maud-tezenas-du-montcel"/>
    <content type="html">Maud Tezenas du Montcel joins Dfns as Head of Marketing to drive brand leadership, growth, and institutional adoption of secure digital asset wallets.We’re excited to welcome Maud Tezenas du Montcel as our new Head of Marketing at Dfns. With a decade of experience in B2B marketing, compliance technology, and crypto, Maud will help sharpen how we communicate our vision, engage with our community, and position Dfns as the leading wallet infrastructure provider for institutions, fintechs, and enterprises. As secure and compliant digital asset infrastructure becomes more critical than ever, Maud’s expertise will drive brand awareness, product positioning, and demand generation, helping financial institutions navigate wallet security, regulation, and digital asset management.A career at the intersection of finance, cloud and cryptoMaud has a strong track record of leading marketing strategies for high-growth companies in web3, digital security, and cloud infrastructure. Before joining Dfns, she was Head of Marketing at Synaps, where she helped establish one of crypto’s leading KYC identity verification solutions. She led marketing initiatives for KYC, AML, and decentralized identity, supporting institutional clients and businesses like Jump, Sygnum, Polygon, 1inch, and The Sandbox in meeting compliance requirements while improving user onboarding.Prior to Synaps, Maud held marketing leadership roles at Stratumn, Oodrive, and Equancy, focusing on B2B growth, brand positioning, and demand generation in fintech and enterprise security. She has experience leading go-to-market strategies, optimizing digital journeys, and executing large-scale lead generation campaigns for regulated industries.From contender to leader in the blockchain wallet space As Head of Marketing, Maud will lead efforts to:Strengthen Dfns’ brand as the premier wallet security infrastructure for financial institutions, fintechs, and enterprises.Expand thought leadership on institutional wallet security, MPC technology, compliance, and risk management in digital assets.Drive demand generation and customer acquisition through data-driven growth strategies, product marketing, and community engagement.Shape industry conversations around wallet security and compliance, ensuring Dfns remains the go-to platform for institutions managing digital assets.Scale marketing operations as Dfns expands into new regions and strengthens partnerships with banks, fintechs, and crypto-native businesses.The demand for secure, compliant, and scalable wallet infrastructure is growing as financial institutions deepen their involvement in crypto and tokenized assets. At Dfns, we’re at the forefront—helping businesses build secure, API-first custody and wallet solutions that meet the highest standards of security and compliance. With Maud leading our marketing efforts, Dfns is well-positioned to set new standards in digital asset security, drive industry-wide conversations, and expand our reach across the financial ecosystem. Welcome to the team, Maud—we’re excited for what’s ahead!‍AuthorsClarisse HagègeCEO &amp;amp; Co-founderClarisse Hagège is the CEO and Cofounder of Dfns. She has an extensive background as a Board Member of the MPC Alliance, Mentor at Techstars Web3 Launchpad, and crypto startup Advisor at Station F. With BSc and MSc degrees in Finance, Economics and Political Science from Sorbonne University, Sciences Po, and Dauphine University, her career spans a decade in investment banking and corporate treasury in Paris and New York, including roles at Goldman Sachs, Merrill Lynch, and Crédit Agricole CIB.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/67d8231c829ca888b888615e_Annoucement%20Team.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Bybit/Safe Hack</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfns.co/article/the-bybit-safe-hack</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/article/the-bybit-safe-hack"/>
    <content type="html">How one compromised laptop led to the largest crypto heist in history. This deep dive breaks down the attack, the systemic weaknesses it revealed, and why crypto must embrace real security beyond “best practices.”The recent Bybit/Safe hack has sent shockwaves through the crypto world… and for good reason. With a jaw-dropping $1.5 billion in ETH stolen, this breach has become the largest crypto theft in history and represents a discrediting vulnerability at the heart of digital asset finance. The most troubling is that it all hinged on a single developer’s computer being compromised, allowing the attackers to inject a malicious JavaScript snippet that hijacked the Safe{Wallet} infrastructure used by Bybit.Despite employing the so-called best practices of multisignature wallets, also known as “multisig wallets”, Bybit still fell victim to a devastating delegatecall exploit. One flipped parameter, changing “operation=0” to “operation=1”, was enough to give attackers complete control to replace Safe’s wallet logic and move 401,000 ETH (~$1.5B) into their own addresses. The level of sophistication of this operation was high, with two malicious smart contracts deployed in advance and a deliberate strategy of delaying fund movement across 900+ wallets, cross-chain bridges, and DEXs to evade immediate detection. It was a perfect storm that exploited security flaws at every level: corporate, infrastructure, application, protocol, and even UX. Investigations are still underway, but SEAL 911 and the FBI believe that TraderTraitor (a North Korean group known for hacking exchanges with distinct tactics) carried out the heist.In this post, we’ll explain how the hack happened, starting from a single developer’s compromised computer and ending with a critical change to one transaction parameter. We’ll then look at the first recommendations from players like Ledger, Binance, and Fireblocks. Their proposed fixes (e.g. eliminating blind signing, adopting stronger multi-sig, adding MPC, multi-level approvals, whitelisting, hardware verification, better operational governance, etc.) are good steps toward preventing new disasters. But let’s be frank here: it’s truly outrageous that $1.5 billion could have been stolen simply because one compromised laptop gave attackers full access to Bybit’s wallet infrastructure. It’s even worse to think that every company using Safe was at risk… Bybit just happened to have the biggest reserves.While each recommendation provides valuable protection, none of them alone is enough. They must all work together in a holistic security framework to bring bank-grade safety to crypto. Without a collective push for stronger, more integrated systems, these attacks will keep happening. It’s time to move beyond fragmented “best practices” and deliver the robust protections digital assets, and their users, truly need.Bybit’s “cold wallet” setup with Safe{Wallet}It happened on February 21, 2025. Surprisingly, the attack didn’t involve a flaw in Bybit’s core systems or in the Ethereum blockchain. Instead, it targeted Safe{Wallet}, a third-party “multisig” platform Bybit trusted. In this post, we’ll examine how Bybit’s “cold wallet” was set up, how a single transaction pulled off the exploit, and what this means for the supposedly secure setups many believed were safe just a week ago. We use quotes around “cold wallet” because “cold” implies a fully offline setup, which isn’t the case with Safe smart contracts and Ledger Nanos.Like most web3 companies, Bybit stored most of its funds in a “cold wallet,” separate from its “hot wallet” and designed to keep assets safe from hackers. This cold wallet ran on a Safe{Wallet} smart contract located at 0x1Db92e2EeBC8E0c075a02BeA49a2935BcD2dFCF4. Safe{Wallet} is a popular multisig platform (read: onchain transaction execution and approval platform). Bybit’s version used a standard proxy contract, whose only job is to forward function calls to an implementation contract that carries the real transaction logic. In Bybit’s case, this critical implementation contract, that was ultimately stored in the proxy’s “slot 0”, was originally located at 0x34CfAC646f301356fAa8B21e94227e3583Fe3F5F. Bybit viewed this as its “cold wallet”, aka the last line of defense for its ETH reserves.Bybit secured its “cold wallet” with a multisig arrangement, requiring multiple employees to approve every withdrawal, which is good. Typically, funds were transferred from the cold wallet to a hot wallet (e.g., 0xf89d7b9c864f589bbF53a82105107622B35EaA40) for day-to-day operations. Each signer (1) used a Ledger hardware wallet, (2) logged into the Safe{Wallet} UI, (3) reviewed the transaction, (4) connected their Ledger to sign, and (5) submitted. Once enough signatures were collected, Safe broadcasted the transaction to Ethereum (6). The proxy contract then called the implementation contract (7), verified the signatures (8), and released the funds (9).For example, on February 3, 2025, transaction 0x3e10310c05bb87269bfd60f67e13fd9dff4da80b4e47a541af1835f15fd96071 transferred 30,000 ETH from the cold wallet to the hot wallet. It called the execTransaction function on the proxy contract (0x1Db92e2EeBC8E0c075a02BeA49a2935BcD2dFCF4) with the following parameters:to: 0xf89d7b9c864f589bbF53a82105107622B35EaA40 (hot wallet) value: 30,000 ETH (30,000,000,000,000,000,000,000 wei) data: (empty) operation: 0 (direct call) safeTxGas: 45,745 dataGas: 0 gasPrice: 0 gasToken: 0x000...000 refundReceiver: 0x000...000 signatures: (multisig signatures from Bybit employees)This is a textbook transfer: The proxy then forwarded this call to the implementation contract, which verified the signatures and sent 30,000 ETH to the hot wallet. Because the operation field was set to 0, it was a straightforward call with no additional complexities. This process was secure and repeatable, relying on Safe{Wallet}’s supposedly battle-tested multisig logic. Until it wasn’t.Anatomy of a carefully orchestrated zero-day exploitOn February 21, 2025, Bybit needed to move 30,000 ETH from the cold wallet to the hot wallet—business as usual. The employees followed the standard process: they logged into the Safe UI, saw the transaction details, connected their Ledger devices, signed it, and submitted it to Safe. The system broadcasted the transaction as expected: 0x46deef0f52e3a983b67abf4714448a41dd7ffd6d32d32da69d62081c68ad7882. At first glance, it looked like another execTransaction call to the proxy contract (0x1Db92e2EeBC8E0c075a02BeA49a2935BcD2dFCF4). But the arguments told a different story:to: 0x96221423681A6d52E184D440a8eFCEbB105C7242 value: 0 data: 0xa9059cbb000000000000000000000000bdd077f651ebe7f7b3ce16fe5f2b025be29695160000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000 operation: 1 (delegatecall) safeTxGas: 45,746 dataGas: 0 gasPrice: 0$ gasToken: 0x000…000 refundReceiver: 0x000…000 signatures: (multisig)Something is off. The transaction’s value is set to 0, so no ETH is being transferred. Also, the operation field was changed from 0 to 1, and there&amp;#x27;s a new data field called delegatecall. Let&amp;#x27;s break it down.This operation has a 1 flag, meaning it’s a delegatecall rather than a regular call. In Ethereum, a delegatecall lets the target contract (0x96221423681A6d52E184D440a8eFCEbB105C7242) run its code using the proxy’s storage. This is critical because any changes to the target’s storage affect the proxy’s storage, including the slot that holds the implementation contract address.The target contract (0x96221423681A6d52E184D440a8eFCEbB105C7242) is simple but dangerous. Written in pseudocode, it looks like this:storage:   	stor0: uint256 at storage 0 def _fallback() payable:   	revert def transfer(address _to, uint256 _value) payable:   	require calldata.size - 4 &amp;gt;= 64       	require _to == _to       	stor0 = _toThe data field (0xa9059cbb…) triggers the transfer function. The first four bytes (0xa9059cbb) are the Keccak-256 hash of &amp;quot;transfer(address,uint256)&amp;quot;, telling the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM) to execute the transfer. The next 32 bytes (0xbDd077f651EBe7f7b3cE16fe5F2b025BE2969516) represent the _to address. The _value is 0, but that doesn’t matter here. When executed, transfer updates stor0 to 0xbDd077f651EBe7f7b3cE16fe5F2b025BE2969516. But since this is a delegatecall, stor0 doesn’t belong to the target contract; it belongs to the proxy’s storage at slot 0. Before the transaction, slot 0 held 0x34CfAC646f301356fAa8B21e94227e3583Fe3F5F, which was Safe’s legitimate implementation. After execution, it was overwritten with an attacker-controlled contract: 0xbDd077f651EBe7f7b3cE16fe5F2b025BE2969516. In a single signed transaction, Bybit’s cold wallet proxy was redirected from Safe’s secure logic to the attacker’s contract. Employees believed they were approving a 30,000 ETH transfer to the hot wallet, but the Safe UI, compromised by a supply chain attack days earlier, masked the real payload. We&amp;#x27;ll get to that part soon.With the proxy now pointing to 0x47666fab8bd0ac7003bce3f5c3585383f09486e2, the attacker acted immediately. That same day, they broadcasted transaction 0xb61413c495fdad6114a7aa863a00b2e3c28945979a10885b12b30316ea9f072c. Instead of calling execTransaction, they used sweepETH on the proxy, which forwarded the call to the new implementation. The attack contract contained this function:def sweepETH(address _param1) payable:   	[...]   	call _param1 with:     	value self.balance       	[...]It’s brutally simple: transfer all ETH in the contract to _param1. In this case, _param1 was 0x47666fab8bd0ac7003bce3f5c3585383f09486e2, an attacker-controlled address. The cold wallet held 401,000 ETH ($1.5 billion). With a single call, the attacker drained it all. No multisig approvals were required. They now had full control of the wallet.Breaking down how Safe{Wallet} was compromisedThe Bybit hack didn’t start on February 21, 2025. It began days earlier with a hidden breach of Safe{Wallet}’s infrastructure. While details are still emerging, forensic reports from Sygnia and Verichains suggest a supply chain attack on the Safe UI, the web interface used by Bybit’s signers. The entry point? A compromised developer’s machine, hacked using tactics linked to North Korea’s Lazarus Group. Here’s how the attack unfolded, from the initial breach to the tampered UI that deceived Bybit’s team.First, hack the developerHacking a machine in a high-stakes environment like Safe’s development team isn’t a quick smash-and-grab. It’s a slow, deliberate process. The Lazarus Group, known for its advanced cyber campaigns, excels in this kind of attack. They don’t force their way in; they exploit trust. Forensic evidence suggests they targeted a Safe UI developer using a familiar tactic: social engineering.It starts with a simple message. A &amp;quot;recruiter&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;job candidate&amp;quot; reaches out on LinkedIn or email, building rapport over days or weeks. They discuss a fake job opportunity or collaboration. Then comes the ask &amp;quot;download and run this sample project&amp;quot; to assess skills. Or maybe they send a PDF exploiting a known vulnerability in an outdated reader. A single click, and a backdoor quietly installs itself. Sometimes, it&amp;#x27;s even easier: a project requiring a quick npm i, pulling in malicious dependencies from a compromised package. In this specific case, forensic analysis revealed a chilling detail: the developer&amp;#x27;s machine was compromised by a Docker container running in privileged mode, with the dangerous &amp;#x27;privileged&amp;#x27; flag concealed, likely craftily, within a configuration file. Nothing seems off. But now, the attacker has access.Once inside, the Lazarus Group takes its time. They scan the developer’s machine for valuable data (e.g. SSH keys, VPN credentials, AWS tokens). In this case, they struck gold: credentials to Safe’s AWS S3 bucket, where the Safe UI’s JavaScript code was stored. This wasn’t luck. It was careful planning, the kind of methodical attack Lazarus is known for when targeting crypto firms.Second, prepare the trapWith stolen AWS S3 credentials, the attackers didn’t rush to upload malware, they studied their prize. Their target was the Safe UI’s codebase, a key part of the multisig workflow. They likely spent days analyzing how it displayed transactions and interacted with Ledger devices. Their goal? Modify it just enough to turn it into a weapon without raising suspicion.On February 19, 2025, they made their move. Using the stolen credentials, they uploaded a tampered JavaScript file to the S3 bucket. This wasn’t a messy hack, it was precise. The modified UI introduced two key changes:Targeted Activation: The malicious code only triggered for Bybit’s multisig signers, identified by their wallet address (0x1Db92e2EeBC8E0c075a02BeA49a2935BcD2dFCF4) or session data. Other Safe users saw nothing unusual. The attackers focused on their biggest target, but in theory, every Safe UI user was at risk.UI Deception: When Bybit’s signers logged in on February 21, the UI showed a routine 30,000 ETH transfer to their hot wallet. Behind the scenes, the transaction data sent to their Ledger devices had been swapped. Instead of an execTransaction for 30,000 ETH (operation: 0), it injected the delegatecall payload we analyzed earlier—operation: 1, targeting 0x96221423681A6d52E184D440a8eFCEbB105C7242.The genius and horror of this attack was its subtlety. The signers saw a familiar interface, connected their Ledger devices, and signed what they thought was a normal transfer. The malicious JavaScript didn’t need to steal keys or hack devices, it simply fed them a lie. The Ledger signed the attack transaction (0x46deef0f…), Safe broadcasted it, and the attackers took control of the cold wallet.Third, wait for the payoffAfter uploading the modified code, the Lazarus Group played the waiting game. They knew Bybit’s cold wallet operations were infrequent and only triggered when the hot wallet needed a refill. On February 21, that moment arrived. Bybit’s signers loaded the Safe UI, pulling the malicious JavaScript from the compromised S3 bucket. The trap sprang: they signed the rigged transaction, and the attacker’s contract took over, draining all Bybit ETH hours later.What the code revealsThe recovered JavaScript code shows how precise the attackers were. Instead of rewriting the whole UI, they changed just a few key lines. One part targeted Bybit’s wallet to keep the attack focused. Another adjusted the transaction display, showing a legitimate transfer while sneaking in the delegatecall payload for signing. These small, careful changes made the attack hard to detect, until it was too late.Billions of dollars cannot be secured by amateursThis compromise wasn’t just Bybit’s problem, it could have easily led to a systemic meltdown similar to what happened with FTX, knowing that Safe stores over a $100 billion (!). The fact that the attackers could infiltrate their UI with such ease raises so many questions. Consider this and let it sink in: every user of Safe was a potential target, Bybit just had the deepest pockets.Moreover, the Bybit/Safe hack has exposed a fundamental truth about crypto security: it doesn’t matter how strong your smart contracts are if the infrastructure behind them is fragile, centralized, and mismanaged. Safe, despite positioning itself as a leading decentralized smart contract wallet, was built on an immature and insecure foundation. Unlike other leaders like OpenZeppelin, which maintains strict security protocols and holds SOC 2 and ISO 27001 certifications, Safe had no such certifications in place. This means no formal audits, no structured compliance processes, and no assurances that security best practices were followed. We will double-click on this later.Security starts with governance, and Safe lacked it. As one insider put it, the team was just “a bunch of devs in Switzerland and Berlin” with no managed endpoints (i.e. engineers worked on personal machines, not company-controlled, security-hardened devices). This is one of the biggest operational security failures imaginable for a company securing billions of dollars in assets. Without managed endpoints, a single phishing attack or malware infection could compromise everything. It’s no surprise that an exploit eventually happened.Safe’s backend wasn’t decentralized at all, it was an over-engineered, centralized mess. Their own Github repository, safe-infrastructure, reveals how their entire system depended on PostgreSQL and Redis databases for transaction state and indexing, RabbitMQ queues to process transaction requests, and a single gateway API (safe-client API) to handle all transaction broadcasts. This wasn’t a decentralized protocol at all, it was a highly fragile and trivially normal system that was used as the backbone of Ethereum’s global treasury management. The entire infrastructure was controlled, maintained, and operated by a small team with no formal security governance. Worse still, it is all configured on one single Docker Compose file, which, once again, is a brittle and dangerous setup for a platform managing billions of dollars.Safe’s infrastructure was so centralized that at one point, its core services were shut down without warning, directly impacting projects relying on its transaction relayers. A frustrated developer called them out on GitHub: “That sounds like quite a big thing for people who build products on top of these services and maybe something that shouldn&amp;#x27;t just be communicated in a Twitter thread.” For a project branding itself as “decentralized,” the ability to unilaterally pause critical infrastructure is a glaring contradiction. This was not a trustless system, it was a single point of failure masquerading as the opposite.Yet, despite this fiasco, billions of dollars remain locked in Safe wallets. While some users exited after the Bybit/Safe breach, most either trust the contract layer blindly or claim to have no other viable alternatives. Onchain data from Dune Analytics shows that Safe’s TVL is still in the billions, proving that the market is slow (or too irresponsible) to react to critical infrastructure failures.The Safe scandal is a wake-up call: crypto security isn’t just about smart contracts, but information security at large, including operational security, governance, and real infrastructure resilience. At some point, the industry needs to stop confusing decentralization theater with actual security. If you’re managing billions of dollars, you need more than good smart contracts. You need real security, real governance, and real engineering discipline. Safe had none of these, and the Bybit/Safe hack was the inevitable result.How to prevent the next billion dollar hackThis $1.5 billion exploit came down to two main flaws: blind signing in an insecure interface and exposing critical secrets in a highly adversarial environment. How do we prevent this from happening again? We’ll break down the weaknesses in Safe’s design, suggest a safer approach, and show how Dfns puts these principles into practice.“Blind signing” and user-side transaction forgingThe Safe UI’s failure started with a critical mistake: it exposed the raw blockchain transaction (i.e. the exact data sent to Ethereum) on the user’s computer. The UI processed this data to show key details (e.g., “Send 30,000 ETH to the hot wallet”), but then forwarded the full transaction to the Ledger device for signing. This setup assumed the user’s computer, used by Bybit employees, was secure. It wasn’t.User devices are a security risk. Employees browse the web, open emails, install apps, and sometimes even play games, any of which could introduce malware. Remote work makes it worse: how do you protect a laptop at home from physical tampering? In Bybit’s case, the compromised Safe UI modified an obscure transaction field from 0 to 1, an invisible change to the signers. The Ledger’s small screen and sub-par UX made verifying the raw transaction (a long hex string like 0xa9059cbb…) almost impossible. The result? Blind signing, where trust in the UI became a fatal weakness.This design treated the user’s computer as the source of truth for creating and signing transactions. That was the mistake. Personal devices are inherently untrustworthy, and critical operations, like crafting a transaction that controls $1.5 billion, should never happen there. If malicious JavaScript can modify the data before it reaches the Ledger, no amount of multisig security can protect you.User-hosted keys are ticking time bombsEven worse, Safe’s setup left critical secrets (i.e. the private keys used for those Ledger signatures) on the user side. While Ledger devices can protect keys from direct theft, the surrounding environment is wide open. Lose the device, have it stolen in a fire, or deal with an employee suddenly leaving, and you&amp;#x27;re in trouble. Multisig helps by requiring multiple signatures instead of one, but key rotations still expose those secrets. If an attacker hijacks the UI (as happened here) or compromises a device, it&amp;#x27;s over the moment a key signs a malicious transaction. No policy or access control can reverse an on-chain signature.Intent-based transactions and secure infrastructureSo, what’s the fix? First, stop forging raw transactions on the user side. Instead, let users express an intent—a plain-English description of what they want (e.g., “Transfer 30,000 ETH from cold wallet to hot wallet XYZ”). This intent gets sent to a secure server operated by the wallet provider. That server—running in a monitored, isolated environment like a confidential computing enclave—translates the intent into a raw blockchain transaction. Why does this work?Centralized Control: The server, not the user’s device, forges the transaction. It’s not browsing Reddit or opening PDFs—it’s a locked-down system dedicated to this task.Policy Enforcement: Before forging, the server checks predefined rules. For Bybit, a policy might say, “Funds can only move from cold wallet to hot wallet XYZ.” If the intent matches, the transaction is crafted; if not, it’s rejected.Human-Readable Validation: Key fields (amount, recipient) can change, but obscure ones (like operation) stay locked. No hidden delegatecalls slipping through.Second, don’t ever expose private keys to users. Instead of holding keys directly, users should get access tokens, which are revocable credentials that authorize the provider’s secure system to sign on their behalf. The actual private keys stay locked inside a Hardware Security Module (HSM) or a Multi-Party Computation (MPC) setup, never leaving the provider’s control. Lose a token? Revoke it. No key leaks, no multisig resets. This follows NIST security best practices (see Recommendation for Key Management, SP 800-57 Part 1 Rev. 5) widely used in traditional information security, and sorely needed in blockchain finance. At Dfns, we call this “network-hosted keys” or the “NHK model” (as opposed to “user-hosted keys” or the “UHK model”). We&amp;#x27;ve been advocating for this key deployment approach since 2019, despite most of the industry rushing to cater to “DeFi” and align with so-called non-custodial setups, or ideals shall we say.Closing the deception gap in admin experiencesThe UI needs a rethink. Safe’s JavaScript-based interface was an easy target. Attackers could swap the displayed transaction with a fake one. A secure UI should be tamper-proof, ideally built into the browser and cryptographically verifiable. This is where WebAuthn and passkeys come in. Using asymmetric cryptography, they authenticate users and sign intents without exposing secrets. Combined with WebAuthn’s latest Secure Payment Confirmation (SPC), operating systems like iOS can now present key transaction details (e.g. amount, recipient, etc.) in a browser-native dialog that JavaScript can’t alter. This ensures users sign exactly what they see.We need strong corporate security more than ever Finally, companies must treat user-side risks as a corporate security issue. Mandate hardware security keys (e.g. Yubikeys) for authentication, enforce regular audits of employee devices, and use confidential computing for sensitive operations. Governance, access controls, monitoring, and attestation must protect the systems forging and signing transactions, not just the keys themselves.The downside of Ethereum’s smart contract upgradabilityNow that we’ve covered the key players in the near-catastrophic chain of events (the smart contract provider, the hardware device, and the exchange employees) it’s time to address the underlying protocol: Ethereum. We’re not afraid to say it. One of the core reasons the Bybit/Safe hack escalated so dramatically is tied to Ethereum’s account-based smart contract model and its approach to upgradability. Unlike UTXO-based models, Ethereum allows smart contracts to store funds centrally under a single contract address. In the case of Bybit, this meant that a vast sum—$1.5 billion—was controlled by a single Safe contract.The real vulnerability, however, was in how that contract could be modified. Safe, like many other Ethereum-based smart contract wallets, supports upgradability via delegatecall, a feature that lets a contract execute external logic while maintaining its own storage. This means an attacker who gains control over the contract’s logic can execute arbitrary code while retaining control over all stored funds. That’s exactly what happened: once the malicious upgrade was deployed, it overrode the contract’s behavior and allowed attackers to drain funds instantly.Ethereum’s flexibility makes it an innovation platform, but they also introduce security tradeoffs. The delegatecall exploit that enabled the Bybit/Safe hack is an inherent risk of Ethereum’s contract architecture, one that other chains mitigate through different account models, or stricter governance mechanisms. But not all blockchains operate this way, and many are inherently more resistant to this type of exploit. Here’s why:UTXO-based models: Unlike Ethereum, these blockchains don’t use account-based smart contracts where funds accumulate in a single address. Instead, funds are controlled by discrete, independent outputs, each locked with specific spending conditions. In Canton for example, each holding is a separate contract (i.e., a distinct UTXO) and cannot be unilaterally upgraded without all signatories’ explicit consent. This inherently limits the blast radius if any single key or interface is compromised. Moreover, the UTXO design ensures you’re signing an exact transaction outcome—no hidden switches, no last-second toggles of malicious flags—so either that specific transaction occurs or nothing happens at all. Together, these architectural choices fundamentally reduce an attacker’s ability to hijack an entire wallet’s balance through a single malicious contract upgrade.Immutable smart contracts: Some blockchains, like Solana and Cosmos, discourage or entirely prevent smart contract upgradability. Once deployed, smart contracts on these networks are immutable unless explicitly designed otherwise. This removes the attack surface that delegatecall-based upgradability creates. While Solana does allow program upgrades, it requires explicit governance approvals rather than an open-ended delegatecall mechanism.Multisig and hardware controls: Some chains implement governance-based upgrades that require multi-sig confirmations or quorum approvals rather than direct admin overrides. This ensures that any contract change goes through multiple verifications, significantly reducing the risk of a single compromised key leading to a systemic failure.If Bybit had used Dfns instead of Safe{Wallet}At Dfns, we’ve built this model from the ground up. Here’s how it works:Passkeys with WebAuthn: Users authenticate using a Yubikey or secure enclave (e.g., on a Mac). Their private key signs a challenge; we verify it with their public key. No shared secrets, no spoofing.Intent-based workflow: Users express an intent (e.g. “Transfer 30,000 ETH from cold wallet to hot wallet XYZ”) and sign it with their passkey. The browser’s WebAuthn UI (via SPC) shows the details, unmodifiable by JavaScript.Server-side forging: Our isolated server, running in a confidential computing environment, validates the intent against wallet policies (e.g., “Only hot wallet XYZ is allowed”). If it passes, the transaction is forged and signed using MPC-stored keys.Token-based access: Users hold access tokens, not keys. If compromised, we revoke the token: no key exposure, no damage.Let’s move forward. Instead of Safe, now let’s imagine Bybit had used Dfns on February 21, 2025. Their cold wallet would have had a policy: “Transfers only to hot wallet XYZ, approved by three employees.” An employee logs in with a Yubikey, enters their PIN, and initiates a transfer: “Move 30,000 ETH to XYZ.” A WebAuthn prompt appears, confirming: “30,000 ETH to XYZ.” They approve it, and two colleagues do the same with their Yubikeys. The signed intent reaches Dfns’ server. The policy engine verifies XYZ, builds the raw transaction (operation: 0), and signs it using MPC in our case. The transaction is broadcasted: 30,000 ETH moves safely. Now, imagine hackers tampering with the UI to display “30,000 ETH to XYZ” while secretly sending an intent for a different address. WebAuthn exposes them, it shows the actual destination, warning the signer. Even if it slips through, the policy engine kills it: the address isn’t XYZ, so the transfer never happens. No delegatecall, no $1.5 billion loss. The raw transaction stays clean because the user side never forges it. Trusting user-side environments for critical operations is a risk we can’t take. The solution? Shift transaction forging to secure servers, protect secrets with tokens, and use tamper-proof UIs like WebAuthn. That’s how we build systems that don’t just survive but thrive in adversarial conditions. At Dfns, we’re proving it works. The next $1.5 billion hack doesn’t have to happen.Corporate security is a product featureThe Bybit/Safe breach highlights a critical issue: infrastructure security is often overlooked in “web3 native” projects. Safe, like many DeFi platforms, relied on smart contracts and Ethereum-based logic, assuming these alone would ensure security. But the attack had nothing to do with smart contract flaws, it happened because a single developer’s compromised laptop gave attackers access to Safe’s AWS S3 environment. This was a failure of corporate security, not blockchain security. Safe lacked SOC 2 or ISO certifications, meaning essential safeguards, like continuous access reviews, third-party audits, and strict cloud governance, were missing. In contrast, Dfns follows zero-trust principles, advanced compliance standards, and strict corporate security protocols to eliminate single points of failure. Unlike setups where one developer can deploy production code unchecked, our processes are continuously monitored, logged, and audited. Any infrastructure changes require peer reviews, automated checks, and multi-party approvals. If Safe had these controls, the S3 breach wouldn’t have happened. Instead of relying on the flawed belief that “a multisig is enough,” we enforce a security framework built on international standards, external audits, and accountability at every level, based on best practices such as:Principle of Least Privilege (PoLP): We issue narrow, time-limited permissions for every role, so even if a developer’s machine were compromised, the attackers couldn’t jump straight into our CI/CD pipeline or rewrite code in AWS.No Single Point of Failure (No SPOF): Any critical change—deployment, config update, key rotation—needs approvals from multiple, independent parties. This design means no single dev, no matter how senior, can unilaterally inject malicious updates.Just-in-Time (JIT) Access: Elevated privileges expire automatically after a short window. Attackers would find those higher-level credentials gone if they tried to exploit them hours or even minutes later.Security goes way beyond smart contractsAt Dfns, we don’t assume that “if our smart contract code is audited, we’re safe.” Security extends beyond onchain logic—it includes developer endpoints, cloud infrastructure, and internal policies. We apply the same rigor to every layer:Strict CI/CD and code signing: Every codecommit is scanned, peer-reviewed, and cryptographically signed. If Safe had enforced a similar process for front-end changes, the malicious snippet would have been flagged long before production.Mandatory MFA and hardware tokens: Employees must use hardware-based MFA for Slack, GitHub, AWS, and other services. This blocks common supply chain attacks that rely on phishing and stolen keys.Continuous monitoring and threat detection: Our SIEM system analyzes logs across all services. Suspicious activity—like an unauthorized front-end modification—triggers alerts and can lock down systems automatically.The Safe breach is a reminder that secure smart contracts don’t mean secure infrastructure. Dfns combines blockchain innovation with rigorous, compliance-driven security to prevent the exact type of compromise that led to Bybit’s $1.5 billion loss. If the industry wants to avoid the next multi-billion-dollar disaster, it must move beyond smart contract audits and adopt zero trust, verifiable compliance, and holistic security—just like Dfns.Thank you to José Aguinaga, CEO of Tungsten, for his insights on digital custody and security. His expertise in governance and risk controls continues to shape the industry’s approach to resilient custody solutions.Must-read references‍José Perez Aguinaga&amp;#x27;s LinkedIn post highlights the critical lessons on digital custody strategy, emphasizing governance measures, risk controls, and the need for robust multi-layer defenses against similar attacks.‍Security Alliance DPRK Advisory led by samczsun presents official guidance and threat intelligence on North Korean (DPRK) state-sponsored hacking, including detailed profiles of infiltration methods, social engineering tactics, and advanced laundering techniques. It underscores how groups like Lazarus leverage front-end compromises and malicious code injections—tactics central to the ByBit hack—and provides best-practice security recommendations to mitigate these risks.‍Elliptic’s Examination of the ByBit Hack covers the scale and laundering strategies behind the hack, delving into how stolen ETH was routed through hundreds of addresses and various no-KYC services. Discusses how forensic blockchain analysis can trace and sometimes freeze illicit funds.‍Chainalysis Report on the ByBit Hack explains how Chainalysis helped track the theft in real-time, identify DPRK-linked addresses, and freeze roughly $40 million in assets. It also underscores the importance of rapid incident response and cross-border collaboration among blockchain intelligence firms and law enforcement.‍Substack Analysis by Harry Donnelly offers a deep dive into the ByBit/Safe exploit—covering the social engineering elements, malicious snippet injection in the user interface, and the smart contract manipulation that enabled the $1.5 billion theft.AuthorsThibault de Lachèze-MurelChief Information Security OfficerThibault de Lachèze-Murel is the Head of Security of Dfns. Before his current role, Thibault held various leadership roles in security at the Stellar Foundation, Google, the French Armed Forces, and the French Ministry of Defense. He holds a MSc in Computer and Information Systems Security from Télécom SudParis and has authored several patents.Christopher Grilhault des FontainesCo-CEO &amp;amp; Co-founderChristopher Grilhault des Fontaines is the co-CEO and co-founder of Dfns. He’s also Chairman of the Supervisory Board of Super Capital and investor at Wagmi Ventures. Chris is a serial founder who’s worked across HR Tech, Sports, Food and Social media industries before joining the world of cybersecurity and blockchain finance at Dfns. He holds a BSc degree in Liberal Arts and Philosophy from the Bordeaux University as well as an MSc degree in Management and Organizational Behavior Studies from Dauphine University.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/67cefcd121cde8e3b0a1deab_the_bybit_hack-min__2_.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Polymesh Support</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfns.co/article/polymesh-support</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/article/polymesh-support"/>
    <content type="html">Dfns now supports Polymesh as a Tier-1 blockchain, enabling secure, compliant wallets for regulated assets and financial institutions.We&amp;#x27;re excited to announce that the Polymesh blockchain is now fully integrated into the Dfns Wallet-as-a-Service platform as a Tier-1 blockchain. This integration enhances our partner ecosystem and brings better features for developers and users on the Polymesh network.What is the Polymesh blockchain?Polymesh is a Layer 1 blockchain purpose-built for regulated assets, offering compliance, identity verification, and security features tailored to financial institutions. Key features include:Purpose-built for security tokens: Polymesh is designed to meet the compliance needs of regulated assets, ensuring seamless tokenization with built-in identity and governance frameworks.Onchain identity verification: Unlike traditional public blockchains, Polymesh requires identity verification for network participants, making it compliant with regulatory standards.Governance and compliance: Polymesh offers a governance model designed for financial institutions, enabling secure and compliant asset issuance, trading, and settlement.Finality and settlement: Polymesh provides instant, deterministic settlement without prefunding, and prevents unwanted transactions or airdrops through trade affirmation requirements.Dfns unlocks Tier-1 status for PolymeshOur Tier-1 integration with Polymesh delivers full wallet and transaction capabilities through Dfns, including:Automatic token detection: Wallets instantly recognize Polymesh’s native token, POLYX, eliminating manual updates and simplifying portfolio management.On-chain transfer history: Track all POLYX transactions effortlessly, ensuring transparency and simplifying audits.Transaction management: Securely generate signatures, transfer POLYX, and broadcast transactions through a single wallet API and interface.Webhook notifications: Get real-time alerts for balance changes and transaction updates, allowing dApps and blockchain services to react quickly and efficiently.Start building with Polymesh and DfnsDfns now supports Polymesh as a Tier-1 blockchain, providing secure and compliant wallets for developers, financial institutions, and users. These wallets are ideal for trading, payments, banking, tokenization, and other financial services.Get started with Polymesh today: app.dfns.io/get-startedAuthorsPierre BeugnetLead Blockchain EngineerPierre Beugnet is Lead Blockchain Engineer at Dfns. He has over 10 years of experience in software engineering roles, specializing in digital assets and financial technology. Before joining Dfns, Pierre held senior positions at Bottlepay (acq by NYDIG), Société Générale, AXA, Crédit Suisse and OVH Cloud, focusing on institutional trading and Bitcoin technologies. Pierre holds a Bachelor&amp;#x27;s and a Master&amp;#x27;s degree in Physics from Pierre and Marie Curie University as well as Polytechnique.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/67c62589b798609291fade40_Annoucement%20integration.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SOC 2 Renewed by KPMG</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfns.co/article/soc-2-renewed-by-kpmg</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfns.co/article/soc-2-renewed-by-kpmg"/>
    <content type="html">Dfns achieves zero-exception SOC 2 Type II certification with KPMG, raising the bar for security and compliance in 2024.Dfns has successfully renewed its SOC 2 Type II certification for 2024 after a rigorous nine-month audit by KPMG, one of the Big Four firms. The audit, covering January 1 to September 30, evaluated the security and availability of our Wallets-as-a-Service (WaaS) system. The report confirms the strength and reliability of our security controls, reinforcing our commitment to protecting our clients&amp;#x27; digital assets with the highest standards of security, availability, processing integrity, confidentiality, and privacy.What makes this achievement stand out is that KPMG&amp;#x27;s report found &amp;quot;no exceptions noted&amp;quot; throughout the entire audit. This is a big step up from Dfns&amp;#x27; 2023 SOC 2 Type II audit, where 3% of our controls had exceptions. This year&amp;#x27;s result highlights Dfns&amp;#x27; commitment to constant improvement and the highest security standards.Key Highlights from the 2024 SOC 2 Type II ReportStrong security controls: The audit reviewed our security and availability measures, covering risk management, encryption, network security, access controls, and operational resilience.Zero issues found: No control deficiencies were reported—every security measure was designed and operated effectively.Independent validation: KPMG, a top global auditing firm part of the “Big Four,” confirmed our systems meet and exceed security standards.Compliance and scalability: Dfns’ infrastructure is built for continuous compliance and seamless performance at scale.Breaking “empty shell” criticism and checkbox mentalitySOC 2 (System and Organization Controls 2) is a voluntary compliance standard for service organizations, established by the American Institute of CPAs (AICPA). Recognized as one of the most rigorous compliance frameworks for technology companies, it assesses both the design and operational effectiveness of security controls over an extended period. The framework is built around five Trust Service Criteria: Security, Availability, Processing Integrity, Confidentiality, and Privacy. SOC 2 Type II, in particular, involves a thorough, independent audit of a company’s systems, processes, and controls over a period of 6 to 12 months, ensuring continuous adherence to these criteria. As financial institutions and fintech platforms demand robust, battle-tested security, this certification provides authoritative validation that Dfns upholds the highest standards of data protection, operational resilience, and compliance maturity.However, SOC 2 is sometimes dismissed as a mere formality, even among security professionals, considered as a compliance exercise without true security rigor. Critics argue that many SOC 2 reports are little more than “empty shells,” offering the appearance of security rather than substantive protection. This skepticism stems from several factors:SOC 2 is not a one-size-fits-all standard. A company can include as few as 100 controls in its report or expand to 1,000, yet both may claim SOC 2 Type II compliance. The difference in their actual security posture, however, could be vast.The credibility of a SOC 2 report depends on the auditor. While an assessment from a lesser-known firm may satisfy the baseline requirements, it does not carry the same weight as an audit conducted by a Big Four firm like KPMG, which adheres to stricter methodologies and higher standards.For some, SOC 2 is a box-ticking exercise. Organizations that approach it as a regulatory hurdle rather than a fundamental security practice may meet the minimum requirements without embedding security into their culture or operations.We acknowledge the criticisms and take them seriously. Our approach to SOC 2 is not about superficial compliance but about ensuring our report is a true reflection of the facts and evidence we put forward to show our commitment to security. At its core, SOC 2 is designed to provide transparency and assurance, demonstrating how an organization safeguards customer data. It should be more than just a credential; it is a foundational framework for establishing trust in an increasingly complex digital environment. With that said, compliance alone does not guarantee security. The true value of a SOC 2 report lies in its details:Scope and depth of controls: A SOC 2 report can encompass a broad spectrum of security controls, from fundamental access management to advanced encryption techniques. The breadth and depth of the controls included in the audit define the rigor of the security assessment. At Dfns, we have deliberately adopted a significantly more extensive and stringent control set than the industry norm, underscoring our commitment to exceeding security expectations.  Ask yourself: How many controls are evaluated? Are they comprehensive and meaningful?Auditor reputation: The credibility of a SOC 2 report is heavily influenced by the reputation and rigor of the auditing firm. An audit conducted by a Big Four firm like KPMG—known for its uncompromising standards and global recognition—holds far greater weight than one performed by a lesser-known entity.  Ask yourself: Was the auditor a recognized authority with stringent methodologies?Transparency and evidence: A well-executed SOC 2 Type II report provides extensive documentation and concrete evidence supporting the auditor’s findings. This level of transparency enables clients to thoroughly assess an organization’s security posture and make informed decisions.  Ask yourself: Are the results verifiable and backed by detailed evidence?Adequacy of security measures: Security controls should not only meet compliance requirements but also align with industry best practices and adapt to evolving threats. A strong SOC 2 report demonstrates resilience beyond the audit period, ensuring continuous protection against emerging risks.  Ask yourself: Do the controls reflect best practices and proactively address evolving threats?Why is Dfns’ SOC 2 report any different?While the criticisms mentioned above are often valid, our SOC 2 report offers a different perspective. Our objective is not to claim superiority over others but to maintain transparency about the controls we have implemented and the evidence supporting their effectiveness—proving, rather than assuming, their reliability. Rather than viewing SOC 2 as a compliance checkbox, we approach it as a dynamic framework for establishing meaningful, verifiable security protections. In 2024 alone, Dfns has implemented over 360 security controls, covering key areas such as:Encryption &amp;amp; key management: AES-256 encryption secures data at rest, while TLS 1.3 protects data in use and in transit. Multi-Party Computation (MPC) with Distributed Key Generation (DKG) and Zero-Knowledge Proofs (ZKP) ensures cryptographic integrity, preventing key reconstitution.Granular access control: Enforced role-based access follows the Principle of Least Privilege (PoLP), with strict separation of environments (production, pre-production, staging, test). Just-in-Time (JIT) access controls and Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) enhance security and minimize exposure.Continuous monitoring: Advanced security tools, including Datadog, AWS CloudTrail, Socket.dev, and Wazuh, provide real-time threat detection across infrastructure and open-source dependencies, ensuring proactive anomaly detection.Incident response preparedness: Regular simulations—like phishing, DDoS, and insider threat drills—ensure operational resilience. A structured incident response plan with severity-based categorization enables swift and effective mitigation, tested at least annually for continuous refinement.Risk &amp;amp; vendor management: Ongoing security diligence includes annual penetration testing, risk assessments, vulnerability scanning, and threat modeling. Third-party oversight extends to application monitoring, AWS SOC 2 report reviews, business continuity planning, and disaster recovery protocols.Robust control environment: Security is embedded in Dfns&amp;#x27; culture through a clear Code of Conduct, meticulous logging, stringent access controls, and unwavering ethical standards.Resilient data recovery: Redundant storage and snapshot technology ensure comprehensive backup and recovery, minimizing the risk and impact of data loss.Beyond rigorous controls and KPMG’s audit, we provide additional guarantees of security diligence:Public transparency: Tools like StatusPage keep clients informed on system health and uptime.Training programs: Mandatory security awareness training upon hire and annually thereafter ensures that all employees remain knowledgeable about security risks.Data protection: Implementation of layered backups and geographically separated data storage (300 miles minimum) ensures data resiliency and disaster readiness.Governance oversight: Regular board reviews of our cybersecurity program, engaging external experts as needed.Whistleblower policy: Clearly outlined anonymous communication channels demonstrate a commitment to ethical practices and transparency.Why this matters for our clientsWhether securing insurance, navigating regulatory requirements, ensuring transparency, or fortifying your security posture, our audit results deliver tangible value. Cyber insurers, for instance, evaluate risk based on the strength of a company’s security controls. A zero-exception SOC 2 Type II audit from KPMG signals a lower risk profile, enabling clients to negotiate better coverage, reduced premiums, and faster underwriting. By validating our security posture through a Big Four audit, we eliminate uncertainty for insurers—directly benefiting our clients.Financial institutions and fintech platforms operate within stringent regulatory frameworks across multiple jurisdictions. Integrating with a SOC 2-certified infrastructure like Dfns allows clients to streamline compliance with GDPR, DORA, ISO 27001, ISO 22380, the GENIUS Act, and other financial regulations. Rather than spending months proving security maturity to regulators, clients can rely on our independently verified controls as a cornerstone of their compliance strategy.A SOC 2 Type II report provides a clear, in-depth view of how security is implemented, tested, and maintained. With over 360 security controls covering encryption, access management, monitoring, and risk assessments, clients gain full transparency into the reliability of the platform they depend on. Unlike generic security assurances, our zero-exception audit proves that every measure we implement has been rigorously tested under real-world conditions.For security and compliance teams, managing third-party risk is an ongoing challenge. Dfns&amp;#x27; SOC 2 certification significantly eases this burden, offering a fully auditable, independently validated security framework. Instead of conducting extensive due diligence from scratch, teams can leverage our audit as a trusted baseline—saving time and reducing risk. With continuous monitoring, real-time threat detection, and an infrastructure built for resilience at scale, security leaders can shift their focus from vendor security gaps to strategic priorities.To learn more about our security practices and to access our SOC 2 Type II report, please contact us: security@dfns.co.AuthorsThibault de Lachèze-MurelChief Information Security OfficerThibault de Lachèze-Murel is the Head of Security of Dfns. Before his current role, Thibault held various leadership roles in security at the Stellar Foundation, Google, the French Armed Forces, and the French Ministry of Defense. He holds a MSc in Computer and Information Systems Security from Télécom SudParis and has authored several patents.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/665eef502b52c00091a2a467/67bf208b57b7aa2e4f562456_SOC%20II%20Renewal-min.jpg"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
