<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Latest Articles | DIA</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.diadata.org/blog/category/latest/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=BrowserlessCSSBridge&amp;browserless_url=http%3A%2F%2F10.0.0.124%3A3050%2F&amp;browserless&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.diadata.org%2Fblog%2Fcategory%2Flatest%2F&amp;url_selector=.box+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2Fpost%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.article-content&amp;content_cleanup=.categories%2C.article-title%2C%5Bitemprop%3D%22author%22%5D&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=%5Bitemprop%3D%22datePublished%22%5D&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=%5Bitemprop%3D%22name%22%5D&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=BrowserlessCSSBridge&amp;browserless_url=http%3A%2F%2F10.0.0.124%3A3050%2F&amp;browserless&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.diadata.org%2Fblog%2Fcategory%2Flatest%2F&amp;url_selector=.box+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2Fpost%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.article-content&amp;content_cleanup=.categories%2C.article-title%2C%5Bitemprop%3D%22author%22%5D&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=%5Bitemprop%3D%22datePublished%22%5D&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=%5Bitemprop%3D%22name%22%5D&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:44+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Cryptography vs PoS: Rethinking Blockchain Security | DIA Oracles</title>
    <published>2025-04-03T22:05:40+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-03T22:05:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.diadata.org/blog/post/cryptography-vs-cryptoeconomics-2025/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.diadata.org/blog/post/cryptography-vs-cryptoeconomics-2025/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Zygis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Cryptography is challenging PoS dominance. Explore how zkVMs, MPC, and restaking reshape blockchain security, trust, and the future of staking in Web3. Recent innovations in cryptographic and cryptoeconomic technologies are reshaping how we think about trust, incentives, and security in blockchain protocols. On the cryptographic front, tools such as Zero-Knowledge Virtual Machines (zkVMs), Multi-Party Computation (MPC), Trusted Execution Environments (TEEs), and Fully Homomorphic Encryption (FHE) are expanding what’s possible in decentralized computation. Meanwhile, restaking has emerged as a new cryptoeconomic primitive, enabling more efficient capital usage for securing networks. These technological breakthroughs in these areas now prompt a vital question: If we can prove anything without incurring large capital requirements, do we still need to spend billions on economic incentives? I’ll explore each element, providing examples and examining the broader implications for the crypto industry. The Great Shifts in Web3 SecurityPart 1: Cryptographic Security Recent advances in verifiable computation and zero-knowledge systems are reshaping the blockchain space. Rather than focusing on separate frameworks, today’s trend leans toward universal proof systems capable of validating large swaths of off-chain or cross-chain transactions with minimal trust. For instance, Succinct uses succinct proof mechanisms such as SP1 to build rollups with ZKP validity proofs or ZK fraud proofs. In a similar vein, RISC Zero with Boundless aims to support arbitrary computations across multiple chains by offloading execution to a cryptographic environment. Both reduce on-chain overhead and potentially lower the capital required for security. Even Ethereum core researcher Justin Drake recently introduced an idea “SNARKification” in Beam chain, which would incorporate SNARK-based, post-quantum cryptography using hash-based signatures that enable real-time consensus proof on standard hardware. On a similar note, Flashblocks are block pre-confirmations issued by the TEE block builder that allow to achieve faster ‘block’ times, or to be precise, transaction times. Recently, Unichain and Base have committed to implementing Flashblocks on their chains. MPC and FHE are still in early development, but solutions like Arcium and Zama are leading the way in adopting these latest cryptographic advancements for on-chain privacy and data encryption, which would unlock another major milestone in the crypto space of having fully verifiable encrypted computation. Part 2: Cryptoeconomics Security Historically, Proof-of-Stake (PoS) chains rely on validators locking up capital. Ethereum, for instance, sees billions of dollars staked, typically offering around 2-4% returns on ETH. Other networks like Solana or Celestia can spend 8-15% on rewards. These figures reflect the magnitude of incentives needed to deter misconduct. But if cryptographic proofs assure correctness, the necessity for large-scale token issuance or high fees may drop. Restaking, where new protocols effectively “rent” security from already-staked capital, amplifies this efficiency by allowing additional services to borrow existing trust relationships. In other words, blockchains can piggyback on Ethereum’s (and other major assets’) security without bootstrapping their own validator sets, reducing overhead and opening up more resources for actual development. Current estimates suggest that restaked capital might cost less than 1% of the total amount of security, which means the savings for protocols can become significantly lower compared to spinning up your own cryptoeconomic security incentive, while also having more robust assets securing the network. EigenLayer and Symbiotic are leading the way in restaking, having attracted $8.5b and $1b in TVL, respectively. Both of these platforms offer similar feature sets for developers building on top of these protocols, gradually reducing the need for pure economic incentives. Given that restaking introduces lower cost to high-quality capital and lower operational overhead, the cryptoeconomic breakthroughs will undoubtedly reshape the crypto landscape, opening up new possibilities for trust, security, and scalability. Can Cryptography Replace Economic Security?Economic incentives remain important for ensuring liveness and punishing actors who disrupt consensus. Yet, if cryptographic proofs can verify state transitions unambiguously, much of the validation process can shift away from capital lockups. For example, if zkVMs successfully prove complex transactions across different blockchains, validators no longer need to store and process each detail themselves. Instead, they can trust the proof, focusing more on block production and finalization. In this model, slashing risk becomes less central – capital lockups act more as a fallback measure. Still, purely cryptographic approaches don’t cover every threat; issues like denial-of-service or collusion might require financial disincentives. However, zkVMs also require incentives for ensuring honest participation in computation. Lagrange has been a good example in the space where it develops a universal ZK Prover Network with restaked capital as a backbone for honest validation. As Lagrange’s CEO &amp;amp; co-founder, Ismael Hishon-Rezaizade, put in a recent panel that I had the honor to moderate on why cryptography still requires cryptoeconomic security: If I request a proof from a given actor at a given point in time, how do I assure that that actor generates the proof property properly? How do I ensure there's liveness, there's censorship resistance, and all of the things that go into developing a protocol that predicates a core function on top of a zero-knowledge proof?Ismael Hishon-RezaizadeLagrange’s CEO &amp;amp; Co-Founder  Staking Isn’t Dead–It’s Just EvolvingEven if advanced cryptographic proofs minimize the reliance on continuous capital lockups, some form of staking likely remains critical for governance, network liveness, and addressing threats beyond state validity (e.g., bribery attacks, censorship, etc.). In many ways, a future dominated by cryptography would see these economic incentives evolve into a more supplemental mechanism. However, expanding restaking usage creates interconnected risk: if multiple protocols depend on the same validator capital, a slash event in one protocol could cascade. Hence, as cryptography takes on more responsibility, the complexity of shared security grows, requiring meticulous designs. This particular issue on the interconnected risk is being solved by using distinct capital for each protocol, however, capital utilization can be higher and thus cheaper for each protocol if it’s reused. Here’s Where Oracles Enter the ChatOracles, as a critical piece of infrastructure in the DeFi stack, stand to gain significantly from both cryptographic and cryptoeconomic advancements, especially in the case of DIA. As a builder in this space, I’m particularly excited about how these technologies unlock new possibilities for oracle design and security. Cryptographic Solution Cryptographic solutions such as zero-knowledge proofs (ZKPs) and verifiable computation can enhance the security and privacy of oracle data. For example, oracles can use ZKPs to prove the validity of data and prevent data manipulation in price derivation. Cryptoeconomic Solutions Cryptoeconomic solutions such as restaking can improve the efficiency and scalability of oracle networks. By allowing multiple protocols to share the same validator capital, oracles can reduce the cost of securing oracle services and increase the availability of data, while having more cryptoeconomic security. Applications and Use Cases Specifically, oracles can leverage cryptographic and cryptoeconomic solutions in the following ways:  Data verification: oracles can use ZKPs to verify the integrity and authenticity of data from various sources, ensuring that the data is accurate and reliable. Data privacy: oracles can use cryptographic techniques to protect the privacy of data sources, ensuring that sensitive information is not exposed. Incentivization: oracles can use cryptoeconomic mechanisms to incentivize data providers to share accurate and timely data, ensuring the quality and reliability of the oracle network. Governance: oracles can use cryptoeconomic mechanisms to enable stakeholders to participate in the governance of the oracle network, ensuring that the network is operated in a fair and transparent manner.  By leveraging cryptographic and cryptoeconomic solutions, oracles can enhance the security, privacy, efficiency, and scalability of its oracle network, providing a more robust and reliable data infrastructure for decentralized applications. Concluding: Proofs Are Winning, but Stakes Still MatterCryptographic proofs and restaking hint at shifting the load from validators onto verifiable computation, networks may cut costs, reduce inflation, and enhance scalability. That said, cryptoeconomics isn’t disappearing anytime soon. In a purely proof-driven world, vulnerabilities could arise from external attacks or governance failures. As a result, these two layers, cryptographic verifiability and economic incentives, will likely continue to coexist. The balance point, however, is shifting: cryptography grows more capable by the day, and the cost of capital for security may steadily decline. The net effect is a more efficient, more scalable crypto ecosystem – one in which trustlessness is increasingly powered by code and proofs, while the economic layer ensures that even the most sophisticated cryptographic solutions remain accountable to the broader network. </content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cms3.diadata.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/How-Cryptography-is-Eating-Cryptoeconomics.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Lasernet Mainnet is Live: DIA Lumina’s Full Rollout is Here | DIA, Cross-Chain Oracles for Web3</title>
    <published>2025-03-26T22:05:42+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-26T22:05:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.diadata.org/blog/post/dia-lumina-mainnet-live/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.diadata.org/blog/post/dia-lumina-mainnet-live/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Mikel Garcia</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">DIA Lumina is now fully live: the first oracle stack to bring full decentralization, transparency, and trustless execution to onchain data. The First Fully Transparent and Trustless Oracle Stack is Now On-chainWith the mainnet deployment of Lasernet, DIA Lumina’s full oracle architecture is now live. This marks a paradigm shift in the Web3 data infrastructure landscape: introducing the first fully decentralized, trustless, and transparent oracle environment. For the first time, developers, DeFi protocols, and Web3 builders can access oracle data that is completely verifiable, and executed trustlessly on-chain. No more black-box oracles. No more unverifiable price feeds. Just pure, transparent, and trustless data, directly from the origin. Lasernet: The Modular L2 Designed for OraclesLasernet is a custom-built Layer 2 rollup designed to process oracle data trustlessly, at scale. It powers the DIA Lumina oracle stack, leveraging optimistic rollup technology and a modular Data Availability (DA) layer, both built by Arbitrum, to bring unparalleled security and efficiency to on-chain data delivery. Unlike traditional oracles that process data off-chain in opaque systems, Lasernet brings every part of the oracle lifecycle on-chain—ensuring full verifiability and decentralization. How Oracles on Lasernet Work  Modular data availability – Lumina ensures secure and cost-effective on-chain storage of oracle data, verifiable at any time. Permissionless access – anyone can deploy an oracle smart contract to build data feeds with custom settings. Contracts live immutable forever on Lasernet. &amp;nbsp; Trustless Data Processing – Every oracle transaction is public, auditable, and resistant to manipulation.  With Lasernet now live on mainnet, DIA Lumina becomes the first oracle ecosystem to fully decentralize every component of its architecture. DIA Lumina OverviewWhat’s Now Live on Mainnet? The Full DIA Lumina StackLasernet’s mainnet deployment marks the completion of the entire DIA Lumina oracle stack, bringing the following components live: Feeders (First-Party Data Sourcing Nodes) Instead of relying on opaque third-party aggregators, Lumina brings first-party data directly from the sources via a distributed network of Feeders. These are nodes that fetch, aggregate, and publish computed data points onto the DIA Lasernet in a verifiable way. Learn more about Feeders Lasernet (L2 Rollup for Oracles) A high-throughput, low-cost Ethereum Layer 2 built to handle oracle data requests on-chain with full verifiability and trustless execution. It inherits Ethereum’s security while enjoying fast 250ms block times and cheap and efficient transactions. Learn more about Lasernet Aggregator (Oracle Computing Smart Contracts) These smart contracts on Lasernet that collect and process data available on the network, enabling the on-chain oracle computation with full transparency and permissionless deployment. Learn more about Aggregator Spectra (Cross-chain Interoperability Framework) DIA leverages Hyperlane’s open-source interoperability framework to connect DIA’s Lasernet to hundreds of layer-1 and layer-2 networks in a trust minimized and open way, via a network of validators. Learn more about Spectra $DIA as the Native Gas Token Lasernet transactions now run on $DIA, embedding real economic utility into the token and aligning incentives across the network. Learn more about DIA token With these components now operational, DIA Lumina is not just another oracle—it’s the foundation for a fully trustless, modular oracle ecosystem. No More Black-Box Oracles: Redefining OraclesLasernet’s deployment isn’t just another mainnet launch—it’s a fundamental shift in how oracles work. Here’s why this matters for DeFi, dApps, and the entire Web3 ecosystem: 100% Transparency Across the Data Journey Legacy oracle designs deliver price feeds that users must trust without verification. With DIA Lumina, every single data point is fully auditable onchain. Trustless Execution at Scale Existing oracles rely on offchain trust assumptions—whether it’s multi-sig-controlled nodes or centralized data providers. Lasernet eliminates these risks by using an L2 rollup to handle data verification transparently and trustlessly. Modular, Cost-Efficient, and Fully Verifiable By optimizing the cost of data processing through rollups, Lasernet delivers oracle data at a fraction of the cost—without compromising security or decentralization. A New Standard for DeFi Security With oracles securing billions in DeFi&amp;nbsp; TVL, accurate and trustless data feeds are critical. DIA Lumina sets a new industry benchmark for data transparency, verifiability, and trustless execution. What’s Next? How You Can Get InvolvedNow that Lasernet is live, it’s time for builders, developers, and projects to start integrating the future of oracles. 👨‍💻 For dApp developers:  Start integrating DIA Lumina oracles into your dApp. Deploy your own oracle or use an existing one.  📈 For chain foundations:  Need decentralized, verifiable data infrastructure to kickstart a robust DeFi ecosystem for your chain? Let’s talk integration.  ⛓ For stakers:  Staking will be introduced soon—stay tuned for updates on how you can participate in securing the network.  The Future of Oracles Starts NowWeb3 has evolved. Blockchains are becoming more modular, scalable, and transparent—so should oracles. Lumina’s mainnet deployment marks a major milestone in oracle design–it’s the first to bring full transparency, decentralization, and trustless execution to the oracle space. Let’s build the future of oracles—together. We’re opening a new chapter in the oracle space with DIA Lumina - a fully open and verifiable oracle architecture, purpose-built to evolve alongside the broader Web3 ecosystem. Designed from the ground up to be the most modular system, Lumina embraces emerging technologies and enables unprecedented transparency, flexibility, and robustness in oracle infrastructure.  The oracle space is about to get a whole lot more interesting.Zygis MarazasDIA’s Head of Product DocumentationExplorer</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cms3.diadata.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/DIA-Lumina-Mainnet-1.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">DIA x Hyperlane: Scaling Lumina’s Cross-Chain Messaging | DIA, Cross-Chain Oracles for Web3</title>
    <published>2025-03-25T22:05:44+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-25T22:05:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.diadata.org/blog/post/hyperlane-scaling-luminas-cross-chain-messaging/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.diadata.org/blog/post/hyperlane-scaling-luminas-cross-chain-messaging/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Mikel Garcia</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">DIA Lumina integrates Hyperlane as its official messaging protocol, enabling trustless cross-chain oracle data transfer across hundreds of blockchains. Introduction: Spectra, the Messaging Protocol Powering DIA’s Next-Gen OraclesDIA’s Lumina stack is set to launch on mainnet soon, bringing a modular, trustless, and fully transparent oracle infrastructure to the blockchain ecosystem. A key enabler of this cross-chain oracle system is Hyperlane, DIA’s official message-passing protocol, which facilitates seamless, permissionless communication between DIA Lasernet and external blockchains. To leverage Hyperlane’s flexibility and permissionless architecture, DIA has deployed its own instance within Lumina, known as Spectra. Spectra is responsible for securely transmitting oracle data between chains, ensuring seamless and decentralized oracle functionality across the ecosystem. Why Hyperlane? A Strategic Choice for DIA’s Cross-Chain OraclesDIA’s vision for Lumina revolves around three core principles: permissionlessness, modularity, and decentralization. When evaluating cross-chain messaging solutions, Hyperlane stood out as the perfect fit. Here’s why: 1. Permissionless by Design Unlike other message-passing protocols that require central approvals or governance control, Hyperlane allows anyone to deploy and operate their own instance. This aligns perfectly with DIA’s goal of making Lumina an open oracle network where developers can freely interact without barriers. 2. Modular Security and Customization Hyperlane’s unique Interchain Security Module (ISM) enables developers to choose different security models based on their needs. For DIA, this means the ability to customize Spectra to ensure high-integrity oracle data transfer across chains while also giving external developers the flexibility to implement their own security mechanisms. 3. Future-Proofing and Scalability Because Hyperlane is a generalized framework, DIA can expand Lumina’s reach to any blockchain, current or future, without modifying the core oracle infrastructure. This makes Spectra a long-term, adaptable solution for cross-chain oracle connectivity. 4. No Chain-Specific Bottlenecks Traditional interoperability solutions often require extensive chain-specific integrations. Hyperlane’s permissionless deployment model eliminates these bottlenecks, allowing DIA to focus on scaling its oracle services without dependency on third-party integrations. DIA’s decision to build their cross-chain messaging layer using Hyperlane is a great example of how permissionless interoperability can unlock powerful decentralized infrastructure. We’re excited to see Hyperlane helping bring Lumina’s trustless oracle network to hundreds of chains. Jon KolCo-Founder of Hyperlane How It Works: The Tech Behind SpectraSpectra, DIA’s custom Hyperlane implementation, acts as the backbone of Lumina’s cross-chain messaging. Here’s how it functions: Core Components of Spectra  OracleTrigger Smart Contract (Lasernet-side): Collects asset price data and propagates it to destination chains via Hyperlane’s message-passing framework. PushOracleReceiver Smart Contract (Destination Chains): Receives and processes oracle data on the target chain. RequestOracle (Destination Chains): Requests, receives and stores oracle data from Lasernet on destination chains Relayers &amp;amp; Validators: Hyperlane’s security model relies on relayers to transport messages and validators to cryptographically verify their authenticity before finalizing them on the destination chain.  Push vs. Pull-Based Oracles DIA’s Spectra-powered oracle framework supports:  Push-Based Oracles: Automatically update target chains at predefined intervals or based on predefined deviations in asset prices. Pull-Based Oracles: This allows developers to request asset prices on demand, which are then retrieved and delivered via Hyperlane’s messaging layer.  What This Means for Developers: Integrating Hyperlane to Connect to DIA OraclesWhile Spectra operates within the Lumina stack, developers looking to connect their own blockchain to DIA Lasernet must integrate Hyperlane. This approach ensures that any chain, regardless of its existing infrastructure, can seamlessly access DIA’s oracle services without requiring direct modifications to Spectra. Key Benefits for Developers:  Permissionless Expansion: Any blockchain can integrate Hyperlane to gain access to DIA’s oracle data, fostering a truly open ecosystem. Customizable Security Models: Developers can select from Hyperlane’s modular security options to fit their risk tolerance and use cases. Seamless Deployment: No need for complex chain-specific adaptations—Hyperlane allows rapid and scalable integration of DIA oracles.  Final Thoughts &amp;amp; What’s NextDIA’s choice of Hyperlane as its official bridge protocol underscores Lumina’s commitment to decentralization, flexibility, and security. By leveraging Hyperlane, DIA has built Spectra, a permissionless, modular, and scalable message-passing protocol tailored to the needs of next-generation oracle applications. As Lumina’s mainnet launch approaches, we’re excited to see developers, projects, and protocols integrate with Hyperlane to connect to DIA’s oracle network. </content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cms3.diadata.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Inside-Spectra.jpg"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
