<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Allbridge on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@allbridge?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fallbridge.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*sse6PUGx3Lxst0vvGIs-CQ.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*sse6PUGx3Lxst0vvGIs-CQ.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fallbridge.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T21:57:33+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Allbridge and Quarkslab Strengthen Partnership with Second Estrela Security Audit</title>
    <published>2025-02-28T13:58:20+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-28T13:58:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-and-quarkslab-strengthen-partnership-with-second-estrela-security-audit-b42ed13d22ec?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-and-quarkslab-strengthen-partnership-with-second-estrela-security-audit-b42ed13d22ec?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Estrela, a decentralized exchange built on Soroban, has successfully completed its second round of security audits conducted by Quarkslab. The latest audit focused on ensuring the security and efficiency of its smart contracts, particularly the 3-pool implementation, confirming that the platform is well-prepared for its upcoming launch.Quarkslab conducted an in-depth review of Estrela’s smart contracts, assessing their resilience against potential vulnerabilities. The audit confirmed that Estrela has a strong security foundation, with no critical issues detected, ensuring a secure environment for users and liquidity providers.Quarkslab has previously audited Estrela, as well as another one of our projects deployed on Stellar, Allbridge Core. Their familiarity with our team and prior experience in auditing Estrela allowed them to conduct a highly efficient security review. Their thorough assessment was vital in ensuring that the smart contracts were correctly implemented, with a particular focus on the 3-pool mechanism.With the security audit now complete, we are getting ready for launch. Quarkslab’s review played a key role in ensuring everything was implemented correctly. The full audit report is available here.For more details on Quarkslab, visit https://www.quarkslab.com/.About QuarkslabQuarkslab is a dedicated team of cyber-security engineers and developers.They aim at forcing the attackers, not the defender, to adapt constantly. Through QLab‘s consulting expertise and R&amp;amp;D, and their software QFlow and QShield, they share and scale their knowledge by making it accessible to everyone. They believe that security is everyone’s concern as there is no freedom if there is no security.Their expertise combines offensive and defensive security in application protection and helps organisations to adopt a new security posture.| Website | Twitter | LinkedIn | Blog |</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Allbridge Core Welcomes Sui as Our 12th Supported Chain!</title>
    <published>2025-02-14T12:55:17+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-14T12:55:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-core-welcomes-sui-as-our-12th-supported-chain-9dbabbcb2511?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-core-welcomes-sui-as-our-12th-supported-chain-9dbabbcb2511?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are thrilled to announce our Sui integration!What is Sui?Sui is a Layer 1 blockchain designed to be both developer- and user-friendly. It supports a wide range of applications with exceptional speed and low costs. Its unique architecture enables the simultaneous processing of multiple transactions, making it both fast and highly scalable.Bringing New Networks to Allbridge CoreWith Sui as our 12th supported chain, we continue to enhance the interoperability of Allbridge Core. This integration introduces a new USDC route, enabling seamless access to the growing Sui ecosystem. By bridging to Sui, users can now leverage its high-performance infrastructure for fast and cost-effective transactions.CCTP-Powered USDC TransfersOur latest update also extends support for Circle’s Cross-Chain Transfer Protocol (CCTP), allowing users to swap USDC between supported chains with zero slippage.Explore our new Sui bridge today and share your feedback!About SuiSui is a first-of-its-kind Layer 1 blockchain and smart contract platform designed to make digital asset ownership fast, private, secure, and accessible. Sui’s unique architecture allows it to handle many transactions simultaneously, making it both quick and scalable.| Website | Twitter | Discord | Blog |About Allbridge CoreAllbridge Core enables the transfer of value between blockchains by offering cross-chain swaps of native stablecoins. Being messaging protocol agnostic, Allbridge Core connects a variety of EVM and non-EVM networks.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Medium | Discord |</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Allbridge Forms Strategic Partnership with Crystal</title>
    <published>2024-11-12T11:24:11+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-12T11:24:11+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-forms-strategic-partnership-with-crystal-f8746673580a?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-forms-strategic-partnership-with-crystal-f8746673580a?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Allbridge Core, a cross-chain stablecoin swap platform, is proud to announce its partnership with Crystal, a leading blockchain intelligence and analytics firm.Boosting Platform Security with CrystalCrystal, known for its expertise in blockchain transaction monitoring and risk assessment, has now become a part of Allbridge Core’s infrastructure, providing us with ongoing transaction monitoring. By utilizing Crystal’s sophisticated screening tools, Allbridge Core bolsters its ability to identify, assess, and mitigate potential risks in real time.Transaction MonitoringAs part of this partnership, we’ve integrated Crystal’s address analysis solution into our platform. Crystal’s advanced monitoring capabilities allow us to assess transactions for potentially malicious wallets associated with cybersecurity incidents, providing our users with a secure bridging experience.Building a Safer DeFi EcosystemThe collaboration between Allbridge Core and Crystal emphasizes the essential role of blockchain analysis tools for cross-chain products. Together our goal is to establish a safer environment for our users and the wider DeFi ecosystems. To learn more about Crystal’s blockchain intelligence solutions, visit their website.About Allbridge CoreAllbridge Core enables the transfer of value between blockchains by offering cross-chain swaps of native stablecoins. Being messaging protocol agnostic, Allbridge Core connects a variety of EVM and non-EVM networks.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Medium | Discord |About CrystalCrystal Intelligence is a leading blockchain intelligence firm empowering financial institutions, law enforcement and regulators with real-time blockchain analysis, investigative and compliance solutions. Our solution helps financial institutions comply with global anti-money laundering regulations efficiently. Investigators and government agencies leverage Crystal’s cutting-edge technology and unique real-time intelligence to solve crypto investigations. Available as a free blockchain explorer, SaaS, or API.| Website | Twitter | LinkedIn| Blog |</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Allbridge Core Expands Solana Ecosystem with New USDT Integration</title>
    <published>2024-10-15T16:00:57+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-15T16:00:57+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-core-expands-solana-ecosystem-with-new-usdt-integration-628e11d19b9a?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-core-expands-solana-ecosystem-with-new-usdt-integration-628e11d19b9a?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are pleased to announce the expansion of our Solana pools with the introduction of USDt. This latest addition is set to broaden the number of available routes on Allbridge Core, providing the USDt community with a gateway into the blooming Solana ecosystem.Expanding our Solana routesOur latest integration will fully unlock the potential of Solana USDt, offering enhanced flexibility to our liquidity providers and contributing to the robust growth of the Solana network’s TVL.“The new USDt pool on Solana not only broadens our service offerings but also paves the way for more seamless cross-chain interactions.”, said Andriy Velykyy, co-founder and CEO behind Allbridge.Unlocking new USDt swapsFor users new to the Solana ecosystem, our convenient Extra Gas feature will facilitate easy wallet top-ups with SOL, ensuring a smooth and user-friendly experience. Our goal is to provide a seamless bridging experience, empowering users to explore the full potential of cross-chain transactions.Our team is excited to support USDt on Solana and remain committed to fostering continuous innovation. This expansion is a testament to our dedication to delivering cutting-edge solutions and maintaining a robust, user-centric platform. Visit Allbridge Core to experience the new USDt route on Solana.About Allbridge CoreAllbridge Core enables the transfer of value between blockchains by offering cross-chain swaps of native stablecoins. Being messaging protocol agnostic, Allbridge Core connects a variety of EVM and non-EVM networks.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Medium | Discord |</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Unleash Your Competitive Spirit with Allbridge Core Leaderboards</title>
    <published>2024-07-30T13:59:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-30T13:59:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/unleash-your-competitive-spirit-with-allbridge-core-leaderboards-989279c62696?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/unleash-your-competitive-spirit-with-allbridge-core-leaderboards-989279c62696?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We’re super excited to roll out our new leaderboard system, a fun and engaging activity designed to enhance your experience within the Allbridge Ecosystem. With this exciting addition, you have your chance to shine while also competing with other players. Let’s explore how you can join the fun and make the most of it!How to Register and Join the FunYou’ll need to register first to participate in the leaderboards, and we’ve made the process incredibly simple. Users can sign in with their preferred wallet (you will also have the option to sync your other wallets within a single profile). And then, just click the registration button to get started.Registrations offer several customization options, allowing you to create a unique personal profile. You can generate various names that fit your preference, each associated with a handcrafted, incredible profile picture prepared by our talented design team. Kudos to our team for making these profiles truly stand out!Your Profile HubOnce you’re registered, it’s all about your personalized profile. This is where you can add more wallets, see your ranking compared to other users, and track your progress. Your profile is a collection of addresses on different chains, all accumulating points under your account. It’s your one-stop shop to see how you stack up against the competition.Earning Points and Leveling UpNow, let’s talk points! You earn points by interacting with the bridge — doing swaps or providing liquidity. Referrals will also earn you points, though this feature becomes available at level 2. As you engage with the bridge, you’ll level up, which increases your point multiplier, allowing you to gain more points faster. It’s all about climbing that leaderboard and showing everyone who’s boss. So, keep an eye on your rank and keep pushing to climb higher.We Want YOUR InputIf you enjoy this activity, we’re considering adding even more features to the leaderboard system. Please share your ideas on how to make it even more exciting! We’re eager to hear your thoughts and make the Allbridge Core experience the best it can be.Get Started and Enjoy the CompetitionWe invite all users to dive in, enjoy the leaderboards, and compete with fellow Allbridge Core members. You can also invite your friends — the more, the merrier. But most importantly, have a blast while doing it! The new leaderboards feature is all about making your experience more fun and engaging. So, what are you waiting for? Get started today and see how high you can climb on the leaderboards!About Allbridge CoreAllbridge Core enables the transfer of value between blockchains by offering cross-chain swaps of native stablecoins. Being messaging protocol agnostic, Allbridge Core connects a variety of EVM and non-EVM networks.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Medium | Discord |</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Allbridge Core, Rango Exchange, and Trust Wallet Unite to Enable Seamless Access into the Celo…</title>
    <published>2024-07-26T15:22:49+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-26T15:22:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-core-rango-exchange-and-trust-wallet-unite-to-enable-seamless-access-into-the-celo-e1d27f14a414?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-core-rango-exchange-and-trust-wallet-unite-to-enable-seamless-access-into-the-celo-e1d27f14a414?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Allbridge Core, Rango Exchange, and Trust Wallet Unite to Enable Seamless Access into the Celo EcosystemCelebrating a New CollaborationWe are thrilled to announce our upcoming collaboration campaign with Rango Exchange and Trust Wallet, focusing on bringing users into the Celo blockchain. This campaign offers DeFi enthusiasts the unique opportunity to experience the Celo ecosystem through a partnership between our entities.Celo-centric Campaign BeginsWe are launching a two-week-long promotion packed with exciting opportunities to win exclusive prizes in celebration of this event. Participants will receive rewards for bridging to the Celo network from BNB, Polygon and Ethereum network, making it an event you won’t want to miss.Our close partner, Rango Exchange aggregator, which previously integrated our solution, plays a major role in providing seamless entry into the Celo ecosystem. At the same time, Trust Wallet is a significant part of this joint promotional campaign, ensuring a smooth and secure user experience.More Opportunities for Stablecoin SwapsThis campaign is not just about entering the Celo ecosystem; it’s about experiencing the unique benefits that Celo provides and offering unparalleled opportunities to liquidity providers. By swapping to Celo, users will receive USDT, getting access to over $470 million USDT market.Experience the convenience of bridging via Rango Exchange and immerse yourself in the dynamic and thriving Celo ecosystem. This collaboration is designed to provide seamless access and unparalleled opportunities for both new and seasoned Celo users. Join us and participate in the future of decentralized finance on Celo!About Rango ExchangeRango is a cutting-edge routing and aggregation protocol for all cross-chain and on-chain swaps, aggregating bridges and DEXs in the crypto world. You can do the cross-chain swap on over +60 chains like Bitcoin, Ethereum, Polygon, Solana, etc.in a decentralized manner.Rango is a new layer on top of all Bridges and DEXs, working as a Bridge Aggregator and DEX Aggregator at the same time to enable seamless on-chain and cross-chain swaps, finding the most efficient, safe, cheap and fast route for swapping from any token on any blockchain to any other token to any blockchain.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Blog |About CeloCelo is an emerging Ethereum Layer-2 and mobile-first blockchain network built for the real world and designed for fast, low-cost payments worldwide. The Celo ecosystem consists of a decentralized, proof-of-stake blockchain technology stack (the Celo Platform), the CELO native token, USDC and USDT (both enabled as gas currencies), several Mento stable assets (cUSD, cEUR, cREAL, eXOF), and popular, blue chip infrastructure including Uniswap V3, Curve, Chainlink, and Rarible, among others. Launched on Earth Day in 2020, the open-source Celo mainnet supports a rich ecosystem of projects (1,000+) contributing to Celo’s global mission of prosperity for all. For more about Celo, visit https://celo.org/.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Blog |About Trust WalletUsed by over 60 million people worldwide, Trust Wallet mobile is an easy-to-use, true multi-chain self-custody wallet, which allows you to store and manage over 9 million crypto assets including NFTs across 70 blockchains. No more storing your assets across multiple custody wallets or exchanges! You’ll have peace of mind knowing all your assets are in one safe place. Your private keys are stored on your device and your assets on-chain meaning you are in full control at all times. Trust Wallet gives you the ability to natively buy, swap, and stake your favorite cryptos without having to leave the app, as well as connect to thousands of Web3 dApps safely with the in-built dApp browser.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Blog |About Allbridge CoreAllbridge Core enables the transfer of value between blockchains by offering cross-chain swaps of native stablecoins. Being messaging protocol agnostic, Allbridge Core connects a variety of EVM and non-EVM networks.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Blog | Discord |</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Celo Transfers are Live on Allbridge Core!</title>
    <published>2024-05-28T16:00:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-28T16:00:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/celo-transfers-are-live-on-allbridge-core-1e560b70e02d?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/celo-transfers-are-live-on-allbridge-core-1e560b70e02d?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are thrilled to unveil our integration with Celo and add it as our 11th-supported blockchain!Introducing CeloCelo is scaling Ethereum with real-world solutions, leading a thriving new digital economy for all. Allbridge Core will facilitate access to the robust Celo ecosystem of 1,000+ projects in over 150 countries through native stablecoin transfers.As part of our commitment to Wormhole, Celo swaps will utilize the Wormhole messaging layer by default, creating a more secure and decentralized multichain experience.Expanding access to Celo with Valora WalletAnother exciting component for the Celo ecosystem is that we will be a listed dApp on Celo-native wallet, Valora. This will enable seamless transfers, natively via smartphone.Layer3 campaignTo celebrate the latest release, we are also launching a dedicated Layer3 campaign in partnership with the Celo Foundation. Users can explore Celo’s roster of stable assets by bridging Tether’s USDT from Arbitrum, Avalanche, Base, BNB Chain, Polygon, or OP Mainnet for points and CUBEs. Learn more about how you can participate here.About CeloCelo is an emerging Ethereum Layer-2 and mobile-first blockchain network built for the real world and designed for fast, low-cost payments worldwide. The Celo ecosystem consists of a decentralized, proof-of-stake blockchain technology stack (the Celo Platform), the CELO native token, USDC and USDT (both enabled as gas currencies), several Mento stable assets (cUSD, cEUR, cREAL, eXOF), and popular, blue chip infrastructure including Uniswap V3, Curve, Chainlink, and Rarible, among others. Launched on Earth Day in 2020, the open-source Celo mainnet supports a rich ecosystem of projects (1,000+) contributing to Celo’s global mission of prosperity for all. For more about Celo, visit https://celo.org/.| Website | Twitter | Discord | Medium |About WormholeWormhole is the leading interoperability platform that powers multichain applications and bridges at scale. Wormhole provides developers access to liquidity and users on over 30 of the leading blockchain networks, enabling use cases that span DeFi, NFTs, governance, and more.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Blog |About Allbridge CoreAllbridge Core enables the transfer of value between blockchains by offering cross-chain swaps of native stablecoins. Being messaging protocol agnostic, Allbridge Core connects a variety of EVM and non-EVM networks.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Medium | Discord |</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Allbridge Core Launches a Bridge to Stellar</title>
    <published>2024-05-23T10:56:49+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-23T10:56:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-core-launches-a-bridge-to-stellar-14156f59e925?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/allbridge-core-launches-a-bridge-to-stellar-14156f59e925?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are excited to welcome Stellar as the 10th chain to join the Allbridge Core ecosystem!Stellar integrationToday marks the completion of our latest integration with the Core bridge, as we are bringing cross-chain stable swaps to Stellar and connecting it to chains like Base, OP Mainnet, and Arbitrum.The key ingredient of this launch was the introduction of Soroban, which allowed us to deliver a top-of-the-line bridging experience.What is Soroban?Soroban is a developer-friendly, Rust-based smart contracts platform designed for scale and sensibility. Its release was an essential part of this integration, as our Core bridge relies on the availability of smart contracts. With Soroban here, we can unlock the Stellar ecosystem to more users through native USDC swaps!Seamless integration experienceThe latest entry to Core also expands our SDK option, allowing Stellar protocols to tap into the liquidity from 9 different supported blockchains. We have several exciting SDK collaborations on the way, and we cannot wait to share more news with you soon!Try our new integration and explore the Stellar ecosystem with Allbridge Core.About StellarStellar is more than a blockchain. Powered by a decentralized, fast, scalable, and uniquely sustainable network made for financial products and services and a thriving and passionate ecosystem that includes a non-profit organization driven by a mission, Stellar is paving the path to unlock the world’s economic potential through blockchain technology. Built with speed and low costs in mind, the Stellar network provides builders and financial institutions worldwide a platform to issue assets, and to send and convert currencies in real time creating real world utility.Founded in 2014, the Stellar Development Foundation (SDF) supports the continued development and growth of the Stellar network and also serves the ecosystem of NGOs, corporations, universities, small businesses, governments, and solo entrepreneurs building on the Stellar network through tooling, funding and strategic collaborations. Together, Stellar is where blockchain meets the real world.| Website | Twitter |About Allbridge CoreAllbridge Core enables the transfer of value between blockchains by offering cross-chain swaps of native stablecoins. Being messaging protocol agnostic, Allbridge Core connects a variety of EVM and non-EVM networks.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Medium | Discord |</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Wormhole Becomes Default Messaging for Allbridge Core</title>
    <published>2024-05-10T14:00:05+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-10T14:00:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/wormhole-becomes-default-messaging-for-allbridge-core-c4cab6f3c9fc?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/wormhole-becomes-default-messaging-for-allbridge-core-c4cab6f3c9fc?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are excited to announce that we are transitioning to Wormhole’s messaging as the new default option for Allbridge Core swaps.What is Wormhole?Wormhole is the most decentralized cross-chain messaging protocol, operated by a decentralized set of 19 validators called Guardians. They observe the Core Contract on each supported chain and produce verifiable approvals when those contracts receive a message from the Wormhole Messaging protocol.Building with WormholeAllbridge Core will leverage the advantages offered by Wormhole’s Guardian network to provide our users with a secure and decentralized cross-chain experience.Transitioning to Wormhole messagingAs part of this transition, Wormhole messaging has been made default for the set of chains that are mutually supported by both of our respective protocols, including chains like Solana, Base, and Arbitrum.This also means that as new chains are added to Wormhole, we will deploy and shift to Wormhole as default, ensuring a seamless and efficient transition for our users. Enter into the new era of Allbridge Core swaps and explore 8 different chains via Wormhole messaging!About WormholeWormhole is the leading interoperability platform that powers multichain applications and bridges at scale. Wormhole provides developers access to liquidity and users on over 30 of the leading blockchain networks, enabling use cases that span DeFi, NFTs, governance, and more.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Blog |About Allbridge CoreAllbridge Core enables the transfer of value between blockchains by offering cross-chain swaps of native stablecoins. Being messaging protocol agnostic, Allbridge Core connects a variety of EVM and non-EVM networks.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Medium | Discord |</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Quarkslab’s Security Audit for Estrela</title>
    <published>2024-05-07T15:42:37+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-07T15:42:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allbridge.medium.com/quarkslabs-security-audit-for-estrela-c71fcae00037?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://allbridge.medium.com/quarkslabs-security-audit-for-estrela-c71fcae00037?source=rss-71297907a7e5------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Allbridge</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are thrilled to continue our collaboration with the Quarkslab team on our upcoming project, Estrela!Introducing EstrelaEstrela is a decentralized platform for efficient low-slippage stablecoin swaps, which is the next major step in our collaboration with the Stellar ecosystem!With Estrela, liquidity providers will be able to deposit liquidity to the pools, earning fees from swap operations and facilitating the swap for the Stellar community.It also allows us to build upon our Allbridge Classic experience and bring additional cross-chain liquidity into Stellar from a number of supported chains.Quarkslab auditFollowing our previous successful work with Quarkslab team we reached out to them to arrange a security review for Estrela. Their expertise in Soroban was invaluable to assure the security of our Estrela’s stable swaps and pool contracts.Estrela roadmapAt the moment, we aim to polish the web experience on Estrela and, once completed, bring it to the Stellar community. Be on the lookout for more Estrela announcements coming soon.For now, you can visit our landing page to get more details about the security assessment.About QuarkslabFounded 10 years ago, Quarkslab is a dedicated team of cyber-security engineers and developers.They aim at forcing the attackers, not the defender, to adapt constantly. Through QLab‘s consulting expertise and R&amp;amp;D, and their software QFlow and QShield, they share and scale their knowledge by making it accessible to everyone. They believe that security is everyone’s concern as there is no freedom if there is no security.Their expertise combines offensive and defensive security in application protection and helps organisations to adopt a new security posture.| Website | Twitter | LinkedIn | Blog |About Allbridge CoreAllbridge Core enables the transfer of value between blockchains by offering cross-chain swaps of native stablecoins. Being messaging protocol agnostic, Allbridge Core connects a variety of EVM and non-EVM networks.| Website | Twitter | Telegram | Medium | Discord |</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
