<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">etherfuse</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://etherfuse.substack.com"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fetherfuse.substack.com%2Ffeed&amp;content_selector=.available-content&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;remove_styles=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fetherfuse.substack.com%2Ffeed&amp;content_selector=.available-content&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;remove_styles=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:06:04+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">It's Policy, Stupid</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T13:30:54+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T13:30:54+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://etherfuse.substack.com/p/its-policy-stupid</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://etherfuse.substack.com/p/its-policy-stupid"/>
    <author>
      <name>Donald Elefson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">James Carville in 1992 said “The Economy, stupid”. Substitute the word “policy” for “Economy” and you might sum up the present situation in the United States. Inconsistent policy has many people concerned about the US dollar and the US fiscal position.
Oak Tree co-Chairman Howard Marks, a great credit investor, summed it up best,  “If people don’t like the dollar, don’t like investing in the US, don’t want to hold an unlimited number of Treasuries; if we just make people mad,” Marks said, “the fiscal situation will be very complicated.”
Let’s take this statement apart piece by piece. It’s a good one.
First, due to policy inconsistency people don’t  like investing in the United States at present. Without trust and consistency in policy, investors are hesitant to take the risk of owning the barometer of US policy, the dollar. Tariffs one day, a 90 day reprieve the next hardly builds trust and confidence.
Further to that, hedge fund titan Ray Dalio in a Bloomberg interview said, “It dramatically affected psychology and attitude about the United States reliability”. This kind of “says” it all.
Second, people are cautious about holding US Treasuries. The US Treasury has long offered more yield than the Euro and the Japanese Yen, the other major global currencies. Add to this the demand that comes from the US dollar being the reserve currency of choice, and you have demand for US bonds and the dollar.
But now, versus the Euro the US dollar only offers 1.2% more yield on a ten-year bond. Is 1.2% more worth the risk of holding the US dollar, with all the factors driving US risk up? The US dollar could easily go down in value over 1% versus the Euro, wiping out the interest rate pick up.
In short, given the Euro potential to go up,getting paid 1.2% for US dollar risk may not make sense.
Third, the US government is making people mad. This is self-explanatory.
Fourth, the fiscal situation, government spending and budget policies, are complicated. The US national debt is projected to be over 100% of GDP. The US administration claims that a slew of tax cuts will stimulate business, and more business will lead to more tax revenue. Theoretically, this could happen, but it is a risky bet.
So, given the headwinds to demand for US dollars and US Treasuries from foreign investors, where is a good place to invest?
Two currencies that may answer this question are the Euro and the Mexican peso. Both currencies can  go up in value versus the US dollar, especially with watered down tariffs.
CETES stable bonds offered on Etherfuse yield approximately 7.5%, which is a 3.3% yield pick up versus the US Etherfuse stable bond. The yield on Etherfuse Euro stable bonds is 2.14%, 2.03% less than the USTRY Etherfuse bond. On a 60% allocation to the peso and a 40% allocation to Euro, the yield pick-up versus the US is 1.2%.
To highlight the potential of European bonds, we can  look at German Bunds, German treasury bonds, versus US Treasuries in the week ending April 11, 2025. In that week, US treasuries experienced their worst weekly performance versus German bonds since 1989. If this can happen in Germany, it can happen in Europe.
Money could leave the dollar unless things become clear regarding US policies on fiscal and trade matters. For, after all, it really is “policy, stupid”.
This blog is for educational and informational purposes only, covering general market trends, industry developments, and asset features. Nothing herein is investment advice, a solicitation, or a recommendation to buy or sell any assets. Etherfuse and its guests may hold stakes in some or all of the assets discussed.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="audio/mpeg" href="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/161091606/858a8f7669dc2ec4ddf6f73492c89a43.mp3"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Peso Pride</title>
    <published>2025-04-08T17:52:12+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-08T17:52:12+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://etherfuse.substack.com/p/peso-pride</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://etherfuse.substack.com/p/peso-pride"/>
    <author>
      <name>Donald Elefson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Given the price movements of the Mexican peso in the last month, you must respect Mexico and its currency. On the back of US tariffs, the Mexican peso should be getting slaughtered. Mexico’s exposure to the US supply chain for industries like autos puts it right in the cross hairs of tariffs, no escape.
Tariffs were originally announced beginning February, and Mexico was given a 30-day reprieve. When tariffs became an issue again on March 3rd, the currency had weakened to a level of 20.73, a level very near its one-year low point.
Between March 3rd and April 4th, the peso strengthened by over 3% versus the US dollar as tariff talks calmed down.
But, since the announcement of President Trump’s steroidal tariff program, the Mexican Peso has weakened versus the US dollar back to the March 3rd level of 20.73, the level when investors viewed tariffs as a big threat.
Confusing, hard to follow. I know.
What is surprising is the fact that it never weakened past its lowest value in the last year. It never passed its weakest point of 20.85.
Who would have thought that it could stay above its low point with things looking so grim. In times past the Mexican peso would have gone way down in value in tandem with other emerging market currencies.
Impressive Mexican peso performance can be explained by many things, but the interest rate differential with the United States may be the most important.
At the time of the peso’s weak point on March 3rd, Etherfuse’s Mexican stable bonds, CETES, were yielding 3.5% more than US dollar stable bonds. As noted earlier, this 3.5% was a cushion, an added return to compensate investors for taking the risk of owning pesos versus the US dollar.
It was good compensation for peso risk because about one month later the currency is unchanged from its low point of 20.73 on March 3rd, . Not great performance at first glance, but on an annual basis if nothing changes between the US dollar and the peso, investors will still make about 3.5% more yield on peso stable bonds than on US stable bonds.
If the dollar goes down further, which is possible, the gain would be even more.
So, the key question to ask right now is will the value of the peso weaken by more than 3% versus the US dollar in the next months? If this happens, currency weakness can wipe out any annual interest rate gain.
So far this has not happened. So far, it may be concluded that the worst is over for Mexico and the peso. They may have weathered the storm nicely.
If the US dollar weakens, the peso trade is great. If the Mexican peso does nothing from this level, stays unchanged, the trade is still good on an annual basis.
Regarding the US dollar, there are few positives going for it, so at a minimum it could stay at this level, unchanged.
A trade  borrowing US dollar stable bonds to finance the purchase of Mexican stable bonds could be a good idea, providing a 3.5% yield pick-up on an annual basis.
But whatever the trade, the key is to watch the peso level of 21.5 to the US dollar, a level that reflects over 3% weakness versus the US dollar at the present time April 8, 2025. If the peso goes to 21.5, the trade doesn’t work.
But, in the end, remember, if nothing changes, all is good.
Whatever happens, you have to respect the peso and Mexico. In times past, a crisis of this magnitude would have crushed the Mexican peso. It has done well, so far,  and should be proud.
This blog is for educational and informational purposes only, covering general market trends, industry developments, and asset features. Nothing herein is investment advice, a solicitation, or a recommendation to buy or sell any assets. Etherfuse and its guests may hold stakes in some or all of the assets discussed.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="audio/mpeg" href="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/160878476/f0f6d89f09a0779e8a1d2a68540f76af.mp3"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Savings Bonds and Christmas Clubs</title>
    <published>2025-03-31T20:59:33+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-31T20:59:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://etherfuse.substack.com/p/savings-bonds-and-christmas-clubs</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://etherfuse.substack.com/p/savings-bonds-and-christmas-clubs"/>
    <author>
      <name>Donald Elefson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">If a country wants to grow in greatness, it must increase its rate of personal savings. To do this, countries need to create products that allow savings habits to be developed across the whole income range of the population. The masses must have a means to save large, small, and micro amounts.
At present, there are countries that have good savings mentalities and some that don’t. In Germany the savings rates hit 11.5% of income in 2024. France’s 4th quarter 2024 household savings rate was 18.4%. These are good, but they can be bigger, greater. The country lagging in the savings race is the United States of America. In 2024 the US personal savings rate was 3.8%, which is lower than the long-term average of 8.56%.
To be great, this must go up.
In times past, a pillar of US savings power was US Savings bonds. In the 1950s,1960s, and 1970s US savings bonds were given for births, weddings, and graduations. They were bought, given, and held to maturity with a sense of pride in the USA.
Pride and savings should combine again.
Also, Christmas Clubs used to be popular in the US. Workers, usually in the retail space, would save money every paycheck. The interest earned was very low if anything at all, but at Christmas time they had money for Christmas gifts.
Conceptually, a product combining the features of US Savings Bonds and Christmas clubs could be a key to savings in the United States, or elsewhere, growing and leading to greatness.
To be fair, both ideas still exist in the United States. The problem is that there is a minimum amount of $25 dollars to buy US savings bonds, and savings clubs are long forgotten. For a savings program to have teeth people must be able to invest “micro” amounts on a monthly or bi-weekly basis. Frankly, a $25 dollar minimum is too much and acts as a headwind to true savings.
A habit of saving “micro” amounts can lead to saving small amounts, and small savings can lead to large savings amounts over time.
It is a habit of savings that is a progression from “micro” to large that can help make a country great.
Crypto, more specifically stable bonds and coins can fill this role. With crypto a saver can invest micro amounts on a regular basis.
To this end, companies like Etherfuse can provide stable short-term government bonds and stable coins denominated in US dollar, Mexican peso, Brazilian Real, Euro, and UK pounds to savers for as little as $1.
With Etherfuse’s products all sorts of people can start regular savings programs in US, Brazil, Mexico, Europe, and the UK no matter how limited or great their funds are at present.
In the end, governments must wake up and find ways to bring more people into the savings game, if they want to be great.
Crypto is a solution and it should be embraced.
This blog is for educational and informational purposes only, covering general market trends, industry developments, and asset features. Nothing herein is investment advice, a solicitation, or a recommendation to buy or sell any assets. Etherfuse and its guests may hold stakes in some or all of the assets discussed.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="audio/mpeg" href="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/160291406/90810dfef6c0d1c3b5a459e689142f68.mp3"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
