<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog – Félix Pago</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.felixpago.com/en/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.felixpago.com%2Fen%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.article-top-title+.text-color-smooth.text-size-regular&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.felixpago.com%2Fen%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.article-top-title+.text-color-smooth.text-size-regular&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:06:09+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Strongest currencies in the world: what are they? – Félix Pago</title>
    <published>2024-09-12T18:50:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-12T18:50:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.felixpago.com/en/blog/living-in-the-usa/finances/strongest-currencies-in-the-world-what-are-they</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.felixpago.com/en/blog/living-in-the-usa/finances/strongest-currencies-in-the-world-what-are-they"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ignacio Remuiñan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The foreign exchange market is one of the biggest objectives of many investors and speculators, but there is much more behind one of the largest markets in the world. ‍It is the place par excellence where currencies are exchanged for different purposes, such as international trade, investment or payment for services abroad. What is a currency? 	Una currency It is a monetary unit used in a region or in a foreign country, that is, external or foreign to our country of origin. ‍As part of international trade, currencies are exchanged in the international money market, and on these tours and operations, their price may fluctuate, taking into account that other currencies also operate.‍However, if the central bank of a given country sets a fixed exchange rate, the price of that currency will be set in relation to other currencies. What is the foreign exchange market? 	 	As a result of the exchange of currencies, the foreign exchange market. This is a decentralized market in which currencies are traded, worldwide. It is known by the name of Forex (Foreign Exchange Market), or Currency Market (Foreign exchange market). ‍In the foreign exchange market, they can be purchased as an investment or as a means of payment abroad. ‍In order to maintain its main feature of being decentralized, there is no single quote for a given currency.How is buying and selling currencies? La buying and selling currencies It is a financial transaction that is currently widely used by investors, since the foreign exchange market is the financial market with the highest growth projection in the world. ‍The purchase and sale of currencies is carried out by peers, that is, exchangeable currencies are offered in pairs, and therefore, the value of the first currency is calculated, which is called base currency.What is currency exchange called?Foreign exchange is the name given to the operation of exchanging one local currency to another. When making payments abroad or a person travels abroad, they need to exchange currencies in order to be able to manage in the currency of that country or in the second most traded currency. ‍Foreign exchange is stipulated by the exchange rate established in Forex or by the monetary policies of the country in which the process is taking place. What are the strongest currencies in the world?Although, the The U.S. dollar is the most traded currency in the foreign exchange market, this It doesn&amp;#x27;t make it the strongest currency of the world, but it stands out for being a reference currency, with a high value and a certain stability compared to other currencies. ‍The strongest currency in the world today comes from Kuwait, a country with a lot of oil. It&amp;#x27;s about the Kuwaiti Dinar (KWD), which has a value equivalent to $3.27. This currency is followed by:‍Bahraini DinarOmani RialJordanian DinarBritish PoundCayman Islands dollarSwiss francEuroUSDCanadian dollar.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/avif" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/6673203f1adece930c30197b/66be2bab4cc76987f3454786_piggybank-bH6e_xFWE-4-unsplash%20(1).avif"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SWIFT code: what is it and what is it for? – Félix Pago</title>
    <published>2024-08-21T00:34:40+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-21T00:34:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.felixpago.com/en/blog/living-in-the-usa/finances/swift-code-what-is-it-and-what-is-it-for</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.felixpago.com/en/blog/living-in-the-usa/finances/swift-code-what-is-it-and-what-is-it-for"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ignacio Remuiñan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Within the world of international operations, there are several numbers, codes and necessary data that banking and financial institutions require to identify other bank branches, inside and outside the country.‍One of them is the SWIFT code, a very important code to be able to transfer or receive money between different countries. What is the SWIFT code? 	El SWIFT code It is an alphanumeric code whose usefulness is of vital importance when communicating between banks at an international level. ‍The acronym SWIFT stands for Global Interbank Financial Telecommunication Company (Society for World Interbank Financial Telecommunication). It is also known as BIC (Bank Identifier Code), and as its name suggests, it is used for identify banks and financial institutions around the world. ‍The SWIFT differs from the IBAN code, since the latter is the one used in the SEPA zone, an area composed of 28 countries of the European Union and other countries of the European continent. What is the swift code for? 	 	The swift code is used for carry out messaging operations or bank transfers between different countries, in an encrypted and secure way. This code identifies the entity receiving the transfer. ‍The swift consists of a series of between 8 and 11 characters (numbers and letters), and is used in those countries that are not part of the SEPA zone. It is formed as follows:‍4 letters that correspond to the bank&amp;#x27;s identification,2 letters that correspond to the country where the bank is located,2 letters or numbers that indicate the location of the bank&amp;#x27;s head office,3 characters that correspond to the identification of the bank branch.‍Sometimes, the last three digits that identify the branch are not necessary. How do I know what the swift code of my account is?In general, the swift code of the bank or financial institution is available in the account details or on banks&amp;#x27; websites or mobile applications. How to get a Swift code? To make or receive an international transfer, the bank can help you obtain the swift code. The code can be requested directly at the bank branch, or through the user&amp;#x27;s website or app.‍In turn, there are different websites that track or check the different bank codes of many countries. ‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/avif" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/6673203f1adece930c30197b/66bbbcbbd9b13658a9e920f2_CODIGO%20SWIFT%20QUE%20ES.avif"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Cash advance: what is it and what is it for? – Félix Pago</title>
    <published>2024-08-21T00:34:27+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-21T00:34:27+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.felixpago.com/en/blog/living-in-the-usa/finances/cash-advance-what-is-it-and-what-is-it-for</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.felixpago.com/en/blog/living-in-the-usa/finances/cash-advance-what-is-it-and-what-is-it-for"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ignacio Remuiñan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">‍A cash advance or cash advance with a credit card, will allow you to get money quickly despite the risks and charges to consider, since it is a loan that the customer can request from the bank at any given time, with immediate effect, since the money is delivered instantly. ‍In this way, the customer borrows money from their credit card limit to count on the monetary amount in cash. Next, you will learn everything about the cash advance.What is cash advance? 	The cash advance is the action of making a cash withdrawal within the credit card limit. The cash advance can be completed using an ATM at a branch of the financial institution where the customer has a bank account, or by phone. ‍In addition, the cash advance allows the customer to withdraw cash (as if it were a debit card), being especially suitable for emergencies, when you need to pay only in cash, goods or services. How does the cash advance work? 	 	The cash advance works in different ways, depending on the method you choose to do it: ‍Using an ATM, where you&amp;#x27;ll need your credit card PIN to get the cash. If you don&amp;#x27;t have the PIN that corresponds to your credit card handy, banks allow you to request it on their Internet websites. Going to one of the offices, where the holder must present a valid identification document to perform the cash advance. Through a telephone call, to transfer the money from the credit line, to an account in the customer&amp;#x27;s name. But this last option is not offered by all banks. ‍In general, the cash advance amounts to a maximum of 30% of the credit card limit or a minimum of $100. What will be deducted from the available credit is the amount of cash requested, together with the corresponding fee or commission. What are the cash advance fees?The amount that the bank charges in advance to the customer who made the cash advance, may range from 3% to 6% of the amount corresponding to the cash advance, or charge a one-time commission of $10, which you must pay even if the money is returned the next day. ‍And with the cash advance requested by the customer, including the fee to be paid. ‍This means that if a customer has a credit card for 1,000 dollars and asks for an advance of 30% of their credit limit, equivalent to 300 dollars, the fee or commission for the cash advance will be deducted from this amount.‍On the other hand, apart from the fact that the charge of the cash advance fee is contemplated, it must be taken into account that the annual interest rate on this type of transaction It is higher than the amount that prevails over consumption made with a credit card. This implies that the balance generated by the cash advance is presented separately, to which it is generated with the usual expenses within the assigned credit line. ‍Finally, if the cash advance is withdrawn using an ATM that is not part of the bank network where the customer has their credit card, it is very likely that the fee for this concept will be even higher. How are cash advances made with a credit card paid?The procedure for paying cash advances is similar to the usual consumption with credit cards: By phone, sending a check by mail, through your bank&amp;#x27;s Internet portal or with the mobile app provided by your financial institution.‍As the interest rate on cash advances is higher, any payment you make will be used by the bank to settle the cash advance debt, because this starts to generate interest immediately.What happens if I don&amp;#x27;t pay a cash advance? 	 	In this case, your debt with the bank will increase, given that the interest rate that prevails on this type of transaction, is higher than that established for ordinary consumption with a credit card. What happens if I pay a cash advance ahead of time?In the first instance, you will be able to solidify your credit reputation with the bank, by paying your debt on time. ‍In addition, it will prevent the debit balance from growing exponentially, especially since the interest rate for cash advance is higher than for any consumption with a credit card.‍In short, cash advance may be an option for dealing with financial emergencies, since it allows you to have money immediately, even outside the bank&amp;#x27;s service hours, when using an ATM, apart from the fact that your request does not need verification or approval by the bank. ‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/avif" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/6673203f1adece930c30197b/66bbb52bde4736baa73312bb_efectivo.avif"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
