<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Glo's Blog - Grow your knowledge about Glo and crypto for good.</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.glodollar.org/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.glodollar.org%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-list+a&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.glodollar.org%2Farticles%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bfs-toc-element%3D%22contents%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.blog-date-wrapper+.text-size-xsmall&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.glodollar.org%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-list+a&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.glodollar.org%2Farticles%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bfs-toc-element%3D%22contents%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.blog-date-wrapper+.text-size-xsmall&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:06:24+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Glo Dollar Joins VeChain: A Partnership For Sustainability and Impact</title>
    <published>2025-03-18T22:06:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-18T22:06:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.glodollar.org/articles/glo-dollar-joins-vechain-a-partnership-for-sustainability-and-impact</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.glodollar.org/articles/glo-dollar-joins-vechain-a-partnership-for-sustainability-and-impact"/>
    <content type="html">With VeChain Foundations $250,000 Donation, Glo Dollar is launching Vechain&amp;#x27;s only stablecoin —one that directly funds the sustainability-driven VeBetterDAOVeChain is a blockchain with a strong focus on sustainability and creating a greener future. Through initiatives like VeBetterDAO, it incentivizes eco-friendly actions, supports carbon management, and enables businesses to track and reduce their environmental impact using blockchain.Sustainable funding for VeBetterDAO, focused on SustainabilityGlo Dollar will not only be joining VeBetterDAO, but profit from Glo Dollar on Vechain will be donated to the VeBetterDAO treasury. As an example, a $10M Glo Dollar marketcap on Vechain, would generate up to $350,000/year in donations for the VeBetterDAO. At $100M, that is $3.5M a year being donated to sustainability projects building in the VeChain ecosystem. VeBetterDAO was launched by VeChain to help build sustainability goals into all kinds of projects. It incentivizes eco-friendly actions by allowing users to earn B3TR tokens for participating in sustainability-focused activities, such as using sustainable apps, voting on governance proposals, and contributing to community discussions.Developers can integrate their eco-friendly applications into the VeBetter ecosystem, accessing resources like a fully operational blockchain, economy, and DAO infrastructure, along with funding opportunities to reward users and foster app growth.These initiatives will help expand the DAOs treasury and their focus on supporting sustainability projects within the VeChain Ecosystem. Glo Dollar Joins VeChain as their only stablecoinVeChain gains a stablecoin that brings more liquidity, enhances DeFi, and enables payments across its ecosystem. Users can transact in Glo Dollar, reducing volatility while increasing accessibility for builders and businesses.Automatic Funding for Sustainability ProjectsEvery Glo Dollar transaction supports sustainability without extra cost to users. The Glo Foundation donates all treasury revenue generated on VeChain to VeBetter DAO, which funds climate and sustainability-focused initiatives. This means VeChain users help fund impact projects simply by holding and using Glo Dollar and integrating it into their dApps.Strengthening VeBetter and Sustainability dAppsVeBetter incentivizes real-world sustainable actions, and Glo Dollar usage amplifies these efforts. Applications like:Cleanify – Rewards users for litter collection.Mugshot – Incentivizes reusable cup usage.GreenCart – Encourages sustainable shopping.Glo Dollar provides a stable asset for rewards, enhancing treasury management and financial planning for dApps. We’re also exploring its use as a real-world payment token, allowing dApp users to spend their rewards and stay motivated to adopt sustainable practices. Expanding DeFi and Treasury SupportWith Glo Dollar, VeChain’s DeFi landscape gains a stablecoin that dApps and DAOs can use to manage treasuries. It also creates a bridge for external liquidity, with pathways for converting Glo Dollar to USD or fiat. How It WorksUsers can acquire Glo Dollar on Vechain through Betterswap or VeSwap, through the Glo Dollar dapp, or through other available options. US businesses can mint Glo Dollars on Vechain directly through our issuer Brale. The fiat backing Glo Dollar will be invested and earn revenue, that will be donated to VeBetterDAO.Developers and projects can integrate it for payments, incentives, and treasury management. VeBetter DAO automatically receives funding from Glo Dollar’s treasury yield, ensuring a constant flow of resources to support sustainable projects.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/622c49f66ed2912f4cef75cc/67d96342ef9e6c623ff0b90c_Vechain_Logo.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Climate Coordination Network joins our list of Funding Recipients</title>
    <published>2025-02-07T22:06:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-07T22:06:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.glodollar.org/articles/climate-coordination-network-and-glo-dollar</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.glodollar.org/articles/climate-coordination-network-and-glo-dollar"/>
    <content type="html">What is Climate Coordination Network?Climate Coordination Network is dedicated to speeding up blockchain-powered climate solutions worldwide, driving different forms of climate action to help build a more sustainable and fair future.By providing grants and support, it helps climate projects cut greenhouse gas emissions and develop key infrastructure for Web3 climate solutions. You might know them from organizing Gitcoin Grants rounds, Giveth rounds, and most recently, their climate round on Octant.To date, Climate Coordination Network has distributed over $4M in grants to climate solutions.We&amp;#x27;re thrilled to support their mission and help them keep making a difference. 🌱Why we’re adding Climate Coordination Network as a Funding RecipientQuality and FitClimate Coordination Network’s success is aligned with our intent of combatting climate change. Through its rounds, Climate Coordination Network distributes grants to hundreds of climate-focused grantees. It’s a simple way for us to make an indirect impact on the funding of many projects—this is similar to the way we’re funding Giveth, Gitcoin, Protocol Guild, and Artizen.Climate Coordination Network has a strong demonstrated track record of positive change made over time. Popular DemandThe Glo community values the Climate Coordination Network for its impactful work, which effectively combines climate action with blockchain principles.Fund Climate Coordination Network’s efforts to accelerate blockchain-enabled climate solutions by holding Glo Dollars. How it works:Go to app.glodollar.org and connect your wallet. You&amp;#x27;ll automatically see your Glo Dollar holdings and the expected funding generated with your Glo Dollars.Click on the Cause Area shown next to the ⚙️ symbol, and select ‘Combat climate change’.</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/622c49f66ed2912f4cef75cc/67a6036d455b8e9816f6859a_Frame%20689%20(1).png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Coala Pay becomes a Glo Funding Recipient</title>
    <published>2025-01-30T22:06:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-30T22:06:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.glodollar.org/articles/coala-pay-funding-recipient</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.glodollar.org/articles/coala-pay-funding-recipient"/>
    <content type="html">Coala Pay is the first recipient of funding from our new ‘Strengthen Humanitarian Aid’ Cause Area, supported by The Stellar Development Foundation following their $250,000 donation to The Glo Foundation.Coala Pay is a last mile money movement and management platform purpose-built for the international aid sector. They help INGOs, foundations, corporate, and government donors to reduce inefficiencies and make good on the promise of localisation.Use Glo Dollars on Stellar to improve aid funding, at no cost to you as a Glo Dollar userThanks to the Stellar Development Foundation (SDF), we’ve added Coala Pay as a recipient for Glo Dollar funds. Now, Glo Dollars on Stellar are powering international aid efforts and supporting a better future for all.‍Glo donates 100% of its profits. How that works on Stellar:You buy Glo DollarsThe fiat backing Glo Dollar is invested and earns revenueThe Glo Foundation uses its portion of the revenue to support Coala PayGlo Dollar users on Stellar can make aid funding better for everybody automatically, without having to make an additional donationCoala Pay will be the default funding option if you buy Glo Dollars on Stellar. With the Glo Dollar app, you can choose to change your cause area to address a wide range of critical issues, such as fighting extreme poverty, combating climate change, or funding Web3 public goods.If you’re using Glo Dollars on another chain, you can also select Coala Pay to be the Funding Recipient of your Glo Dollar holdings:Go to app.glodollar.org and connect your wallet. You&amp;#x27;ll automatically see your Glo Dollar holdings and the expected funding generated with your Glo Dollars.Click on the Cause Area shown next to the ⚙️ symbol.Why supporting Coala Pay makes a differenceSending money to a local aid organization halfway around the world should be as easy as donating to a crowdfunding campaign.Legacy financial systems weren’t built for international aid. They make it harder to help during crises and slow down the aid process.Coala Pay is changing that. Its tools help aid organizations deliver faster, cheaper support. By leveraging Web3, Coala Pay directs more funds to grassroots organizations working locally.International aid should feel like mutual aid. And with anticipated shortfalls in aid funding, Glo holders have an opportunity to step in—helping bridge critical gaps and ensure frontline organizations get the support they need.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/622c49f66ed2912f4cef75cc/679b5984726f248c69f800c4_Frame%20376.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
