<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog - Goldsky</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://goldsky.com/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=BrowserlessCSSBridge&amp;browserless_url=http%3A%2F%2F10.0.0.124%3A3050%2F&amp;browserless&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fgoldsky.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=section+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bclass%5E%3D%22Markdown_container__%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=p.text-gs-text-secondary&amp;date_selector_index=0&amp;date_format=M+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=BrowserlessCSSBridge&amp;browserless_url=http%3A%2F%2F10.0.0.124%3A3050%2F&amp;browserless&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fgoldsky.com%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=section+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=%5Bclass%5E%3D%22Markdown_container__%22%5D&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=p.text-gs-text-secondary&amp;date_selector_index=0&amp;date_format=M+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:06:30+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SimpleHash Alternative: Migrating to Goldsky After the Phantom Acquis…</title>
    <published>2025-02-28T22:06:27+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-28T22:06:27+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://goldsky.com</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://goldsky.com"/>
    <author>
      <name>Goldsky</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">SimpleHash’s acquisition and what it means for you If you’re reading this, you’ve likely heard the news that SimpleHash was acquired by Phantom and will be shutting down services on March 27, 2025. Huge congratulations to Olly and the team! It’s well-deserved recognition of the platform they’ve built. For customers, this means that there’s less than a month to migrate your infrastructure. You’re probably feeling a mix of stress and pressure to quickly find a SimpleHash alternative and you’re not alone — we’ve been getting a lot of messages from people looking for a replacement that’s reliable, scalable, and easy to transition to. The good news is that we’ve been a close partner of SimpleHash for over 2 years and can help get you what you need before the deadline. Our team is deeply familiar with their data, significantly easing your transition. Unexpected migrations are never easy. But they sometimes lead to discovering better solutions. We're here to help you not just replace what you're losing with SimpleHash, but potentially improve your infrastructure in the process. Our SimpleHash migration support package Understanding the urgency of the situation, we've created a special onboarding process for SimpleHash customers:  Priority onboarding: We’ll fast-track your implementation to meet the March 27th deadline. White-glove support: Our team will walk you through the process and ensure your services continue without disruption. 3 months of free service: A welcome to give you breathing room as you settle in with us :)  To get this package, fill out our quick priority migration form. Why we might be the right fit for you We've built Goldsky to excel in specific areas that matter most to teams requiring high-performance infrastructure. If these are top priority for you, you’re at the right place.  Speed, scalability, and reliability. Goldsky is battle-tested at scale by some of the most demanding products and chains. MetaMask, Polymarket, Arweave, Optimism, Rainbow, and Stellar all rely on our infrastructure for critical operations. Infrastructure that can handle serious volume. Our systems currently process over 100M messages and transfer more than 36GB+ of data per minute without breaking a sweat. 24/7 human support when you need it. Our team provides genuine 24/7 support, so if issues arise, you’ll have real people helping you solve them. Specialized in token balance and transfer data. If your primary needs revolve around tracking token balances and transfers, our systems are optimized specifically for these high-frequency operations.  Why we might NOT be the right fit We believe in being upfront about where we excel and fall short, and understand that we may not be the right fit for everyone.  Limited chains (but increasing coverage). We’ve been partnering with SimpleHash, meaning we can provide the exact same data you’ve been using. However, we don’t yet have the same chain support, but we’re getting full coverage across all chains. Custom solutions available. That said, if you have specific needs that fall outside our current offering, or SimpleHash’s, we're open to discussing custom work to fill those gaps – especially for teams facing the March 27th deadline.  How long will it take to switch from SimpleHash to Goldsky? Depending on your existing usage pattern, teams can expect to migrate in under a day or two, but it depends on your specific implementation and needs. If you were using SimpleHash’s Kafka feature, you can switch to Goldsky in under a day depending on chain coverage. As an added bonus, you can use the data in any of our other supported sinks. We plan to have direct drop-in API support running soon. Migrate today If you're facing the March 27th deadline, fill out our priority migration form. While we're confident in our ability to serve your needs, we understand that finding the right fit is important. If you have any questions about whether Goldsky is the right solution for your specific use cases, we're happy to have an honest conversation about it. </content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/gif" href="https://goldsky.com/images/blog/covers/simplehash_to_goldsky.gif"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Redefining Yield Management with Superform - Goldsky</title>
    <published>2024-10-08T22:06:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-08T22:06:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://goldsky.com</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://goldsky.com"/>
    <author>
      <name>Goldsky</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Introducing Superform Superform is redefining how users interact with yield across multiple chains through its permissionless, modular protocol. As a central hub for liquidity and vault management, Superform simplifies cross-chain transactions, providing a smooth and efficient user experience. Goldsky’s support powers two essential components within the Superform ecosystem:  Safari XP Rewards Program: Enables real-time updates on user balances and activities, leveraging Subgraphs as data sources for Mirror pipelines. SuperScan Explorer: Aggregates cross-chain data, presenting a comprehensive view of protocol activity and vault interactions.  These capabilities allow protocols to seamlessly list vaults and manage yield opportunities while giving users complete control over their cross-chain yield management. This collaboration creates a seamless environment for tracking and managing multi-chain assets with unparalleled transparency and accuracy. Key Components of the Superform Protocol At the heart of Superform’s platform are two key components that leverage Goldsky’s data infrastructure to provide a seamless cross-chain experience: Safari XP Program  A monthly tournament-based rewards system where users earn XP points and exclusive NFTs based on their time-weighted Total Value Locked (TVL). Points are updated in real-time, ensuring accurate cross-chain balances across multiple vaults. Features gamification elements like leaderboards and tier-based rewards to drive engagement and competition.   SuperScan Explorer  A multi-chain explorer that aggregates data from various chains to provide a comprehensive view of cross-chain activity, similar to Etherscan but with multi-chain compatibility. Enables users to track deposits, withdrawals, and yield interactions across multiple chains, enhancing visibility and control over their assets.  These components create an interconnected environment for both users and protocols to optimize yield management and monitor multi-chain assets with ease.  Behind the Scenes To power a multi-chain rewards program and a comprehensive explorer like Superform’s, real-time data aggregation and efficient cross-chain synchronization are crucial. That’s where Goldsky’s Subgraphs and Mirror come in, ensuring that all vault interactions and user balances are accurately tracked and reflected in near real-time. By leveraging Goldsky, Superform is able to deliver a high-performance platform that meets the demands of both users and protocols. Let’s break down how this integration works: Subgraphs as the Foundation for Data Aggregation Superform’s ecosystem is built on Subgraphs designed to index and track protocol activity across its vaults. Each Subgraph captures a variety of data, from user deposits and withdrawals to cross-chain transactions, presenting this information in a structured and accessible format. This indexed data serves as the primary data source for Goldsky’s Mirror pipelines, enabling real-time observability. Mirror Pipelines for Cross-Chain Synchronization Once data is indexed by Subgraphs, Mirror pipelines step in to aggregate, process, and synchronize it across multiple chains. This allows Superform to maintain up-to-date user balances, track liquidity across various vaults, and support seamless cross-chain yield management without manual intervention. Looking Forward The collaboration between Superform and Goldsky is more than just a technical integration—it’s a reimagining of how data can flow seamlessly across chains to create a truly unified DeFi experience. By leveraging Goldsky’s Subgraphs and Mirror pipelines, Superform has been able to unlock real-time updates, enhanced observability, and a reliable infrastructure that supports complex data flows. These innovations provide Superform’s users with the transparency, speed, and accuracy they need to navigate a constantly evolving DeFi landscape. With Goldsky powering both the Safari XP Rewards Program and the SuperScan Explorer, Superform is equipped to deliver a unique, cross-chain solution that offers unmatched control and insight into yield management. The integration doesn’t just set a new benchmark for the industry—it also opens the door for future possibilities. As Superform continues to evolve and add new capabilities, Goldsky will remain an essential partner in supporting their growth, helping to redefine what’s possible in the world of multi-chain DeFi. </content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://goldsky.com/images/blog/covers/superform_announcement.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Goldsky x World Chain: Fueling the Next Wave of Onchain Innovation</title>
    <published>2024-10-03T22:06:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-03T22:06:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://goldsky.com</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://goldsky.com"/>
    <author>
      <name>Goldsky</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Introduction Goldsky is bringing its data power to World Chain, an L2 that is part of the Superchain ecosystem and built on the OP Stack, designed to put verified humans at the forefront of onchain interactions. With complete support for Mainnet and Sepolia Testnet, Goldsky’s integration makes querying, tracking, and streaming onchain data effortless. World Chain’s unique approach prioritizes verified users through World ID’s Proof of Personhood, creating a network built for authentic human engagement. By integrating with World Chain, Goldsky is enabling developers to tap into a structured, real-time data ecosystem that powers everything from DeFi protocols to identity-based solutions. The result? A powerful synergy that unlocks faster insights, better performance, and the potential to reimagine what’s possible in a human-first, onchain world.  Supporting World Chain’s Vision As World Chain scales to accommodate more verified human users, the need for a stable and reliable data infrastructure becomes paramount. With reliability at the forefront, Goldsky’s infrastructure ensures that real-time data remains accessible and accurate, even as network activity intensifies. This unwavering support reinforces the core principles of transparency and integrity that World Chain champions, building a foundation that developers can trust. Subgraphs simplify the process of retrieving structured data, making it easy to trace interactions, query transaction histories, and analyze user behavior. Whether it’s high-volume transactions or more granular onchain events, Subgraphs provide the efficient querying needed to understand how users are engaging with apps on the network. This depth of insight gives developers the confidence to optimize their applications and deliver better user experiences. Mirror pipelines take data accessibility a step further by offering uninterrupted, real-time data streams directly to developer databases. This allows for dynamic integration with custom analytics tools, enabling developers to build dashboards, automated alerts, and other data-driven features. With real-time insights at their disposal, developers can monitor the state of the network as it happens, responding quickly to shifts in user behavior or network trends. This combination of Subgraphs and Mirror pipelines provides the perfect toolkit for building high-performance applications that can grow alongside World Chain’s expanding user base. By prioritizing transparency, stability, and real-time data access, Goldsky’s infrastructure supports the creation of an ecosystem where accurate, accessible information fuels innovation, trust, and meaningful use cases that cater to verified human users.  Getting Started Ready to dive in? Start building on World Chain today. Check out our documentation for detailed guides and setup instructions:  Introduction to Subgraphs Use slug ‘worldchain’ for Mainnet Use slug ‘worldchain-sepolia’ for Testnet   Introduction to Mirror FAQ  We’ll see you onchain 🫡 </content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://goldsky.com/images/blog/covers/worldcoin_announcement.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
