<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Huma Finance</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.huma.finance"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.huma.finance%2Frss.xml&amp;content_selector=.blog-post__body&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.huma.finance%2Frss.xml&amp;content_selector=.blog-post__body&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:06:40+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing Huma 2.0: Real Yield on Solana</title>
    <published>2025-04-09T23:27:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-09T23:27:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.huma.finance/introducing-huma-2.0-permissionless-real-yield-on-solana</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.huma.finance/introducing-huma-2.0-permissionless-real-yield-on-solana"/>
    <author>
      <name>info@huma.finance (Huma Finance)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="blog-post__body"&gt;             &lt;span id="hs_cos_wrapper_post_body" class="hs_cos_wrapper hs_cos_wrapper_meta_field hs_cos_wrapper_type_rich_text" style="" data-hs-cos-general-type="meta_field" data-hs-cos-type="rich_text"&gt;&lt;h2 style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 18px; text-align: left; font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;Today marks a pivotal moment for Huma and the DeFi ecosystem as we launch Huma 2.0, our permissionless, compliant, and composable yield platform built on Solana. With Huma 2.0, we're opening access to stable, double-digit yield generated by real payment financing activities. The opportunities previously reserved for institutions are now available to everyone—and it's about&amp;nbsp; time. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;By making our product permissionless, we’ve now made real yield accessible to everyone, allowing anyone, anywhere to earn from the flow of real-life commerce.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 24px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;What Huma 2.0 Offers: Features Built for You&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="hs-embed-wrapper hs-fullwidth-embed" data-service="vimeo" data-responsive="true" style="position: relative; overflow: hidden; width: 100%; height: auto; padding: 0px; min-width: 256px; display: block; margin: auto;"&gt;&lt;div class="hs-embed-content-wrapper"&gt;&lt;div style="position: relative; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; padding-bottom: 56.34%; margin: 0px;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/1074109657?app_id=122963" width="426" height="240" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture; clipboard-write; encrypted-media" title="#HUMA_2_0_PREFINAL_V1" style="position: absolute; top: 0px; left: 0px; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: none;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!--more--&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 18px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;We've designed Huma 2.0 with flexibility and choice at its core, rolling out a set of features that let users choose how they want to earn. Here’s a breakdown of what’s inside:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Choose the path that suits your goals:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 18px; text-align: left;"&gt; &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classic mode:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides stable, double-digit real yield (currently 10.5% USDC APY, updated monthly) combined with baseline Huma Feathers. Think steady, predictable, sustainable.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maxi mode:&lt;/strong&gt; Built for Huma maxis. Skip the USDC yield (0% APY) to maximize Huma Feathers, earning up to 25x the feathers during the limited-time launch promotion. Go big, go all-in.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility:&lt;/strong&gt; LPs can &lt;strong&gt;switch the mode&lt;/strong&gt; of their existing positions anytime, at no extra charge beyond gas fees.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional Lock-ups for more rewards:&lt;/strong&gt; While not required, locking your deposit for 3 or 6 months significantly increases your Feather reward multipliers. The longer the commitment, the bigger the multiplier. During the lock-up period, users generally cannot withdraw their funds without forfeiting some accrued rewards, thus ensuring predictable liquidity management for Huma and stable returns for users. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt; &lt;h4 style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46; font-weight: normal; font-size: 18px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;$PST: Liquid &amp;amp; composable LP token:&lt;/span&gt; Depositing in Classic mode gets you the liquid LP token $PST (PayFi Strategy Token). It represents your share, is yield-bearing, and is built for DeFi composability, plugging right into the Solana ecosystem. Our Huma 2.0 launch integration partners are:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46; font-size: 18px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jup.ag/" rel="noopener"&gt;Jupiter&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;span style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;Swap $PST for USDC anytime, instantly.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46; font-size: 18px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.kamino.finance/" rel="noopener"&gt;Kamino&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;span style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;Borrow USDC against your $PST. Loop, farm, and maximize yield (coming soon).&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46; font-size: 18px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://rate-x.io/" rel="noopener"&gt;RateX&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;span style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;Split PST to enter leveraged YT/PT strategies (coming soon)&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt; &lt;h4 style="font-weight: bold; line-height: 1.5;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 18px;"&gt;Referral system:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 18px;"&gt; Grow the community and get rewarded. Earn 10% of the Feathers collected by friends you invite for one entire year.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 24px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why This Launch Matters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 18px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;Let’s be &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;REAL&lt;/span&gt;. Finding stable, sustainable double-digit yield is a hard task. Historically, it's been reserved for top institutions and family offices, while most people settled for fractions of a percent. much of DeFi yield, despite unlocking access, has been driven by speculation, token emissions, and market cycles, often proving unsustainable, especially in bear markets. DeFi yield typically comes from token incentives or staking rewards tied to highly speculative activity, making them prone to volatility and heavy fluctuation depending on market cycles. The timing for Huma 2.0 couldn't be more critical. DeFi is ready for a new type of yield – one that is grounded in real life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;Against this backdrop, the tools for a better system are rapidly maturing. Stablecoins are experiencing insane growth, with transaction volumes recently climbing to a reported $35 trillion, highlighting their rapid adoption as efficient financial rails. Huma leverages these stablecoins and blockchain technology to power its PayFi network.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 18px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;This confluence – the market's need for sustainable yield and the rise of stablecoins – makes now the perfect time for Huma 2.0. By using stablecoins and on-chain liquidity, Huma's PayFi network accelerates global payments, generating stable, double-digit yield that originates from real financial activity. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 24px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real Life, Real Yield: Stable Through Bull or Bear&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.huma.finance/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot%202025-04-10%20at%2003.19.23.png?width=8820&amp;amp;height=4968&amp;amp;name=Screenshot%202025-04-10%20at%2003.19.23.png" width="2940" height="1656" alt="Screenshot 2025-04-10 at 03.19.23" style="height: auto; max-width: 100%; width: 2940px;" sizes="(max-width: 2940px) 100vw, 2940px"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 18px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46; font-weight: normal;"&gt;We can’t stress it enough; &lt;span style="font-size: 18px;"&gt;t&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;his yield is built different!&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;PayFi yield is earned from real financial activity – transaction fees paid by businesses using the network. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Here’s the engine: &lt;/span&gt;Each time a business taps into the PayFi network to settle a payment, it pays a daily fee (typically 6 to 10 basis points) to access liquidity until it is repaid. Because the liquidity is repaid frequently—often within one to five days—the same capital can be recycled many times per year. That rapid turnover creates a compounding effect that drives strong, recurring yields for liquidity providers. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The result is stable, double-digit yield that doesn’t depend on bull markets or token farming. This yield doesn't follow market cycles. Markets go up and down; PayFi yield doesn’t. Whether crypto is booming or dipping, people still spend, send, and settle – that's where the yield comes from. This makes Huma’s stable, double-digit yield incredibly attractive and reliable, &lt;strong&gt;especially&lt;/strong&gt; in bear markets when other sources may dry up. It’s powered by real businesses moving real money. As long as global commerce continues (and we all know it will), the yield is sustainable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 24px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join the PayFi Movement&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46; font-size: 18px;"&gt;Huma 2.0 goes beyond a new platform; it's an invitation to participate in a more open, efficient, and accessible financial future, embodying our mission to accelerate the movement of money for a world that’s always on. It reflects the Huma ethos – a reminder to aim higher, break free from what holds us back, and embrace the endless possibilities that lie beyond.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 18px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;Every past revolution in finance has served the few. Remember those who weren’t invited to the last financial revolution – the one led by PayPal, Stripe, and other gatekeepers? This time, it's different. The barriers are gone, the system is changing, and the power is no longer centralized. PayFi is opening up access.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="line-height: 1.5; font-size: 18px; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;With Huma 2.0, you can actually be part of the next financial revolution. By joining now, you gain early access to this unique yield source, accumulate Huma Feathers, and get in ahead of our upcoming Token Generation Event (TGE), as we prepare to be the first major project to launch on Jupiter's upcoming LFG 2.0 platform. Early support for real-life finance comes with real upside.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #423b46;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to earn Real Yield? Start earning now: https://app.huma.finance/&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;p style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 1.5; text-align: left;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;           &lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://blog.huma.finance/hubfs/Huma%202.0%20press%20release%20%281%29.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Splyce &amp; Huma Unveil SOLMATE to Keep Solana Yield Sustainable Amid SIMD-228 Staking Shifts</title>
    <published>2025-03-13T21:39:04+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-13T21:39:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.huma.finance/splyce-huma-unveil-solmate-amid-solanasimd-228-staking-shift</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.huma.finance/splyce-huma-unveil-solmate-amid-solanasimd-228-staking-shift"/>
    <author>
      <name>info@huma.finance (Huma Finance)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="blog-post__body"&gt;             &lt;span id="hs_cos_wrapper_post_body" class="hs_cos_wrapper hs_cos_wrapper_meta_field hs_cos_wrapper_type_rich_text" style="" data-hs-cos-general-type="meta_field" data-hs-cos-type="rich_text"&gt;&lt;p style="font-size: 24px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pairing Staking Rewards and Real-World Yield for Smarter, More Resilient Returns.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solana’s staking landscape is on the verge of a major shift. With &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2025/03/06/s"&gt;&lt;span&gt;SIMD-228 poised to slash SOL staking rewards&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, investors will need new strategies to maintain strong, sustainable yields. Splyce Finance and Huma Finance have partnered to launch SOLMATE, an innovative decentralized exchange-traded fund (dETF) that pairs liquid staking with real-world cash flows — helping investors navigate this new reality.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 24px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 24px;"&gt;A More Efficient Approach to Solana Yield. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;SOLMATE is a USDC-denominated Multi-Yield dETF designed to optimize capital efficiency and risk-adjusted returns. It seamlessly integrates:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JupSOL – &lt;/strong&gt;Jupiter’s top-performing liquid staking token.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PayFi Strategy Token (PST)&lt;/strong&gt; – Huma’s upcoming liquid LP token, targeting double-digit yield backed by fees derived from real-world payment flows.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This dual-yield structure provides diversification and stability, allowing investors to maintain upside exposure while reducing volatility in a post-SIMD-288 environment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“We built the liquid PayFi Strategy Token to establish the transactional economy and sustainable real-world yield as a core DeFi primitive. Splyce’s diversified strategy empowers every SOLMATE to enhance SOL LSTs’ returns with fees collected from real-world payment flows. It’s truly groundbreaking,” said &lt;strong&gt;Erbil Karaman, Co-founder of Huma Finance. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;“SOLMATE represents the next evolution of on-chain investing. By combining real-world cash flows with Solana’s DeFi ecosystem, it offers investors a more stable yield without sacrificing upside exposure. This approach ensures capital remains productive, liquid, and positioned for growth,” said &lt;strong&gt;Manuel Rensink, Co-founder of Splyce Finance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick Ducoff, Head of Institutional Growth at Solana Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;, noted the broader implications: “Structured investment strategies are a key step in the evolution of Solana’s financial ecosystem.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;SOLMATE is fully permissionless and set to integrate with Solana’s leading DeFi protocols in the upcoming months, providing deep liquidity, frictionless access to decentralized money markets, and a robust portfolio management framework for both retail and institutional investors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Splyce Finance. &lt;/strong&gt;Splyce Finance is a permissionless Solana-native platform pioneering the launch of index- and yield dETFs. Designed for both asset managers and investors, Splyce delivers an on-chain platform for diversified yield generation. For more information, visit &lt;a href="https://splyce.finance/"&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://splyce.finance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and follow &lt;a href="https://x.com/SplyceFi"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Splyce on X&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="font-size: 18px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;About Huma Finance. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;Huma is the first PayFi network, powering financing of global payments with instant access to liquidity—anywhere, anytime. With $3B+ in transaction volume and zero defaults to date, Huma is set to bring trillions in payment volume on-chain, eliminating the efficiencies in cross-border payment financing while providing investors with sustainable yield backed by real-world activity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://x.com/humafinance" style="font-size: 11px; background-color: #ffff00;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;           &lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://blog.huma.finance/hubfs/Splyce%20x%20Huma%20%281%29.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Patrick F. Campos Joins Huma Finance as Chief Business Officer</title>
    <published>2025-02-14T13:59:35+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-14T13:59:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.huma.finance/patrick-campos-joins-huma-finance-as-cbo</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.huma.finance/patrick-campos-joins-huma-finance-as-cbo"/>
    <author>
      <name>info@huma.finance (Huma Finance)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="blog-post__body"&gt;             &lt;span id="hs_cos_wrapper_post_body" class="hs_cos_wrapper hs_cos_wrapper_meta_field hs_cos_wrapper_type_rich_text" style="" data-hs-cos-general-type="meta_field" data-hs-cos-type="rich_text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Huma Finance welcomes Patrick F. Campos as Chief Business Officer (CBO), where he will lead strategic growth, forge key industry partnerships, and advance the company’s expansion in real-world asset (RWA) financing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Patrick has built a career at the intersection of finance, blockchain, and regulation, tackling challenges in liquidity, capital efficiency, and market infrastructure. As former Chief Strategy Officer at Securrency, he was instrumental in developing institutional-grade blockchain-based financial and regulatory technology, focusing on tokenization, compliance, and global capital markets. His work has centered on solving inefficiencies in financial systems and unlocking new opportunities in decentralized finance and payments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!--more--&gt; &lt;p&gt;With a background in corporate strategy, capital markets, and regulatory frameworks, Patrick has advised companies in Web3, DeFi, digital payments, and financial technology, helping to shape investment and growth strategies. He has also held senior roles at King &amp;amp; Spalding, Baker Botts, and Chadbourne &amp;amp; Parke LLP, where he structured complex financial transactions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Patrick has been deeply involved in Huma’s vision, having previously served as a strategic advisor to both Huma and Arf. He has already contributed to shaping the company’s approach to liquidity, working capital solutions, and financial infrastructure. In his new role, he will focus on expanding Huma’s global presence, strengthening industry partnerships, and positioning Huma as a key player in payment financing innovation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I’m thrilled to join the dynamic Huma Finance team to help to create new decentralized paradigms for real-world asset finance” said Patrick Campos. “Next-generation financial products must meet the needs of a new global marketplace of crypto-savvy DeFi investors while leaving space for regulatory innovation through thoughtful structuring and proactive engagement. I’m looking forward to working closely with Erbil Karaman, Richard Liu, and the rest of the team to bring to life their vision of a vibrant PayFi ecosystem in which Huma Finance will be both trailblazer and protagonist."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Beyond finance, Patrick has a track record of building and leading high-performance teams, shaped by his experience as a United States Marine Corps officer, a founder of the Emirates American Football League and the Emirates Gridiron League, and a head coach of multiple American football teams.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;His leadership will accelerate Huma’s efforts to redefine global liquidity, credit, and access to capital.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;           &lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://blog.huma.finance/hubfs/Screenshot%202025-02-14%20at%2016.30.16.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
