<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Web3 Security Resource Center | Hypernative</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.hypernative.io/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hypernative.io%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date-cat-texxt&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hypernative.io%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date-cat-texxt&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:06:42+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How Ether.fi Maximizes User Rewards With Hypernative&amp;#x27;s Staking Monitoring | Hypernative</title>
    <published>2024-12-12T22:06:42+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-12T22:06:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.hypernative.io/blog/how-ether-fi-maximizes-user-rewards-with-hypernatives-staking-monitoring</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.hypernative.io/blog/how-ether-fi-maximizes-user-rewards-with-hypernatives-staking-monitoring"/>
    <content type="html">In May 2024, ether.fi partnered with Hypernative to secure its growing liquid restaking ecosystem. The leading liquid restaking protocol with more than $9B in TVL has now expanded the coverage to include real-time monitoring of validator performance.‍Over the past several months, Hypernative successfully demonstrated its effectiveness in real-time monitoring of validator performance, detecting missed rewards, empty blocks, and validator exits. Thanks to the timely alerts, ether.fi was able to detect an operational issue with one of its operators, leading to a speedy resolution that saved thousands of dollars. ether.fi is also leveraging Hypernative&amp;#x27;s validator performance reports to monitor the performance of its validators and compare between operators.‍‍You can&amp;#x27;t manage what you can&amp;#x27;t measure. Hypernative provides unparalleled real-time insights into our validators performance and is an indispensable tool for maximizing user returns. The periodic reports constitute an important tool, enabling assessment and comparison of our operators to ensure optimal performance.Staking monitoring complements our real-time security monitoring engagement with Hypernative, broadening the coverage to include a central component of our operations.‍Mike SilagadzeCo-founder &amp;amp; CEO @ ether.fi‍Hypernative&amp;#x27;s comprehensive solution for Ethereum staking monitoring allows customers to quickly address misconfigured validators, avoiding significant fund loss. Hypernative also provides periodic validator performance reports, enabling continuous operational improvement and performance comparison between validator cohorts. The solution covers:‍Validator performance (slashings, missed proposer rewards, sync rewards, attestations rewards etc.);Unexpected validator exits;Empty blocks production;Execution Layer (EL) rewards not received to the corresponding EL address;Unexpected deposits for validators pubkeys (&amp;quot;validator hijacking&amp;quot;);Periodic validator performance reports (comparison between validator cohorts, such as validators grouped by different operators).‍While the Hypernative Platform is first and foremost a security platform, it is also an effective tool for detecting operational issues, including missed rewards, and unexpected validator exits. We are thrilled to expand our collaboration with Ether.fi to include staking monitoring.‍Gal SagieCo-founder @ Hypernative‍Read more: Ether.fi Brings Real-Time Protection to Liquid Restaking With Hypernative‍Hypernative Platform uses battle-tested, sophisticated machine learning models, heuristics, simulations, and graph-based detections to identify threats with high accuracy and give customers precious minutes to respond before exploits can do damage. The system monitors security, technical, financial, governance and other risks. Hypernative Platform detected 99.5% of hacks last year with less than 0.001% false positive rate and saved $500M of funds to date.‍Over 150 Web3 projects already rely on Hypernative’s real-time enterprise-grade platform that monitors over $100B worth of digital assets across more than 45 chains. The list includes Balancer, Blockdaemon, Chainalysis, Chainlink, Circle, Consensys, Ethena, Etherfi, Galaxy, Linea, Quantstamp, Solana, Starknet, and Uniswap.‍Reach out for a demo of Hypernative’s platform, tune into Hypernative’s blog and our social channels to keep up with the latest on cybersecurity in Web3.‍Secure everything you build, run and own in Web3 with Hypernative.‍Website | X (Twitter) | LinkedIn</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/66cf619b4f6688c8ec30b28d/675af17f4bfe5536d22931ef_Blog%20-%20Case%20Study%20-%20Ether.fi.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How Kinetic Stopped a Hack and Saved $5M With Hypernative | Hypernative</title>
    <published>2024-11-26T22:06:42+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-26T22:06:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.hypernative.io/blog/how-kinetic-stopped-a-hack-and-saved-5m-with-hypernative</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.hypernative.io/blog/how-kinetic-stopped-a-hack-and-saved-5m-with-hypernative"/>
    <content type="html">On Oct. 31, Kinetic Market, the premier lending protocol on the Flare Network, was able to save $5M thanks to a detection by Hypernative that alerted the protocol to an exploit in progress.The hacker utilized flash loans and exploited a permission vulnerability in a whitelisted liquidator, masquerading as a Uniswap pool. The attacker then performed a sophisticated price manipulation exploit and leveraged the combination of a collateral factor on kUSDT and a liquidation bonus to make self-liquidation profitable.‍Early-Warning Detection‍Hypernative first detected that an exploit was being staged at 08:19:55 UTC, when the attacker created their first contract. The system raised an alert about an impending attack at 8:26:02, before the first hack transaction, when a failed transaction revealed the target of the exploit. Kinetic was able to pause the market shortly after, limiting the loss to a fraction of possible damages. Kinetic said that all of the users will be made whole.‍‍The accuracy of Hypernative&amp;#x27;s detection and the speed with which they responded helped avert the worst-case scenario. We have finalized the process to automate the pause function that was used so successfully in this incident to make our response to future exploits even faster and more effective.‍Lindsay IronsideCo-founder @ Kinetic‍Important Update:The Kinetic Protocol has been paused due to @HypernativeLabs&amp;#39;s detection of an in-progress security exploit.This quick response halted the progress of the bad actor and saved $4M+It will remain in effect until we can 100% confirm the safety of the protocol. pic.twitter.com/vH1lpGP6wn&amp;mdash; Kinetic.Market☀️ (@Kinetic_Markets) October 31, 2024 ‍This type of attack is usually out of an audits scope, as it involves a specific configuration (not the code itself), certain market conditions, and issues with third-party code. Hypernative&amp;#x27;s machine learning models identified the hack using out-of-the-box detection settings available to all platform customers.‍Flare&amp;#x27;s Ecosystem-Wide Security‍Kinetic&amp;#x27;s experience is proof of the tangible returns projects get from proactive investment in security. In August, the protocol joined the ecosystem-wide security umbrella offered in the partnership between Hypernative and Flare and immediately upgraded its monitoring to unlock automated onchain response capability. Kinetic was already in the process of enabling automated pause functionality at the time of the attack. ‍The Hypernative Chain Program covers a broad range of attack surfaces and risk vectors including bridges, internal infrastructure smart contracts, multisig wallets, treasury and token allocations, and more. Projects building on Flare get access to Hypernative Platform and receive assistance in configuring and setting up security monitoring and prevention flows.‍Read more: Flare Activates Ecosystem-Wide Protection With Hypernative‍While we await a post-mortem analysis of today&amp;#39;s security issues with Kinetic, we want to emphasize Flare Foundation&amp;#39;s proactive approach to security through key partnerships:• Immunefi for application protection• Hypernative for real-time risk monitoring• Elliptic for…&amp;mdash; Flare ☀️ (@FlareNetworks) October 31, 2024 We see a growing number of chains going beyond the standard security protocol to make sure that the most important projects in their ecosystem are protected too. This incident is a perfect example of how a protocol, a chain and a security provider can work together to save the day.Gal SagieCo-founder @Hypernative‍Over 150 Web3 projects already rely on Hypernative’s real-time enterprise-grade platform that monitors over $100B worth of digital assets across 45 chains. In addition to Flare, the list of blockchains choosing Hypernative&amp;#x27;s ecosystem protection package includes Solana, Starknet, Mode, Zircuit, Astar, Berachain, Sei, Stacks, Stellar, and Kinto.‍Hypernative uses battle-tested, sophisticated machine learning models, heuristics, simulations, and graph-based detections to identify threats with high accuracy and give customers precious minutes to respond before exploits can do damage. The system monitors security, technical, financial, governance and other risks. Hypernative detected 99.5% of hacks last year with less than 0.001% false positive rate and saved more than $500M of funds to date.‍Reach out to find out how you can leverage the Hypernative and Fordefi integration and secure everything you build, run, and own in Web3.‍‍Website | X (Twitter) | LinkedIn</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/66cf619b4f6688c8ec30b28d/673fd8d4e395730ee7b073db_Blog-Kinetic.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Hypernative Picked by Ethereum Foundation to Enhance Protocol Security | Hypernative</title>
    <published>2025-04-03T22:06:42+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-03T22:06:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.hypernative.io/blog/hypernative-picked-by-ethereum-foundation-to-enhance-protocol-security</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.hypernative.io/blog/hypernative-picked-by-ethereum-foundation-to-enhance-protocol-security"/>
    <content type="html">The Ethereum Foundation (EF), a non-profit that supports the Ethereum ecosystem, chose Hypernative&amp;#x27;s real-time threat detection and prevention solution to enhance the security of the world&amp;#x27;s most popular smart contract protocol. ‍The EF is at the frontier of a new kind of organization: one that supports a blockchain ecosystem without controlling it. It is part of a larger community of organizations, individuals, and companies that fund protocol development, grow the community, and advocate for Ethereum.‍&amp;quot;At the Protocol Security Research Team at the EF, our focus is on securing the network and its critical components. By augmenting the work our team does with the Hypernative real-time threat monitoring and prevention platform on monitoring the Ethereum network to detect early warning signals, we are able to spend more of our time on activities like reviewing clients, hard forks, run bug bounty programs, and creating tooling that make the Ethereum protocol more secure.&amp;quot; Fredrik SvantesProtocol Security Research Team LeadEthereum Foundation‍Hypernative is working with EF&amp;#x27;s Protocol Security Research team to improve onchain events monitoring and increase operational security. As part of the collaboration, the EF will receive custom reports on the health of staking validators and operators and alerts when performance falls below a pre-defined threshold. The scope of monitoring encompasses:Consensus layer monitoring, including voting participation, mass slashing, empty blocks production etc.L2s monitoring, including liveness and verificationsEthereum Foundation operational security monitoringAnd more‍Hypernative&amp;#x27;s Ethereum staking monitoring solution enables customers to quickly address misconfigured validators and avoid significant fund loss by tracking validator performance, unexpected validator exits, validator hijacking, and much more. Hypernative also provides periodic validator performance reports, enabling continuous operational improvement and performance comparison between validator cohorts.‍“Together, the Ethereum mainnet, its Layer 2s, and other EVM-compatible chains are at the forefront of blockchain adoption and represent the majority of onchain activity monitored by Hypernative. We’re very proud to support the Ethereum Foundation’s mission to secure the ecosystem and help it thrive.”Gal SagieCo-founder &amp;amp; CEOHypernative‍Hypernative Platform uses battle-tested, sophisticated machine learning models, heuristics, simulations, and graph-based detections to identify threats with high accuracy and give customers precious minutes to respond before exploits can do damage. The system monitors security, technical, financial, governance and other risks. Hypernative Platform detected 99.5% of hacks last year with less than 0.001% false positive rate and saved $2B of funds to date.‍The EF joins over 200 Web3 projects that rely on Hypernative’s real-time enterprise-grade platform that monitors over $100B worth of digital assets across more than 60 chains. The list includes Amber, Aptos, Balancer, Blockdaemon, Chainlink, Circle, Consensys, Ethena, eToro, Galaxy, Kraken, Linea, Morpho, Quantstamp, Reown, Solana, Starknet, and Uniswap.‍Reach out for a demo of Hypernative’s solutions, tune into Hypernative’s blog and our social channels to keep up with the latest on cybersecurity in Web3.‍Secure everything you build, run and own in Web3 with Hypernative.‍‍Website | X (Twitter) | LinkedIn</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/66cf619b4f6688c8ec30b28d/67ec87d7fb94d163e23db348_blog-cover-ef2.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
