<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">JSON Next Data Bridge</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://example.com"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=JsonNextDataBridge&amp;context=Main&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Finfinitywallet.io%2Fblog&amp;items_field=props.pageProps.blogData.featuredData&amp;article_field=attributes.slug&amp;prefix=https%3A%2F%2Finfinitywallet.io%2Fblog%2Farticle%2F&amp;title_field=attributes.title&amp;author_field=&amp;pubdate_field=attributes.createdAt&amp;pubdate_source=json&amp;date_format=&amp;content_field=attributes.article&amp;scrape_content_selector=&amp;article_json_field=&amp;content_cleanup_regex=&amp;json_tag=&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://example.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://example.com/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=JsonNextDataBridge&amp;context=Main&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Finfinitywallet.io%2Fblog&amp;items_field=props.pageProps.blogData.featuredData&amp;article_field=attributes.slug&amp;prefix=https%3A%2F%2Finfinitywallet.io%2Fblog%2Farticle%2F&amp;title_field=attributes.title&amp;author_field=&amp;pubdate_field=attributes.createdAt&amp;pubdate_source=json&amp;date_format=&amp;content_field=attributes.article&amp;scrape_content_selector=&amp;article_json_field=&amp;content_cleanup_regex=&amp;json_tag=&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:06:54+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Discover the Polygon zkEVM Network</title>
    <published>2025-01-11T14:56:35+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-11T14:56:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://infinitywallet.io/blog/article/discover-polygon-zkevm-infinity-wallet</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://infinitywallet.io/blog/article/discover-polygon-zkevm-infinity-wallet"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are excited to have integrated Polygon zkEVM within the Infinity Wallet! This integration enables users to seamlessly manage, use and interact with the Polygon zkEVM blockchain, offering a robust suite of features to power your Polygon zkEVM experience!&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Understanding Polygon zkEVM&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polygon zkEVM is a Layer-2 network, built to be an Ethereum scalable solution utilizing zero-knowledge technology to provide low cost and high throughput transactions. It aims to create a seamless and high-performance foundation for decentralized applications (DApps) and Web3 services. By leveraging zero-knowledge proofs and maintaining compatibility with the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM), Polygon zkEVM enables developers to build and scale seamlessly while maintaining Ethereum’s security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A core innovation of Polygon zkEVM is its use of zk-rollups, a technique that validates transactions on-chain in a compressed manner while preserving the security and decentralization of Ethereum. This approach significantly enhances scalability and reduces costs, making Polygon zkEVM a powerful tool for large-scale applications such as DeFi, gaming, and supply chain solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Key Features of Polygon zkEVM&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Scalability:&lt;/strong&gt; Polygon zkEVM uses zk-rollups to aggregate transactions and generate cryptographic proofs that are submitted to Ethereum. This process significantly increases transaction throughput while reducing costs, making the network highly efficient and scalable.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Ethereum Compatibility: &lt;/strong&gt;Polygon zkEVM is fully compatible with Ethereum’s existing tools, such as Solidity and developer frameworks. This ensures that developers can build decentralized applications with quick finality and improved performance, all within the Ethereum ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized Validation: &lt;/strong&gt;The zk-rollup mechanism relies on a decentralized network of validators to ensure integrity and accuracy. This guarantees the system’s security while maintaining trust less operations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Polygon zkEVM’s Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polygon zkEVM stands out due to its innovative architecture that optimizes both scalability and security. Key components include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zk-Rollup: &lt;/strong&gt;zk-rollups enable Polygon zkEVM to handle thousands of transactions per second off-chain while maintaining Ethereum’s base-layer security. This method reduces on-chain data, alleviating congestion on the mainnet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eSTARK Proofs and FRI: &lt;/strong&gt;Polygon zkEVM uses advanced zero-knowledge proof systems such as eSTARK (Efficient Scalable Transparent Arguments of Knowledge) and FRI (Fast Reed-Solomon Interactive Oracle Proofs of Proximity) to ensure high-performance proof generation. These methods allow for efficient validation of large-scale data without compromising security or performance.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compression with FFLONK SNARKs: &lt;/strong&gt;Once the eSTARK proofs are generated, they are further compressed using FFLONK SNARKs (Succinct Non-Interactive Arguments of Knowledge) to create the final zk-proof. This compression reduces the size and computational requirements for on-chain verification, optimizing the overall process.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Commitment and Proof Verification: &lt;/strong&gt;Polygon zkEVM uses a Merkle tree-based structure to store and manage state commitments. Proofs are verified on-chain through smart contracts, ensuring computational efficiency and trustless operations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVM Equivalence: &lt;/strong&gt;Unlike some Layer-2 solutions that require custom tooling or significant adjustments, Polygon zkEVM provides EVM equivalence, allowing developers to use existing Ethereum tools and smart contracts without modification. This reduces the learning curve and accelerates adoption.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validator Decentralization:&lt;/strong&gt; Validators play a critical role in the Polygon zkEVM ecosystem. They are responsible for creating zk-rollup proofs and submitting them to the Ethereum mainnet. A decentralized network of validators ensures that the system remains secure and robust against centralized points of failure.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Future of Polygon zkEVM&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polygon zkEVM is poised to play a pivotal role in the next phase of blockchain innovation. By addressing Ethereum’s scalability challenges without sacrificing security or decentralization, it provides a solid foundation for the growth of Web3 applications. The network’s focus on reducing costs, maintaining compatibility with Ethereum, and enhancing throughput makes it an ideal choice for developers and enterprises alike looking for a fast, secure and cost efficient L2 network.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Unlock the Power of Polygon zkEVM with Infinity Wallet&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The integration of Polygon zkEVM into Infinity Wallet provides users with a robust and user-friendly Polygon zkEVM Wallet on Desktop, with Mobile coming soon. This update not only simplifies asset management but also introduces a suite of features to maximize the utility and accessibility of Polygon zkEVM within the Infinity Wallet ecosystem. Whether you are transferring assets, swapping, interacting with Web3/DApps or tracking your portfolio, Infinity Wallet ensures a seamless and efficient experience, making it easier than ever to harness the potential of Polygon zkEVM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;🔗 Seamlessly Send, Receive, Request, and Manage Polygon zkEVM Assets&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether you need to send or receive Polygon zkEVM assets, request payments, or manage your holdings, Infinity Wallet provides a user-friendly interface that makes these tasks straightforward and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image_resized" style="width:100%;" src="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_wallet_60a279ac4c.png" alt="Polygon zkEVM Wallet" srcset="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_wallet_60a279ac4c.png 245w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_wallet_60a279ac4c.png 500w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_wallet_60a279ac4c.png 750w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_wallet_60a279ac4c.png 1000w" sizes="100vw" width="1000"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;🔄 Cross-Chain Dex Aggregator&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;No more navigating through multiple exchanges or dealing with cumbersome conversion processes. With a few clicks, you can perform cross-chain swaps between multiple chains and tokens via the Infinity Wallet Dex Aggregator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image_resized" style="width:100%;" src="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polyong_dex_ad764ded5a.png" alt="Polygon zkEVM DEX" srcset="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polyong_dex_ad764ded5a.png 245w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polyong_dex_ad764ded5a.png 500w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polyong_dex_ad764ded5a.png 750w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polyong_dex_ad764ded5a.png 1000w" sizes="100vw" width="1000"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;📈 Portfolio Tracking and Complete Transaction History&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keeping track of your crypto is crucial. Our integrated portfolio tracker provides a comprehensive overview of your Polygon zkEVM assets, complete with detailed transaction history, empowering you with deeper insights and control over your assets and DApps interacted with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image_resized" style="width:100%;" src="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_infinitywallet_1_f08b58adb1.png" alt="Polygon zkEVM Portfolio Dashboard" srcset="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_infinitywallet_1_f08b58adb1.png 245w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_infinitywallet_1_f08b58adb1.png 500w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_infinitywallet_1_f08b58adb1.png 750w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_infinitywallet_1_f08b58adb1.png 1000w" sizes="100vw" width="1000"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;meta charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color:transparent;color:#000000;font-family:Arial,sans-serif;font-size:13pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre-wrap;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌐&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Web3 Browser&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Infinity Wallet’s first of its kind Web3 Browser allows you to interact with the decentralized web directly from your wallet. This eliminates the need for browser extensions, providing a faster, more secure and streamlined experience. Bringing full control and access to all Web3 services directly within the Infinity Wallet ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image_resized" style="width:100%;" src="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_web3_4a543888ba.png" alt="Polygon zkEVM Web3 Browser" srcset="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_web3_4a543888ba.png 245w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_web3_4a543888ba.png 500w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_web3_4a543888ba.png 750w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/polygon_web3_4a543888ba.png 1000w" sizes="100vw" width="1000"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;🛒 DApp Store&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discover and use a wide variety of decentralized applications (DApps) through the Infinity Wallet’s DApp Store. With Polygon zkEVM now integrated, users can easily explore and discover Polygon zkEVM DApps, and easily connect and interact with them. All without leaving the wallet!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image_resized" style="width:100%;" src="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_dapps_dbaf2b943c.png" alt="Polygon zkEVM DApp Store" srcset="https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_dapps_dbaf2b943c.png 245w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_dapps_dbaf2b943c.png 500w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_dapps_dbaf2b943c.png 750w, https://infinitywallet-blog.b-cdn.net/aptos_dapps_dbaf2b943c.png 1000w" sizes="100vw" width="1000"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;➕ And Many More Features&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Infinity Wallet is packed with many features to enhance your crypto journey, along with support for a wide range of blockchains and cryptocurrencies, allowing you to manage all your assets in one place. We are continuously building and updating our platform to deliver new features and improvements, for an ever-enhancing user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The integration of Polygon zkEVM in the Infinity Wallet is a testament to the growing importance of interoperability and user-centric solutions in the blockchain space. By integrating Polygon zkEVM with Infinity Wallet's comprehensive one-stop multi-chain wallet solution, users gain access to a powerful platform for managing their assets and engaging with the Polygon zkEVM ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explore the new Polygon zkEVM integration today and unlock the full potential with the Infinity Wallet. Stay tuned for more exciting updates as we continue to expand our ecosystem to deliver unparalleled value to users!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
