<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Liquify on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40liquify&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*a2-ov9io13epH4I7geMFbQ.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*a2-ov9io13epH4I7geMFbQ.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40liquify&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:07:26+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Cross-Chain Solutions and the Critical Role of Node Infrastructure</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T05:32:58+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T05:32:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/cross-chain-solutions-and-the-critical-role-of-node-infrastructure-51488919a10c?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/cross-chain-solutions-and-the-critical-role-of-node-infrastructure-51488919a10c?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The blockchain world is expanding at lightning speed, but every network often operates like a standalone island, limiting the reach and utility of decentralised finance (DeFi), gaming, NFTs, and other Web3 applications. Cross-chain technologies aim to break down these barriers by connecting diverse blockchains into an integrated ecosystem.How Do Cross-Chain Technologies Work?Cross-chain solutions unify separate blockchains so that assets and data can move freely among them. Here are the major mechanisms:1. BridgesBridges establish direct pathways between blockchains, allowing users to transfer assets with minimal friction. In addition to well-known bridging protocols like Wormhole and Multichain, THORChain leverages trust-minimised cross-chain liquidity pools, enabling native swaps between different networks.2. Atomic SwapsAtomic swaps enable a trustless exchange of assets across blockchains — no third-party custodians required.3. Sidechains and ParachainsNetworks such as Polkadot and Cosmos rely on sidechains or parachains to offload work from the main chain, enhancing scalability and cross-network connectivity. Our partner Self Chain, has recently integrated CosmWasm into its Layer 1 infrastructure, enabling developers to deploy smart contracts that are interoperable across Cosmos-based ecosystems. This opens the door to cross-chain applications, DAOs, and DeFi protocols that can interact natively with other IBC-compatible chains — solidifying Self Chain’s role in the growing cross-chain ecosystem.4. Interoperability ProtocolsInteroperability protocols set universal standards for data and asset movement, enabling multiple blockchains to operate in harmony. Our long-term partner POKT Network provides decentralised RPC endpoints for simpler cross-chain development, while Pyth Network delivers real-world market data to various blockchains. By offering these core services, both POKT and Pyth help different networks operate in unison, expanding the utility of cross-chain solutions.As businesses and developers realise the benefits, many blockchains are actively integrating these solutions, enhancing network utility and user experience.What Business Problems Do Cross-Chain Technologies Solve?1. Global Finance and PaymentsCross-chain solutions streamline cross-border payments, making them faster and more cost-effective — vital for institutions moving substantial sums across multiple digital-asset networks.2. DeFi and LiquidityBy linking different ecosystems, cross-chain protocols let DeFi projects tap into liquidity from various blockchains. This not only accelerates growth but also makes services more accessible to a broader user base.3. Gaming and NFTsCross-chain technology lets gamers or NFT collectors move assets across diverse virtual worlds, creating richer gaming environments and uniting once-siloed NFT platforms. DeFi Kingdoms has its own bridging mechanisms to move tokens and NFTs across multiple chains, ensuring smooth multi-chain gameplay and DeFi integrations.4. Corporate IntegrationEnterprises often juggle multiple blockchains for tasks like supply chain management and data synchronization. Cross-chain tech unifies these processes, saving time and reducing administrative complexity.The Role of Node Providers in the Cross-Chain EcosystemCross-chain solutions thrive on reliable node infrastructure. However, setting up and managing nodes across various networks can be time-consuming, expensive, and technically complex. Many companies lack the resources to operate their own full nodes for each blockchain they wish to support.That’s where Liquify comes in. We specialise in providing enterprise-grade node infrastructure, serving over 90+ blockchain networks. Liquify’s global coverage means businesses can harness cross-chain technologies without the burden of building and maintaining in-house node operations.Why Liquify?Bare Metal Infrastructure: Liquify runs dedicated servers in 6 global locations — USA (East and West), UK, Germany, Japan, and Singapore — removing virtualisation overhead and guaranteeing consistently high performance for even the most demanding Web3 applications. This approach achieves 40–80% better cost efficiency than typical cloud solutions.High Throughput: Liquify is optimised to handle billions of daily RPC calls, ensuring a frictionless experience even during peak network demand.Lower Latency: Strategic data centre placements enable rapid data transfers, critical for applications requiring near real-time cross-chain interactions.Scalability and Reliability: Our globally distributed infrastructure offers 99.99% uptime, meeting the standards needed for mission-critical blockchain applications.Dedicated Support: From proof-of-concept to large-scale deployment, Liquify’s team of experts assists at every step, making cross-chain integration simpler and more cost-effective.Start small with our free plan (includes up to 50,000 daily requests), or choose a higher tier for more demanding applications. Visit our Liquify Portal to sign up, explore options, and scale as your project grows. Whether you’re building DeFi services, cross-chain games, or enterprise-grade solutions, Liquify’s node infrastructure and dedicated support make multi-chain integration easier than ever.ConclusionCross-chain technologies bridge the gaps between previously isolated blockchains, enabling faster, cheaper, and more versatile transactions. Whether it’s empowering cross-border payments, enhancing liquidity in DeFi, enabling seamless NFT transfers, or simplifying corporate data integration, these innovations redefine what’s possible in the crypto economy.If you’re aiming to take advantage of cross-chain solutions without handling node deployment and maintenance yourself, Liquify has you covered. Our blockchain-as-a-service platform provides secure, cost-efficient, and scalable node infrastructure for over 90+ networks, helping your business stay competitive in a rapidly evolving market.Ready to integrate cross-chain technologies into your operations? Visit Liquify Portal or Contact us today for a dedicated consultation and discover how our services can bring your multi-chain vision to life.Bookmark our blog, subscribe to our monthly newsletter and follow us on social media to stay informed about the latest news and developments in the Liquify ecosystem.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Liquify Adds Base Support to RPC Gateway, Enabling Enterprise-Grade L2 Access</title>
    <published>2025-02-14T11:02:23+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-14T11:02:23+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/liquify-adds-base-support-to-rpc-gateway-enabling-enterprise-grade-l2-access-48f3a9894354?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/liquify-adds-base-support-to-rpc-gateway-enabling-enterprise-grade-l2-access-48f3a9894354?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We’re scaling our infrastructure every week and currently processing over 2 billion daily RPC calls per day across 90+ networks. This week, we’re announcing the integration of Base into our newly launched RPC Portal. This addition enables developers and users to access Base’s high-performance Layer 2 blockchain through Liquify’s enterprise-grade infrastructure.​​Base is a Layer 2 blockchain solution developed by Coinbase to enhance Ethereum’s scalability and reduce transaction fees. It operates using rollup technology, which processes transactions off-chain before bundling them onto the Ethereum mainnet for finalization.This integration leverages Liquify’s robust infrastructure spanning six global locations across the US, EU and Asia, ensuring 99.99% uptime and enterprise-grade performance for all users interacting with the Base network — it also provides high-performance, low-cost L2 infrastructure access to businesses of all sizes and is especially valuable for developers and users looking to leverage Base’s unique features, including its Ethereum compatibility, optimistic rollup security, and cost-effective transaction processing at a fraction of L1 fees.By using Liquify’s RPC Portal, users can access these capabilities starting with the free tier of 50,000 daily requests, while larger projects can opt for paid plans starting at $75/month or customize enterprise solutions for dedicated support.Developers building on Base can benefit from:Immediate access through Liquify’s battle-tested infrastructureReal-time analytics and monitoring capabilitiesArchive node access for historical data queriesHybrid architecture combining centralized performance with decentralized resilienceEnterprise-grade uptime and supportThis integration marks another milestone in Liquify’s mission to democratize access to enterprise-grade blockchain infrastructure, making high-performance L2 solutions like Base accessible to developers of all sizes.To start building on Base through Liquify’s RP Portal, visit portal.liquify.com. For enterprise inquiries, contact dara@liquify.io.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Liquify Adds DeFi Kingdoms Support to RPC Gateway, Enabling High-Performance Access to Leading…</title>
    <published>2025-02-13T08:20:06+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-13T08:20:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/liquify-adds-defi-kingdoms-support-to-rpc-gateway-enabling-high-performance-access-to-leading-b7eab8cdb07b?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/liquify-adds-defi-kingdoms-support-to-rpc-gateway-enabling-high-performance-access-to-leading-b7eab8cdb07b?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Liquify Adds DeFi Kingdoms Support to RPC Gateway, Enabling High-Performance Access to Leading GameFi ProtocolWe’re scaling our infrastructure every week and currently processing over 2 billion daily RPC calls per day across 90+ blockchain networks. This week, we’re announcing the integration of DeFi Kingdoms into our newly launched RPC Portal. This addition enables developers and users to access DeFi Kingdoms’ innovative GameFi protocol through Liquify’s enterprise-grade infrastructure.DeFi Kingdoms, known for its unique blend of DeFi mechanics and gaming elements, has established itself as a leading blockchain gaming platform with extensive NFT and DEX functionalities. By integrating with Liquify’s RPC Gateway, developers can now access this dynamic ecosystem through the same reliable infrastructure trusted by major protocols worldwide.The integration leverages Liquify’s robust infrastructure spanning six global locations, ensuring 99.99% uptime and enterprise-grade performance for all users interacting with the DeFi Kingdoms network. This aligns perfectly with Liquify’s mission to democratize access to high-performance blockchain infrastructure.The integration is particularly exciting for developers and users looking to leverage DeFi Kingdoms’ unique features, including its NFT Heroes system, DEX functionality, and cross-chain capabilities. Through Liquify’s RPC Gateway, users can access these capabilities starting with the free tier of 50,000 daily requests, while larger projects can opt for paid plans starting at $75/month or customize enterprise solutions for dedicated support.Developers building on DeFi Kingdoms can benefit from:Immediate access through Liquify’s battle-tested infrastructureReal-time analytics and monitoring capabilitiesArchive node access for historical data queriesHybrid architecture combining centralized performance with decentralized resilienceEnterprise-grade uptime and supportThis integration marks another milestone in Liquify’s mission to democratize access to enterprise-grade blockchain infrastructure, making advanced GameFi protocols like DeFi Kingdoms accessible to developers of all sizes.To start building on DeFi Kingdoms through Liquify’s RPC Gateway, visit portal.liquify.com. For enterprise inquiries, contact dara@liquify.io.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Liquify Adds Arbitrum Support to RPC Gateway, Enabling Enterprise-Grade Access to Leading L2</title>
    <published>2025-02-12T09:41:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-12T09:41:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/liquify-adds-arbitrum-support-to-rpc-gateway-enabling-enterprise-grade-access-to-leading-l2-34a0c4181fcf?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/liquify-adds-arbitrum-support-to-rpc-gateway-enabling-enterprise-grade-access-to-leading-l2-34a0c4181fcf?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We’re scaling our infrastructure every week and currently processing over 2 billion daily RPC calls across 90+ networks. This week, we’re announcing the integration of Arbitrum into our newly launched RPC Portal. This addition enables developers and users to access Arbitrum’s leading Layer 2 solution through Liquify’s enterprise-grade infrastructure.Arbitrum, known for its optimistic rollup technology and Ethereum compatibility, processes thousands of transactions per second at a fraction of L1 costs. By integrating with Liquify’s RPC Gateway, developers can now access this high-performance network through the same reliable infrastructure trusted by major protocols worldwide.The integration leverages Liquify’s robust infrastructure spanning six global locations, ensuring 99.99% uptime and enterprise-grade performance for all users interacting with the Arbitrum network. This partnership particularly strengthens Web3 adoption by providing high-performance, low-cost L2 infrastructure access to businesses of all sizes.The integration is especially valuable for developers and users looking to leverage Arbitrum’s unique features, including its EVM compatibility, optimistic rollups, and cost-effective transaction processing at a fraction of Ethereum’s fees. Through Liquify’s RPC Gateway, users can access these capabilities starting with the free tier of 50,000 daily requests, while larger projects can opt for paid plans starting at $75/month or customize enterprise solutions for dedicated support.Developers building on Arbitrum can benefit from:Immediate access through Liquify’s battle-tested infrastructureReal-time analytics and monitoring capabilitiesArchive node access for historical data queriesHybrid architecture combining centralized performance with decentralized resilienceEnterprise-grade uptime and supportThis integration marks another milestone in Liquify’s mission to democratize access to enterprise-grade blockchain infrastructure, making advanced L2 solutions like Arbitrum accessible to developers of all sizes.To start building on Arbitrum through Liquify’s RPC Gateway, visit portal.liquify.com. For enterprise inquiries, contact dara@liquify.io.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Liquify Adds Solana Support to RPC Gateway, Enabling High-Performance Access to Leading L1</title>
    <published>2025-02-11T08:56:39+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-11T08:56:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/liquify-adds-solana-support-to-rpc-gateway-enabling-high-performance-access-to-leading-l1-d665358b3218?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/liquify-adds-solana-support-to-rpc-gateway-enabling-high-performance-access-to-leading-l1-d665358b3218?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We’re scaling our infrastructure every week and currently processing over 2 billion daily RPC calls per day across 90+ networks. This week, we’re announcing the integration of Solana into our newly launched RPC Portal. This addition enables developers and users to access Solana’s high-throughput blockchain through Liquify’s enterprise-grade infrastructure.Solana, known for its blazing-fast transaction speeds and low costs, processes up to 65,000 transactions per second through its innovative Proof of History consensus mechanism. By integrating with Liquify’s RPC Gateway, developers can now access this high-performance network through the same reliable infrastructure trusted by major protocols worldwide.The integration leverages Liquify’s robust infrastructure spanning six global locations, ensuring 99.99% uptime and enterprise-grade performance for all users interacting with the Solana network. This aligns perfectly with Liquify’s mission to democratize access to high-performance blockchain infrastructure.The integration is particularly exciting for developers and users looking to leverage Solana’s unique features, including its parallel transaction processing, composable architecture, and sub-second finality. Through Liquify’s RPC Gateway, users can access these capabilities starting with the free tier of 50,000 daily requests, while larger projects can opt for paid plans starting at $75/month or customize enterprise solutions for dedicated support.Developers building on Solana can benefit from:Immediate access through Liquify’s battle-tested infrastructureReal-time analytics and monitoring capabilitiesArchive node access for historical data queriesHybrid architecture combining centralized performance with decentralized resilienceEnterprise-grade uptime and supportThis integration marks another milestone in Liquify’s mission to democratize access to enterprise-grade blockchain infrastructure, making high-performance L1 solutions like Solana accessible to developers of all sizes.To start building on Solana through Liquify’s RPC Gateway, visit portal.liquify.com. For enterprise inquiries, contact dara@liquify.io.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Major Updates to THORChain Validator Dashboard</title>
    <published>2025-02-05T09:17:17+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-05T09:17:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/major-updates-to-thorchain-validator-dashboard-84961b8f70d4?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/major-updates-to-thorchain-validator-dashboard-84961b8f70d4?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We’re excited to announce significant improvements to the THORChain Validator Dashboard. After a year of maintaining and monitoring the dashboard, the Liquify front end team has implemented comprehensive updates to enhance UX and functionality.What’s NewOur latest release brings substantial improvements to both the frontend and backend architecture:Modern UI OverhaulWe’ve completely redesigned the user interface, making it more intuitive and visually appealing. The new design provides a cleaner, more efficient way to monitor validator performance.Enhanced PerformanceThrough a complete restructuring of our codebase, we’ve significantly improved the dashboard’s performance. Both frontend and backend have been rewritten from the ground up to ensure faster load times and more responsive interactions.Advanced AnalyticsWe’ve introduced new features to help validators track and optimize their performance:Price Chart: Track price movements over time with our new charting functionalityLeaderboards: Easily identify the best and worst performing nodes across churnsVersion Toggle: Switch between the new and classic dashboard versions while we gather community feedbackComing SoonWe’re not stopping here. Our roadmap includes several exciting features that will be rolling out soon:Network Statistics: Comprehensive metrics about the THORChain networkConfig Data: Detailed configuration information for validatorsRunepool Integration: Enhanced monitoring of RUNE poolsVault Tracking: Improved visibility into vault performanceVoting Dashboard: Monitor and participate in network governanceWhy These Updates MatterAs active participants in the THORChain ecosystem, we understand the critical role that validators play in maintaining network security and efficiency. These updates reflect our commitment to providing the tools necessary for optimal validator performance and network health!Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to enhance the dashboard with new features and capabilities.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Boundless Launch: Revolutionizing Global Connectivity</title>
    <published>2025-01-20T12:16:11+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-20T12:16:11+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/boundless-launch-revolutionizing-global-connectivity-7dd1185f7d32?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/boundless-launch-revolutionizing-global-connectivity-7dd1185f7d32?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Today we launch Boundless, our decentralized eSIM service developed to completely transform the way we stay connected across borders.Traditional “connectivity” has some issuesIt’s true. Many of the people reading this regularly travel internationally for events, conferences or vacations, or are in a permanent state of flux as digital nomads, and have long struggled with staying connected globally. Traditional carriers charge excessive roaming fees, while purchasing local SIM cards is sometimes inconvenient, time-consuming and confusing — even modern eSIM solutions often require separate purchases for different regions.This is where Boundless comes inAs the latest innovation in the Decentralized Physical Infrastructure Networks (DePIN) industry, Boundless offers a revolutionary approach to mobile connectivity.What are its key features?Global Coverage: Access 5G networks worldwide — without the need for multiple eSIMs or local purchasesPrivacy-First: Leveraging decentralization for data obfuscation, ensuring user privacyNo KYC Required: Purchase and use the service without lengthy identification processesCrypto-Friendly: Pay with traditional methods or cryptocurrencies, including Bitcoin, Ethereum, USDC, and DentXLiquify, Dent and DecentralisationBy partnering with Dent, developers of the Dentnet blockchain, we’re able to offer unprecedented privacy and flexibility with Boundless. The decentralized nature of the service ensures user data is aggregated and obfuscated (unidentifiable), while maintaining the ability to address any security concerns.Boundless UI &amp;amp; beyondBoundless isn’t just another blockchain infrastructure project or 5G marketplace — it’s a user-friendly interface that simplifies the process of purchasing 5G data, making advanced technology accessible to everyone.While services like Bloxsim, Helium, DCConnect Global, and Roam are developing decentralized telecommunication technologies, Boundless offers something different — a unique combination of privacy, ease of use, and global coverage.Visit goboundlessnow.com to experience the future of global connectivity.The future of connectivity is decentralized, and Boundless is leading the charge.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing Liquify’s RPC Gateway: Where Infrastructure Meets Innovation</title>
    <published>2025-01-13T13:02:07+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-13T13:02:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/introducing-liquifys-rpc-gateway-where-infrastructure-meets-innovation-44a50acfde0b?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/introducing-liquifys-rpc-gateway-where-infrastructure-meets-innovation-44a50acfde0b?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Enterprise-grade blockchain infrastructure should (and soon will) be accessible to everyone. Today, we’re proud to announce Liquify’s RPC Gateway, combining our battle-tested bare metal infrastructure with decentralized network capabilities through POKT Network.As POKT Network’s leading validator and infrastructure provider, this launch represents a natural evolution of our partnership. Operating across six global locations with self-owned infrastructure supporting 90+ networks, Liquify currently processes around 2 billion RPC calls per day with 99.99% uptime.Our gateway introduces several innovations:Cross-chain support: 29+ networks including ETH, BSC, SOL, AVAX, ThorchainHybrid architecture: Centralized performance meets decentralized resilienceAdvanced analytics dashboard for real-time monitoringArchive node access for historical data needsStreamlined endpoint managementEchoing the above, we’re also democratizing access to enterprise-grade infrastructure:Free tier: 50K daily requestsPaid plans from $75/monthEnterprise solutions with dedicated infrastructure and supportFor established protocols and foundations seeking high-performance infrastructure, our enterprise tier offers:Dedicated bare metal nodesCustom solutions and specialized endpointsDirect access to our infrastructure team24/7 technical supportThe future of blockchain infrastructure should combine the reliability of centralized systems with the resilience of decentralized networks. With our RPC Gateway, that future is now accessible to everyone.Start building today: portal.liquify.comEnterprise inquiries: dara@@liquify.io-The Liquify Team-</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Powering Blockchain Innovation: Liquify and Cido.ai Partnership</title>
    <published>2024-11-07T15:32:46+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-07T15:32:46+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/powering-blockchain-innovation-liquify-and-cido-ai-partnership-70f2134eef06?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/powering-blockchain-innovation-liquify-and-cido-ai-partnership-70f2134eef06?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Just as a library preserves humanity’s historical knowledge, Liquify’s RPC archival infrastructure will serve as the cornerstone for Cido’s data indexing, ensuring that every piece of information remains accessible and secure.IntroductionHistorical blockchain data is becoming increasingly valuable. Among its many uses, it’s the foundation upon which DeFi is built, with billions of dollars in value locked in smart contracts onchain. Liquify’s collaboration with Cido provides the critical RPC archival infrastructure ensuring blockchain history remains accessible and secure.Cido is a leader in blockchain indexing, capable of serving access to real-time data and fully syncing blockchains much faster than current solutions. Their platform enables developers to deploy and go live in seconds, offering unparalleled speed and efficiency. With the integration of Liquify’s battle-tested RPC archival infrastructure, Cido can enhance its product suite and continue its mission of making blockchain data accessible to all.Enhancing Blockchain InfrastructureIf blockchains are the highways of the digital economy, Liquify’s RPC archival nodes are the watchtowers, keeping meticulous records of every transaction. Our infrastructure is crucial for Cido, ensuring that their indexing technology operates at peak performance. Liquify’s RPC archival nodes act as time capsules, preserving the complete history of transactions and making this data readily available for Cido’s platform and its users.With Liquify’s robust infrastructure network, Cido gains access to a comprehensive historical archive, enabling them to deliver real-time data solutions with reliability and speed.What Makes Cido Unique?Cido stands out in the blockchain industry by providing an unmatched indexing solution that prioritizes speed and efficiency. Their on-demand indexing capability allows programmers to save time on iterating and development cycles, drastically reducing time-to-market. In addition, Cido has engineered its platform to outperform competitors by a staggering margin, leveraging advanced parallel data processing, bulk indexing, state caching, pre-computation, and functional algorithms. This means they can handle massive volumes of data in real time, far exceeding the performance of benchmark solutions.Moreover, Cido is designed to scale effortlessly as chains process more transactions and onchain data grows. The architecture not only adapts to increasing demands on the infrastructure, but does so at a much lower cost than competitors. This cost efficiency, combined with their comprehensive suite of data solutions — ranging from transactional data to smart contract interactions — ensures that developers have everything they need at their fingertips. Cido’s interoperable architecture allows seamless integration with standard blockchain nodes, empowering developers to access data without the complexities often associated with custom solutions.“Indexing infrastructure needs to evolve to serve a world of multiple, fast-moving blockchains and Cido delivers on that vision. Digital systems across the world are adopting blockchain architectures and as this second digital transformation continues, the demand for real-time indexing of that data will skyrocket. Our partnership with Liquify is an important step in that direction, combining Cido’s best-in-class indexing with Liquify’s Infrastructure as a Service model serving the world’s most important projects. Cido is positioned to serve that market and provide scalable, reliable and fast indexing when and where it’s needed most.”ConclusionAs blockchain technology continues to reshape our digital world, the importance of preserving and accessing its data becomes increasingly important. Through our partnership, Liquify is helping Cido unlock the full potential of blockchain data, transforming onchain history into a foundation for future innovation.About CidoCido is revolutionizing the way developers and enterprises interact with blockchain data. With its state-of-the-art “Proof of Truth” blockchain indexer, Cido delivers low query latency, high scalability, and unparalleled real-time data access across both EVM and non-EVM networks. Built to address critical challenges like network latency, RPC dependency, and inefficiency, Cido’s modular, chain-agnostic architecture is engineered for the high-throughput future demands of the Web3 ecosystem. From DeFi and gaming to AI, Cido ensures fast, reliable, and scalable access to onchain data — powering the next generation of decentralized applications.About LiquifyLiquify operates nodes on over 60 networks, providing fully bare-metal infrastructure as a service tailored for blockchain enterprises. Specializing in RPCs, validators, indexers, and dashboards, Liquify is committed to high uptime and bespoke solutions, making us a trusted partner in the blockchain ecosystem.Stay updated on our latest developments and offerings by following us on X and subscribing to our newsletter. For real-time updates, join our Telegram community!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Liquify’s Data Standards: Welcome to Tier 3 and 4</title>
    <published>2024-10-22T07:22:37+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-22T07:22:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@liquify/liquifys-data-standards-welcome-to-tier-3-and-4-14f93279af96?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@liquify/liquifys-data-standards-welcome-to-tier-3-and-4-14f93279af96?source=rss-63263a363ae6------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Liquify</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In the high-stakes world of blockchain technology, infrastructure quality can make or break operations. Liquify is revolutionizing this space with our premium bare-metal blockchain infrastructure, underpinned by stringent compliance and world-class data centers.Our global network of 300 servers isn’t just expansive — it’s strategically housed in top-tier data centers across the US, EU, and Asia. These aren’t just any facilities; we’re talking about Tier 3 and Tier 4 data centers in key locations like US East and West (Arizona, DC), London, Germany, Singapore, and Japan.What sets Tier 3 and 4 data centers apart? They offer N+1 or 2N redundancy, meaning multiple backup systems for critical components. This translates to 99.99% (Tier 3) and 99.995% (Tier 4) uptime, far surpassing lower-tier alternatives. These facilities boast advanced cooling systems, robust physical security, and guaranteed power redundancy — essential for the 24/7 demands of blockchain operations.Liquify’s commitment to excellence is further evidenced by our on-going application for ISO compliance in the UK. This isn’t just a badge — it’s a testament to our adherence to international standards for information security management. For our clients, this means assured data protection, risk management, and operational excellence.Our team also conducts yearly third party internal and external audits/penetration tests of our infrastructure and web applications. Furthermore, we conduct weekly vulnerability scanning and ensure a swift remediation of any vulnerabilities found.Our infrastructure supports over 60 chains, handling an impressive 2 billion+ daily RPC calls and managing $250+ million in assets. Unlike cloud providers, our bare-metal approach offers greater control, customization, and cost-effectiveness, crucial for blockchain’s unique demands.From RPCs and nodes to custom monitoring tools, Liquify provides end-to-end solutions. Our client roster, including Thorchain and Pyth, speaks to the trust we’ve built in the industry.By choosing Liquify, you’re not just getting servers — you’re gaining a partner committed to the highest standards of performance, security, and compliance in blockchain infrastructure.Bookmark our blog, subscribe to our monthly newsletter and follow us on social media to stay informed about the latest news and developments in the Liquify ecosystem.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
