<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">lumenscan - Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/lumenscan?source=rss----ab8e91ac31c0---4"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Flumenscan&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Flumenscan&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:07:38+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Lumenscan Notifier Bot is Released!</title>
    <published>2020-05-10T23:22:38+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-10T23:22:38+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/lumenscan/lumenscan-notifier-bot-is-released-223e291ca2e8?source=rss----ab8e91ac31c0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/lumenscan/lumenscan-notifier-bot-is-released-223e291ca2e8?source=rss----ab8e91ac31c0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Lumenscan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hi Stellar Family!The Lumenscan Notifier Bot is now online.You may be asking, what is it?Lumenscan Notifier Bot is a Telegram bot that allows to you simply monitor stellar accounts events like transactions, operations, and paymentsNow let’s talk about how the bot works, The notifier bot has four sections:1- New Account 2- My Accounts 3- Setting 4- Feedback1- New AccountHere you can enter the accounts that you want to trackOnce you click the “New Account” button, you should enter your public keyif the public key is valid, the account will be added to your list of accounts2- My AccountsHere, you can view and manage your accounts.Once you click “My Accounts” you can see your list of accountsBy clicking “Delete,” you can permanently delete an accountBy clicking “Transaction,” you can enable or disable notifications for your new transactions.By clicking “Payment,” you can enable or disable notifications for your new payments.By clicking “Operation,” you can enable or disable notifications for your new operations.Note: By default, all notifications are active. So, if a friend sends you 1 XLM, you’ll receive three notifications: one for the payment, another for the transaction, and another for the operation (because a payment is always inside a transaction, which is an operation)You can customize your notifications to match your preferences and receive fewer notifications. Most people users prefer getting notified only when a payment is made (when assets are moved).So, you can disable notifications for operations and transactions if you want.3- SettingThis section lets you configure the settings for your bot. Right now, you can only use Russian or English as your bot language.After you click “Settings”, you can switch between Russian and English.4-FeedbackHere, you’ll be able to send us any feedback you have on the notification bot.Once you click the Send button, you can write your feedback.We’re open to all your suggestions and consider each request from our users very carefully. The technical team will do everything they can to implement all the features you need to have a great experience with Lumenscan. Don’t hesitate to let us know what you need.Notifications formatThere are three types of notifications:Transaction2. Operation3. PaymentIf you click “View in Lumenscan”, you can view more details in the explorerNote we use from event/stream model for connection with Horizon and this prevents additional requests on the Horizon server.Also, this is the first version of the notifier bot. Let us know if you see any bugs and help us improve.To get started and use from bot, click on the linkhttps://t.me/lumenscannotifierbotThank you for reading this post.Lumenscan Notifier Bot is Released! was originally published in lumenscan on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Lumenscan Monthly Traffic Report</title>
    <published>2020-04-21T15:43:13+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-21T15:43:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/lumenscan/lumenscan-monthly-traffic-report-64441277df47?source=rss----ab8e91ac31c0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/lumenscan/lumenscan-monthly-traffic-report-64441277df47?source=rss----ab8e91ac31c0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Lumenscan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Hi Stellar Family!In this post, we have published the monthly traffic of Lumenscan explorer based on the number of active users, countries, and devices.And we are very happy that Lumenscan is being used in most countries of the world.Date : 20 March 2020 / 20 April 2020Source : Google analyticsActive Users30 days: 3197 days: 261 day: 6Device1-Desktop (79.6%)2-Mobile (20.2%)3-Tablet (0.2%)Country1-Brazil: 112 (29.34%)2-United States: 73 (19.06%)3-Canada: 24 (6.27%)4-Mexico: 17 (4.44%)5-Kingdom: 15 (3.92%)6-Netherlands: 13 (3.39%)7-Iran: 11 (2,87%)8-Argentina: 9 (2.35%)9-United Arab Emirates: 8 (2.09%)10-France: 8 (2.09%)11-Chile: 7 (1.83%)12-Colombia: 7 (1.83%)13-Germany: 7 (1.83%)14-Sweden: 6 (1.57%)15-Dominican: 5 (1.31%)16-Ireland: 5 (1.31%)17-Peru: 5 (1.31%)18-China: 4 (1.04%)19-Russia: 4 (1.04%)Thank you for reading this post.Lumenscan Monthly Traffic Report was originally published in lumenscan on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">fHow does the Lumenscan explorer help the Stellar network?</title>
    <published>2020-04-13T21:57:41+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-13T21:57:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/lumenscan/fhow-does-the-lumenscan-explorer-help-the-stellar-network-7d60b48ef1fc?source=rss----ab8e91ac31c0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/lumenscan/fhow-does-the-lumenscan-explorer-help-the-stellar-network-7d60b48ef1fc?source=rss----ab8e91ac31c0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Lumenscan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">How does the Lumenscan explorer help the Stellar network?Do you know anything about the Lumenscan explorer? We will introduce you to this new useful and effective tool. But before that, let’s talk a little bit about the Stellar network. Stellar is one of the most popular digital currency networks in the world, and its currency is called the lumen or XLM. The main goal of the Stellar network is to facilitate financial transactions among people around the world. Such a system makes it possible to transfer money cheaply, safely and easily to different parts of the world.Stellar is a blockchain network. As we know, all blockchain networks must work on a decentralized mechanism so that network members can see all the transactions that take place in the network. In such an environment, nothing is hidden from the eyes of network members. In fact, transparency is one of the most important requirements for digital currency networks. In these networks, information flows freely and users can easily search for anything they want. But, this is not possible in a physical bank and you cannot have any control over the transactions made in it.Stellar blockchain network, like other blockchain networks, must have a dedicated and efficient explorer so that users can use it to access all information about network transactions such as transaction status, number of transactions, blocks, etc. In fact, any blockchain network like Stellar needs an appropriate background to achieve its goals.we should know that Stellar is a really strong network with so many potential characteristics. We just need a modern, capable and up-to-date explorer to show all of these amazing features, designed based on understanding user needs and expectations. Today, the lack of a suitable tool has created a deep gap between users and the Stellar network, and users cannot make good use of the Stellar Network’s capacities. A robust explorer is similar to a bridge that connects users and the Stellar network environment to each other.Let me give you an example. Imagine discovering a large oil field. Wow! It is fantastic! But if you do not have the proper digging equipment to extract oil, your discovery will not be useful. Here, the Stellar network is like the same oil field. For reaching oil you need to use the right tool (efficient explorer).The next point is that the Stellar network has a complex structure which may be difficult for most users to understand. This can prevent many users from accessing and embracing the Stellar network. Thus, here we need a tool which can turn this complex structure into a simple and comprehensible one for everyone. That’s what an explorer should be able to do.The main goal of the Stellar network is to become a large and potent platform for money transfer around the world. Such a platform needs a suitable tool to achieve its goals and perform well. A tool that can create a significant correlation between the design and the sound core of the Stellar network. Lumenscan is a new explorer for Stellar Network that makes Stellar an amazing experience with its unique and user-friendly design.The Lumenscan explorer is an efficient tool for the stellar network provides an attractive user interface for the Stellar network. Users can use this explorer to easily access all the information they need on the network. Unless there is a proper balance between the core of blockchain networks and their Basic tools, we cannot make the most of the potential benefits of these networks.Thank you for reading this post.fHow does the Lumenscan explorer help the Stellar network? was originally published in lumenscan on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">A new ledger explorer for Stellar</title>
    <published>2020-03-24T14:16:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-24T14:16:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/lumenscan/a-new-ledger-explorer-for-stellar-a998953b19a7?source=rss----ab8e91ac31c0---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/lumenscan/a-new-ledger-explorer-for-stellar-a998953b19a7?source=rss----ab8e91ac31c0---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Lumenscan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Regards to the Stellar Community.In this post, I’m going to introduce Lumenscan, a ledger explorer for the Stellar Network. It allows you to view and search for transactions, addresses, operations, and assets on the network.You might think Stellar already has several explorers, like Stellar.expert and Steexp. What makes Lumenscan different?What separates Lumenscan from other explorers is its modern UI/UX design. Our team has put a lot of effort into building Lumenscan so that you can have the best experience exploring Stellar.Let’s compare the transaction details page of the three explorers.Transaction hash:09e9bbefbf4f55293c4df2f82f39644b8e579f3b4cddb66a019884669f0da2191-stellar.expertSee on the website2-SteexpSee on the website3-LumenscanSee on the websiteNext, we get to the operation details page, which is an important part of Stellar. If you look at the other explorers, you can see that they don’t let you view full details of each operation. You may even have to view the data in JSON format, which is not something most users want to do. We all prefer working with an intuitive UI. Lumenscan lets you see all the details of an operation so that you can understand how it works. You can also search for operations by their IDs.Now, let’s take a look at the operation details page on the three explorers.Operation ID:1237334809022668811-Stellar.expertSee on the website2-Steexp-3-LumenscanSee on the websiteHere, you can see an operation of the type path payment strict receive. You can’t see operation details for Steexp because it doesn’t support them.For example, with Lumenscan you can easily view the path of an operation path payment and go to the token page by clicking on each path. This is how Lumenscan makes it easy to connect the parts of Stellar.Each field also features a description that displays when you hover your mouse over the question mark icon. These descriptions are perfect if you’re just learning about the network.After working with Lumenscan, you’ll see that it has many cool features. For example, other explorers don’t give you a list view of the operations in a ledger. when you put all these features together, you get a comprehensive solution that makes working with Stellar much more pleasant.We used the Horizon API to retrieve network data, but we ran into some issues. For example, Horizon doesn’t seem to offer an API that gives an asset’s trades or its operations.We also used Stellar.expert to build some of the features like the watchlist and assets page, since we didn’t have a lot of time before the competition. In the future, we’re going to implement our own structure with our own API.If you want to learn more about Lumenscan, check out our proposal on Galactictalk.I must point out that I wasn’t trying to sabotage other explorer applications. My aim was to point out the differences.One last point to mention. If a network has well-designed tools and applications, it can accelerate growth and build its community much faster than the competitors.Thank you for reading this post.A new ledger explorer for Stellar was originally published in lumenscan on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
