<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">MoneyGram Blog - Insights on Money Transfers &amp; Finance</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.moneygram.com/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.moneygram.com%2F&amp;url_selector=.blogListing+a.list_wrapper&amp;url_pattern=&amp;content_selector=.contentWraper&amp;content_cleanup=h1%2CpostDateInner&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.moneygram.com%2F&amp;url_selector=.blogListing+a.list_wrapper&amp;url_pattern=&amp;content_selector=.contentWraper&amp;content_cleanup=h1%2CpostDateInner&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:07:51+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">A simple guide to understanding currency exchange rates</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:07:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:07:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.moneygram.com/financial-literacy-month.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.moneygram.com/financial-literacy-month.html"/>
    <content type="html">                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  April 8, 2025 • News and Promotions~MoneyGram in the News                                                                                                                                            A fundamental part of world commerce and finance, exchange rates determine the value of one currency for conversion to another.  In this blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into exchange rates and how they work.  What goes into an exchange rate?  There are two types of exchange rates in the marketplace: fixed and free-floating.  A fixed exchange rate is when a central bank or government ties a country&amp;rsquo;s currency to another country&amp;rsquo;s currency or commodity. Many currencies are pegged to the euro or US dollar. For example, the Danish krone is often pegged to the euro.  If a country is rich in natural resources like precious metals, crops and oil, its currency will often fluctuate with its value. These are usually referred to as commodity currencies.  On the other hand, free-floating exchange rates aren&amp;rsquo;t tied to a government &amp;ndash; but to the greater marketplace. Variables like supply, demand, speculation and the strength of respective currencies determine exchange rates.  Due to the volatility and decentralization of the free-floating market, exchange rates can change in as little as a second, regardless of the time.  How do exchange rates work?  Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to transfer money from the United States to Mexico. If you transfer $100, and the exchange rate is 1 US Dollar (USD) for 21 Mexican Pesos (MXN), the receiver would get 2,100 MXN.  Suppose you send currency from a country with a strong economy, higher interest rates and/or political stability. In that case, this will often lead to favorable exchange rates &amp;ndash; meaning the country&amp;rsquo;s currency will go farther in a country that may not have the same conditions.  On the flip side, if a country&amp;rsquo;s currency is weaker relative to other currencies, imports become more expensive, and exports become cheaper. This constitutes an unfavorable exchange rate.  Does every remittance provider offer the same exchange rate?  No, not every remittance provider offers the same exchange rate. Foreign exchange service providers make money by buying and selling currency according to bid and ask prices.  Each entity asks for different bid (what they will pay for a currency) and ask price (what they will sell a currency for). The difference in price is called the spread. Due to this, exchange rates will vary depending on what each entity wants their spread to be.  An example is at airport currency exchanges. When you arrive at your destination&amp;rsquo;s airport with cash from your home country, these exchanges are ready to convert your cash, but with typically higher markups due to the convenience factor.  Where can I find great exchange rates* on my next money transfer?  With MoneyGram, sending money with great exchange rates* is fast and easy.  You can see real-time exchange rates to over 200 countries and territories in the MoneyGram&amp;reg; app or our website in a few taps or clicks.  Need to send money directly to your friends and family? With around-the-clock service to bank accounts, mobile wallets, debit cards and for cash pickup at approximately 450,000 locations worldwide, receiving money is reliable and convenient.  Make sure your loved ones get more of what you send today.  &amp;nbsp;  *MoneyGram makes money from currency exchange.                                                                                  MoneyGram                                                                                                                                                      Currency Exchange Rates                                                                                                                                                      FX Rates                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How you can save on your summer abroad</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:07:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:07:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.moneygram.com/save-on-your-summer-abroad.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.moneygram.com/save-on-your-summer-abroad.html"/>
    <content type="html">                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  March 17, 2025 • News and Promotions~MoneyGram in the News                                                                                                                                            Whether your summer destination consists of sunny skies, calm countrysides, bustling cityscapes, or beautiful mountain ranges &amp;ndash; traveling internationally can be tricky.  &amp;nbsp;  Make a travel budget  It&amp;rsquo;s easy to start overspending on those long vacations to paradise. By creating a travel budget, you can stay within your means and even save a little extra.  Do some research on your destination to get an idea of how much you want to put aside for your budget. After you find the amount that&amp;rsquo;s right for you, creating another savings account can help manage your travel expenses.&amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp;  Compare flight &amp;amp; accommodation pricing  With so many airline and lodging options available for worldwide travel, finding the best (and most affordable) options can be overwhelming.  For airfare, using flight comparison websites can help you find the right option for you and your group. Making your travel dates flexible and searching within a country&amp;rsquo;s tourist off-season can help lower overall costs. You can also save around $35-50 by packing light and bringing carry-on luggage to avoid checking a bag.  Traveling with a group of friends or family? Using homestay services and hostels can help break up the overall cost and save money compared to what you would traditionally spend on hotels.  &amp;nbsp;  Use public transportation  Public transportation is an easy and super-affordable way to explore your destination. It can help you get from point A to B at a fraction of the cost of a rental car or rideshare!  With transit maps available online, finding convenient places to get on and off of public transit is at your fingertips. Sometimes, you can board a train or a bus as soon as you arrive at the airport. Just a few minutes of research can save you hundreds, if not thousands, in your travel budget.  &amp;nbsp;  Avoid airport currency exchanges  When you arrive at your destination&amp;rsquo;s airport with cash from your home country, airport currency exchanges are usually there to help convert your existing cash to the appropriate currency. However, these currency exchanges come with a high markup on exchange rates.  With MoneyGram, you can avoid those expensive currency exchanges and ATMs by sending yourself cash in advance.  With a tap or a click using the MoneyGram&amp;reg; Money Transfers app or our website, you can deliver funds to over 440,000 cash pickup locations in 200+ countries and territories worldwide.                                                                                  MoneyGram                                                                                                                                                      Summer Travel                                                                                                                                                      Planning for Summer Travel                                                                                                                                                      Summer Abroad                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Tax tips and resources for immigrants &amp;amp; expats</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:07:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:07:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.moneygram.com/tax-tips-and-resources-for-immigrants-and-expats.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.moneygram.com/tax-tips-and-resources-for-immigrants-and-expats.html"/>
    <content type="html">                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  March 12, 2025 • News and Promotions~MoneyGram in the News                                                                                                                                            &amp;nbsp;  As an immigrant or an expat, you may wonder, how do taxes work in the United States?&amp;nbsp;  Throughout this blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll answer some questions you may have about US federal income taxes and what may or may not apply to you.  &amp;nbsp;  What are income taxes?  In the United States, there are three types of income tax:  Federal, which is applied to all US citizens, green card holders and non-US citizens that have satisfied the &amp;ldquo;substantial presence test&amp;rdquo; as defined by the Internal Revenue Service (IRS). Federal income tax rates range from 10% to 37%, depending on your tax bracket.  State and local, which are applied under similar guidelines as federal, but depend on the state and locality you reside in. However, state income tax is not required by every state. The states that do not have a state income tax include:&amp;nbsp;    Alaska  Florida  Nevada  New Hampshire  South Dakota  Tennessee  Texas  Washington  Wyoming    &amp;nbsp;  What do I need to pay taxes on?  The IRS requires all global income to be reported, whether you are an immigrant or an expat. This includes salary, wages, interest on savings accounts, royalties and dividends.  &amp;nbsp;  What do I need to file my taxes?  In order to file taxes, you need one of the following:&amp;nbsp;    Social Security Number (SSN)  Individual Taxpayer Identification Number (ITIN)    You are an employee if you completed a W-4 tax form when you were hired. At the start of each year, you will receive a Form W-2 that shows how much you made and paid in taxes last year.  For self-employed individuals, taxes are not deducted from paychecks. Therefore, it is important to track your income over the course of the year.  If you need to request an SSN, click here. For ITINs, click here.  &amp;nbsp;  What are tax credits and deductions?  You can save money on your taxes with tax credits and deductions. Credits can lower the amount you owe or help you get a refund. Deductions simply lower the income you are taxed on.  If you are an expat, you can receive a foreign-earned income exclusion or foreign tax credit to avoid paying double taxes.  &amp;nbsp;  When do I need to pay my taxes by?  The IRS requires all taxpayers to file a tax return by April 15.  &amp;nbsp;  Can someone help me file my taxes?  Yes! Various organizations can guide you through the process of filing a tax return, including:  The Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) program provides help to people who make $67,000 or less, people with disabilities and limited English-speaking taxpayers.&amp;nbsp;  Additionally, the IRS provides services like Free File and Direct File, where you can file your taxes for free.  &amp;nbsp;  When will I receive my tax refund?  Depending on the tax service you use, you should receive your refund within 21 days.  But, when you open a MoneyGram account in the MoneyGram&amp;reg; app, you can receive your tax refund up to 2 days earlier* when you set up direct deposit. It&amp;rsquo;s easy and only takes a few taps!    Disclaimer: Early access to direct deposit funds is based on the timing in which we receive notice of impending payment from the Federal Reserve, which is typically up to 2 days before the scheduled payment date but may vary.  MoneyGram does not provide tax or accounting advice. This blog is for informational purposes only, and is not intended to provide, and should not be relied on for, tax or accounting advice. Please consult your own tax and accounting advisors.                                                                                  MoneyGram                                                                                                                                                      Tax Tips                                                                                                                                                      US Tax Guide                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
