<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Myaza | Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://myaza.co/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fmyaza.co%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=article+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=article+.prose&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=article+.text-xs.text-tc-secondary+div&amp;date_format=jS+F%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fmyaza.co%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=article+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=article+.prose&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=article+.text-xs.text-tc-secondary+div&amp;date_format=jS+F%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:07:56+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Top Sites Nigerians Are Using to Buy Domains Smoothly in 2025</title>
    <published>2025-04-06T22:07:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-06T22:07:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://myaza.co/blog/top-sites-nigerians-are-using-to-buy-domains-smoothly-in-2025</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://myaza.co/blog/top-sites-nigerians-are-using-to-buy-domains-smoothly-in-2025"/>
    <author>
      <name>@myazahq</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Let’s talk about something that feels small on the surface but holds massive power underneath—a domain name.That tiny string of words you type into your browser—like yourname.com—is more than just a digital tag. It’s your identity online. Your shop front. Your brand. It’s how people will find you, remember you, and take you seriously. Whether you’re launching a side hustle, opening your fashion store, starting a food blog, or simply trying to secure your name online before someone else grabs it, buying a domain name is often the first bold step.But here’s what no one tells you at the start—it’s not always as easy as it sounds.Sure, the internet is filled with places that promise you domain names in “just one click.” But when you start trying to figure out where to buy, how much to pay, and how to actually pay from Nigeria, that’s when the wahala starts to show.So if you’ve ever sat staring at a payment screen, wondering which card won’t get declined this time… or you’ve asked a cousin in Canada to help you pay for your own domain… then this post is for you.Let’s walk through the best places to buy your domain and how to finally stop payment stress from slowing down your vision.First, What Makes a Domain Name and a Domain Registrar Important?If you&amp;#x27;re new to this whole website thing, here&amp;#x27;s a quick one: your domain name is what people type to find you (like mystore.com), and the registrar is the service you use to buy and manage it.Now, not all registrars are created equal. Some are super easy to use, others offer the cheapest rates, and a few come with those hidden charges that only reveal themselves during renewal. And if you&amp;#x27;re paying from Nigeria, you also want a registrar that accepts international cards without drama.Best Places to Buy a Domain in 2025Let’s break down a few trusted domain registrars where you can safely buy that perfect web address.1. NamecheapAsk anyone who&amp;#x27;s been online for a while, and they&amp;#x27;ll probably tell you they got their first domain on Namecheap. It&amp;#x27;s popular for a reason: low prices, clean interface, and no shady stuff.You can get a domain for as low as $9–$12 per year, and they throw in free privacy protection too (so your phone number and email don&amp;#x27;t end up on spam lists).Best for: First-timers, freelancers, creatives, and small business owners.2. GoDaddyThey’ve been around for decades. And it shows. GoDaddy offers everything—domain names, email, hosting, website builders, all in one spot.But GoDaddy loves to upsell, so you might need to uncheck a few boxes before you checkout.Best for: Businesses that want everything in one place.3. Squarespace Domains (Formerly Google Domains)If you&amp;#x27;re someone who loves a clean interface and wants everything synced with Google tools like Gmail and Google Drive, then Squarespace Domains (which took over Google Domains) might be your plug.Best for: People already in the Google or Squarespace ecosystem.4. DynadotNot very mainstream, but among developers and tech-savvy folks, Dynadot is known for being reliable, secure, and affordable—especially if you want to manage multiple domains.Best for: Tech bros, devs, and designers.5. PorkbunCute name, serious value. Porkbun is one of those services that feels underground but delivers top-notch value. They offer really low prices and include free domain privacy protection.Best for: People who like deals and clean user interfaces.Paying for Domains from Nigeria or Anywhere with Card RestrictionsNow, here’s the thing a lot of people don’t talk about: paying for these domains.Most of the platforms above require payment in USD or other foreign currencies. For many in Nigeria, this is where the real wahala begins. A lot of regular bank cards don’t support international payments reliably, and even when they do, you might be hit with terrible exchange rates or outright payment declines.Some people even end up calling vendors or asking friends abroad to help with a simple domain payment. It shouldn’t be this hard.That’s why tools like the Myaza USD card make all the difference.The Myaza virtual USD card gives you the freedom to pay on international platforms without begging a cousin in the UK or searching for some random “vendor” on Twitter who will charge you ₦5,000 just to help you make a $10 payment.With the Myaza app, you can:Fund your account using USDT (or other flexible methods)Create a dollar card instantlyUse it on platforms like GoDaddy, Namecheap, Squarespace, and morePay for your domain without those “payment failed” errors or unfair conversion ratesIt’s the kind of peace of mind that makes launching your dream website feel… possible again.And it doesn’t stop at domains…you can use the same card to pay for Canva, ChatGPT, Shopify, Netflix, or even that newsletter tool you’ve been eyeing for months. </content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://images.ctfassets.net/2czzg1m3mrvd/2xMrQS9pkapSQUHdOQkDLs/acbab91b8bd761fd93d7936b8d0a047e/April_7th_BLOG_POST.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How to Receive Money in USDT, USD, and Other Dollar Equivalents Instantly</title>
    <published>2025-04-02T22:07:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-02T22:07:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://myaza.co/blog/how-to-receive-money-in-usdt-usd-and-other-dollar-equivalents-instantly</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://myaza.co/blog/how-to-receive-money-in-usdt-usd-and-other-dollar-equivalents-instantly"/>
    <author>
      <name>@myazahq</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Ever had someone say, &amp;quot;I’ll send you dollars,&amp;quot; and then boom—next thing, you’re stuck figuring out how to actually receive it? Maybe it’s a remote job paying in USD, a friend abroad trying to send you money, or a client who insists on paying in USDT. But between bank restrictions, crazy exchange rates, and delays, receiving dollars can feel like an extreme sport.Good news is— It doesn’t have to be complicated. Whether you want to receive USDT, USD, or any other digital dollar, there are easy, stress-free ways to do it. Let’s break it down.Why Receiving Dollars Can Be a HassleIf you’ve ever struggled to receive USD, you already know the deal. Traditional banks? They’ll make you fill endless forms, charge ridiculous fees, and sometimes even hold your funds for days. Naira bank accounts? Forget it—most don’t support direct USD deposits. Even PayPal isn’t always an option for Nigerians due to restrictions.And when it comes to crypto payments like USDT, many people get stuck on what wallet to use, what network to select, or how to convert it to local currency without losing half of it to fees. But don’t worry—there’s a way out.The Best Ways to Receive Money in USD or USDT1. Using a Virtual Dollar AccountA virtual dollar account is an easy way to receive and hold USD without stress. Unlike regular banks, these accounts are built for seamless international transactions. Platforms like Myaza let you open a free dollar account in minutes—no paperwork, no drama. Once you have it, you can receive payments from anywhere in the world and withdraw at your convenience.2. Receiving Money via USDT (Tether)If someone wants to send you money in USDT, you need a crypto wallet that supports stablecoins. Myaza makes this super easy—you can receive USDT across different networks like Solana, Ethereum, Binance Smart Chain, and Polygon. Just copy your wallet address, share it with the sender, and get paid instantly. No delays, no conversion struggles.3. Direct Bank Transfers (But Be Careful)Some international clients or employers can send USD directly to a domiciliary account. But here’s the catch—banks have high fees and low exchange rates. You might get your money, but by the time you convert it, you’ve already lost a chunk of it. This is why many people now prefer digital USD options like USDT or virtual dollar wallets.What Happens After You Receive USD or USDT?Once you’ve received your funds, the next step is deciding what to do with them:Withdraw to Naira: If you need the money in naira, platforms like Myaza let you swap digital USD to naira instantly at better rates than banks.Hold Your Funds in USD: If you prefer to keep your money in dollars to avoid exchange rate fluctuations, your Myaza account lets you store it safely.Spend Directly Online: Need to make an international payment? Use Myaza’s virtual dollar card to spend online without stress. No restrictions, no failed transactions.Finally…Whether you’re getting paid in USD, USDT, or any other digital dollar, you don’t have to stress over how to receive it anymore. With Myaza, you get a smooth, fast, and reliable way to accept payments, hold your funds, and withdraw them when needed. No more declined transactions, ridiculous bank charges, or waiting for days to access your money.So, the next time someone says, &amp;quot;I’ll send you dollars,&amp;quot; you already know what to do. Sign up on Myaza, get your free dollar account, and receive money seamlessly—anytime, anywhere.Ready to start? Click here to set up your account now. </content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://images.ctfassets.net/2czzg1m3mrvd/R4ZYSfiyjlniOD5UYHwHc/72c73c26cf377381b96dca54eba83d96/April_2nd_BLOG_POST.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How to Find Reliable Suppliers and Buy Safely on Alibaba &amp;amp; AliExpress</title>
    <published>2025-04-01T22:07:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-01T22:07:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://myaza.co/blog/how-to-find-reliable-suppliers-and-buy-safely-on-alibaba-and-aliexpress</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://myaza.co/blog/how-to-find-reliable-suppliers-and-buy-safely-on-alibaba-and-aliexpress"/>
    <author>
      <name>@myazahq</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">So, you’ve finally decided to start that business or get that product you’ve been eyeing, and everyone is telling you, “Just buy from Alibaba or AliExpress!” Sounds easy, right? Until you actually go on the site and realize—wait, where do I even start?With thousands of suppliers, different shipping options, and a mix of ridiculously cheap and suspiciously expensive prices, sourcing from these platforms can feel like trying to find a needle in a haystack. But don’t worry, this guide will walk you through everything you need to know—how to find legit suppliers, avoid scams, and get the best deals without stress.Alibaba vs. AliExpress – What’s the Difference?Before diving in, let’s clear up the confusion. Alibaba and AliExpress are not the same, even though they’re owned by the same company.Alibaba is mainly for bulk buying (wholesale). It’s perfect for business owners, dropshippers, and resellers who want to buy in large quantities at lower prices.AliExpress is for retail shopping. It’s ideal if you want to buy just a few items for personal use or small-scale sales.Now that this is settled, let’s move on to how to source and buy products the smart way.Step 1: Finding the Right Supplier (Without Getting Scammed)This is the most crucial step. Not all suppliers are trustworthy, and ending up with fake or low-quality products is the last thing you want. Here’s how to find the best suppliers:Check the Supplier’s Reputation – On Alibaba, look for Gold Suppliers with high ratings. On AliExpress, check seller reviews and ratings before making a purchase.Read Reviews &amp;amp; Customer Feedback – Always go through the reviews and see what previous buyers are saying about the product quality, shipping time, and overall experience.Look for Verified Suppliers – On Alibaba, suppliers with a &amp;quot;Verified&amp;quot; badge have gone through extra authentication, making them more trustworthy.Ask for Sample Orders – If you’re buying in bulk, always request a sample before placing a large order. This helps you check the quality before making a big investment.Step 2: Understanding Pricing &amp;amp; NegotiationOn Alibaba, pricing is usually negotiable, especially if you’re ordering in large quantities. Here’s how to get the best deal:Compare Prices from Different Suppliers – Don’t jump on the first price you see. Message multiple suppliers and compare their offers.Negotiate Like a Pro – Don’t be afraid to ask for discounts. Many suppliers expect buyers to negotiate, so start lower than your budget and work your way up.Check for Hidden Costs – Always ask if the price includes shipping, customs duties, or extra charges. What looks cheap at first may cost more in the long run.On AliExpress, prices are usually fixed, but discounts, promo codes, and seasonal deals can help save money.Step 3: Choosing the Best Shipping MethodShipping is one of the biggest challenges when buying from Alibaba and AliExpress, especially if you’re in Nigeria or other African countries. Here are the most common options:Express Shipping (DHL, FedEx, UPS) – Fast but expensive. Best for urgent orders.Sea Freight – Cheaper for bulk orders, but it takes weeks to arrive. Ideal for business owners who can plan ahead.AliExpress Standard Shipping – Affordable and reliable for smaller items. Usually takes two to four weeks.ePacket – A budget-friendly shipping option for small packages. Faster than regular mail but cheaper than express shipping.Always check the estimated delivery time before ordering. Some suppliers offer free shipping, but it can take months to arrive.Step 4: Making Secure PaymentsTo avoid losing money, never pay suppliers directly via bank transfers unless they are fully trusted. Instead, use:AliPay or AliExpress Buyer Protection – Ensures you get a refund if the product isn’t delivered or is different from what was advertised.Escrow Service on Alibaba – The payment is held until you confirm that the order is received in good condition.Avoid Deals Outside the Platform – If a supplier asks for payment via WhatsApp, Telegram, or a personal account, it’s a red flag.Step 5: Clearing Customs &amp;amp; Receiving Your OrderOnce your order arrives in your country, customs may charge import duties or taxes depending on the value of your goods. Here’s how to prepare:Find Out Your Country’s Import Rules – Some items, such as electronics or large shipments, may require additional paperwork.Have Some Extra Money Ready – Customs fees aren’t always predictable, so budget a little extra just in case.Use a Reliable Clearing Agent – If shipping via sea freight, a clearing agent may be needed to clear goods smoothly.Final Thoughts – Shop Smart, Avoid StressSourcing from Alibaba and AliExpress can be highly profitable, whether for business or personal shopping. To avoid stress:Research suppliers before paying.Always check reviews and request samples.Compare prices and negotiate for the best deal.Choose the right shipping method based on your needs.Pay securely using verified payment methods.With the right approach, high-quality products can be sourced at amazing prices without unnecessary risks. </content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://images.ctfassets.net/2czzg1m3mrvd/54Vi9uXMnpwpNFFy2zRovn/40172ede879aa9e3cab5158ade9bc9f4/April_3rd_blog_post.jpg"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
