<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by NOWNodes on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@nownodes?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40NOWNodes&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*I70JrGEmN0_LhNv7dBUEJw.jpeg</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*I70JrGEmN0_LhNv7dBUEJw.jpeg</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40NOWNodes&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:08:12+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">XRP Update Version 2.4.0: Everything You Need to Know</title>
    <published>2025-03-18T12:45:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-18T12:45:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/xrp-update-version-2-4-0-everything-you-need-to-know-0d9ec3ccb8d1?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/xrp-update-version-2-4-0-everything-you-need-to-know-0d9ec3ccb8d1?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">XRP UpdateXRP Ledger, one of the most in-demand networks, continues to evolve, offering new opportunities for users and developers. The latest XRP update, Version 2.4.0, is not a hard fork, but it brings significant changes to the network’s development. This version includes support for dynamic NFTs, enhanced security measures, expanded transaction capabilities, and various bug fixes. Let’s take a closer look at what this update brings!New Features in XRP Ledger 2.4.0Dynamic NFTs (XLS-46)One of the key innovations in Version 2.4.0 is the introduction of dynamic NFTs. Unlike traditional NFTs, whose metadata remains unchanged, dynamic tokens allow updates to the URI containing information about the digital asset. This feature opens new possibilities for creating more engaging NFT projects.How It Can Be Used:Game items that change properties based on a player’s achievements.Collectible NFTs that can be updated with new images or data.Tokens with variable parameters, such as changing value or access conditions.Deep Asset Freezing (XLS-77)Issuers can now block asset transfers for specific users. This feature helps meet regulatory requirements and prevents illegal transactions involving digital assets.Liquidity Pool Protection from Frozen AssetsTo prevent liquidity issues, a new rule prohibits LP token transfers if the liquidity pool contains even one frozen asset. This improvement is especially important for decentralized exchanges (DEXs) operating with liquidity pools.Transaction Flag VerificationThe update also introduces flag verification for the CredentialCreate, CredentialAccept, and CredentialDelete transactions. This prevents potential errors and enhances network security.Improvements for Developers and UsersTransaction SimulationA new transaction simulation mode allows developers to test transactions without actually executing them. This provides the ability to preview results and avoid errors before submitting transactions to the network.Enhanced UNL SecurityAn important update affects the UNL (Unique Node List). Participants can now set a minimum number of validators required for consensus. This strengthens network resilience and reduces the risk of centralized control.Optimized Data SearchSupport for filtering blockchain objects by type has been added, making API interactions more convenient and speeding up data retrieval.Advanced LoggingNew detailed logging mechanisms allow recording every step of the validation and proposal process in the network. This significantly simplifies error diagnostics and blockchain performance analysis.Bug FixesVersion 2.4.0 resolves several critical issues, improving the network’s stability:Fixed double fee deduction issue during transactions.Resolved compilation errors on Windows when using Visual Studio 2022.Updated validator voting algorithms, ensuring proper display.Revised documentation and configuration settings for better developer usability.Additional ImprovementsBesides the major changes, this update also includes:Enhanced code development and testing processes.Optimized compilation processes, improving network performance.Updated developer guidelines, simplifying the process of making code modifications.Stronger logging controls, improving network activity analysis.ConclusionThe XRP Ledger Version 2.4.0 update is not a hard fork. However, it significantly expands the network’s functionality, making it more flexible, secure, and user-friendly for both users and developers. Support for dynamic NFTs, new security mechanisms, and improved transaction testing tools ensure the stable development of the system and its compliance with modern requirements.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How Cross-Chain Technologies Work and Why Businesses Need Them</title>
    <published>2025-03-12T16:42:06+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-12T16:42:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/how-cross-chain-technologies-work-and-why-businesses-need-them-883954bee10a?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/how-cross-chain-technologies-work-and-why-businesses-need-them-883954bee10a?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Cross-Chain TechnologiesThe company Circle has introduced an update to the Cross-Chain Transfer Protocol (CCTP V2), significantly speeding up the processing of cross-network USDC transactions — from 13–19 minutes to just a few seconds. The new version features improved smart contracts and APIs that ensure fast asset transfers between Ethereum and L2 networks.This update demonstrates the growing interest of businesses in cross-chain technologies, as they simplify transfers and open up new opportunities in the crypto economy! However, a major issue in the blockchain industry is the fragmentation of networks, where each blockchain operates as a separate island. This kind of technologies technologies solve this problem by enabling different blockchains to interact with each other.How Do Cross-Chain Technologies Work?Cross-chain technologies allow different blockchains to interact, creating a unified ecosystem. There are several key mechanisms for interaction:Bridges connect different networks, allowing assets to be transferred between them. Examples: Wormhole, Multichain.Atomic Swaps provide decentralized asset exchange without intermediaries.Sidechains and Parachains are alternative networks operating alongside main blockchains such as Polkadot and Cosmos.Interoperability Protocols establish standards ensuring blockchain compatibility, such as LayerZero and Axelar.Many blockchains are already integrating cross-chain solutions, recognizing their importance. These developments enhance their functionality and usability!What Business Problems Do Cross-Chain Technologies Solve?Network fragmentation limits the efficiency of businesses operating in the crypto space. However, these kind of technologies address key issues across various industries:Financial sector: Accelerates and reduces the cost of cross-border payments, improving the efficiency of international transactions.DeFi and liquidity: Allows users from different blockchains to connect, increasing access to financial instruments.Gaming and NFT: Ensures compatibility of gaming assets and NFTs across different metaverses.Corporate solutions: Automates processes and simplifies data transfer between blockchain networks.The Future of Cross-Chain TechnologiesAs cross-chain technologies become increasingly in demand, the field will continue to evolve, leading to enhanced functionality and technological advancements:Security improvements: Development of more robust protocols to protect transactions.Regulatory impact: Legislative changes may influence the rules governing cross-chain operations.ConclusionCross-chain technologies remove barriers between blockchains, providing businesses with more convenient, faster, and more secure solutions. They accelerate cross-border payments, enhance liquidity, simplify corporate processes, and expand DeFi and NFT opportunities.In a competitive environment, companies implementing cross-chain solutions gain a strategic advantage. Major players like Circle are already actively developing this technology, making the blockchain ecosystem more efficient.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Cardano vs. Algorand: Which Consensus is More Reliable?</title>
    <published>2025-03-11T15:40:43+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-11T15:40:43+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/cardano-vs-algorand-which-consensus-is-more-reliable-926bc8e3d08f?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/cardano-vs-algorand-which-consensus-is-more-reliable-926bc8e3d08f?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Cardano vs AlgorandCardano and Algorand are two blockchain projects offering innovative solutions in decentralized technologies. Both utilize Proof-of-Stake (PoS) consensus mechanisms, but take different approaches to security, scalability, and attack resistance. But which consensus mechanism is better? Let’s find out!Overview of Consensus MechanismsCardano: OuroborosCardano uses the Ouroboros consensus mechanism, the first mathematically proven secure PoS protocol. The key principles of this consensus mechanism are:The network is divided into slots and epochs, within which Slot Leaders are selected to create blocks.Leader selection is based on a random process that considers the stake share of participants.The protocol supports delegation, allowing ADA holders to stake their coins in pools to earn rewards.Ouroboros provides resistance to 51% attacks through cryptographic security proofs.Algorand: Pure Proof-of-StakeAlgorand, on the other hand, employs a unique Pure Proof-of-Stake (PPoS) mechanism that minimizes barriers to participation in consensus. Key features of this mechanism include:Validators (consensus participants) are randomly and secretly selected from all ALGO holders, making network attacks more difficult.All nodes can participate in proposing and voting on blocks.The algorithm ensures instant transaction finality, eliminating the risk of forks.PPoS provides high transaction speed and decentralization.Reliability and SecurityAttack ResistanceCardano: As mentioned earlier, Ouroboros is mathematically proven to be secure and resistant to 51% attacks. An attacker would need to control a significant portion of the network’s stake and coordinate actions well in advance.Algorand: PPoS makes predicting future validators impossible, complicating attacks. However, if a large share of ALGO ends up under the control of a single group, it could impact the network.Centralization vs. DecentralizationCardano: Decentralization happens gradually. Initially, the network was controlled by IOHK (the developer), but as the number of staking pools grows, Cardano is becoming increasingly decentralized.Algorand: The entire ALGO stake is considered when selecting validators, reducing centralization risks. However, it is worth noting that the initial token distribution was relatively centralized.Security Audits and PrecedentsCardano has undergone formal verification and academic research confirming its security.Algorand utilizes cryptographic VRF (Verifiable Random Function) signatures, which enhance trust in the system.Performance and Fork ResistanceBlockchain performance determines how quickly and efficiently the network can confirm transactions. Fork resistance, on the other hand, indicates the likelihood of the network splitting into two independent chains. The table below shows how Cardano and Algorand take different approaches to solving these issues.As seen here, Algorand excels in transaction confirmation speed, but Cardano is developing the Hydra solution, which will significantly increase throughput.ConclusionBoth blockchains offer reliable consensus mechanisms, but their approaches differ:Cardano (Ouroboros) focuses on rigorous mathematical security and formal verification.Algorand (PPoS) prioritizes high speed and decentralization without requiring delegation.The choice between them depends on your goals: if strict scientific verification is essential, choose Cardano; if instant transaction finality and flexibility are more important, go with Algorand. The decision is yours!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Ethereum Update: What’s New in Geth 1.15.2 and Prysm 5.2.0</title>
    <published>2025-02-27T11:52:16+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-27T11:52:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/ethereum-update-whats-new-in-geth-1-15-2-and-prysm-5-2-0-ab05d267206e?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/ethereum-update-whats-new-in-geth-1-15-2-and-prysm-5-2-0-ab05d267206e?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Ethereum UpdateIn anticipation of the upcoming Ethereum update — Pectra, client software updates essential for node and validator operations have been released. Two key releases — Geth 1.15.2 and Prysm 5.2.0 — are closely connected and introduce important changes in block processing, network synchronization, and support for an increased gas limit.Why Are These Updates Needed? Ethereum operates on two levels:Execution Layer (EL) — the execution client, such as Geth, responsible for transaction execution, smart contract processing, and block creation.Consensus Layer (CL) — the consensus client, such as Prysm, responsible for coordinating validator operations, monitoring block finalization, and ensuring network integrity.For the network to function smoothly, both layers must interact seamlessly. Let’s dive into each release in more detail:Key Changes in Geth 1.15.2The Geth 1.15.2 update is focused on bug fixes and node optimization:Fixed the block construction mechanism on the mainnet, which was disrupted in previous versions.Enabled the QUIC protocol by default, improving network connections between nodes. The protocol operates over UDP on port 13000.Improved support for the increased gas limit, which is crucial for the future scalability of the network.Restored functionality for DNS peer discovery, which was accidentally disabled earlier.Fixed issues related to node configuration, including those concerning NAT and P2P connections.What’s New in Prysm 5.2.0The Prysm 5.2.0 update introduces several crucial improvements for validators:Added support for Electra and EIP-6110, which affect deposit handling and consensus mechanisms.Fixed node state rollback errors, reducing the risk of data corruption in case of failures.Enhanced the peer discovery system, speeding up the synchronization process.Introduced additional monitoring metrics that allow for more precise tracking of node and validator status.Fixed API errors, including issues related to REST requests, subscriptions, and block processing.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Solana vs Base: Where Is It Better to Create Meme Tokens?</title>
    <published>2025-02-26T12:45:44+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-26T12:45:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/solana-vs-base-where-is-it-better-to-create-meme-tokens-23b0e65903d4?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/solana-vs-base-where-is-it-better-to-create-meme-tokens-23b0e65903d4?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Solana VS BASEMeme tokens remain a trending phenomenon, with new tokens emerging daily. But how do you create a standout meme token among the competition? Key factors influencing a meme token’s success include transaction speed, gas fees, available tools, and ecosystem support. Choosing the right network is already half the battle in launching a successful crypto project.Solana and Base are two of the top choices for creating meme tokens. Let’s explore which one is the better option!Solana and Base: Key FeaturesSolana and Base have different architectures and operational principles, directly impacting the ease of creating meme tokens.Solana attracts meme token creators with its high throughput and near-zero fees, making it convenient for launching and trading tokens. Meanwhile, Base, as a Layer 2 solution for Ethereum, offers compatibility with Ethereum’s ecosystem and support from major centralized exchanges such as Coinbase.Ease of Creating Meme TokensLaunching a meme token on either network requires specific tools.On Solana, the most popular tools include Metaplex, Solana Token Creator, and Candy Machine. These services allow for quick creation and deployment of SPL tokens.On Base, standard tools include OpenZeppelin and Thirdweb, with Hardhat and Remix being commonly used for deploying contracts.Cost and Transaction SpeedOne of the main factors when choosing a network for meme tokens is the cost of operations.Solana transactions are nearly free, with confirmation times of less than a second.Base transactions are cheaper than those on Ethereum but more expensive than those on Solana (~$0.01 per swap).For developers focused on mass issuance and active trading, Solana is more attractive due to its low costs. However, Base can be a great choice for those looking to leverage Ethereum’s ecosystem advantages.Security and Network StabilityBlockchain reliability is another key factor.Solana has experienced network outages and congestion issues, raising concerns about stability.Base uses Optimistic Rollups, relying on Ethereum’s infrastructure, which is considered more stable.Despite technical difficulties, Solana is continuously improving its architecture, while Base benefits from Ethereum’s resilience.Final Comparison and RecommendationsConclusionThe choice between Solana and Base depends on your project’s goals and priorities:If your focus is on low fees and high transaction speeds, Solana is an excellent option.If you prioritize Ethereum compatibility and centralized exchange support, Base might be the better choice.Both networks have their own strengths and trade-offs. Developers should assess their long-term strategy and technical requirements before selecting the optimal blockchain for their meme token.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Terra Classic v3.4.0 Update: Key Changes</title>
    <published>2025-02-25T17:01:41+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-25T17:01:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/terra-classic-v3-4-0-update-key-changes-e10df793e872?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/terra-classic-v3-4-0-update-key-changes-e10df793e872?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Terra ClassicTerra Classic continues to evolve, and the latest v3.4.0 update marks a significant step toward improving the network’s stability and security. In this update, developers have completed the removal of forks, fixed issues related to multi-transfers, and implemented critical security updates.In this article, we’ll break down the specific changes introduced in the update, how they affect developers using Terra Classic, and what steps should be taken to maximize the benefits of the network’s new capabilities.What is Terra Classic?Terra Classic is a decentralized blockchain that uses the Delegated Proof-of-Stake (DPoS) mechanism and supports smart contracts on CosmWasm.Terra Classic continues to grow thanks to the efforts of its community and independent developers. It remains one of the most popular platforms for decentralized applications (dApps) running on the Cosmos SDK and has an active ecosystem of developers and validators.Key Changes in the Terra Classic v3.4.0 Update1. Removal of Forks: Transition to Official VersionsOne of the major technical improvements is the complete removal of forks from the blockchain’s core components. Previously, Terra Classic used modified versions of the Cosmos SDK, CometBFT, and Inter-Blockchain Communication (IBC), which made maintenance and integration with the Cosmos ecosystem more complex. Now, the network operates on official stable versions:Cosmos SDK v0.47.14 — Manages accounts, transactions, and validators.CometBFT v0.37.15 — The consensus mechanism responsible for block finalization.IBC v7.4.1 — The inter-chain communication protocol ensures stable connectivity with other blockchains.This transition makes Terra Classic more compatible with other projects in the Cosmos ecosystem, simplifies network maintenance, and reduces the likelihood of errors caused by custom modifications.2. Security FixesA key aspect of the update is critical security improvements. Vulnerabilities have been patched in the following modules:Wasmvm v1.5.8 — The virtual machine used for executing smart contracts in Terra Classic. Developers can now be confident that their contracts are protected from known attacks.CometBFT v0.37.15 — Two critical vulnerabilities (ASA-2025–001 and ASA-2025–002) have been fixed, which could have impacted network stability.Additional fixes (CWA-2025–001, CWA-2025–002) — Addressed vulnerabilities related to transaction processing and security verification mechanisms.These updates are crucial for the entire ecosystem as they enhance the blockchain’s resilience against potential attacks and unauthorized modifications.3. Fixing Tax Calculation in Multi-TransfersPreviously, a bug in the network caused the tax collection mechanism to work incorrectly during mass transfers (Multisend). This issue has now been fixed, ensuring that taxes are calculated correctly when multiple transactions are sent within a single operation. This improvement enhances transaction transparency and eliminates potential discrepancies in tax calculations.What Does This Mean for Developers?1. Simplified Development and Project MaintenanceThe removal of forks and the transition to standard versions of the Cosmos SDK, CometBFT, and IBC make the development environment more predictable. Developers can now use official documentation and tools without facing issues caused by custom modifications.2. Enhanced Smart Contract SecurityThe updated version of Wasmvm includes vulnerability fixes, making smart contract deployment in Terra Classic more secure. Developers can be assured that their applications are operating in a protected environment.3. More Stable Transactions and CalculationsThe corrected tax mechanism eliminates errors that could lead to incorrect calculations in multi-transfers. This is particularly important for projects dealing with bulk payments and automated fund distribution systems.ConclusionThe Terra Classic v3.4.0 update is an important step toward increasing blockchain stability, security, and usability. Developers gain access to a more reliable platform that is compatible with the latest tool versions, while users can trust that their transactions are secure.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Types of Blockchain Nodes: A Complete Guide</title>
    <published>2025-02-24T16:34:11+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-24T16:34:11+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/types-of-blockchain-nodes-a-complete-guide-84a8af5ff5e6?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/types-of-blockchain-nodes-a-complete-guide-84a8af5ff5e6?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In web3, blockchain nodes are the backbone that ensures security, transaction validation, and data storage. These nodes are critical to maintaining the decentralized nature of the system and ensure that everything operates smoothly. While all nodes contribute to the blockchain, each type has a different function. Some nodes store complete transaction histories, while others focus on processing transactions, securing the network through mining or staking, or assisting in governance. Understanding these various types of blockchain nodes is key to effectively engaging with the technology.What Are Blockchain Nodes?A blockchain node is essentially any computer or device integrated into a blockchain network. These nodes are vital because they handle the storage, verification, and forwarding of transaction information, guaranteeing the network’s decentralized and transparent nature. Without nodes, there wouldn’t be a way to confirm or disseminate data throughout the blockchain, making the entire system inoperable.Various node types execute distinct roles within a blockchain, ranging from transaction verification to governance support. Let’s explore the specific categories of blockchain nodes and the advantages they offer.Types of Blockchain NodesFull NodesFull nodes hold an entire copy of the blockchain and are responsible for validating transactions independently. They ensure every transaction adheres to the rules of the network, thus contributing to its security and decentralization.Key Features &amp;amp; Benefits:Stores the complete transaction history, maintaining accuracy and transparency.Independently validates transactions and blocks, minimizing reliance on external parties.Strengthens blockchain security by rejecting invalid transactions and adhering to consensus rules.Ideal Use Cases:Developers and businesses requiring complete access to the blockchain.Cryptocurrency exchanges and wallet providers.Users who want to contribute to decentralizing the network.Light NodesOften referred to as Simplified Payment Verification (SPV) nodes, light nodes operate by not keeping the complete blockchain. They selectively download block headers and depend on full nodes to confirm the validity of transactions.Key Features &amp;amp; Benefits:Requires much less storage and processing power than full nodes.Synchronizes with the blockchain more quickly.Allows users to verify transactions without running a full node.Ideal Use Cases:Mobile and desktop wallets that need quick access to the blockchain.Users who prefer to use blockchain services without consuming many resources.MasternodesMasternodes are a form of full nodes with additional responsibilities, such as enabling instant transactions, participating in governance, and enhancing privacy. Running a masternode often requires staking a specific amount of cryptocurrency as collateral.Key Features &amp;amp; Benefits:Offers additional functionalities like governance and privacy features.Generates passive income for operators through rewards.Helps stabilize the network due to long-term investment.Ideal Use Cases:Common in blockchain networks like Dash and PIVX, which employ governance models.Investors who want to earn rewards while helping secure the network.Mining NodesIn Proof-of-Work blockchains, mining nodes play a crucial role by tackling intricate mathematical problems. Solving these puzzles allows them to verify transactions and incorporate new blocks into the blockchain.Key Features &amp;amp; Benefits:Ensures blockchain security by preventing fraudulent activities.Miners earn rewards in cryptocurrency and transaction fees.Requires high computational power and specialized hardware.Ideal Use Cases:Vital for PoW-based networks such as Bitcoin.Used by miners who invest in hardware to earn cryptocurrency rewards.Staking NodesStaking nodes are part of Proof-of-Stake (PoS) networks. In these networks, nodes lock up their tokens to validate transactions and help secure the blockchain.Key Features &amp;amp; Benefits:More energy-efficient compared to mining nodes.Generates staking rewards for participants.Increases network security by incentivizing token holders to remain involved.Ideal Use Cases:Common in PoS-based blockchains like Ethereum 2.0 and Cardano.Ideal for crypto holders looking to earn rewards without the need for mining equipment.Archive NodesArchive nodes store the complete history of the blockchain, including all past transactions, smart contracts, and balances.Key Features &amp;amp; Benefits:Provides detailed access to historical data, useful for research and analytics.Crucial for regulatory compliance, blockchain explorers, and forensic investigations.Ideal Use Cases:Required by auditors and blockchain research organizations.Used by businesses that need full access to the blockchain’s historical data.RPC NodesRemote Procedure Call (RPC) nodes provide external applications and services with direct access to blockchain networks. They allow businesses and developers to interact with the blockchain without maintaining their own full nodes.Key Features &amp;amp; Benefits:Offers fast and reliable access to the blockchain via APIs.Reduces the need to run a personal full node, while ensuring real-time access to blockchain data.Facilitates efficient transaction broadcasting and smart contract interactions.Ideal Use Cases:Used by Web3 developers and decentralized applications (dApps).Necessary for businesses that want to integrate blockchain capabilities without technical overhead.Commonly used in networks like Ethereum, Binance Smart Chain, and Polygon.ConclusionGrasping the various types of blockchain nodes empowers developers, investors, and users to make well-considered choices regarding their engagement with blockchain networks. From securing the network and earning rewards to developing decentralized applications, selecting the suitable node type is crucial for a more seamless blockchain journey.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Injective Nivara Mainnet upgrade: New Developer Opportunities</title>
    <published>2025-02-18T14:12:16+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-18T14:12:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/injective-nivara-mainnet-upgrade-new-developer-opportunities-529fc5888bc8?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/injective-nivara-mainnet-upgrade-new-developer-opportunities-529fc5888bc8?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">inInjective Nivara Mainnet upgrade: New Developer OpportunitiesInjective Nivara Mainnet is bringing significant improvements in network stability, enhanced performance, and new opportunities for developers. Nivara Mainnet upgrade marks a key milestone in the evolution of Injective, optimizing validator operations and enhancing how applications interact with the blockchain.What is Injective?Injective (INJ) is a high-performance Layer 1 blockchain designed specifically for decentralized finance (DeFi) and digital asset trading. Built on Cosmos SDK and Tendermint, it offers low fees and near-instant transaction confirmation times.Key Features of Injective:Scalability — The ability to handle thousands of transactions per second without network congestion.Ethereum compatibility — EVM support and integration with Ethereum via the Peggo bridge.Decentralized trading infrastructure — Allows the creation of markets for trading futures, derivatives, and other financial instruments.Developer-friendly ecosystem — Provides the flexibility to build smart contracts and applications using cutting-edge blockchain technology.What’s New in Injective Nivara Mainnet?The Injective v1.14.0 upgrade includes several key improvements aimed at increasing network stability and enhancing the developer experience:Blockchain OptimizationReduced load on validators, improving decentralization.Enhanced transaction processing speed with lower latency.Peggo Update to v1.14.1Improved functionality of the Ethereum-Injektive bridge, making cross-chain operations more reliable.Fixed issues related to asset transfers between chains.Upgrade to Go 1.22Enhanced multithreading support, improving overall blockchain speed and efficiency.Improved security with updated data handling mechanisms.Support for New Docker ImagesAdded images for amd64 and arm64, simplifying node deployment across various devices, including Mac M1/M2.What Does This Mean for Developers?The Injective Nivara Mainnet upgrade is not only about improving network stability but also about creating a better development environment:Faster application performance — Transactions are processed more quickly with reduced network load.Improved Ethereum integration — Cross-chain operations are now even more efficient.Updated development environment — The support for Go 1.22 improves code reliability and security.Flexible deployment options — New Docker images provide easy deployment and scalability.ConclusionThe Injective Nivara Mainnet upgrade is a significant step forward in blockchain development, focused on improving network stability, performance, and providing developers with better tools to build decentralized applications.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Top 5 Blockchains for Web3 Game Development in 2025</title>
    <published>2025-02-14T12:12:34+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-14T12:12:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/top-5-blockchains-for-web3-game-development-in-2025-c76aa8a1faa9?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/top-5-blockchains-for-web3-game-development-in-2025-c76aa8a1faa9?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In 2025, the choice of blockchain for a Web3 game becomes even more crucial, as each blockchain offers unique advantages for different types of games. Developers are seeking ways to create unique game projects with transparent economies, unique digital assets, and opportunities for integration with the real world. But what to choose? Let’s dive into the top 5 blockchains for Web3 game development in 2025:1. Polygon — The Optimal Solution for Ethereum-Compatible GamesPolygon (MATIC) is a Layer 2 solution for the Ethereum network that offers low transaction fees and high transaction speeds while maintaining full compatibility with Ethereum. This makes Polygon the ideal choice for developers who want to leverage Ethereum’s power but avoid high transaction costs and scalability issues.Why Polygon is the Go-To Choice for Scalable Games?Ethereum Compatibility: Everything that works within the Ethereum ecosystem can be integrated into Polygon without additional complexity. NFT standards (ERC-721) and tokens (ERC-20) can easily move between these blockchains.Low Fees and High Speed: Polygon addresses Ethereum’s main issue — high transaction fees. Developers can create multiplayer games with microtransactions and ensure fast and cost-effective operations.Support for NFTs and Game Economies: Polygon is widely used in metaverses like Decentraland and The Sandbox, which support trading and exchanging unique digital assets.Example Game: The Sandbox — a popular metaverse where players can create, own, and monetize their in-game assets, using Polygon’s capabilities for fast and low-cost transactions.2. Solana — Blockchain for Large-Scale and Fast-Paced GamesSolana (SOL) continues to be one of the fastest and most scalable blockchains on the market. It attracts developers creating games with intense activity and a large number of players, where high throughput and minimal latency are crucial.Why Solana is Perfect for Massively Multiplayer Online Games?High Speed: Solana can process up to 65,000 transactions per second, allowing the creation of large-scale multiplayer games with high-speed requirements.Low Fees: With low fees for both users and developers, games with microtransactions and in-game purchases run efficiently.Support for NFTs: Solana actively supports NFT creation and interaction, enabling the integration of unique in-game items, characters, and collections into the game’s economy.Example Game: Star Atlas — an ambitious space game that uses Solana’s capabilities for a dynamic gameplay experience with active trading of NFT assets.3. Polkadot — Innovation Through Cross-Blockchain InteractionPolkadot (DOT) offers unique opportunities for building cross-blockchain applications. This is an inter-chain platform that enables blockchains to work together, creating an ecosystem where assets can move across different blockchains.Why Polkadot Matters for Web3 Games?Cross-Blockchain Interaction: Full support for interaction between different blockchains opens up new possibilities for creating games that can exchange assets across ecosystems.Scalability and Security: Polkadot offers high levels of security and scalability, which are important for developing games with a large number of users and complex logic.Cross-Platform Compatibility: Games on Polkadot can operate on multiple blockchains simultaneously, giving developers flexibility in choosing technology for various aspects of the game.Example Game: Developers on Polkadot are building games that can interact with other blockchains, giving them flexibility in choosing technology for different game features.4. Theta Network — Streaming and Content as Part of the Gaming ExperienceTheta Network (THETA) is a blockchain focused on streaming and video content. This solution is ideal for games that rely heavily on video content, streaming, audience interaction, and the ability to reward users for their participation.Why Theta is the Ideal Choice for Video Content-Driven Games?Streaming and Video Content: Games using Theta can integrate streaming capabilities and content interaction. Players can share their gaming sessions in real-time, and viewers can receive rewards.Rewards for Participation: Theta allows users to earn tokens for activities, whether it’s streaming or participating in game events.Support for VR and AR: Theta is actively developing capabilities for virtual and augmented reality, opening new possibilities for creating immersive game worlds.Example Game: Theta.tv — a streaming platform where players can not only broadcast their gaming sessions but also earn tokens by participating in collaborative streams.5. VeChain — for Real-World Assets and TransparencyVET is a blockchain focused on supply chain management, but its capabilities extend far beyond traditional use. It is is perfect for games that require integration with real-world assets and high transparency of data.Why VeChain is Unique for Web3 Games?Integration with Real Assets: Games on VeChain can integrate real-world goods or assets with physical certificates. This opens up new opportunities to create games with unique assets tied to the real world.Transparency and Immutability: For games requiring high data reliability (e.g., for collectible items), VeChain provides transparency and verifiability.Longevity of Assets: Virtual assets, such as in-game items, can be tied to real-world goods, providing new paths for monetization and interaction with the real world.Example Game: In VeChain, developers can create games where digital assets, such as rare collectible items, can be not only virtual but also physical goods with verified history and origin.ConclusionIn 2025, the choice of blockchain for your Web3 game depends on what goals you have for your project. If you need high speed and low fees, Solana (SOL) and Polygon (MATIC) are excellent choices. For games with video content integration, consider Theta Network (THETA). If your project requires cross-blockchain interaction, Polkadot (DOT) is the best option. For games that involve real-world assets, VeChain (VET) is the way to go.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Sui network update 73: What’s New</title>
    <published>2025-02-13T12:31:39+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-13T12:31:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nownodes.medium.com/sui-network-update-73-whats-new-675931966ce0?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nownodes.medium.com/sui-network-update-73-whats-new-675931966ce0?source=rss-e1ca260efd61------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>NOWNodes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">This update includes many substantial changes that impact network performance and developer experience. Let’s dive into the most important changes and why they matter.What Has Changed in the Sui Protocol?Consensus OptimizationA garbage collection mechanism has been implemented in the consensus process, automatically removing outdated data. This significantly reduces network load and enhances overall efficiency.Faster and More Efficient Data Compressionzstd compression has been added for the testnet network, reducing the amount of transmitted data and speeding up consensus operations.Smart Ancestor SelectionThe new smart ancestor selection algorithm improves decision-making within the consensus mechanism, making it more predictable and reliable.Improvements in CLI and MoveUpgrade Compatibility CheckA new --verify-compatibility flag has been introduced, allowing developers to check updates before publishing them. This helps prevent errors when deploying new contract versions.Improved Move.tomlWhen creating a new project using sui move new, the Move.toml file now automatically sets override = true for the framework. This prevents source verification errors and makes working with Move smoother.Source Verification ConfigurationWhen publishing and upgrading contracts, a warning now appears indicating that source verification will become optional in future releases. Developers can already disable verification using the --skip-dependency-verification flag or enable it with --verify-deps.Why Is This Important for Developers?The Network Is Faster and More StableThe updated consensus mechanism, which removes outdated data, reduces node load and speeds up transaction processing. This is particularly important for developers working with high-traffic dApps, as improved performance reduces latency and enhances user experience.Fewer Issues When Working with MoveChanges to Move.toml eliminate source verification errors that previously caused issues when building projects. This makes smart contract development more predictable and reliable, allowing teams to focus on functionality rather than resolving technical compatibility issues.Safe and Predictable UpdatesThe new compatibility check flag allows developers to identify potential problems before deploying new contract versions. This is especially beneficial for teams operating in production environments, as it reduces the likelihood of failures and unexpected issues during updates.ConclusionSui 73 upgrade is a step forward in the evolution of the network, making it more towards being stronger, efficient, and developer-friendly. We will be on our toes watching out for new changes and the seamless operation of the infrastructure!</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
