<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by OCTO on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@octo_press?source=rss-703f834a6b69------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40octo_press&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*EgdC6TpbaAgIoiQmnl6k7A.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*EgdC6TpbaAgIoiQmnl6k7A.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40octo_press&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:08:15+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The future of NFTs, digital assets and markets. Pt. 2</title>
    <published>2023-05-05T21:27:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-05T21:27:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@octo_press/the-future-of-nfts-digital-assets-and-markets-pt-2-21f0304a2101?source=rss-703f834a6b69------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@octo_press/the-future-of-nfts-digital-assets-and-markets-pt-2-21f0304a2101?source=rss-703f834a6b69------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>OCTO</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Credit: Forbes + some good old editingNon-Fungible Tokens, or NFTs for short, represent the newest blockchain derivative, often associated with images. However, while the physical manifestation can take any shape or form, including text, music, files of various formats, or no physical form at all, the underlying concept and the driving technology truly give the blockchain industry a new meaning. At the time of writing, the space is predominantly populated by images, which is understandable, given the easily-digestible format. Since 2014, the NFT market has boomed over the year 2021 and now has an estimated market capitalization of over $11.3 billion with the expectation to hit $250 billion by 2030. With that being said, the NFT space is spread across essentially all active blockchains, while being recognized as an integral part of all ecosystems, contributing to the community engagement, increased liquidity and a monetization tool for businesses and individuals.In the spirit of the true Web3 competition, the NFT space has already shown early signs of evolution, which will undoubtedly continue in the future too. Ever-growing complexity of NFT projects, more applicable utilities, innovative use cases and even the increasing attention of scammers are the direct advocates of the looming mass-adoption of the technology. However, just like in any other open market industry, the infrastructure too plays a crucial role. Marketplaces, various bridging protocols, interoperability of assets, safety features, regulations, among many other puzzle pieces — all empower the NFT industry with legitimacy.History lessonNow, let us take a step back and indulge in a quick rundown of the history of NFT marketplaces.Ascribe, a name that only the geekiest crypto enthusiasts remember, was the first NFT protocol, which existed in 2014–2018. Surprisingly, the protocol supported and operated NFTs on Bitcoin, something that is often reported as being merely impractical or even impossible. The year Ascribe shut down its operations matches with the introduction of the ERC721 standard on Ethereum, although with a slight delay, which, of course, is not a coincidence. As the historical farewell message on Ascribe’s website states to this day “it’s clear that ascribe was at least a few years too early to market. However, it’s also clear that ascribe has massively influenced our own subsequent work, and the learnings and protocols” — a perfect introspection.Birth of the giant, namely OpenSea, perhaps the most famous NFT marketplace, took place in December 2017 after raising as little as $120,000 in pre-seed round. Effectively, this is the first mainstream-targeting NFT marketplace to offer NFTs from different collections and creators, as the previous NFT projects had the minting and secondary market storefronts located on their respective websites. To this day, OpenSea remains one of the NFT marketplace industry titans and a home to over 80 million NFTs and 2 million unique users, which landed its valuation at 14 billion dollars. Today, OpenSea supports not only Ethereum, but also Polygon, Klaytn, Solana, Arbitrum, Optimism, Avalanche and BNB chain, essentially covering all of the largest blockchains. Moreover, OpenSea attracted big brands like Pepsi, Adidas, Coca-Cola and Nike among others to launch their official collections.SuperRare launched in April 2018 and positions itself in the niche of curated NFT artwork, as opposed to the profile picture (PFP) projects that were only starting to get popular. Currently, the marketplace continues its crypto-art approach, having over 38,000 digital pieces of artwork collected worth $180 million in artist fees.KnownOrigin also launched in April 2018 becoming a direct competitor to SuperRare not just by stealing some of the audience’s attention, but also the niche of digital artwork. However, in June 2022 eBay purchased KnownOrigin, which should be considered as one of the signs of the impending mass-adoption and an industry with high potential overall.Nifty Gateway becomes one of the groundbreaking, yet simple, marketplaces in 2018 by offering USD purchases of NFTs with credit cards. Even to this day this feature is absent in many marketplaces, partially due to the lack of NFT and crypto regulations, hence troublesome partnerships with card processing services. As their official website states their slogan of “We will not rest until 1 billion people are collecting NFTs.”, the platform continues attracting new artists and collectors, offering curated art collections as well as welcoming top brands like Starbucks, who cautiously test the NFT industry.Winter 2019 commemorates the launch of Rarible, yet another NFT marketplace giant, which currently support Ethereum, Tezos, Immutable X and Polygon — some of the most prominent NFT blockchains.Crypto.com, a well-known Singapore-based cryptocurrency exchange launches its own marketplace in 2021 by focusing on strategic collaborations with big brands like Coca-Cola and UFC.Finally, a new type of NFT marketplace in the list appears — Royal, which becomes the host to music NFT, as opposed to the familiar PFPs or artwork collectibles. The marketplace was founded by DJ 3LAU (also a backer of OpenSea) with the support of musicians like The Chainsmokers, Logic and Kygo and shortly following by Nas and Diplo.Magic Eden appeared in 2021 as a Solana-based marketplace, which was an obvious strategy due to Solana’s booming popularity at the time. Currently the marketplace also supports Polygon, Ethereum and Bitcoin, yet the NFT projects created remain predominantly on Solana.Binance, which needs no introduction at this stage, also launched its own NFT marketplace in 2021 utilizing its in-house BNB chain. Currently, Binance marketplace is deemed as one of the main NFT gaming hubs.Sudoswap appeared in October 2021, and offered a revolutionary at the time option to swap NFTs instead of having to buy/sell. Yet, the popularity and the fame came later, around June 2022 when the platform introduced its unique on-chain AMM trading, which allowed not only for an immediate NFT liquidity, but also offered additional way of earning via the NFT liquidity pools.Uniswap, yet another famous crypto exchange has entered the NFT marketplace industry by acquiring Genie in mid-2022. It’s an NFT marketplace, nothing special.Finally, the latest disruptor of the marketplace industry is Blur. While its original selling point was being 10x times faster than many other marketplaces, the true attention cost this aggregator an arm and a leg. Blur which positioned itself as a marketplace for ‘NFT pro traders’ rewarded the users for active trading by airdropping over $300 million worth of token within the 3 rounds. Zero fees and a lack of enforcement for creator fees forced OpenSea to commit to similar terms as part of their ongoing war. Regardless, Blur had managed to outperform OpenSea by the sales volume in the past month, scoring over $1 billion vs OpenSea’s $480 million. However, two questions remain unanswered. Firstly, is the Blur’s current popularity sustainable in the long run given the massive upfront investment a.k.a. buying its audience? And, secondly, since Paradigm was the main investor of Blur, as well as OpenSea — what does it mean for the future of those marketplaces?A couple of last-minute honorable mentions:World’s most prominent auction house Sotheby’s launched its own P2P (secondary market) NFT marketplace after having a short history of a few, yet expensive NFTs sold in the previous years. Moreover, the story about Beeple’s ‘The First 5000 Days’ collage NFT been sold for over $69 million at Christie’s auction house certainly contributed to Sotheby’s NFT agenda.At the time of writing, Amazon (yes, that one), has not yet launched their NFT marketplace, which is rumored to be due on May 15 2023. How will it be, what would it offer and would the alleged fiat payments be enough to take a slice of the market — are all the questions the time would provide us the answers with soon.The premiseClearly, the brief glimpse into this chronology omitted a lot of other NFT marketplaces, especially the unknown local ones of the smaller blockchains. Therefore, one might get an impression that the industry is already well-saturated. However, while the aforementioned market competition logically results in innovation, the picture remains being imperfect at large, and especially within the blockchains of smaller market capitalization. While the top-5 blockchains show a great abundance of marketplaces and other protocols, the less known blockchains often exhibit complete lack of various NFT-related services or even existing marketplaces altogether. Moreover, one can often witness a lack of certain services and features even among the largest blockchains.The other issue that speaks for itself is the prevailing crypto tribalism, which we define as user-specific preference and/or prejudice towards some blockchains over others. Although one can attempt to argue why a particular blockchain is the best overall, many agree that different networks serve to solve their niche purposes, alike different tools are used for different processes when building a house. This premise leads to the next-generation world order, where the technological and social aspects are governed by the appropriate blockchains.However, another factor for this to be successful is the seamlessness of the process and the convenience of use to the customer. It is abundantly clear that the current population of crypto users are not only more adventurous (liberal, proactive, creative — pick your suitable adjective), but are also forced to be more tech savvy. Clearly the use of a credit card is a lot more convenient that crypto, it is more readily supported overall, while the use process is simple enough for children, elderly or other people far from technology.And finally, the topic of safety. Although it is a multifaceted topic in itself, it is definite that the rise of popularity in crypto and NFTs has led to the undesirable, yet inevitable attention from scammers and hackers. Whilst the latter is supposedly harder to protect against, even those often heavily rely on social engineering with up to 98% of breaches happening due to the victim’s lack of caution. And as history of NFT scams shows us, most of the scams happen due to the lack of clear communication and ability to verify information, that is users fall victim to the misinformation due to the lack of clear channels of communication.Credit: jakegallen @ TwitterThe solutionAll these points have brought us to the conclusion that the current state of NFT marketplaces (and other related infrastructure) is lacking a lot of compulsory and even logical steps in evolution. There are a few key features we derived that seem crucial both for the spirit of Web3 and mass adoption. They are:Central (yet decentralized) platform for NFT interactionWide-spread blockchain availabilityEase of use and real seamlessness of user experienceExhaustive list of activitiesCreator-centered community interactionSafety, communication and interactionsEase of useNow, let us elaborate on these in more details.1) Central platform for NFT interactionImmediately, it is important to distinguish the terms ‘central’ and ‘centralized’. Central platform merely refers to users world-wide having a hub, their go-to place if they want to do anything with NFTs. Currently, the industry is comprised of many marketplaces per blockchain, sometimes as high as tens per network. Although competition is the driver of innovation, given the current level of adoption makes most of these platforms unpopular, unprofitable and ultimately drag down the projects and the holders of their digital assets. Moreover, due to the business nature of such platforms, they are forced to charge high fees, which both affects the project creators and the users. By using the economies of scale principle, a next-gen platform should allow for smaller fees, while providing higher quality of service, thus becoming a central hub for digital assets.2) Wide-spread blockchain availabilityCrypto tribalism is currently prevalent, and would exist in the future to a small extend, although we see it becoming less apparent. However, at this stage we witness not only the lack of high-quality marketplace services, but frequently a complete lack of a marketplace in otherwise sound blockchains. This often forces project creators that are fans of a particular chain to search for other blockchain alternatives where they can launch the project. While this is arguably unfair itself, it also is detrimental to the ecosystems of smaller blockchains, as many projects can utilize NFTs as an additional tool, yet are forced out of their respective habitats. NFTs should be available to the creators regardless of their blockchain preference, just like the users who seem to support and engage with their fellow natives more than outsiders.3) Ease of use and real seamlessness of user experienceBuilding directly on top of the previous point, it is vital for the crypto industry at large to be as simple and seamless for the average Joe as technologically possible. Not only we want to be a puzzle piece in the interoperability infrastructure for the sake of our egos, but also, we see a great synergy that the chain-agnostic experience can bring to the blockchain community at large. Various project collaborations, cross-use of technology and pure promotion of great project that deserve larger audience — all of this is possible in a perfect chain-agnostic world. Therefore, it is not a surprise at all that many companies solely focus on building various interoperability protocols to bridge the gap between various networks. As a good representation, think of a local grocery shop, which imports goods from 10 different countries with each product being sold in its country-of-origin currency. Not so convenient. Our desire is to build an infrastructure that allows one-click automation to purchase any NFT from any supported blockchain, as long as one has enough intrinsic value (fiat value) in the account, without the need of external exchanges and the associated fees.4) Exhaustive list of activitiesWhile this seems straight-forward at first, even the largest monopolists like OpenSea or Blur seem to have numerous limitations to what they offer. ‘Sweep the floor’ function is relatively new and is often missing, swap functionality is absent (except Sudo Swap), just like fiat support, and the list goes on. Looking at the smaller marketplaces we often see a relatively primitive functionality altogether: mint, buy/sell. While everyone enjoys referring to the term ‘Web3’ in conjunction with ‘freedom’, the current state of the industry is clearly limited by the activities selection. In order to enlist more options, the user has to look elsewhere. In our vision, the one-stop-shop marketplace should exceed the needs of a user by providing ALL the functionality in one place, from one account. Users should have the ability to utilize any complex smart contract, mint their collections in various ways, create collection liquidity pools, hold auctions with customizable structure, trade, swap, engage with the community, privately chat, vote, showcase their trophies, utilize analytic tools…(and all that with an easily digestible interface for any chain and less fees).5) Creator-centered community interactionWe often contemplate why is it that norm for the creators to have so many channels of communication with their community — Discord, Telegram, Twitter, Medium, YouTube, and so on. Each one of those platforms takes the creator’s time to manage, not to mention the various limitations they pose. For instance, if a creator wants to have a series of cartoons based on the NFT project accessible only to the members, the best bet so far is to use Telegram, Discord or Patreon (sometimes). Not everyone uses Telegram, Discord has a limitation of supported formats and file sizes (even with maxed out Nitro boosts), Patreon requires additional payment, which also happens to be in fiat. A next-gen NFT marketplace should not only allow, but encourage the creators to have a dedicated section with content, whether it be video, text, image or 3D model, gated by their collection’s NFTs or special drops for exclusive VIP experience. Additionally, a creator must have a clear and convenient way of communicating with the supporters, holding polls and posting updates &amp;amp; announcements.6) Safety, communication and interactionsWhy do many people buy NFTs? Of course, many do it in the anticipation of profit, some do it for the technology (minority so far) or the unique experience. Regardless, the users become a part of a closed community who they enjoy interacting with, further hyping each other, come up with new ideas and as history shows us, even start businesses around it together. One of the crucial caveats that the modern industry arguably has, is the ability to directly communicate with the peers. As mentioned above, one has to resort to other means of communication like Discord, Twitter or others, in order to…well, do anything, essentially. Whether it is to offer another user to buy his/her rare NFT, exchange opinions about the new piece of content, or settle personal business — all can be done privately in an on-chain messenger, which not only stores the messages, but also encrypts all the data. Might not seem like a big deal to use other means of communication, but by using the built-in messenger, one is able to stay anonymous, while having the certainty that the other party is not an imposter or a scammer, but is the genuine owner of a particular NFT. Moreover, the L1 P2P encryption protocol would allow for completely private conversations for those suspecting governments or corporations in data espionage.7) Ease of useWhile the crypto community has developed greatly over the past few years, bringing many innovative projects and gifted individuals, the true mass adoption can only come with the ease of use. Not coincidently at all that the new standard of ERC-4337 is being developed, which was described as the tool ‘for the next 1 billion users to adopt crypto’. Likewise, the use of ChatGPT would not have been so ubiquitous if one had to install custom neural libraries via PowerShell, connect a few external modules, set-up a Linux-based local server, etc. The overall ease of use, in other words, the user convenience, makes any product more available to the mass. And that in turn brings more attention, investment, brilliant projects and finally innovation. The next generation app should provide the most comprehensive service, while being easily accessible, including various demographics, niches and interests.Moreover, our humble experience shows that the smaller blockchains often exhibit monopolistic behavior of their marketplaces, which in turn, just like any economist would immediately conclude, means higher fees. While certain marketplaces like Rarible justify their 30% cut by providing exclusive and curated access to reputable artists, it is certainly not the case when a small local marketplace charges 50% for a project driven by an enthusiast. Needless to say, we find it atrocious.It is crypto winter outside, bears can be heard roaring. However, citing the wise King Solomon — “this too shall pass”. The markets would pick up again, prosperity will once again flourish within the worthy projects and innovators will discover new shapes of wheels.Non ducor ducoFollow us on Twitter and Discord for updates!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The future of NFTs, digital assets and markets. Pt. 1</title>
    <published>2023-04-27T20:02:59+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T20:02:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@octo_press/the-future-of-nfts-digital-assets-and-markets-7fdb85dff319?source=rss-703f834a6b69------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@octo_press/the-future-of-nfts-digital-assets-and-markets-7fdb85dff319?source=rss-703f834a6b69------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>OCTO</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Credit: news18.comWhen the biased reporters unfoundedly announce NFTs to be over, we, the crypto enthusiasts simply shrug our shoulders. However, when the statistics of some of the largest NFT marketplaces begin to shake, all we are left with is to wonder about the future of this industry.Credit: Binance NewsWhen coming up with the topic of this introductory article, admittedly I was overwhelmed both by the general lack of information and insights, as well as the presence of some incredible pieces of detective archeology revolving around the world of NFTs. Some of the information and ideas of said pieces will be included in this article too.So, why is it so vital to philosophize on the topic of NFTs, other types of digital assets and the corresponding markets? Well, firstly, it can give the reader an idea of where we are headed and how vast the space already is. Secondly, it could spark some ideas that would ultimately become the defining infrastructural solutions of the future.Now, let’s take a slight step back. Look around you. Take a deep breath, make the time slow down and look around. We are so paced by various things that we more often than not miss the shifting paradigms of the world surrounding us. The world is constantly changing, digital assets are not an exception. In fact, this world, often referred to as Web3 is moving even faster, a month in Web3 can feel like half a year in the Web2 world — Einstein’s theory of relativity in action.Our dear reader, most likely you are already familiar with NFTs, at least theoretically, so the development of this industry seems normal now. Yet, if we do some digging into the past, how the industry was shaping up, then a lot of discoveries and, most importantly, conclusions can be made. With that being said, I welcome you to a history lesson where we would quickly recap the meaningful development of NFTs and marketplaces.NFT industry at largeCredit: HaytHuyt @ Rarible.comMany conventional journalists and news reporters were quick to jump to the conclusion of NFTs dying amidst the crypto winter of 2022. The allegations, as the time showed, were purposely based on the skewed data, yet the global NFT market indeed took a dive correlating to the crypto market. Nevertheless, the industry is not likely to disappear altogether since it has now become clear that the technology holds more than simple PFPs or memes. But how deep does the rabbit hole go then? For that, let us have another quick dive, this time outlining the NFT evolution over time.The first ever NFT is believed to be the Quantum created by Kevin McCoy for the Sotheby’s auction, where the NFT was sold for $1.5 million, while being created on the newcomer of blockchains at that time, Ethereum. We shall overlook the law suit related to that particular piece of digital history, but you read about it here.Alex Tew. Who is it you might ask? Well, he was the 21-year-old lad from the UK that got his share of fame after making $1,000,000 by selling 1 million pixels on his website, essentially, marketing it as “own a piece of internet history!”. Rings the bell now? Maybe a little since it was in the UK, yet a few news publishers like the BBC picked up on the story. However, what actually remains unknown to the majority is the successor of Alex’s project, namely PixelMap.io, the first NFT-based pixel board created by Ken Erwin back in 2016. Even though the board seemingly comprises of empty space, it is surely not free, as most of those NFT pixels are now wrapped on Ethereum and can be bought on OpenSea. (It was created in 2016, so no ERC721 standard back then!)CryptoPunks (2017) — 10,000 pieces NFT collection of portrait pixel-art, also commonly referred to as the first NFT project ever! Which is actually not the case, in fact there are quite a few projects that we omitted in our journey so far, even excluding the ones in this article. Nevertheless, CryptoPunks as an NFT project is a fundamental pioneer of the ERC721 standard, which the NFT market uses to this day. Moreover, the highest CryptoPunk sale at $23.7 million in 2022, along with the lowest price of over $90 thousand at the moment of writing, surely contributed to the mass-media exposure of NFTs as a cultural movement. (Yes, technically, this is V2 of CryptoPunks that we are talking about, while V1 sells for lower prices, but still in the realm of thousands of dollars).After CryptoPunks the idea of NFTs starts growing over the fractured crypto communities, yet no one could predict what was about to happen in the next few years.MoonCatRescue launched on August 9, 2017 — the first cat NFT, and the first generative art NFT project created on Ethereum with a supply of 25,440 in the collection.Following the success, another cat-loving project, CryptoCats appeared on November 12, 2017. However, the project was forgotten and finally re-discovered in March 2021 by an NFT archeology movement. And yes, such a profession is now a thing too. And while being on the topic of cats, here is another one — CryptoKitties, 50 thousand pieces collection minted on November 23, 2017.Finally, March 14, 2018 something more meaningful than a simple PFP / collectibles project takes the crypto communities by storm, namely Axie Infinity, the first ever Play-to-Earn (P2E) game on blockchain. Early adopters of the game started to make serious money, which spurred numerous viral shorts and videos on social media, essentially gaining ever more public traction. As of April 2023, there are 1.96 million active users, even though the tokenomics of the game were already in a bad shape and the earnings were almost non-existent for more than a year. However, Axie Infinity gave a whole new meaning to NFTs and arguably created a new niche.Let’s jump ahead, obviously missing a few projects on the way, to the early 2020 when COVID-19 started. The global population finds itself in ‘solitary confinements’ and internet is the only thing that allows for risk-free and entertaining socialization. The NFT boom is looming. Many artists, content creators and crypto heads not only learn about NFTs, but also seek extra cash. At that point PFPs offer a way to differentiate yourself from the normies, while also being a part of a closed community of like-minded people scattered across the web. And these people start working on their own NFT projects in the hopes of selling the next million-dollar project.April 2021 saw the launch of the Bored Ape Yacht Club (BAYC), which is now a household name not only for crypto nerds, but mass media. At the time, the 10,000 pieces of bored monkeys’ portraits sold like candies for the measly price of 0.02 ETH, but now hold the floor of 50 ETH (around $96,000). Moreover, Yuga Labs worth $8.1 billion, the founding company of the BAYC collection remains the dominant force of the Web3 space to this day. Also, their total volume on OpenSea alone is currently 1,035,000 ETH, or almost $2 billion, besides many celebrities like Eminem, Snoop Dogg, Justin Bieber and Jimmy Fallon being the proud owners.The apes start the NFT craze.AI’s vision of ‘NFT craze’It is now mid-2021, the beginning of the NFT boom. The aforementioned NFT marketplaces are now settled in their niches, creation of a collection is not complex anymore and OpenSea, among others, offers a complete no-code approach, all one needs is to upload the images and make a few tweets. In the meantime, the macro view also changes, essentially forcing blockchains to support the third-party creation of, and even build their own NFT marketplaces. The gold rush has officially been announced.NFT projects are now created not on a monthly, but on a daily basis, Twitter and Discord are now home to NFT projects’ marketing and promotions. Clearly, increased competition renders many projects unable to sell-out, coupled with many deliberate rug-pulls (a scenario where the creator abandons the project after collecting the money, thus leaving the buyers holding the bags). Additionally, while more people enter the NFT space, the growth is not comparable by the exploding number of projects. And just like in evolutionary biology, all of these factors drove the NFT industry to adapt to the scarcity of potential buyers and limited money circulation.Below we have compiled a list of the enforced evolutionary changes the NFT projects had to undergo from 2021 to now. In no particular order, as well as ignoring the inventors who came up with a certain feature.PFP onlyPFP with social media like Twitter and Discord for the community to feel unitedRoadmap with simple utility like ‘creating a community of supporting peers’ and a fancy website to match the socks latest in fashionRoadmaps start including more useful utilities like staking, DAO, merchandise, airdropsBig brands cautiously start joining the NFT testing polygonAI-generated art creeps into NFTs being the next cool thing for a short period of timeHigh quality 3D models take over the NFT space to oppose the simplistic, often 8-bit, PFPsMetaverse hype starts Decentraland, Sandbox, Facebook renamed to Meta. Metaverse ideologists point fingers at the movie Ready Player One screaming in unison ‘this!’Celebrities enter the scene: Akon, Bieber, Steve Aoki, Snoop Dogg, Lana Rhodes (yeah, that one) and others. Many celebrities launch their own NFT projects, many rug pull (Logan Paul — multiple proven rug pulls, Soulja Boy scamming 3 NFT projects in one week, etc.)Real world businesses start experimenting with the NFT format: tickets, rentals, customer loyalty cards, etc. NFTs implicitly start to take some of the functionality of QR codesQuality of production ramps up — projects now compete with content like videos, articles, P2E games, IP rights that extend to real businessesThe rise of ETH alternatives and VC funds invest into P2Es (remember StepN?). NFTs are now for solemn folks tooFree-mint degen art as a form of defiance and social message (started with Goblin Town) becomes too successful, spurs into a separate subculture. Many Twitter profiles change from ‘NFT collector and crypto investor’ to ‘NFT degen’Bear market starts…NFT projects rug — is the NFT culture dead?And the last point brings us full circle to the very beginning of the article. So, is the NFT industry dying? There are many arguments, numerous quality articles (like Financial side of NFTs Pt.3) and an overwhelming amount of ‘ifs and buts’ to consider. However, given the actual technological usability of NFTs, as well as the global market cap, it is very unlikely to see them disappear. This is not to mention that the obvious decline in the NFT space is in direct correlation with the ongoing crypto winter.Moreover, some of us who have been in the crypto space long enough, have already spotted the black cat of the Matrix glitches, the Déjà vu, if you wish. In 2017 we had something similar in nature to the contemporary phenomenon of NFTs, that thing was ICOs. Initial Coin Offerings at the time were just emerging, it was a new way for companies to raise capital like in an IPO, but without the need for “lawyers, bankers or regulatory approval and were more akin to Kickstarter-style crowdfunding, except funds were raised in cryptocurrency”. By the year 2019 the ICO craze was over, billions of dollars were raised during the two-year period, needless to say that the majority of it was never to be seen again. It simply sunk into the pockets of devious creators, who have put up a show of serious intentions to attract the profit-seeking investors. In 2018 alone, more than $14 billion were raised in ICOs with less than 8% of companies existing after 6 months of their respective ICO. Back then, ICOs were a new thing, completely unregulated and only requiring a website and a fancy roadmap to get some traction. Slap some marketing on top, sprinkle with a few conference attendances and you got yourself a solid pouch full of gold. Of course, the 2018 crypto winter contributed to the inevitable demise and subsequent regulatory frameworks for ICOs, but that is beside the point. What is important is the path that NFTs as an industry is likely to take. NFTs are already being scrutinized by the SEC, the recently passed Markets in Crypto Assets (MiCA) policy of the EU mentions them without regulatory restrictions so far, and surely more attention will come from regulatory bodies in the next few years. Perhaps, some regulation could prove to be advantageous, as to avoid various scams and deliberate rug pulls that ultimately shed negativity on the entire ecosystem. But I digress.Credit: The Gentlemen (you need to watch it if you haven’t)From the current standpoint many NFT projects will die, it is law of the jungle, nothing personal. Just like any business or any content creation process, the cut-throat competition will effectively determine the survivors. The standards will inevitably be elevated further, making the entrance harder for the newcomers. Innovation and complexity will be synonymous to the NFT industry. Regulation will be around too, whether we want it or not. And with all of that the infrastructure will be built in parallel.When researching, we came across an elegantly formulated sublimate of this, here:Credit: jakegallen @ TwitterWhile crypto tribalism is still persistent, the ever-growing accessibility of various bridges and integrations will likely to bring blockchain technologies to our regular lives sooner or later. The true adoption would mean having an app in your phone run on blockchain without you ever noticing it, a Netflix subscription via an NFT and Netflix itself running on Theta DRM technology, etc. And all of that will inject itself seamlessly much sooner than we might expect.To be continued…soonFollow us on Twitter and Discord for updates!</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
