<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Pure JSON Bridge</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://example.com"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=PureJsonBridge&amp;context=Main&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fpaychant.com%2Fapi%2Fblog%2Fapi%2Fposts%3Fpagination%5Bpage%5D%3D1%26pagination%5BpageSize%5D%3D7%26filters%5Bcategories%5D%5Bname%5D%5B%24contains%5D%3D%26filters%5Btitle%5D%5B%24contains%5D%3D%26sort%5B0%5D%3Ddate%253Adesc%26populate%3Ddeep%252C2&amp;items_path=data&amp;article_field=attributes.slug&amp;title_field=attributes.title&amp;prefix=https%3A%2F%2Fpaychant.com%2Fblog%2F&amp;author_field=&amp;pubdate_field=attributes.publishedAt&amp;date_format=&amp;content_field=attributes.sections&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://example.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://example.com/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=PureJsonBridge&amp;context=Main&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fpaychant.com%2Fapi%2Fblog%2Fapi%2Fposts%3Fpagination%5Bpage%5D%3D1%26pagination%5BpageSize%5D%3D7%26filters%5Bcategories%5D%5Bname%5D%5B%24contains%5D%3D%26filters%5Btitle%5D%5B%24contains%5D%3D%26sort%5B0%5D%3Ddate%253Adesc%26populate%3Ddeep%252C2&amp;items_path=data&amp;article_field=attributes.slug&amp;title_field=attributes.title&amp;prefix=https%3A%2F%2Fpaychant.com%2Fblog%2F&amp;author_field=&amp;pubdate_field=attributes.publishedAt&amp;date_format=&amp;content_field=attributes.sections&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:08:31+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Stablecoins: Providing USD Liquidity for Businesses in Africa</title>
    <published>2025-03-05T08:07:17+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-05T08:07:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://paychant.com/blog/stablecoins-providing-usd-liquidity-for-businesses-in-africa</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://paychant.com/blog/stablecoins-providing-usd-liquidity-for-businesses-in-africa"/>
    <content type="html">[{"id":120,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"# Stablecoins: Providing USD Liquidity for Businesses in Africa\n\nAccess to U.S. dollars is a critical challenge for businesses across Africa. With over 70% of African currencies experiencing significant depreciation, many companies struggle to secure stable and reliable liquidity for international trade, procurement, and operational expenses. Traditional banking channels often impose restrictions on dollar access, leading to delays, high forex fees, and unfavorable exchange rates.\n\nStablecoins\u2014digital currencies pegged to the U.S. dollar\u2014are emerging as a game-changing solution. By offering instant, borderless access to USD liquidity, stablecoins enable African businesses to bypass banking limitations, transact seamlessly, and protect their capital from currency volatility.","component":"rich-text"},{"id":121,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"## The Role of Stablecoins in Business Transactions\n\nFor importers, exporters, and service providers, stablecoins provide a frictionless way to settle invoices, pay suppliers, and receive payments from international clients without the inefficiencies of traditional finance. Unlike wire transfers, which can take days and incur high fees, stablecoin transactions settle instantly at a fraction of the cost. Additionally, businesses leveraging stablecoins avoid reliance on unstable local banking systems, ensuring they can hold value in a currency that retains purchasing power. This is especially crucial for companies operating in regions where local currencies fluctuate unpredictably, disrupting financial planning and trade.","component":"rich-text"},{"id":122,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"## How Paychant is Unlocking USD Liquidity for African Businesses\n\nAt Paychant, we are making stablecoin-powered USD liquidity more accessible to businesses across Africa. Our platform provides seamless on- and off-ramp solutions, allowing businesses to convert stablecoins like USDT and USDC into local currencies via mobile money and bank transfers. This ensures companies can easily integrate stablecoins into their operations without technical complexities.\n\nBy bridging the gap between stablecoins and local payment systems, Paychant is enabling African businesses to access digital dollars effortlessly, facilitating faster payments, reducing costs, and promoting economic stability. As stablecoins continue to gain traction, they are poised to become a vital tool for African enterprises seeking reliable, efficient, and inflation-resistant financial solutions.","component":"rich-text"}]</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How Stablecoins Unlock Africa’s Economic Efficiency</title>
    <published>2025-03-04T11:04:07+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-04T11:04:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://paychant.com/blog/how-stablecoins-unlock-africa-economic-efficiency</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://paychant.com/blog/how-stablecoins-unlock-africa-economic-efficiency"/>
    <content type="html">[{"id":115,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"# How Stablecoins Unlock Africa\u2019s Economic Efficiency\n\n2025 marks the 11th year anniversary of stablecoins, digital currencies that combine the speed, accessibility, and transparency of blockchain with the stability of major fiat currencies. In Africa, where financial inefficiencies and currency volatility are major challenges, stablecoins have emerged as a game-changer. They provide a seamless way to transact across borders, hedge against inflation, and access digital dollars without relying on traditional banking systems.\n\n\nOver the past decade, stablecoins have seen exponential growth, reaching a market cap of $205 billion and facilitating trillions in transactions annually. While they serve different purposes globally\u2014from acting as a digital version of cash to powering financial markets\u2014their impact in Africa is particularly profound. In many countries, where local currencies face constant devaluation, stablecoins offer a more reliable store of value and a frictionless medium for payments.\n\n\nFor businesses, stablecoins enable instant global transactions at lower costs, bypassing slow, expensive, and outdated financial rails. Traditional cross-border payments in Africa often require multiple intermediaries, adding unnecessary fees and delays. For example, a merchant in Kenya receiving payments from a supplier in Ghana may have to navigate several banks and currency exchanges, incurring high costs. Stablecoins eliminate these barriers, enabling direct, near-instant, and cost-effective transactions.","component":"rich-text"},{"id":116,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"\n## How Paychant is Powering Africa\u2019s Stablecoin Revolution\n\nAt Paychant, we are bridging the gap between stablecoins and Africa\u2019s local economies by providing an easy, accessible on- and off-ramp for digital dollars. By integrating mobile money and local payment methods, we empower businesses and individuals to convert between stablecoins like USDT and USDC and their local currencies seamlessly. Our solution supports cross-border remittances, payroll payments, and inflation-resistant savings, making financial transactions more efficient and inclusive.\n\nWith over 277 mobile payment methods across Africa and a low bank card penetration rate, Paychant is solving the region\u2019s biggest payment challenges by leveraging the power of stablecoins. By reducing reliance on costly and inefficient traditional systems, we are helping unlock Africa\u2019s economic potential, making financial services more accessible for millions.","component":"rich-text"}]</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Stablecoins are discovering a strong market demand in Africa</title>
    <published>2025-03-04T11:12:16+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-04T11:12:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://paychant.com/blog/stablecoins-are-discovering-a-strong-market-demand-in-africa</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://paychant.com/blog/stablecoins-are-discovering-a-strong-market-demand-in-africa"/>
    <content type="html">[{"id":117,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"# Stablecoins are discovering a strong market demand in Africa.\n\nUnlike speculative crypto assets, stablecoins\u2014digital currencies pegged to fiat like the US dollar\u2014offer real utility, solving fundamental financial challenges such as currency volatility, expensive remittances, and inefficient cross-border payments.","component":"rich-text"},{"id":118,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"## Why Stablecoins Matter in Africa\n\nAfrica\u2019s financial landscape is unique, characterized by high inflation, fragmented banking systems, and a reliance on mobile money. Many local currencies have experienced sharp devaluation, making it difficult for individuals and businesses to store wealth and transact effectively. Stablecoins provide a reliable alternative by offering access to digital dollars, protecting purchasing power, and enabling seamless global transactions.\n\nAdditionally, cross-border payments in Africa remain slow and costly, with fees on international remittances averaging 8%\u2014the highest in the world. Traditional banking infrastructure is often outdated and reliant on intermediaries, causing delays and inefficiencies. Stablecoins eliminate these barriers, enabling instant, low-cost transfers across borders.","component":"rich-text"},{"id":119,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"## Paychant: Driving Stablecoin Adoption in Africa\n\nAt Paychant, we are accelerating the adoption of stablecoins by integrating them into Africa\u2019s financial ecosystem. Our platform provides seamless on- and off-ramps for USDT, USDC, and other stablecoins, allowing users to convert digital assets into local currencies via mobile money and bank transfers. This makes it easier for businesses, freelancers, and everyday users to transact, save, and hedge against inflation.\n\nBy supporting local payment methods and reducing reliance on expensive financial intermediaries, Paychant is helping stablecoins achieve product-market fit in Africa. With growing adoption, stablecoins are set to play a critical role in improving financial inclusion, driving economic efficiency, and empowering millions across the continent.","component":"rich-text"}]</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Paychant focuses on Stablecoins Amid Surging Demand in Africa</title>
    <published>2024-10-07T21:00:45+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-07T21:00:45+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://paychant.com/blog/paychant-focuses-on-stablecoins-amid-surging-demand-in-africa</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://paychant.com/blog/paychant-focuses-on-stablecoins-amid-surging-demand-in-africa"/>
    <content type="html">[{"id":110,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"Stablecoins like USDC and USDT are solving real-world challenges in money transfers, far beyond the speculative nature associated with other cryptocurrencies. Since the inception of crypto, much of the conversation has centered on price speculation and market surges. As a result, we initially broadened our services to speculative crypto assets. However, this year\u2019s user transaction data has presented a clear shift. In 2024 alone, stablecoins accounted for approximately 98% of our total transaction volume. This rapid uptake highlights the need to realign our focus towards stablecoins offerings, which are proving to be a driving force in reshaping Africa's payment landscape.\n\nIn recognition of this shift, we have redesigned our website to emphasize our commitment to stablecoin solutions across Africa.\n\n![paychant_website_blog.png](https:\/\/res.cloudinary.com\/paychant\/image\/upload\/v1728334477\/strapi\/paychant_website_blog_24ecf73f19.png)","component":"rich-text"},{"id":111,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"The rise of stablecoins is revolutionizing cross-border and domestic transactions in Africa. Most of our users leverage stablecoins for faster, more cost-efficient payments, particularly in regions where traditional banking infrastructure remains limited and unreliable. Stablecoins have emerged as a solution to the inefficiencies of conventional payment methods. Our platform empowers users to access USDC and USDT, seamlessly converting them between local fiat currencies. With these tools, stablecoins have proven to be a success in facilitating payments across Africa. Our data shows a steady increase in stablecoin transactions, further solidifying their relevance.\n\nStablecoins are evolving into a global settlement infrastructure, increasingly integrated with the traditional financial system. In Africa, they are becoming the new digital equivalent of the Dollar and Euro. Paychant\u2019s platform enables businesses to incorporate stablecoins into their payment and settlement workflows, bridging the gap between fiat currencies and stablecoins.","component":"rich-text"},{"id":112,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"**Conclusion:**\n\nStablecoins are more than just a medium for digital dollars\u2014they are also a financial tool for hedging against inflation and currency fluctuations. At Paychant, we see the greatest adoption of stablecoins in cross-border payments and settlements, particularly where Africa's banking infrastructure is most inadequate. Our core focus is now on stablecoins, enabling individuals and businesses across Africa to transition between fiat and digital currencies seamlessly. By harnessing the power of stablecoins, we are building the future of payments in Africa.","component":"rich-text"}]</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Paychant integrates the Stellar Anchor Platform (SEP-24)</title>
    <published>2024-07-31T12:48:49+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-31T12:48:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://paychant.com/blog/paychant-integrates-the-stellar-anchor-platform-sep-24</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://paychant.com/blog/paychant-integrates-the-stellar-anchor-platform-sep-24"/>
    <content type="html">[{"id":109,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"Paychant is pleased to announce its integration of the Stellar Anchor Platform via the SEP-24 protocol, enabling access to the network\u2019s \u201cHosted Deposit &amp; Withdrawal\u201d standard. This strategic move allows Paychant to seamlessly support Stellar wallets with a broad range of local payment options across Africa for fiat on- and off-ramping. As a result, wallets and applications built on the Stellar network can now leverage Paychant to facilitate the on- and off-ramping of USDC and XLM.\n\nThe SEP-24 protocol offers an out-of-the-box solution that simplifies the integration process, providing wallets and applications with access to multiple payment rails for deposits and withdrawals. With SEP-24, Paychant\u2019s on- and off-ramp services are accessible to all wallets within the Stellar ecosystem, ensuring a more inclusive payment infrastructure and delivering a seamless user experience for onboarding and off-boarding on the Stellar blockchain.\n\nThis integration marks a significant milestone in Paychant\u2019s mission to drive economic innovation in Africa. By embedding Paychant\u2019s on\/off-ramp widget natively within any Stellar wallet, African users can easily convert local currency into USDC using their preferred payment methods. This capability empowers users with greater control over their financial assets, providing protection against economic volatility.\n\nThrough this SEP-24 integration, Paychant connects all wallets and applications on the Stellar network to Africa's traditional fiat rails in Nigeria, Ghana, Kenya, and Uganda. This enables a seamless in-app experience for Stellar USDC on- and off-ramping, simplifying the exchange between fiat and crypto assets via local bank transfers, USSD, and mobile money.\n","component":"rich-text"}]</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Paychant's 2023 Year in Review</title>
    <published>2023-12-30T11:54:11+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-30T11:54:11+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://paychant.com/blog/paychant-2023-year-in-review</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://paychant.com/blog/paychant-2023-year-in-review"/>
    <content type="html">[{"id":101,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"Unlike preceding years, 2023 was a tough year in the web3 ecosystem. Despite these hurdles, there were moments of triumph for us, as we remained resilient, driven by our belief in the web3 ecosystem in Africa. Paychant remained firm in navigating the market with innovative solutions that will improve the overall financial ecosystem in Africa.\n\n2023 was monumental for our development, a year marked by pioneering the first truly Africa's localized fiat on and off-ramp service, making a significant breakthrough for mass users in Africa to seamlessly cash in and cash out digital assets in local fiat currency via Mobile money wallet and bank transfer particularly in Nigeria, Ghana, Kenya, and Uganda.\n\nWe're excited about innovative updates, expansions, and partnerships that are ahead of us in 2024.","component":"rich-text"},{"id":100,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"##  Setting the Standard for Local Fiat on and off-ramp in Africa\n2023 marks a noteworthy milestone for Paychant, as we launched the industry's first and only truly Africa's localized fiat on and off-ramp payment infrastructure that is easily embeddable for all digital wallets and dApps. Covering **4 countries and currencies in Africa (NGN, GHS, KES, and UGX)** with support for **40+ digital assets**, our fiat on and off-ramp became a game-changer for seamless crypto-to-fiat conversions in the Africa web3 ecosystem.\n\nOur commitment to our diverse customer base, spanning across various regions and age groups, underscores the widespread adoption and inclusivity of our platform. We leveraged our unparalleled understanding of Afrca's crypto ecosystem to provide the best UX ensuring every user enjoys **instant mobile money and bank cash in \/ cash out in Africa**. ","component":"rich-text"},{"id":103,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"## Partnership success that catalyzes our 2023 growth\n\nOur trusted and reliable solution distinguishes us as the preferred local fiat on and off-ramp choice for our major partners that have entered the African market, such as;\n\n- [Opera MiniPay](https:\/\/www.opera.com\/products\/minipay) - Opera MiniPay is a stablecoin wallet built on the Celo Blockchain, MiniPay enables users to cheaply save, send, and receive money instantly in Africa.\n- [Cenoa wallet](https:\/\/www.cenoa.com\/) - A $7M Seed-backed DeFi wallet that improves access to dollar-based products for people hit by inflation in emerging markets.\n- [Hurupay](https:\/\/www.hurupay.com\/) - A self-custodial wallet that enables Africans to send and receive payment internationally.\n- [Flooz](https:\/\/flooz.xyz\/) - A DeFi wallet to buy, trade, send, and manage any crypto assets and NFTs.","component":"rich-text"},{"id":106,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"## 2023 - Our year of valued partnership with Opera\n\n![paychantxminipay-min.png](https:\/\/res.cloudinary.com\/paychant\/image\/upload\/v1703930746\/strapi\/paychantxminipay_min_a0a97107ec.png)\n\nThis year, we partnered with **Opera**, who chose us as their **leading fiat on and off-ramp provider in Africa**. This partnership enabled the 150 million users of** Opera MiniPay** to cash in and cash out their Stablecoin Celo Dollar (cUSD) effortlessly into fiat via mobile money and bank transfer in Nigeria, Kenya, Ghana, and Uganda. Our partnership with Opera signifies our capability to provide fast and secure financial services, which further solidifies our position as a leader in the local fiat on and off-ramp market in Africa.\n\nAs we bring 2023 to a close, reflecting on what a year it has been, it has been a year filled with significant innovation, growth, and progress in our entire journey. We are grateful to every partner who supported us in 2023 to make it such an incredible year. Thank you for being a part of our journey this year.\n\nMay the upcoming year, 2024, be another exciting chapter for Paychant!","component":"rich-text"}]</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Paychant, making fiat to crypto transactions simple and secure</title>
    <published>2023-11-07T10:19:12+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-11-07T10:19:12+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://paychant.com/blog/paychant-making-fiat-to-crypto-transactions-simple-and-secure</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://paychant.com/blog/paychant-making-fiat-to-crypto-transactions-simple-and-secure"/>
    <content type="html">[{"id":98,"__component":"dynamic.rich-text","rich_text":"# Paychant, making fiat to crypto transactions simple and secure.\nBuying and selling crypto should be easy, simple and secure. This is what we are doing at Paychant.\nPaychant is a bridge connecting African traditional finance to the web3 world. Born and made in Africa, Paychant is revolutionalizing the crypto to fiat experience for African by embedding African local payment methods within the withdraw and purchase process. Imagine a platform that allows you to buy and sell crypto in just a few clicks. On Paychant buy and sell transactions involve 4 simple steps. Forget about the usual crowded interfaces, Paychant interface is well thought of, making it easy for first time and experienced crypto traders to buy and sell crypto with no huddles. \nPaychant onboarding process is seamless. Verify your mobile number\/email address and identity by uploading your identity document to start transacting.\nPaychant is embracing decentralised finance and self custody. By allowing you to buy to and sell from your non custodial crypto wallet and fiat wallet we are making sure you are in full control of your funds and ensure transaction security. \n\nPaychant is integrated on Cenoa wallet, Hurupay app and MiniPay wallet. These integrations allow Africans to buy and sell crypto assets using Paychant in just a few click with out leaving the apps.\nAre you looking for a convinient way to move fia to crypto or the opposite, [Paychant](https:\/\/paychant.com\/buy-crypto) is the way to go.\n","component":"rich-text"}]</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
