<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Raum Network | RaumFi DEX | Chrysalis | RaumStore on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@raumnetwork?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fraumnetwork.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*w1tdoaV3XBo0QLbco7IKmA.jpeg</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*w1tdoaV3XBo0QLbco7IKmA.jpeg</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fraumnetwork.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:09:17+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Enhancing User Experience: Latest Updates on RaumFi DEX and RN Bridge Optimization</title>
    <published>2023-08-27T22:06:13+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-08-27T22:06:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://raumnetwork.medium.com/enhancing-user-experience-latest-updates-on-raumfi-dex-and-rn-bridge-optimization-8688c7224317?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://raumnetwork.medium.com/enhancing-user-experience-latest-updates-on-raumfi-dex-and-rn-bridge-optimization-8688c7224317?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raum Network | RaumFi DEX | Chrysalis | RaumStore</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Introduction:In the ever-evolving landscape of decentralized finance (DeFi), Raum Network continues to strive for excellence by implementing innovative solutions that benefit our community of users. From optimizing transaction fees on RaumFi DEX to drastically reducing transaction times on RN Bridge, our commitment to providing efficient and user-friendly solutions remains unwavering. In this article, we delve into the recent updates and improvements that have been rolled out in the past month, highlighting the significant strides we’ve made to enhance your experience within the Raum Network ecosystem.1/ Fee Optimization on RaumFi DEX:One of our top priorities has always been to provide a seamless trading experience on RaumFi DEX. We’ve successfully implemented fee optimizations, ensuring that users can enjoy lower transaction costs while trading their favorite tokens. Our fee structure has been revamped to reward high-volume traders, allowing them to benefit from reduced fees based on their trading tier. This enhancement not only incentivizes active participation but also contributes to a more balanced and equitable trading environment. And yes, access to RaumFi DEX is provided to OG patrons but we are process to integrate more patrons as well in next quarter!!2/ Tier Benefits for Traders:Recognizing the importance of creating an inclusive and rewarding trading ecosystem, we’ve introduced tier benefits for traders on RaumFi DEX. With these benefits, users can expect enhanced perks as they progress through different trading tiers. These benefits encompass reduced fees, exclusive access to new token listings, priority participation in airdrops, and personalized support. By aligning rewards with trading activity, we aim to empower traders to optimize their trading experience and achieve their financial goals.3/ RN Bridge Optimization &amp;amp; RNIP 2 Implementation:A significant breakthrough that has garnered attention in recent weeks is the remarkable optimization of RN Bridge, our solution for seamlessly transferring RN tokens between the Polygon and StarkNet blockchains. Leveraging the advancements in StarkNet v.0.12.1, we’ve managed to slash the transaction time from approximately 30 minutes to less than 5 minutes. This achievement is a testament to our relentless pursuit of technical excellence and our dedication to providing efficient and rapid solutions for our users. Along with that, RNIP 2 has also been implemented after a DAO vote and patrons have till 15th of November 2023 to migrate their RN tokens to Starknet. Any RN tokens left on polygon network after mentioned timestamp will be deemed lost.4/ Looking Ahead:As we continue to refine and expand our suite of products, these recent updates are just a glimpse of what’s to come within the Raum Network ecosystem. Our mission remains centered on offering innovative solutions that contribute to the growth of decentralized finance and provide exceptional value to our community.5/ Conclusion:At Raum Network, we’re committed to driving positive change within the DeFi space by consistently enhancing our products and services. From optimizing fees and introducing tier benefits on RaumFi DEX to dramatically improving transaction times on RN Bridge, our recent updates reflect our dedication to creating a user-centric environment. As we move forward, we invite you to join us on this exciting journey, where innovation meets accessibility, and where the possibilities of decentralized finance continue to unfold.Stay tuned for more updates, as we’re eager to share the next wave of advancements that will shape the future of Raum Network.To learn more about our latest updates and join our community, visit raum.network[Connect with us on Twitter]</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Seamlessly Bridging RN Tokens from Polygon to Starknet: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
    <published>2023-06-11T18:45:14+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-11T18:45:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://raumnetwork.medium.com/seamlessly-bridging-rn-tokens-from-polygon-to-starknet-a-step-by-step-guide-86dc661aceec?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://raumnetwork.medium.com/seamlessly-bridging-rn-tokens-from-polygon-to-starknet-a-step-by-step-guide-86dc661aceec?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raum Network | RaumFi DEX | Chrysalis | RaumStore</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Introduction:As the blockchain ecosystem continues to evolve, the need for interoperability between different networks becomes increasingly vital. Raum Network recognizes this need and has developed a revolutionary solution to bridge RN tokens from Polygon to Starknet. This bridge enables users to seamlessly transfer their RN tokens between these two powerful blockchain platforms, unlocking new opportunities and expanding the reach of their investments. In this blog post, we will provide you with a step-by-step guide on how to bridge your RN tokens, ensuring a smooth and secure transition.Step 1: Prepare your WalletsBefore initiating the token bridge process, ensure that you have two wallets set up — one on the Polygon network and another on the Starknet network. Also add Raum Network Token Contract on StarkNet wallet i.e. 0x054f20994579087ecae673f3904d7ffd433707ddd6c658743901b1805cc62929a) As an example, we have taken Argent Wallet here. You can use Braavos Wallet as well. The procedure for adding RN Token contract is same.b) Add the RN Token contract address provided above.c) Verify again the contract address and RN token details. Then click on continue.You can also verify on StrakScan as well.Make sure to have sufficient MATIC in your Polygon wallet to cover the transaction fees. We would suggest to have at least 5.5 MATIC for seamless transaction experience.Step 2: Connect to the Raum Network Bridge InterfaceVisit the official Raum Network bridge website i.e. https://v1.bridge.raum.network/swap Connect your Polygon wallet to the bridge interface by clicking on the “Connect Wallet” button and selecting the Polygon network.Step 3: Enter StarkNet Wallet Address and AmountEnter the StarkNet Wallet in section one &amp;amp; amount of RN tokens you wish to bridge from Polygon to Starknet. Take note of any minimum or maximum transfer limits specified by the bridge.Step 4: Confirm the TransferReview the transaction details, including the amount of RN tokens, the destination network (Starknet), and the associated fees. Ensure that all information is accurate before proceeding.Step 5: Approve the TransferAuthorize the transaction by clicking on the “Approve” button. This step may require you to sign the transaction using your Polygon wallet. Confirm the transaction details once again and proceed with the approval.Step 6: Wait for ConfirmationOnce the transaction is approved, the bridge will initiate the transfer process. Wait for the confirmation on the Polygon network, indicating that the tokens have been successfully locked and burned on Polygon.Step 7: Monitor the ProgressMonitor the bridge interface or check your transaction history on PolygonScan to track the progress of your token transfer. This step ensures transparency and allows you to stay informed about the status of your tokens.Step 8: Receive Tokens on StarknetAfter the tokens have been successfully transferred to Starknet, they will become available in your Starknet wallet. You can view your updated token balance and utilize them within the Starknet ecosystem.Conclusion:Bridging RN tokens from Polygon to Starknet opens up a world of possibilities for Raum Network users. With the step-by-step guide provided in this blog post, you can seamlessly transfer your RN tokens, unlocking the potential of both networks and enjoying the benefits they offer. Embrace the power of interoperability and expand your investment horizons with Raum Network’s groundbreaking token bridge.Please note that the token bridge process and associated fees may be subject to change. Stay updated with the latest information and instructions provided by Raum Network to ensure a smooth token bridging experience.Plus if you need any additional assistance regarding trxn support or any other aspect do ping us on our Discord channel or email us at “support@raum.network” and we will help you out✌️.Start your journey towards cross-chain compatibility today and embrace the future of decentralized finance!Disclaimer: This blog post is intended for informational purposes only. Always exercise caution and do thorough research before participating in any token bridge or cryptocurrency-related activity.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Exploring RaumFi DEX: Revolutionizing Decentralized Trading on Starknet</title>
    <published>2023-06-08T06:01:44+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-08T06:01:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://raumnetwork.medium.com/raumfi-dex-introduction-454417d74a57?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://raumnetwork.medium.com/raumfi-dex-introduction-454417d74a57?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raum Network | RaumFi DEX | Chrysalis | RaumStore</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">IntroductionThe decentralized finance (DeFi) revolution has introduced a multitude of innovative platforms aiming to disrupt traditional financial systems.Among them, Raum Network’s RaumFi DEX has emerged as an exciting project that promises to transform the landscape of decentralized trading. Leveraging the power of Starknet, a Layer 2 scaling solution for Ethereum, RaumFi DEX is poised to provide an unparalleled trading experience while maintaining the security and decentralization that DeFi enthusiasts crave.In this article, we delve into the world of RaumFi DEX and explore its potential to reshape the decentralized trading ecosystem.1. The Rise of Raum NetworkBefore diving into RaumFi DEX, let’s take a moment to understand the underlying force behind this project. Raum Network, a forward-thinking blockchain platform, has been making waves in the industry with its vision to build a sustainable, scalable, and user-friendly decentralized storage and build ecosystem around it. With a focus on bridging the gap between Web 2.0 and Web 3.0, Raum Network aims to enable seamless interaction between traditional internet users and the decentralized world.2. Enter RaumFi DEXAt the core of Raum Network’s ecosystem lies RaumFi DEX, a decentralized exchange that promises to provide lightning-fast trades and near-zero fees. What sets RaumFi DEX apart from other decentralized exchanges is its integration with Starknet, a Layer 2 scaling solution developed by StarkWare. Starknet’s innovative technology allows for off-chain execution of transactions while maintaining the security and transparency of the Ethereum blockchain. This means users can enjoy the benefits of fast, cheap, and efficient trading without compromising on the decentralization that makes DeFi so powerful.3. Advantages of Starknet IntegrationBy building upon Starknet, RaumFi DEX tackles some of the major pain points of decentralized exchanges. Let’s explore some of the advantages this integration brings:a. Lightning-Fast Trades: Starknet’s Layer 2 solution enables RaumFi DEX to process trades with near-instantaneous speed. Gone are the days of slow transaction confirmations and network congestion, as RaumFi DEX leverages the power of off-chain computations to provide users with a seamless trading experience.b. Cost-Effective Trading: Ethereum’s scalability limitations often result in high gas fees, discouraging users from engaging in frequent trading activities. However, with Starknet’s Layer 2 solution, RaumFi DEX significantly reduces transaction costs, making it accessible to traders of all sizes. This opens up new possibilities for high-frequency trading and attracts a wider user base to the DeFi ecosystem.c. Enhanced Scalability: By offloading most of the computational work to the Starknet Layer 2 solution, RaumFi DEX can handle a higher throughput of transactions, eliminating bottlenecks and enabling the platform to scale effectively. This scalability is crucial for accommodating the growing demand for decentralized trading.4. A User-Friendly InterfaceWhile speed, cost-efficiency, and scalability are essential, a user-friendly interface is equally crucial for mass adoption. RaumFi DEX places a strong emphasis on creating an intuitive and seamless trading experience. The platform is designed to cater to both experienced traders and newcomers to DeFi, offering a simple yet powerful interface that empowers users to navigate the decentralized trading ecosystem effortlessly.5. Security and DecentralizationOne of the core tenets of DeFi is the trustless nature of transactions. RaumFi DEX recognizes the importance of security and decentralization and upholds these principles in its architecture. By integrating with Starknet, the platform leverages the underlying security of the Ethereum blockchain while enjoying the benefits of off-chain computation. Users can trade with confidence, knowing that their assets are protected by the robustness of the Ethereum network.6. The Road AheadRaum Network’s commitment to innovation and user-centric design positions RaumFi DEX as a game-changer in the DeFi space. The integration with Starknet paves the way for a decentralized exchange that combines the best of both worlds: scalability and security. With ongoing development and continuous improvement, RaumFi DEX aims to revolutionize decentralized trading and contribute to the widespread adoption of blockchain technology.ConclusionThe RaumFi DEX, built upon the Starknet Layer 2 solution, is set to transform the way we trade in the decentralized finance ecosystem. By providing lightning-fast trades, low fees, enhanced scalability, and a user-friendly interface, RaumFi DEX addresses the pain points of existing decentralized exchanges. With Raum Network’s commitment to innovation and the power of Starknet, RaumFi DEX has the potential to reshape the decentralized trading landscape, driving DeFi adoption to new heights. As we look to the future, the combination of Raum Network’s vision and the capabilities of Starknet sparks excitement for what lies ahead in the world of decentralized finance.Resources:Website: https://raum.networkTokenomics:https://ipfs.io/ipfs/bafybeidirfw2al7hknkzkumn6fqszramtr2h3e4ognfqim3bezqgpl7jwyWhitepaper:https://ipfs.io/ipfs/bafybeibgnzlq54mu6ydr5dbipacsfsapsbdriy4uponnpc67bq5qxd4ag4 Transparency Sheet: https://www.raum.network/transparency-sheetSocials:Twitter: https://twitter.com/RaumNetwork Guild: https://guild.xyz/raum-network Telegram Channel: https://guild.xyz/raum-network Discord: https://discord.com/invite/3TRy4pzzHn</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Unlocking Cross-Chain Potential: Raum Network’s RN Bridge Revolutionizes Token Bridging from…</title>
    <published>2023-06-07T21:35:49+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T21:35:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://raumnetwork.medium.com/raum-network-rn-bridge-309ab614e26?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://raumnetwork.medium.com/raum-network-rn-bridge-309ab614e26?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raum Network | RaumFi DEX | Chrysalis | RaumStore</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Unlocking Cross-Chain Potential: Raum Network’s RN Bridge Revolutionizes Token Bridging from Polygon to StarknetIntroductionAs the blockchain ecosystem continues to expand, interoperability between different networks has become a crucial aspect of decentralized finance (DeFi). Raum Network, an innovative blockchain platform, has introduced the RN Bridge, a groundbreaking solution that enables seamless token bridging from Polygon to Starknet.In this article, we explore the transformative capabilities of the RN Bridge and its potential to revolutionize cross-chain token transfers, enhancing accessibility and liquidity in the DeFi landscape.1. The Need for Cross-Chain Bridges:As blockchain networks proliferate, the ability to transfer assets and tokens across different chains becomes essential for fostering collaboration and expanding liquidity pools. Cross-chain bridges bridge the gap between disparate networks, allowing users to transfer assets from one chain to another, unlocking new opportunities for decentralized trading and investment. Raum Network’s RN Bridge addresses this need by offering a reliable and efficient solution for token bridging from Polygon to Starknet.2. The Power of Polygon and Starknet Integration:Polygon has gained significant traction as a Layer 2 scaling solution for Ethereum, offering fast and low-cost transactions. On the other hand, Starknet, developed by StarkWare, provides a Layer 2 solution with enhanced scalability and security. By integrating with both Polygon and Starknet, the RN Bridge combines the strengths of these platforms, enabling users to bridge RN tokens seamlessly between the two networks.3. Seamless Token Bridging with RN Bridge:The RN Bridge simplifies the process of transferring RN tokens from Polygon to Starknet and vice versa (currently users can only bridge their RN Tokens from Polygon to StrakNet). Users can initiate token transfers with a few simple steps, leveraging the RN Bridge’s intuitive interface. This frictionless experience enhances accessibility, allowing users to take advantage of opportunities across multiple chains while reducing the complexities associated with cross-chain transactions.4. Enhanced Accessibility and Liquidity:The RN Bridge significantly enhances accessibility and liquidity in the DeFi ecosystem. By bridging RN tokens between Polygon and Starknet, users can tap into the vibrant liquidity pools available on both networks. This unlocks opportunities for arbitrage, trading, and accessing a wider range of DeFi protocols, thereby expanding the possibilities for decentralized finance participants.5. Security and Trust:The RN Bridge prioritizes security and trust, ensuring the safety of users’ assets during the token bridging process. Raum Network follows rigorous security protocols and audits to mitigate potential risks and vulnerabilities. Users can have confidence in the integrity of their transactions, knowing that their tokens are protected throughout the bridging process.6. Paving the Way for Cross-Chain Innovation:The RN Bridge from Raum Network represents a significant step forward in cross-chain interoperability. By bridging RN tokens between Polygon and Starknet, Raum Network is actively contributing to the development of a robust and interconnected blockchain ecosystem. The RN Bridge opens the door to further innovation and collaboration between different networks, driving the evolution of decentralized finance and propelling the industry into new frontiers.ConclusionRaum Network’s RN Bridge serves as a game-changing solution, facilitating seamless token bridging from Polygon to Starknet. By integrating the strengths of both platforms, the RN Bridge empowers users to access liquidity and opportunities across multiple chains, enhancing the accessibility and potential of decentralized finance. As cross-chain interoperability continues to evolve, Raum Network’s RN Bridge stands at the forefront, unlocking new possibilities for DeFi participants and catalyzing innovation in the blockchain ecosystem.Resources:Website: https://raum.networkTokenomics:https://ipfs.io/ipfs/bafybeidirfw2al7hknkzkumn6fqszramtr2h3e4ognfqim3bezqgpl7jwyWhitepaper:https://ipfs.io/ipfs/bafybeibgnzlq54mu6ydr5dbipacsfsapsbdriy4uponnpc67bq5qxd4ag4Transparency Sheet: https://www.raum.network/transparency-sheetSocials:Twitter: https://twitter.com/RaumNetworkGuild: https://guild.xyz/raum-networkTelegram Channel: https://guild.xyz/raum-networkDiscord: https://discord.com/invite/3TRy4pzzHn</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Raum Network — Introduction To Decentralised Storage</title>
    <published>2022-04-10T19:38:59+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-10T19:38:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://raumnetwork.medium.com/raum-network-introduction-to-decentralised-storage-a563ab81b735?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://raumnetwork.medium.com/raum-network-introduction-to-decentralised-storage-a563ab81b735?source=rss-264cee13f06c------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Raum Network | RaumFi DEX | Chrysalis | RaumStore</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Raum Network — Introduction To Decentralized StoragePhoto by Shubham Dhage on UnsplashA Web3 based object storage solution for large enterprises as well as individual end-users.Unlike a centralized server operated by a single company or organisation, decentralized storage systems consist of a peer-to-peer network of user-operators who hold a portion of the overall data, creating a resilient file storage sharing system. Here the authors introduce Raum Network, a web3.0 based Object Storage Solution for large enterprise and individual end-users. The contract is completely stored in blockchain, thus making it auditable and transparent for the end-users. Decentralisation also reduces the dependency on the third party, decreasing the risk of failure.For the enterprise level, Raum Network provides the extreme functionality of assigning roles as per the hierarchy. The complete roles mapping is managed on the basis of public address (what we call, Digital Signature). This means every enterprise can manage the roles (For example, read-only access or read-write access) as per the requirements.Raum Network FeaturesWallet Connect Access — Raum Network will provide the user to login in the system from any provided list of wallets. This feature will work as a Single Sign off system to facilitate a faster and secure login for the users. The combination of public key and private key will be used as a digital signature to allow user login.Role-Based Access — Raum Network will provide extreme functionality only for the enterprise level to assign the roles as per the hierarchy. There can be one or multiple managers who can provide or revoke access from the people.Multiple Gateways for Storage Access — Raum Network will have multiple gateways. These will be divided into quorum (1 main node, 2 failover nodes) to access our storage so that even one node goes down next nearest available gateway node will always be available to access the storage without any downtime.Storage Tiers — We will provide storage so that it suffices every end-user use case. It will be divided into three storage classes (Standard Class, Cold Class, Archival Class). Where the user can decide which type of data they want to store in the storage class category.Raum Network SolutionObject Storage solution(S3) for large enterprise as well as Independent end user -Raum Network will be providing Object Storage Solutions better known as S3 Storage for both the Independent User or Large or Medium Scale Enterprises in terms of providing a significant better scalability,security and Cost management Solution.Different Tiers for different use cases ( Concurrent Addition, backup, Archival Storage) — Raum Network will be providing Different Tiers of Storage as per the needs of the Client.Currently we are working on providing Archival Storage,Concurrent Addition and backup Storage as per the end user require.Easily integrated with Web 2 as well as Web 3 infra — All the Services provided by Raum Network can easily be integrated with Web 2.0 as well as Web 3.0 providing Users with Control over their data ,Better connectivity,Ubiquity and many other features bundled with Web 3.0Main Admin can decide roles and manage data access points for sub users — Raum Network will be Providing Role Based Access Control (RBAC) where the Main Administrator can Provide one or multiple Access Roles as per the Requirement as well as provide and manage Different Data Access Point for the Sub Users for Easy Access to The Shared Data.Scalable Infrastructure (data nodes will increase/decrease in size &amp;amp; will be dynamic in nature) — Raum Network will be Built Upon an Scalable Infrastructure model so that it will always have the required Data Nodes as the Users Availability as well as the Data Nodes will be Dynamic in Nature i.e The Size of the Data Node can be Increased or Decreased as per the User Requirement.Data stored on the network can vary from 0 byte to 5 TiB at time — Raum Network Will be providing Data Storage on the Network Varying from 0 Bytes Upto 5 Tebibytes so that anyone can have their data stored without facing any storage issues.Multiple gateway’s implemented so that the end user will can access storage at lowest latency. — Raum Network will be implementing Connection through Multiple Gateway which in terms will be providing Better and Faster Connectivity throughout the Globe along with Less Chances of EavesDropping on a Particular Gateway.Follow us to stay updatedWebsite: https://www.raum.network/Twitter: https://twitter.com/RaumNetworkTelegram: https://t.me/RaumNetworkDiscord: https://discord.com/invite/6VVJukGfTn</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
