<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.ripe.money/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ripe.money%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fpost%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.section-blog+.container&amp;content_cleanup=.mins-read%2C.blog-sidebar%2C.section-blog-home&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ripe.money%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fpost%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.section-blog+.container&amp;content_cleanup=.mins-read%2C.blog-sidebar%2C.section-blog-home&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:09:29+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Ripe Money</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:09:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:09:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.ripe.money/post/applepay</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.ripe.money/post/applepay"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;div class="text-block-4 mb-1"&gt;Perspective&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 class="text-big-summary mb-2"&gt;Apple&amp;#x27;s NFC move excites crypto enthusiasts, but Ripe is delivering payments in Southeast Asia today&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph mb-5 max-730"&gt;While Apple&amp;#x27;s NFC announcement hints at an exciting future, Ripe delivers crypto payments today via even more prevalent financial rails, and no vendor adoption needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="w-layout-grid grid-6"&gt;&lt;div id="w-node-_795ada0f-6a50-4d5c-d72f-32bf60638338-b78a1a5e"&gt;&lt;div class="w-richtext"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;#x27;s recent announcement about opening up its Near Field Communication (NFC) technology to third-party developers has sent waves of excitement through the cryptocurrency community. Many see this as a potential game-changer for crypto adoption, envisioning a future where iPhone users can make tap-to-pay transactions using digital currencies like Bitcoin or stablecoins like USDC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this development is promising, it&amp;#x27;s some time away from reality. Vendors would need to accept cryptocurrencies directly, manage crypto treasuries, and navigate the complexities of converting digital assets to fiat currencies. These are significant hurdles that could slow down real-world implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;enter Ripe: a solution that&amp;#x27;s ready&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the crypto world eagerly anticipates the potential of Apple&amp;#x27;s NFC opening, there&amp;#x27;s a solution already making waves in Southeast Asia: Ripe. Remarkably similar to what crypto enthusiasts hope Apple&amp;#x27;s move will enable, but with several key advantages:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;immediate availability &lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the speculative future of NFC-enabled crypto payments on iPhones, Ripe is operational right now. It&amp;#x27;s a decentralized application (dApp) that can be used within existing crypto wallets—Phantom, Backpack, Metamask—making it immediately accessible to users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;no vendor adoption needed&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ripe&amp;#x27;s genius lies in its ability to work within existing payment infrastructures. It allows users to pay with cryptocurrencies wherever e-wallets like GrabPay, GCash, or Momo are accepted. This is particularly significant in Southeast Asia, where these e-wallets are far more prevalent than Apple Pay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;seamless off-ramping&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ripe handles the conversion of crypto to local currencies, eliminating a major pain point for vendors. This means businesses can start accepting crypto payments without changing their existing systems or dealing with the complexities of managing digital assets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;targeting a crypto-ready market&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Southeast Asia has one of the highest rates of crypto ownership globally. By focusing on this region, Ripe is tapping into a market that&amp;#x27;s already primed for crypto payment solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;platform agnostic&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike Apple&amp;#x27;s solution, which would be limited to iOS devices, Ripe works across various platforms and devices, making it more accessible to a broader user base.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;the promise of immediate impact&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Apple&amp;#x27;s NFC announcement hints at an exciting future, Ripe is delivering on the promise of crypto payments today. By bridging the gap between cryptocurrencies and widely-used e-wallet systems, Ripe is driving real-world adoption in a region where digital currencies are already gaining significant traction, particularly as a medium for remittance flows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This approach demonstrates that sometimes, the most effective solutions are those that work within existing frameworks rather than requiring wholesale changes to established systems. Ripe&amp;#x27;s ability to make crypto payments as simple as using an e-wallet, without requiring vendors to adapt their practices, positions it as a frontrunner in the race to mainstream crypto adoption.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;looking ahead&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we look to the future of cryptocurrency payments, it&amp;#x27;s clear that solutions like Ripe are paving the way. While developments like Apple&amp;#x27;s NFC opening are exciting and hold great potential, the impact of platforms that solve real-world problems today, and, by utilizing existent financial rails, preclude the need for vendor adoption, cannot be overstated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="w-node-aa439d3d-2f41-124a-c1f8-fc35b7655552-b78a1a5e" class="blog-read-holder"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Ripe Money</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:09:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:09:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.ripe.money/post/renaissance</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.ripe.money/post/renaissance"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;div class="text-block-4 mb-1"&gt;Perspective&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 class="text-big-summary mb-2"&gt;Ripe wins 4th place, DeFi/Payments in global Solana “Renaissance” hackathon&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph mb-5 max-730"&gt;It was an incredible experience to participate in the recent Colosseum Renaissance Hackathon, one of the world&amp;#x27;s largest blockchain hackathons sponsored by Solana.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="w-layout-grid grid-6"&gt;&lt;div id="w-node-_795ada0f-6a50-4d5c-d72f-32bf60638338-b78a1a5e"&gt;&lt;div class="w-richtext"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were over 8,000 participants, over 1,000 project submissions, and over 95 countries represented from around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ripe Wins 4th Place in the DeFi/Payments Track&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our startup, which enables the use of cryptocurrencies, particularly stablecoins, to send fiat currency to popular e-wallets like GrabPay and GCash, entered the DeFi/Payments track of the hackathon. After an intense few weeks of development and refining our presentation, we were honored to be selected as the 4th place winner in the category.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;In addition to to our win in the global DeFi category, Ripe also participated in both the Saros Super App and The Philippines-based side tracks, where it was a winner in both, and &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Most Innovative Project&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; in the Philippines.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Renaissance was an amazing opportunity to not only put our skills and ideas to the test on a big stage, but also to meet and connect with so many other talented developers and entrepreneurs in the ecosystem. The energy and innovation on display from all the participants was truly inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond just the competition itself, one of the biggest benefits was the chance to get introductions to various companies and organizations interested in partnering with us. As a young startup, these connections are invaluable as we continue to raise funding and scale our solution to bring everyday crypto payments to more users across Southeast Asia and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We came away from this experience with an even more heightened sense of motivation and validation for the real-world impact our service can have. Seeing the high quality of all the blockchain projects at the event really drove home how much potential there is in this space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you to Colosseum, the coordinators, for putting together such an incredible event. In the meantime, we&amp;#x27;ll be following up on the many great connections we made as we continue our mission to make digital payments more accessible and empowering through crypto rails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="w-node-aa439d3d-2f41-124a-c1f8-fc35b7655552-b78a1a5e" class="blog-read-holder"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Ripe Money</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:09:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:09:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.ripe.money/post/celo-camp</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.ripe.money/post/celo-camp"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;div class="text-block-4 mb-1"&gt;Perspective&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 class="text-big-summary mb-2"&gt;Ripe wins gold at Celo Camp Batch 7&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class="paragraph mb-5 max-730"&gt;The 30 participants of Celo Camp’s 7th cohort hailed from 20 different countries, representing regenerative finance (ReFi) and decentralized finance (DeFi) projects, impact-driven initiatives, payment solutions, technical infrastructures, and creator economies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="w-layout-grid grid-6"&gt;&lt;div id="w-node-_795ada0f-6a50-4d5c-d72f-32bf60638338-b78a1a5e"&gt;&lt;div class="w-richtext"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Celo Camp, the virtual acceleration and mentorship program created in partnership by the Celo Foundation and Upright in 2020, hosted startup founders on a shared journey to further Web3 innovation through intentional community building and guided educational experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to receiving fast-track access to Celo grants, prizes in cUSD are awarded to teams and projects to recognize their progress throughout camp, including their projects’ respective impact. Top prizes were decided by a voting process that included input from representatives of Upright, the Celo Foundation, Celo Camp mentors, and the broader Celo community. Congratulations to all!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ripe Wins the 1st Place Gold Prize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During Celo Camp, Ripe built an application that is able to scan QR codes from GCash — the leading e-wallet in the Philippines and accepted by over 139,000 merchants — and to use cUSD from Valora to send Philippine Pesos to the recipient.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;About his time at Celo Camp, Sam Silver, co-founder at Ripe, said:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;“Ours is a business reliant on connection and collaboration. Not only did we receive robust community support from the team at Celo Camp, we also met with smart and generous founders interested in partnering with us too. Through the Celo Camp mentorship program, we were connected with the Valora staff who provided amazing support and guidance throughout camp.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ripe continues to work closely with Celo product managers to integrate more natively with Valora, build out their backend transfer and exchange infrastructure, and raise a pre-seed round.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="w-node-aa439d3d-2f41-124a-c1f8-fc35b7655552-b78a1a5e" class="blog-read-holder"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
