<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Scalps on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@scalps.finance?source=rss-f48304c6c198------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40scalps.finance&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*ueZwbssZqwPwa77pSxRZHg.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*ueZwbssZqwPwa77pSxRZHg.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40scalps.finance&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:09:33+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How Scalps uses Soroban smart contracts to offer powerful branded Loyalty NFTs to merchants around…</title>
    <published>2023-08-01T09:06:42+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-08-01T09:06:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@scalps.finance/how-scalps-uses-soroban-smart-contracts-to-offer-powerful-branded-loyalty-nfts-to-merchants-around-818f5ad6bf82?source=rss-f48304c6c198------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@scalps.finance/how-scalps-uses-soroban-smart-contracts-to-offer-powerful-branded-loyalty-nfts-to-merchants-around-818f5ad6bf82?source=rss-f48304c6c198------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Scalps</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">How Scalps uses Soroban smart contracts to offer powerful branded Loyalty NFTs to merchants around the worldDisclaimer: The approaches to using Soroban smart contracts outlined in this post are experimental and do not represent best practices for the use of Stellar smart contracts. Functions and methods used may change, or be optimized during smart contract development by Scalps. Developers should do their own research on how to use Soroban in their own projects.Scalps is an online discovery engine, and blockchain payments platform, that allows consumers to discover crypto-friendly merchants around the world, subscribe to their loyalty programs, and take advantage of discounts, membership, event access, and branded collectibles.At its most basic level, the Scalps Loyalty Management System uses the POINTS token, an asset issued on the Stellar network, to apply discounts at point-of-sale to in-store purchases. POINTS are pegged to the US dollar, 1 POINT = $0.01, allowing them to be converted, and applied as discounts, to bills denominated in any currency. POINTS are traditional Stellar assets and do not need smart contracts to function, however smart contracts can be used to automate the POINTS distribution aspects of various loyaltycampaigns run on the Scalps platform.Scalps will use Soroban smart contracts to: 1. Automate claims of the POINTS Stellar asset. 2. Apply discounts to payments at participating merchants. 3. Mint and manage Loyalty NFTs with various features, such as discount cards, tiered membership, event access, and branded collectibles.How we use Soroban smart contracts?There are a number of Soroban SDKs available as listed here:https://soroban.stellar.org/docs/category/sdks Scalps aims to use the Soroban Rust SDK for distribution of POINTS discount tokens, as well as minting, verifying, and transferring Loyalty NFTs. POINTS-based discounts are the base level loyalty layer, while Scalps also offers merchants the option to mint 4 types of branded Loyalty NFTS, managed by smart contracts, for even more functionality and customer engagement.The Loyalty NFTs are:Discount NFTsVIP Membership NFTsEvent Access NFTsCollectible NFTs1. Discount NFTsScalps Discount NFTs operate like, and can be designed to resemble, a retail store discount card. Like in-store discount cards, the NFTs have a validity period and a fixed discount level that can be applied to in-store purchases. Conditions may apply and these will also be included in the NFT’s JSON file for easy reference by customers.Smart Contract FeaturesDiscount NFTs are distributed by merchants via campaigns set up on the Scalps platform. These NFT’s can be claimed by customers in the same way POINTS loyalty tokens are claimed, via the Scalps platform or in-store.a. Minting Discount NFTs:When a customer claims a Discount NFT via a merchant campaign on the Scalps platform, the NFT is minted using the mint function from the Soroban Rust SDK’s contract.rs module. Contract.rs is one of several available modules, that can be used as is, or modified for additional functionality.b. NFT JSON Data.In addition to standard token attributes stored in meta data, a JSON file describing the token is published to meta data or IPFS. In the latter case the IPFS hash is stored in contact meta data. Information in the JSON file includes the NFT Symbol, NFT Image, Start Date, End Date, Merchant Identifier, Campaign Identifier, Discount Percentage, Conditions, Status etc. Meta data strings are stored on-chain using the write_token_urifunction from metadata.rs. The decision to use meta data or IPFS will mostly be driven by cost of storing data on chain.c. Applying Discount NFTs.When the customer uses the NFT in-store, a QR code is generated, which is scanned by the merchant. The data in the QR code is then passed to an internal API which then accesses the smart contract to match the merchant and campaign, and check the validity of the Discount NFT and the applicable discount. Discount NFTs that have expired or are not issued by a specific merchant are rejected.2. Membership NFTsScalps Membership NFTs operate like tiered membership programs offering, for example, Platinum, Gold and Silver membership, or other tier structures configured by merchants. Like Discount NFTs, Membership NFTs also have a validity period, and the benefits and conditions are also embedded in the NFT’s JSON file.Smart Contract FeaturesMembership NFTs are distributed by merchants in-store. Merchants can mint Membership NFTs using contract.rs either by uploading a CSV of pre-existing physical membership card tiers and card numbers, or by creating Membership NFTs that act as virtual membership cards. In the latter case, membership card numbers will be generated automatically by the smart contract which will store the issued membership numbers in Persistent or Instance storage. Like Discount NFTs, additional Membership NFT info willbe stored in a JSON file written to meta data or uploaded to IPFS and the hash will be stored in the contract’s meta data.a. Minting Membership NFTs:Scalps will use the mint function in the contract.rs file to mint NFTs representing different tiers of the membership program. In the case where merchant uploads a CSV, a new function called upload_preapproved_membership_numbers will be used. The mintfunction will be modified to accept additional data, such as the tier level and the associated benefits for each Membership NFT. In most cases this data will be written to a JSON file which will be uploaded to IPFS with the hash stored in contract data storage.b. NFT JSON Data.Information in the JSON file includes the NFT Symbol, NFT Image, Start Date, End Date, Merchant Identifier, Campaign Identifier, Discount Percentage, Tier, Tier Benefits, Tier Conditions, Status etc. This data will be read by the smart contract to determine the validity of the NFT and provide the associated benefits to the customer. Meta data strings are stored on-chain using the write_token_uri function from metadata.rs. The decision touse meta data or IPFS will mostly be driven by cost of storing data on chain.c. Managing Tiers and Benefits:The metadata.rs file can be modified to include additional functions like read_tier and write_tier to store and retrieve tier information from the JSON file for each NFT. Similarly, functions like read_benefits and write_benefits will be added to manage and retrieve benefit descriptions for each tier.d. Distributing Membership NFTs:When a customer signs up for a physical membership card in-store or online, the merchant can initiate an action that mints a Membership NFT tied to the same membership card number directly to a customer’s Stellar wallet. Typically, in this scenario, the customer will present a QR code to the merchant, which is then scanned to start the minting process.3. Event Access NFTsScalps Event Access NFTs work like electronic tickets, granting holders access to different kinds of events. Event Access NFTs typically have short validity windows but can range from a few hours for a play/concert, a few days for a music festival, or even a season for season tickets to a football club. Again, conditions of use can be embedded in the NFT’s metadata.Smart Contract FeaturesEvent Access NFTs will typically be distributed/sold by merchants either in-store or online. Once the merchant has received payment for the NFT, merchant scans a QR code generated by the customer to mint the Event Access NFT to the customer’s wallet.a. Minting Event Access NFTs:Since Event Access NFTs have different validities and uses, like Discount NFTs, and Membership NFTs, additional NFT info will be stored in a JSON file uploaded to IPFS, and the hash will be stored in the contract’s meta data. Scalps will use the mint function in the contract.rs file to mint single or multiple use NFTs with different validity periods. The smart contract will keep track of validity, number of uses, and the status of the NFTwhich will be read from a JSON file uploaded to IPFS.b. NFT JSON Data.Information in the JSON file includes the NFT Symbol, NFT Image, Start Date, End Date, Start Time, End Time, Merchant Identifier, Campaign Identifier, Conditions, Status etc. This data will be read by the smart contract to determine the validity of the NFT and allow or reject access to the event. Meta data strings are stored on-chain using the write_token_uri function from metadata.rs. The decision to use meta data or IPFS willmostly be driven by cost of storing data on chain.c. Reading Event Access NFTsEvent Access NFTs can be checked by a person manning a gate using the Scalps wallet or by a machine that as integrated a specific event access API. Each NFT will generate a QR code, which will be scanned by the person or by access equipment. The smart contract will return values that determine whether to allow or reject access to the event.4. Branded CollectiblesScalps Branded Collectibles NFTs are unique branded NFTs in a series that consumers can collect just for their novelty value. They can be configured by merchants as standalone collectibles or part of a series that unlocks in-store benefits. Global NFT data is stored in meta data and NFT-specific information is stored in an IPFS JSON file and the logic that unlocks them is governed by the smart contract.Smart Contract Featuresa. Minting Branded Collectibles NFTs:Branded Collectibles NFTs will primarily be used for branding. As such they will be the most artistic and unique of the loyalty NFTs. Merchant’s can create a series of NFTs and run various campaigns for users to collect them. These NFTs generally will not have expiry dates. Like the other loyalty NFT types, additional info for these will be stored in a JSON file uploaded to IPFS, and the hash will be stored in the contract’s meta data.Scalps will use the mint function in the contract.rs file to mint these NFTs in advance, and merchants can create campaigns that determine how they are disbursed. The mint function in contract.rs will be modified to store different data for the different types of collectibles The smart contract will keep track of the series using Persistent or Instance storage and information read from a JSON file uploaded to IPFS.b. NFT JSON Data.Information in the JSON file includes the NFT Symbol, NFT Image, Merchant Identifier, Campaign Identifier, Collection Identifier, Series Number, etc. This data will be read by the smart contract to determine the status of collection and determine if any additional benefits should be unlocked. Meta data strings are stored on-chain using the write_token_uri function from metadata.rs. The decision to use meta data or IPFS willmostly be driven by cost of storing data on chain.c. Reading Branded Collectible NFTsGenerally, Branded Collectible NFTs are mostly a branding exercise and customers collect them mostly for their novelty. However, they can be designed to unlock a benefit when an entire series has been collected. In these scenarios, the merchant will scan a QR code displayed by the customer and the smart contract will determine if the entire series has been collected by reading collection state data and unlock the related benefit.Storage and FeesOne of the important considerations for any project using Soroban smart contracts is how to handle storage and how to design contracts that don’t incur prohibitive fees. Contract data has a lifetime meaning that it will expire at some point. While data lifetimes can be “bumped” or extended, it is important to choose the right type of storage. Soroban features three types of storage: Persistent, Temporary, and Instance. Persistent andInstance data can be restored after expiry but Temporary data is deleted permanently from the ledger upon expiry.In terms of fees, Temporary data incurs the cheapest fees while Persistent and Instance data incurs the most. Due to the fee implication and the data requirements of Scalps loyalty programs, we also add a fourth storage option which is data that is stored on the InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) for free that can persist outside the scope of any smart contract. So we have Temporary data suitable for transactional information such as price feeds, Instance data that persists only during the lifetime of the contract instance,Persistent data that can expire independently of the contract instance, and IPFS data that exists totally independently of the smart contract.As a general principle, we will store NFT-specific data in JSON files stored in IPFS as mentioned above. We will store contract specific data such as Membership NFT card numbers, tier information and other data that doesn’t change from merchant to merchant or campaign to campaign as Instance or Persistent data. And finally, transaction-related data such as exchange rates as Temporary data. Wherever fees turn out to be prohibitiveor impractical Scalps will consider using off-chain data such as JSON files stored on IPFS, and storing the hash of such data in contract meta data.In conclusion, Soroban smart contracts offer exciting new features that enable a broad variety of new use cases on Stellar. By offering a multi-faceted loyalty program on Stellar, powered by smart contracts, Scalps will empower merchants around the world with powerful new tools to attract new customers, keep existing ones, and grow their businesses. We look forward to sharing even more exciting use cases for Soroban as webuild out the Scalps merchant discovery and payments ecosystem.For additional information please refer to the Technical Specification document at https://github.com/scalpsco/soroban-nft-smart-contract-poc which lists the key modules that will be used in the Scalps loyalty system for authorization, minting, burning, transfers and data storage.https://github.com/scalpsco/soroban-nft-smart-contract-poc which lists the key modules that will be used in the Scalps loyalty system for authorization, minting, burning, transfers and data storage.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Bootstrapping without funding philosophy</title>
    <published>2022-12-09T11:27:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-12-09T11:27:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@scalps.finance/bootstrapping-without-funding-philosophy-96261e6024c2?source=rss-f48304c6c198------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@scalps.finance/bootstrapping-without-funding-philosophy-96261e6024c2?source=rss-f48304c6c198------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Scalps</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">https://scalps.financeThe Scalps core team is one of the unique teams within the blockchain, crypto and web3 industry. We aim to turn concept dreams to functional realities without the lure of available investment funding.Investment funding as well as accelerator programmes have clear advantages. Advantages include funding which helps to accelerate the growth of a company and mentorship to guide a founding team. In my opinion the long term drawbacks outweigh the short term benefits.For startup teams, the acquisition of traditional investment funding as well as funding via grants too early on within the bootstrapping cycle can be tricky for teams. It shifts their core philosophy to pivot their mission statements from the benefits of sharing and giving a “slice” or “scalp” with everyone, to one of greed and affluence.bootstrapping vs fundingDrawing parallels between accelerated growth vs slower growthWe see many examples of these within recent times. The astronomical rise of ecosystems within the industry such as Terra Luna, Celsius, FTX and others funded through questionable means. Driven by the greed and egos of their investors as well as tied into the macro economic factors of the world today.The opposite holds true for traditional slower growth eco systems such Cardano or Ethereum with a strong philosophy around decentralization and community growth and sharing.The views above are for demonstrative purposes based on a neutral observation of recent events and I do not hold any bias, prejudice or judgement around these organisations.Strategic team alignment around the Scalps philosophyThe core philosophy and mindset of Scalps team members is based around builders and sellers. If we look at this from a spiritual perspective, the drive and passion for builders to build should equally be matched by the drive and passion by sellers to sell. The environment we create is for active engagement and synergy between builders and sellers.core team cultureA strong core team with a balanced approach to building and acquiring funding through transparent means separates us from the rest of the teams within the industry. Slower organic growth with noble intentions outweighs fast growth with negative funding influences.At Scalps we share this philosophy with the users, businesses and partners who join us. The aim is to grow this organisation organically with the goal of building a truly decentralized community. A foundation is set for builders and sellers to operate without the noise and influence of external funders or investors whose pure drive is derived from a “making money” perspective. We see this method of operation in many regional, religious, ethnic, cultural, modern and even virtual communities who share economic prosperity via their networks.ConclusionThe current narrative around blockchain technology is somewhat skewed and aimed towards the current status quo which views “making money” as the “ultimate reward”. In truth blockchain offers far more than crypto, NFTs or DeFi, etc.When we look at networks both physically and spiritually, the internet should be free, web3 should be free, building should be free, reaping benefits should be free and the greatest of all shared amongst all.Through decentralization, we create enough market share and opportunities for all.Join us to share, spread and reap the benefits of our philosophy today.These views were expressed by Samir Franciscus on behalf of Scalps.Join Scalps | Business signup | User signup | Partner signupConnect with Scalps | LinkedIn | Twitter | Telegram | Facebook | Instagramhttps://www.scalps.finance</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Overview of a bear market</title>
    <published>2022-11-28T13:27:54+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-11-28T13:27:54+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@scalps.finance/overview-of-a-bear-market-b30bb0d9ef16?source=rss-f48304c6c198------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@scalps.finance/overview-of-a-bear-market-b30bb0d9ef16?source=rss-f48304c6c198------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Scalps</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">https://scalps.financeThe bear market has sunk its claws into the industry, but is it a long-term position? Big projects like Etherium, Polygon, Solana etc. have lost over 80% in their value. But we still hold onto hope and are planning for stabilization in the ecosystem. There are not many things we can control in times like this. However, there is something we can control: how we react and behave as builders in a bear market. It’s essential to continue building and innovating while prices come back while reframing how we view this bear market. Regardless of how bad the situation may seem we as builders have to see it as an opportunity that will contribute to stronger teams, projects and assets in the long run.Coming back to our project Scalps and what advantages we see during these tough times. There are a few things we can achieve as a team:Greater decentralisationToo much power or too much leverage in the hands of founders, investors or whales has been revealed as a weakness in troubled crypto markets. Now that most of the Ponzi schemes have been revealed and VCs don’t hold their tokens, people have a chance to buy back tokens for a fairly affordable price. The appetite for more decentralization is already growing. With Solana’s advantage being one of the top projects in scalability now it has a chance to enhance another valuable blockchain feature — decentralisation. Affordable price allows as well for builders to purchase tokens without getting any loans.With Scalps, we strive to provide the best possible structure where we enhance all three main values of blockchain: Security, Scalability and Decentralisation.Cleansing of the industryWhen the crypto tide goes out, that’s when the Ponzi schemers, rug-pullers and fair-weather traders are revealed. Times like these show us who is for real. The strong among us will adapt and survive. A bear market is about resetting, revisiting what is essential, and leveraging internal resources to innovate and improve. It’s not a time to sleep and wait.Room for greater ideasDown markets create more space for bright ideas and builders to earn more attention though builders have to work under uncertainty of the future of the industry overall. But as we know Bitcoin and crypto were “dead” several times in the past decade. In these environments, good ideas can properly take root. Take Scalps we started with the simple idea to solve a simple problem that nobody has gone through as of now. We keep building despite all the “blood” in the market because we are committed to delivering a solution and positively impacting the industry by raising trust in crypto and showcasing the real use case as the main idea behind our project.While some of the best people will lose their jobs in the downturn, there will be good places for good people to land on their feet and help to make positive change.Enhancement of DAOThese are tough times for people, and many will be turned off of the crypto space forever. Especially with recent events with FTX trust is broken because some biggest players in the space happened to be another Ponzi schemers. But for us who stick with fundamentals and don’t tweak ideas behind each invention in the crypto industry e.g DAO, NFTs times are appropriate to offer your solution for certain problems in the industry. In my opinion, we need to focus on the collective mind because everyone can enhance certain features in projects and DAO benefits it better than anything. People start waking up, there is a massive value shift in people’s consciousness and everyone wants to be heard. Implementing DAO in your company’s structure will benefit the working environment of your workflow leading to better work performance and an overall healthy ambience in the company.Follow us!LinkedInTwitterTelegramFacebookInstagram</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
