<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Sentit on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@sentit?source=rss-6885b7752f85------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsentit.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*rVVuyMCu0bsIgGbspey_KA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*rVVuyMCu0bsIgGbspey_KA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsentit.medium.com%2F&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:09:36+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Sentit — Payment via Email</title>
    <published>2020-11-11T13:02:55+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-11T13:02:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://sentit.medium.com/sentit-payment-via-email-73189547e2ba?source=rss-6885b7752f85------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sentit.medium.com/sentit-payment-via-email-73189547e2ba?source=rss-6885b7752f85------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Sentit</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Sentit — Payment via EmailProject title:SendIt — Blockchain payment via EmailSummary:SendIt is on a mission to simplify the use of blockchain for everyday users. SendIt is a simple but powerful wallet that allows anyone to send and receive payments via their normal email, Users can use and interact with the Stellar blockchain just like they would with their normal bank app, without needing to know the technical part of it. It is no doubt that the greatest challenge to blockchain mass Adoption is caused by the complexity of blockchain and the fact that not everyone can understand the technical part of the blockchain, not everyone will understand what public key, private key, consensus algorithm, validators, smart contract, hashing, cryptography, encryption, decentralization and other technical terms really mean, These terms make Blockchain Really hard to use for someone who just wants to enjoy control of their Money and the security blockchain provides, Sendit is solving this problem.Category:Applications, tools, and infrastructureGoals:SendIt is on a mission to make Blockchain services accessible to everyone.Simplify the use of Blockchain for Everyday users, Encouraging mass adoption.Financial Inclusion for All through stellar BlockchainTimeline:We have launched the testnet version for everyone to check out (With limited features), and we will appreciate the feedback. Within Two months, we will launch on the mainnet with Support for a few stablecoins and XLM. As we progress, we will integrate more stablecoins and other assets supported on StellarDex.Description:The present dapps are really doing a great job, but there is still a need to embrace the everyday users (the masses), Using any of the present wallets requires you to provide your recipient&amp;#39;s public key, Which can actually be a serious challenge to someone who has not been in the space before. SendIt has provided an awesome solution to this, users don’t need to Know anything about the public key part of the blockchain to enjoy the benefits of blockchain, With SendIt, users can send/transfer funds to anybody just by knowing their recipient&amp;#39;s email address (not a Federated address). If your friend Bob owns the email address bob@yahoo.com, you will be able to transfer any trust asset to Bob just by typing his email address (bob@yahoo.com), and he will get a notification of the fund and can do whatever he wishes with it. When sending to Bob for the first time, you will encrypt this transaction with a pin, Bob can only claim ownership of the fund if he has the Pin for this Transaction.In another attempt to encourage mass adoption of the blockchain, Users of SendIt will be able to Hold Asset A and send Asset B to another user, via their Email, Public address, or federated account (this will be only for assets available on Stellar Dex). Example You are a father/husband who works in the UK and has a family in Nigeria, You will be able to transfer USD and Your family will get NGN (almost instant, thanks to Stellar&amp;#39;s awesome structure) without the need for any of the parties to visit a bank for this transaction, and the fund is available to be withdrawn immediately to your local account (thanks to Stellar Anchors). Imagine sitting on your couch at home (say, in London, the UK, China. etc.) and being able to send me Naira without the need to visit a bank for FX or the need to Visit the Exchange to sell one token for another. You get to see the amount that will be deducted from Your account before Sending. This feature will be available for all assets added to the wallet.It is no doubt that blockchain provides tons of advantages compared to the traditional financial system, and with SendIt, Users will be able to enjoy the benefits of Stellar Blockchain without having to know the technical part of it. Users will have TOTAL CONTROL OF THEIR FUNDS, SECURITY, LOW TRANSACTION FEE, FAST TRANSACTION TIME (3 SECONDS), and many other advantages.Experienced Users of Blockchain wallets are also welcome to use SendIt, Transfers via federated and Public Key addresses will also be made available for everyone, Experienced Blockchain Users will be able to add custom assets, and these custom assets will be available for email transfers too. Users will be able to receive trusted assets via their federated address and public key from other Experienced users, and they will be able to get trusted assets via their email too.The test version of the wallet is available to be tested out by anyone, Custom asset addition isn’t available for the testnet version at the moment. For deposit, You can mimic the deposit of both USD and NGN, and the amount you enter will be credited for testing (not more than 20k). We plan to launch with USD, XLM, and NGN, and add custom assets, More assets will be added as we progress.ALL TRANSACTIONS PROCESSED ON SENDIT ARE BLOCKCHAIN BASED (Can be viewed Right on Stellar.expert)</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
