<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">SiBorg</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mirror.xyz/0x075E07cFacE72E7256a47509C833C1515d2508b6"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fmirror.xyz%2F0x075E07cFacE72E7256a47509C833C1515d2508b6%2Ffeed%2Fatom&amp;content_selector=%23__next&amp;content_cleanup=span%2C+svg%2C+form%2C+button&amp;remove_styles=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CssSelectorFeedExpanderBridge&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fmirror.xyz%2F0x075E07cFacE72E7256a47509C833C1515d2508b6%2Ffeed%2Fatom&amp;content_selector=%23__next&amp;content_cleanup=span%2C+svg%2C+form%2C+button&amp;remove_styles=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:09:39+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SiBorg Ads Pre-Sale Announcement</title>
    <published>2024-06-21T16:01:35+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-21T16:01:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://mirror.xyz/0x075E07cFacE72E7256a47509C833C1515d2508b6/veL71libJTmpiUGB_pa7dxrJlNucam2O0d0auT4HgYQ</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mirror.xyz/0x075E07cFacE72E7256a47509C833C1515d2508b6/veL71libJTmpiUGB_pa7dxrJlNucam2O0d0auT4HgYQ"/>
    <author>
      <name>Maxime</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">SiBorg Ads Pre-Sale Announcement
SiBorg
Last week, we introduced SiBorg Ads as a new solution designed to transform advertising on the SiBorg App. By leveraging blockchain technology to tokenize advertising parcels, it enables direct ownership and trading of ad spaces.
 We are excited to announce that we are launching the pre-sale of 100 premium ad spaces on Tuesday, June 25th. But what exactly is an ad space? 
It&amp;#x27;s a digital parcel in the SiBorg application. Each parcel is linked to a search ticker associated with our search bar. Purchasing an ad space gives the owner the right to propose a specific ad on top of this parcel, which will be displayed whenever that term is searched in the app!
 
SiBorg Ads owners can customize their ad space and benefit from the visibility associated with the platform.
 
For example, a user, an investor, or a brand could buy a search ticker like &amp;quot;Bitcoin&amp;quot; and display their own ad with a link to redirect to their platform.
 
 
Premium ad spaces are linked to specific tickers that are generally more frequently searched in our application.
 Introducing the SiBorg Ads buying process. SiBorg Ads Marketplace 
Enter the SiBorg Ads marketplace and find a premium ad space to bid on. For this pre-sale, from Tuesday 25th to Saturday 29th, 20 new premium ad spaces will be auctioned each day. Note that each auction lasts 24 hours.
 
 Bid-to-Earn Auction 
Once an ad space is chosen, the second step is to participate in the auction.
 
We chose a &amp;quot;Bid-to-Earn&amp;quot; auction mechanism, enabling the highest bidder to win the ad space while also rewarding every participant who gets outbid.
 
How the Bid-to-Earn auction works:
 
 
 
When a user sends money to place a bid, a formula calculates the incentives the user will receive if outbid.
 
 
 
When a higher bidder comes in, the user will receive their full bid back plus the incentive.
 
 
 
At the end of the auction, the ad space (NFT) will be sent to the winner, and SiBorg will receive the highest bid minus the incentives.
 
 
 
 Mystery boxes 
Once a bid is successfully submitted, the user will either receive rewards if outbid, or, if not outbid, they will get the ad space and earn additional mystery boxes.
 
Mystery boxes are a new type of incentive introduced in the SiBorg ecosystem. The content of mystery boxes will be revealed later but will include various rewards.
 
The number of mystery boxes received is proportionate to the value of the bid. This way, the higher you bid, the higher the reward will be in case of winning the auction.
 Referral 
Once a wallet is connected to the SiBorg Ads Marketplace, users will be able to share their referral code. In this case, users will earn boxes when their referrals win an auction. Both the referrer and the referee will earn the same amount of mystery boxes.
 What&amp;#x27;s next? 
The pre-sale is just the first step for SiBorg Ads. Following the pre-sale, users will be able to submit an ad to be displayed on their ad space. Users will be free to change the ad proposal at any time and free to resell it on the open market, enabling investment in the future visibility of the platform. Ad proposals will be reviewed by the SiBorg team to avoid any inappropriate content.
 
In a second phase, more tickers will be released, and in the near future, we aim to be permissionless in the sense that users will be able to mint an ad space linked to any keyword.
 
Prepare for the future of advertising with SiBorg Ads! Join us as we revolutionize ad spaces on the SiBorg App using blockchain technology. Stay tuned for the pre-sale beginning on Tuesday, June 25th.
Subscribe to SiBorg
Receive the latest updates directly to your inbox.
Mint this entry as an NFT to add it to your collection.
Verification
This entry has been permanently stored onchain and signed by its creator.
Arweave Transaction
Vjm42vr01aTpBHN…Rnclh4sCeJwOLRY
Author Address
0xe68D4c4C2704F60…6bF3C1c6eEc858F
Content Digest
veL71libJTmpiUG…am2O0d0auT4HgYQ</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://images.mirror-media.xyz/publication-images/MXblU6TyoekE-83vSXG9s.jpeg?height=3200&amp;amp;width=6400"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing SiBorg Ads: Investing in the Future of Advertising</title>
    <published>2024-06-13T15:57:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-13T15:57:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://mirror.xyz/0x075E07cFacE72E7256a47509C833C1515d2508b6/zFL6hWap8QHl8Ibm1cipuHtozKQC0Dzk0ssCZya1pK4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mirror.xyz/0x075E07cFacE72E7256a47509C833C1515d2508b6/zFL6hWap8QHl8Ibm1cipuHtozKQC0Dzk0ssCZya1pK4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Maxime</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Introducing SiBorg Ads: Investing in the Future of Advertising
SiBorg
As highlighted in our first article, the advertising industry faces several challenges, ranging from mass behavior modification and data vulnerability to misalignment of interests between sponsors and media, resulting in low-quality or even scammy advertisements.
 
However, a key insight from our first article was that each technological revolution has led to the emergence of new monetization mechanisms. For example, radio enabled mass audience targeting, television introduced visuals that increased consumer engagement, the internet sparked the rise of the pay-per-click industry, and social media enabled the targeting of advertisements through programmatic ads. The natural evolution from Web2 to Web3 involves blockchain technology, which enables decentralization, giving more control and choice to communities, facilitating direct payments, and, notably, allowing digital ownership.
 
Nevertheless, we have not (yet) found a new monetization mechanism emerging from this new technological evolution.
 Introducing SiBorg Ads: 
While developing the SiBorg app, we encountered challenges related to in-app monetization, a common issue among many companies, including those rooted in Web2. For newly launched applications with relatively low user bases, it is particularly challenging to generate revenue from ads. This creates a loop where funds from advertisements are necessary for marketing campaigns, but attracting advertisers requires significant user engagement and fulfilling various KPIs—yet, to attract users, funds are again necessary.
 
We explored different options like donations and premium subscriptions but were not convinced by adopting just one of them, as each approach brings its own set of challenges.
 
That&amp;#x27;s when we began developing SiBorg Ads, a blockchain-based solution.
 Key Features of SiBorg Ads: 1. Benefits from Digital Ownership: 
By introducing digital ownership over traditional advertising spaces, individuals can now own a segment of a website or a DApp dedicated to advertising. This ownership allows investors to contribute to the future visibility of a media platform. Ad spaces carry two types of value:
 
 
 
The current market value, similar to traditional ads, which depends on present KPIs and visibility.
 
 
 
The potential future visibility, depending on the growth of the platform. This model allows new media and DApps to get funded as anyone can buy an ad space based on their projections of the media&amp;#x27;s future visibility. It also opens opportunities for speculators, as an owner of a digital ad space can sell it at any time, speculating on the gap between current visibility and potential future visibility.
 
 
 2. Alignment of Interests: 
Now, as sponsors also become investors by owning digital parcels of the media, their goal is to maximize visibility for either sponsorship purposes or to sell the ad space at a higher price, enhancing the quality of the ads.
 
In this first version of SiBorg Ads, users&amp;#x27; data are not utilized, ensuring 100% privacy. However, in future versions, we may offer the option to use off-chain and on-chain data to deliver a more targeted experience, but only if users opt in.
 3. Media Change of Perspective: 
With SiBorg Ads, media and DApps receive upfront payments when ad spaces are purchased. Additionally, the media also earn royalties from the secondary market.
 
SiBorg Ads reduce intermediaries, ensuring a higher return on investment for sponsors with only three stakeholders involved: the sponsor (which can be any user or brand seeking visibility), the SiBorg Ads marketplace, and the SiBorg app where the ad is displayed.
 
Furthermore, the media maintain control over what is published, preventing scammy ads. Meanwhile, sponsors can be certain of where and when their ads will be deployed.
 
In our upcoming article, we will delve deeper into how SiBorg Ads works, exploring the user flow and more. Stay tuned for major announcements.
 Resources 
First Article: Exploring the Evolution and Current Challenges of the Advertising Industry
Subscribe to SiBorg
Receive the latest updates directly to your inbox.
Mint this entry as an NFT to add it to your collection.
Verification
This entry has been permanently stored onchain and signed by its creator.
Arweave Transaction
-VaJWwNmEp7-abp…MHkthtueu9P141Y
Author Address
0xe68D4c4C2704F60…6bF3C1c6eEc858F
Content Digest
zFL6hWap8QHl8Ib…0Dzk0ssCZya1pK4</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" href="https://images.mirror-media.xyz/publication-images/4BvD0Lr2jvEmBwMSdA_YT.jpeg?height=510&amp;amp;width=1020"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Exploring the Evolution and Current Challenges of the Advertising Industry</title>
    <published>2024-06-05T18:02:08+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-05T18:02:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://mirror.xyz/0x075E07cFacE72E7256a47509C833C1515d2508b6/Xs4A5zPmIM1aWW5vndDPhU8jx4ASMyKdrl75lJt3NAs</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mirror.xyz/0x075E07cFacE72E7256a47509C833C1515d2508b6/Xs4A5zPmIM1aWW5vndDPhU8jx4ASMyKdrl75lJt3NAs"/>
    <author>
      <name>Maxime</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Exploring the Evolution and Current Challenges of the Advertising Industry
SiBorg
Welcome to the opening chapter of our enlightening series on the transformative landscape of advertising. Join us in exploring the storied past and pressing challenges facing today’s advertising industry, one of the most discussed topics at SiBorg recently.
 A Brief History of Advertising 
Advertising isn&amp;#x27;t a modern invention. It dates back to the late 19th century with the emergence of print media. Newspapers and magazines expanded the reach and frequency of advertisements, marking the beginning of structured advertising. By the 1920s, radio advertising had taken the stage, becoming a popular medium to reach a mass audience, particularly for consumer goods. The post-World War II era ushered in television advertising, which combined visual impact with targeted strategies aimed at niche audiences, significantly enhancing consumer engagement.
 
The digital age accelerated these trends with the rise of the internet and email marketing in the 1990s, introducing models like pay-per-click advertising. By the 2010s, programmatic advertising had revolutionized the scene by automating the buying and selling of ads, optimizing targeting, and reducing costs. This era marked the dominance of giants like Facebook and Google in the advertising realm.
 Mass Behavior Modification 
The evolution of advertising has not been without its pitfalls. A notable issue is behavior modification by platforms such as social media and entertainment sites, which can lead to user addiction. Here’s how the cycle works:
 
 
 
Platforms capture attention by leveraging human emotions, leading to addiction.
 
 
 
Increased user time on the platform allows for more extensive data collection.
 
 
 
This data is sold to advertisers, enabling highly targeted ads that further increase user engagement.
 
 
 
A feedback loop is created where ad revenue fuels the refinement of engagement strategies.
 
 
 
 
This manipulation of emotions can have severe consequences, including social anxiety and depression, as platforms use tactics that may emphasize negative reinforcement over positive.
 Alignment Challenges Between Media Platforms and Advertisers 
Today&amp;#x27;s advertising landscape often fails to incentivize the creation of high-quality ads, leading instead to an influx of low-quality, sometimes deceptive advertising. Many of us have encountered less-than-trustworthy ads promising the latest &amp;#x27;airdrop&amp;#x27; or miracle product. Moreover, the reliance on user data to maximize revenue can create alignment challenges, including:
 
 
 
Brand safety risks, where ads might appear alongside controversial or inappropriate content.
 
 
 
Ad fraud, where the authenticity of clicks and impressions can be questionable, diminishing return on investment.
 
 
 
An increase in intermediaries, complicating the ad delivery process and affecting transparency.
 
 
 Data Privacy: A Double-Edged Sword 
On one hand, users often prefer relevant ads that resonate with their interests. On the other, handling such data responsibly requires immense care to avoid manipulation and privacy breaches. Mishandling of data is rampant, with incidents like the Twitter API leak in 2022 or the Cambridge Analytica scandal in 2018 affecting millions. Despite regulatory attempts, loopholes and challenges persist, leaving user data vulnerable.
 
Looking ahead, our subsequent articles will delve into how web3 technologies aim to redefine these challenges, championing a new era of advertising where transparency and user empowerment are paramount. Stay tuned for an engaging exploration into the future of advertising, guided by innovation and user-centric principles.
 
In the second article, we will explore what Web3 can bring to the advertising industry and how SiBorg can propel this industry into a new era
 Resources 
 
 
Cointelegraph article
 
 
 
Article explaining the main issues with Web2
 
 
Subscribe to SiBorg
Receive the latest updates directly to your inbox.
Mint this entry as an NFT to add it to your collection.
Verification
This entry has been permanently stored onchain and signed by its creator.
Arweave Transaction
34LWYThKG_MuEpH…WNIlkf54R7tKl5w
Author Address
0xe68D4c4C2704F60…6bF3C1c6eEc858F
Content Digest
Xs4A5zPmIM1aWW5…MyKdrl75lJt3NAs</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://images.mirror-media.xyz/publication-images/N4DgZESpjxFn7j0I0PMCR.png?height=661&amp;amp;width=1321"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
