<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">ICHI - Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fichifarm&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fichifarm&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:06:45+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">ICHI Partners with SaucerSwap on Hedera</title>
    <published>2024-04-05T10:44:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-04-05T10:44:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-partners-with-saucerswap-on-hedera-d86524cacb38?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-partners-with-saucerswap-on-hedera-d86524cacb38?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Bringing single-sided liquidity provision vaults to users in the Hedera ecosystem.Liquidity provision plays a crucial role in facilitating seamless trading experiences and ensuring market efficiency. As the DeFi ecosystem continues to grow, the demand for innovative solutions to optimize liquidity management becomes increasingly apparent. In response to this demand, we are proud to announce our collaboration with SaucerSwap and the HBAR Foundation, which will see ICHI’s automated liquidity management technology integrated into the SaucerSwap platform.Active Liquidity ManagementICHI is at the forefront of automated liquidity management, offering sophisticated algorithmic strategies designed to optimize liquidity provision on decentralized exchanges (DEXs). Our technology enables users to seamlessly provide liquidity across a wide range of token pairs while earning on-chain yield in the process. By dynamically adjusting liquidity positions based on market conditions, ICHI’s Yield IQ vaults are designed to maximize returns for liquidity providers (LPs) while mitigating risks associated with impermanent loss.SaucerSwap has emerged as a leading DEX built on the robust infrastructure of the Hedera network. With its commitment to transparency, security, and user-centric design, SaucerSwap provides traders and LPs with a seamless and efficient trading experience. By leveraging the unparalleled speed and cost-effectiveness of the Hedera network, SaucerSwap has quickly gained traction within the DeFi community, attracting users seeking a fair, accessible, and decentralized trading platform.SaucerSwap’s V2 LaunchSaucerSwap V2 introduces concentrated liquidity, a feature allowing LPs to allocate capital within specified price ranges. This innovation significantly enhances capital efficiency, fee earnings, and risk mitigation for LPs compared to V1. With each liquidity position represented by a non-fungible token (NFT), LPs can adapt to market conditions effectively, maximizing fee earning potential. SaucerSwap V2 also implements a multi-tiered fee structure, ensuring appropriate compensation for LPs based on the risk associated with different token pairs. The launch of V2 perfectly ties in with ICHI’s automated liquidity management solution.Additionally, the Liquidity-Aligned Reward Initiative (LARI) provides token incentives for efficient liquidity contributions. LPs no longer need to stake their liquidity position NFTs to earn rewards, simplifying the user experience and optimizing gas efficiency. Unlike V1’s yield farm, LARI supports various HTS tokens for rewards, enabling projects to customize campaigns for their liquidity pools. Rewards accumulate based on the duration a position remains within the active tick range, and participants receive rewards through automatic airdrops at the end of each epoch.Empowering Users with Choice and FlexibilityThrough our collaboration with SaucerSwap we have a goal to empower users with choice and flexibility in liquidity provision on the Hedera network. SaucerSwap users gain access to ICHI’s single-token deposit Yield IQ vaults, enabling them to participate in a diverse array of liquidity pools across various token pairs. Whether it’s stablecoin pairs, more volatile pairs or liquidity pairs for emerging DeFi projects, SaucerSwap users have the flexibility to provide liquidity where they see fit, all while earning on-chain yield through ICHI’s automated liquidity management solution. The best part is that, it is all single-sided, so users only need to provide one side of the pair to earn more of their favorite token.Our dynamic liquidity management algorithms ensure that liquidity positions are continuously adjusted to adapt to changing market conditions, further enhancing the resilience of SaucerSwap’s liquidity pools.How Does Yield IQ Exactly Work?Yield IQ’s process is simple and efficient. Users deposit their preferred tokens into the platform, and Yield IQ allocates these tokens into concentrated liquidity AMMs, without initiating any swaps. In return, users receive LP tokens representing their share in the liquidity pool.The true magic unfolds as Yield IQ, powered by Chainlink Automation, dynamically adjusts the concentrated liquidity position based on token arrangements and real-time market conditions. Users earn trading fees when trades occur, supplementing potential token appreciation. With vigilant oversight of token composition, Yield IQ guards against harmful arbitrage and market shifts. Users can withdraw their initial deposit and earnings at any time by exchanging LP tokens for their share of assets in the vault.Whether in bull or bear markets, Yield IQ’s continuous monitoring and rebalancing mechanisms safeguard users from over-exposure and potential losses. This feature is particularly advantageous in volatile market conditions.Why Yield IQ? Simplicity and results. It offers:Single-token liquidity depositsAutomated management that grows deposits of this tokenVigilantly adjusts the liquidity composition between the two tokens, mitigating the risk of over-selling the deposited tokenUsers are now able to deposit into Yield IQ vaults through SaucerSwap’s user-friendly interface. There are numerous pairs to choose from and available for anyone who wishes to provide liquidity using Yield IQ.Please check out here which single-token deposit pools are available.Final ThoughtsSaucerSwap V2’s concentrated liquidity feature, combined with ICHI’s automated liquidity management technology, empowers users with flexibility, efficiency, and earning potential. LPs can strategically allocate capital, maximize fee earnings, and mitigate risks, while participating in a diverse array of liquidity pools. The implementation of LARI further incentivizes efficient liquidity contributions, enhancing protocol governance and broadening the distribution of SAUCE tokens. This collaboration exemplifies the ongoing innovation and collaboration driving the DeFi ecosystem forward, paving the way for a more accessible, efficient, and sustainable decentralized financial landscape.About SaucerSwapSaucerSwap is a decentralized exchange that goes beyond the ERC20 standard by leveraging HSCS and HTS, inheriting the full advantage of the Hedera network. It serves as a one-stop shop for DeFi on Hedera, offering a full-suite of services including a token swap, liquidity pools, yield farms, single-sided staking, and more.Learn more by visiting SaucerSwap’s LinkTree.About ICHIICHI is a concentrated liquidity manager that enables the use of sophisticated algorithmic strategies on AMMs. With its fully automated Yield IQ vaults, ICHI allows for all token holders to earn from liquidity provision. True to the spirit of DeFi, Yield IQ is governed by a self-executing smart contract, ensuring impartiality and decentralization. This ensures unrestricted, permissionless access and unalterable protocol behavior, serving as a truly decentralized financial tool.Learn more by visiting the ICHI Website, Medium, Twitter or Telegram.ICHI Partners with SaucerSwap on Hedera was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">QuickSwap Introduces Automated Liquidity Management with ICHI’s Yield IQ Vaults</title>
    <published>2024-01-10T11:24:10+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-01-10T11:24:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/quickswap-introduces-automated-liquidity-management-with-ichis-yield-iq-vaults-601c5752eec7?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/quickswap-introduces-automated-liquidity-management-with-ichis-yield-iq-vaults-601c5752eec7?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">ICHI and QuickSwap have joined forces bringing smart liquidity provision to users on the Polygon network. QuickSwap, an Automated Market Maker (AMM), has gained immense popularity for its speed and cost-effectiveness. With the introduction of ICHI’s innovative vault technology, QuickSwap is set to elevate the DeFi user experience by launching twelve new liquidity pools.QuickSwap: A Polygon PioneerQuickSwap, a next-generation layer-2 decentralized exchange and automated market maker, has become a go-to platform for users seeking fast transactions and minimal fees. Built on the Polygon network, users can effortlessly trade ERC-20 tokens, leveraging the speed and cost advantages of Polygon. Despite its similarities to Uniswap, QuickSwap stands out due to its commitment to audited code, vibrant community and a user-friendly, permissionless environment.Additionally, what makes QuickSwap unique is the fact that it’s a one-stop-shop for all your DeFi actions such as swapping, LPing, staking, and farming to earn rewards. It also comes built with other useful features like QuickPerps (a decentralized Perpetual Exchange), active liquidity management and more.ICHI’s Vault Technology Revolutionizes LiquidityICHI’s Yield IQ vault technology is set to augment QuickSwap’s liquidity provision, introducing efficient and profitable liquidity provision. The launch of these new vaults on Polygon empowers users with unprecedented liquidity options.ICHI’s vaults operate on the principle of dynamic liquidity management. For example, in the MATIC/QUICK vault, users can deposit their tokens, become Liquidity Providers (LPs) and earn fees from swaps made by other users. The same model applies to the MATIC/ETH vault and so on. ICHI’s algorithm ensures optimal token concentration, mitigating risks and offering LPs protection from significant losses during market fluctuations. The best part is that all of this is single-sided, so you only need to deposit one side of the pair to earn more of your favorite token.How Does Yield IQ Exactly Work?Yield IQ’s process is simple and efficient. Users deposit their preferred tokens into the platform, and Yield IQ allocates these tokens into concentrated liquidity AMMs, such as Uniswap V3, without initiating any swaps. In return, users receive LP tokens representing their share in the liquidity pool.The true magic unfolds as Yield IQ, powered by Chainlink Automation, dynamically adjusts the concentrated liquidity position based on token arrangements and real-time market conditions. Users earn trading fees when trades occur, supplementing potential token appreciation. With vigilant oversight of token composition, Yield IQ guards against harmful arbitrage and market shifts. Users can withdraw their initial deposit and earnings at any time by exchanging LP tokens for their share of assets in the vault.Whether in bull or bear markets, Yield IQ’s continuous monitoring and rebalancing mechanisms safeguard users from over-exposure and potential losses. This feature is particularly advantageous in volatile market conditions.How Can I Access Yield IQ Vaults?Users are now able to deposit into Yield IQ vaults through QuickSwap’s user-friendly interface. Pairs include MATIC, ETH, USDC, wBTC and more!ICHI’s vaults welcome single-sided deposits of blue-chip assets, pairing these deposits with the QUICK token, to strengthen its liquidity. As more blue-chip assets enter the system, $QUICK gains resilience against market volatility, benefiting the QuickSwap community.Closing ThoughtsQuickSwap, renowned for its efficiency and low fees as a layer-2 decentralized exchange, introduces twelve new liquidity pools, allowing users to seamlessly participate in dynamic liquidity provision. ICHI’s vaults, operating on the principle of dynamic liquidity management, offer a unique and efficient way for users to become liquidity providers and earn fees without the need for complex processes. As DeFi continues to evolve, this collaboration sets a new standard for secure, efficient, and user-centric liquidity provision on the Polygon network.About QuickSwapQuickSwap is the leading DEX on Polygon PoS, Polygon zkEVM, and Dogechain that’s fully decentralised and community-driven, building a comprehensive suite of DeFi products called the DragonFi ecosystem. It’s renowned for its high-performance, cost-efficient DeFi platforms, and pioneering role in onboarding new users and capital to the broader Polygon ecosystem.About ICHIICHI is a concentrated liquidity manager that enables the use of sophisticated algorithmic strategies on AMMs. With its fully automated Yield IQ vaults, ICHI allows for all token holders to earn from liquidity provision. True to the spirit of DeFi, Yield IQ is governed by a self-executing smart contract, ensuring impartiality and decentralization. This ensures unrestricted, permissionless access and unalterable protocol behavior, serving as a truly decentralized financial tool.Learn more by visiting the ICHI Website, Medium, Twitter or Telegram.QuickSwap Introduces Automated Liquidity Management with ICHI’s Yield IQ Vaults was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">ICHI Partners with RAMSES Exchange on Arbitrum</title>
    <published>2023-12-18T13:51:33+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-18T13:51:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-partners-with-ramses-exchange-on-arbitrum-4e323810a3ff?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-partners-with-ramses-exchange-on-arbitrum-4e323810a3ff?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Bringing single-sided liquidity provision vaults to more users in the Arbitrum ecosystem.Blockchain trading has undergone significant evolution in recent years, but one aspect that has remained a challenge is liquidity provision. Decentralized exchanges (DEXes) have typically struggled to match the liquidity and efficiency of their centralized counterparts. However, DeFi is evolving fast and more projects are coming out with innovative ways to increase capital efficiency, making more liquid markets for all participants.RAMSES, the native liquidity layer on Arbitrum, takes a unique approach on ve(3,3) Decentralized Exchange infrastructure with innovative concentrated liquidity (CL) and Bribe Infrastructure. RAMSES offers enhanced capital efficiency and tokenomics that allow protocols to bootstrap liquidity on Arbitrum, while providing users with the best trading experience.ICHI x RAMSES: A Powerful PartnershipICHI is teaming up with RAMSES Exchange to bring optimized liquidity provision to the RAMSES community on the Arbitrum chain. One of the key highlights of this partnership is the availability of vaults for single-sided liquidity provision through the RAMSES frontend. These vaults offer users a unique opportunity to participate in liquidity provision on the Arbitrum chain, with a range of assets and pairs to choose from. Let’s take a closer look at these vaults:These vaults represent various trading pairs, allowing users to provide liquidity with their preferred assets, all single-sided! What does this mean? It means you only need one side of the pair i.e. USDC to earn more of it as ICHI’s Yield IQ algorithm optimizes the concentration of your deposit token.👌Understanding Concentrated LiquidityUnlike traditional liquidity pools, where liquidity is spread across a wide range of prices, CL allows liquidity providers to concentrate their assets within a specific price range. RAMSES not only introduces CL but also incorporates a unique Bribe Infrastructure, making liquidity provisioning even more efficient. RAMSES is already generating substantial weekly revenue, a portion of which is designated for veRAM holders. It can generate impressive returns, with $1 in fees and bribes for each $1 in total value locked (TVL). This performance, combined with CL, transforms liquidity provision into a highly competitive activity.LPs on RAMSES pools are incentivized to maintain tighter spreads to secure a larger share of rewards. This competition leads to deeper liquidity pools and attracts higher trading volumes, reminiscent of the competitive nature of market-making in traditional financial markets.Benefits for veRAM VotersIn RAMSES pools, trading fees are shared among LPs, voters, and the ecosystem fund. veRAM voters capture a significant portion of these fees, ranging from 75% to 90%, while LPs earn between 10% and 25%. The ecosystem fund receives 0% to 5% of the fees. This fee structure encourages LPs to participate in RAMSES CL pools, as the potential for higher earnings is significant.The Impact of RAMSES in DeFiVe(3,3) DEXs have already made liquidity provisioning competitive by introducing emissions, but RAMSES takes this to the next level. It creates the most competitive liquidity provision market in the DeFi space.This opens up exciting opportunities for various participants:Specialized market makers can provide liquidity.Builders can develop yield and asset management services.Projects can incentivize deeper liquidity by offering bribes to RAMSES CL pools.Average liquidity providers can pursue higher yields by participating in RAMSES CL pools.Looking AheadThe partnership between ICHI and RAMSES is poised to bridge the gap between DEXes and traditional exchanges. By enhancing liquidity provisioning and competitiveness, RAMSES can attract higher trading volumes, benefiting veRAM holders, LPs, and traders. RAMSES remains committed to sustainability and capital efficiency, making it a powerful force in the DeFi ecosystem.About RAMSESRAMSES is the native liquidity layer on Arbitrum, revolutionizing ve(3,3) Decentralized Exchange infrastructure. RAMSES offers unparalleled capital efficiency and innovative tokenomics, creating a robust decentralized economic system within the Arbitrum ecosystem. Join the RAMSES community and be part of this liquidity revolution today.About ICHIICHI is a trustless market-making protocol that enables the use of sophisticated algorithmic strategies on Uniswap V3. With its fully automated Yield IQ vaults, ICHI allows for all token holders to earn from liquidity provision. True to the spirit of DeFi, Yield IQ is governed by a self-executing smart contract, ensuring impartiality and decentralization. This ensures unrestricted, permissionless access and unalterable protocol behavior, serving as a truly decentralized financial tool.Learn more by visiting the ICHI Website, Medium, Twitter or Telegram.ICHI Partners with RAMSES Exchange on Arbitrum was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">ICHI and Ascent Partner to Introduce Yield IQ Vaults on Horizen EON</title>
    <published>2023-11-30T17:22:19+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-11-30T17:22:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-and-ascent-partner-to-introduce-yield-iq-vaults-on-horizen-eon-fb893b7a8fb4?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-and-ascent-partner-to-introduce-yield-iq-vaults-on-horizen-eon-fb893b7a8fb4?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">ICHI is teaming up with Ascent Exchange, the native liquidity layer on Horizen EON blockchain. This dynamic partnership opens the gateway for early users on the Horizen EON network to delve into optimized liquidity provision strategies. Joining forces, ICHI and Ascent Exchange promise a seamless and efficient liquidity provision experience on Ascent Exchang — The Next-Gen Liquidity Layer on Horizen Eon.Ascent’s MissionAscent is an innovative Automated Market Maker (AMM) set on a mission to redefine the integration of new protocols, revolutionizing the landscape with a dynamic market for AEX emissions. This unique approach empowers protocols to incentivize veAEX holders, providing a flexible avenue for growth and scalability. Inspired by the proven models of Curve &amp;amp; Solidly, Ascent’s ve(3,3) tokenomics and flywheel effect have been meticulously designed to maximize rewards and optimize liquidity, ensuring an unparalleled trading experience on the Horizen EON network.ICHI’s Yield IQ: A Practical Solution for DeFi EarningsICHI introduces a pragmatic approach to liquidity provision in the DeFi space. Unlike conventional methods, Yield IQ challenges the notion that trading fees minus impermanent loss leads to undesirable outcomes for volatile tokens. Instead, it operates as an income generator, effectively managing risks and earning income for token holders.How Yield IQ WorksUsers deposit their preferred tokens (single-sided), and Yield IQ allocates them to a concentrated liquidity automated market maker (AMM), such as Uniswap V3. In return, users receive LP tokens, representing their shares in the liquidity pool. The strength of Yield IQ lies in its ability, powered by Chainlink Automation, to dynamically adjust the liquidity position based on token arrangement and market conditions. This ensures users earn trading fees and supplement token appreciation. With the flexibility to withdraw the initial deposit and earnings at any time, Yield IQ provides a straightforward yet powerful solution.Whether in bull or bear markets, Yield IQ’s continuous monitoring and rebalancing mechanisms safeguard users from over-exposure and potential losses. This feature is particularly advantageous in volatile market conditions.Ascent: Native Liquidity Layer on Horizen EONSimultaneously, Ascent is making significant strides as a native liquidity layer on the Horizen EON blockchain. Ascent Exchange’s mission is to become the liquidity backbone of the Horizen EON network, facilitating seamless onboarding for new and existing protocols through capital-efficient liquidity bootstrapping.Launching as the first decentralized exchange with ve(3,3) tokenomics on Horizen EON, Ascent gains a valuable first-mover advantage, setting the standard for trading on this evolving blockchain. The collaboration with Wave GP, Horizen EON’s dedicated liquidity provider, ensures deep and stable liquidity gauges, enhancing the overall trading experience for users.Their dedication lies in ensuring a decentralized and fair distribution model. Ascent prioritizes regular users of core protocols on the Horizen EON, extending support to projects seeking to enhance their liquidity through Ascent. Their unique approach allows them to promote best practices among stakeholders and foster a vibrant community of enthusiastic Ascent supporters, all achieved independently of discounted token sales or venture capital engagements.The Partnership: Yield IQ Enhances Ascent’s Liquidity OfferingThe collaboration between ICHI and Ascent represent a synergistic approach to smart liquidity provision, creating a commitment to efficiency leading to a more comprehensive ecosystem. This ecosystem addresses the challenges of liquidity provision such as capital inefficiency while offering users a practical and user-friendly platform to earn on-chain yield.How Can I Access Yield IQ Vaults?Users are now able to deposit into Yield IQ vaults through Ascent’s s user-friendly interface. The following pairs are available and ready for anyone who wishes to provide liquidity using Yield IQ.1) ETH-USDC2) ETH-BTC3) ETH-wZEN4) AVAX-wZEN5) USDT-wZEN6) BTC-wZEN7) USDC-wZEN9) USDC-USDTBluechip asset vaults and bluechips paired with ZEN provides users with various liquidity provision options to suit their needs. Deposit one asset and earn more of it as the Yield IQ algorithm does its magic.Important: The LPs must not be staked in the AEX farm in order to earn trading fees. If the LP is staked in the farm then only AEX rewards are earned.User BenefitsUsers are empowered with a simplified and efficient way to provide liquidity on Horizen EON. Additionally, users benefit from single-sided deposits, that auto-adjust the concentrated liquidity position based on token arrangement and market conditions, leading to potential fee earnings, and the flexibility to withdraw assets at any time.Closing thoughtsTogether, ICHI and Ascent create a synergistic ecosystem, committing to efficiency and offering users a practical and user-friendly platform for on-chain yield. With the unique ability to deposit into Yield IQ vaults through Ascent’s user-friendly interface, users gain access to a range of pairs, providing diverse options for liquidity provision. The user benefits are clear — a simplified, efficient, and flexible approach to providing liquidity on Horizen EON. As this partnership paves the way for a more comprehensive ecosystem, it strengthens the overall EON ecosystem.About Horizen EONEON stands as a beacon of innovation within the blockchain space. It is a fully EVM-compatible sidechain and smart contract platform, engineered for massive scalability. EON facilitates swift access to Horizen’s burgeoning ecosystem, with features like the Cross-Chain Transfer Protocol (CCTP) and zkSNARKs enabled permissionless cross-chain communications. Horizen itself, the powerhouse behind EON, guarantees a secure, reliable, and robust environment with a vast node network for decentralization, zero downtime, and enhanced security measures against 51% attacks.About Ascent ExchangeAscent Exchange is the Next-Gen Liquidity Layer on Horizen Eon. At our core, we are driven by a community-centric approach, unyielding commitment to decentralization, scalability, security, and innovation-driven functionality. These foundational principles underscore our journey towards excellence in decentralized finance.About ICHIICHI is a trustless market-making protocol that enables the use of sophisticated algorithmic strategies on Uniswap V3. With its fully automated Yield IQ vaults, ICHI allows for all token holders to earn from liquidity provision. True to the spirit of DeFi, Yield IQ is governed by a self-executing smart contract, ensuring impartiality and decentralization. This ensures unrestricted, permissionless access and unalterable protocol behavior, serving as a truly decentralized financial tool.Learn more by visiting the ICHI Website, Medium, Twitter or Telegram.ICHI and Ascent Partner to Introduce Yield IQ Vaults on Horizen EON was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">ICHI Partners with THENA: Pioneering On-Chain Market Making On BNB Chain</title>
    <published>2023-11-10T17:02:15+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-11-10T17:02:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-partners-with-thena-pioneering-on-chain-market-making-on-bnb-chain-4f42e3f93a34?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-partners-with-thena-pioneering-on-chain-market-making-on-bnb-chain-4f42e3f93a34?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">ICHI has partnered with THENA, a next-generation liquidity layer operating on the BNB Chain, specifically designed to be a protocol for protocols. This partnership marks the opening of on-chain market-making vaults, aimed at reducing downside volatility, thereby enhancing the overall resilience of the DeFi ecosystem.Unveiling THENAThis next-generation liquidity layer operates on the BNB Chain (BSC) and is specifically designed as a protocol for other protocols. THENA’s unique approach ensures that its main stakeholders — veTHE holders, Liquidity Providers (LPs), users, and protocols — are aligned through innovative ve(3,3) dynamics that govern $THE emissions. $THE emissions, combined with protocol bribes and pool-generated fees, serve as the foundational pillars of THENA’s economic model.At its core, THENA is a decentralized exchange protocol that brings together the best elements of popular platforms like Curve and Uniswap. THENA has also launched the first intent-based perpetual exchange on BNB, currently in beta (alpha.thena.fi). The result is a trading experience characterized by low fees and minimal slippage. Another distinctive feature of THENA is its ability to generate passive income streams for users. There are no deposit or withdrawal fees, and individuals maintain full control over their assets. This means that users can stake their assets on the platform and enjoy a hassle-free source of income.THENA is more than just another DeFi platform; it represents the future of DeFi liquidity. With a commitment to security, transparency, and community-driven governance, THENA is poised to become the go-to solution for DeFi projects seeking to flourish in the BNB Chain ecosystem. As a protocol for protocols, it exemplifies the core principles of openness, accessibility, and innovation.On-Chain Market MakingMarket making is a crucial element in DeFi, providing liquidity and stability is key in the often turbulent seas of crypto markets. ICHI’s Yield IQ is a groundbreaking solution designed to enhance the resiliency and efficiency of market making. It offers a streamlined approach for the deployment of assets on-chain, providing market makers with the essential liquidity needed for DeFi projects to thrive. In doing so, Yield IQ not only enhances THENA’s resilience but also fortifies the broader DeFi ecosystem, ensuring that liquidity provision remains steadfast even in the face of market uncertainty.Yield IQ VaultsThe heart of this partnership lies in ICHI’s automated, single-deposit Yield IQ vaults, which have earned a reputation for their effectiveness in creating market-making opportunities. In simple terms, ICHI’s vaults allow assets to be deployed on-chain (single token deposits), enabling market makers to provide liquidity in an efficient and decentralized manner. This liquidity, in turn, facilitates smoother trading and can help reduce the downside volatility experienced in bear markets. Market makers, using ICHI’s vaults, are better equipped to handle market fluctuations, providing the essential liquidity needed to support DeFi projects.Why Yield IQ? Simplicity and results. It offers:Single-token liquidity depositsAutomated management that grows deposits of this tokenVigilantly adjusts the liquidity composition between the two tokens, mitigating the risk of over-selling the deposited tokenUsers are now able to deposit into Yield IQ vaults through THENA’s user-friendly interface. The following pairs are available and ready for anyone who wishes to provide liquidity using Yield IQ.BNB-THEUSDT-THEETH-THEUSDC-THEICHI Vaults are reshaping the crypto landscape with an innovative approach to managing liquidity. These vaults welcome single-sided deposits of blue-chip assets, pairing these deposits with the Thena token, $THE, to strengthen its liquidity.In simple terms, there’s a close connection between the liquidity of blue-chip assets and the $THE token. As more blue-chip assets enter the system, $THE gains resilience against market volatility, benefiting the Thena community.This strategy is referred to as ‘Vault Power.’ Thena’s goal is to maximize this Vault Power, with a target of around 40%. Achieving this milestone will strengthen the stability and security of the $THE token, contributing to a more stable and prosperous ecosystem for all.How Does Yield IQ Work?Yield IQ’s process is simple and efficient. Users deposit their preferred tokens into the platform, and Yield IQ allocates these tokens into concentrated liquidity AMMs, such as Uniswap V3, without initiating any swaps. In return, users receive LP tokens representing their share in the liquidity pool.The true magic unfolds as Yield IQ, powered by Chainlink Automation, dynamically adjusts the concentrated liquidity position based on token arrangements and real-time market conditions. Users earn trading fees when trades occur, supplementing potential token appreciation. With vigilant oversight of token composition, Yield IQ guards against harmful arbitrage and market shifts. Users can withdraw their initial deposit and earnings at any time by exchanging LP tokens for their share of assets in the vault.About THENATHENA is a decentralized exchange protocol built on BNB Chain that combines the best of Curve and Uniswap to offer an optimal trading experience with low fees and low slippage. Designed to be a protocol for protocols, THENA’s tokenomics allow any project to tap into an open and permissionless incentive marketplace to incentivize liquidity. With an emphasis on security, transparency, and community governance, THENA is the future-proof solution for DeFi liquidity.Website | Discord | LinksAbout ICHIICHI is a trustless market-making protocol that enables the use of sophisticated algorithmic strategies on Uniswap V3. With its fully automated Yield IQ vaults, ICHI allows for all token holders to earn from liquidity provision. True to the spirit of DeFi, Yield IQ is governed by a self-executing smart contract, ensuring impartiality and decentralization. This ensures unrestricted, permissionless access and unalterable protocol behavior, serving as a truly decentralized financial tool.Learn more by visiting the ICHI Website, Medium, Twitter or Telegram.ICHI Partners with THENA: Pioneering On-Chain Market Making On BNB Chain was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Ve(3,3) DEXes: A Game-Changer in DeFi Tokenomics</title>
    <published>2023-09-19T10:29:04+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-09-19T10:29:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/ve-3-3-dexes-a-game-changer-in-defi-tokenomics-992b3172872a?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/ve-3-3-dexes-a-game-changer-in-defi-tokenomics-992b3172872a?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">IntroductionIn the ever-evolving world of decentralized finance (DeFi), innovation is the key to staying ahead. One remarkable advancement in DeFi tokenomics is the Ve(3,3) model, which was introduced by Andre Cronje, the founder of Yearn Finance. This model combines elements from Curve’s vote-escrow mechanism and OlympusDAO’s (3,3) staking, creating a groundbreaking approach to DeFi. In this blog, we’ll delve into the Ve(3,3) concept, its implications, and how it’s revolutionizing DeFi.The Genesis of Ve(3,3)The Ve(3,3) concept was brought to life by Andre Cronje, who initially introduced it with the release of Solidly Exchange. Despite his departure from DeFi in March 2022, this innovative approach to tokenomics continues to thrive. The co-founder of Fantom, Cronje, outlined his calculations on how the Ve(3,3) model could shape the future of DeFi.Traditional DEXes and Their ChallengesTo appreciate the significance of Ve(3,3) DEXes, we must first understand the limitations of traditional decentralized exchanges (DEXes). Traditional DEXes primarily generate yield through swap fees. However, to attract liquidity while demonstrating decentralization, they introduced governance tokens. These tokens enabled holders to vote on project proposals. But a significant drawback emerged — whales holding large amounts of tokens could wield disproportionate voting power, undermining the decentralization principle.A clear example of this occurred when a crypto VC, held 15 million Uniswap tokens, giving them over 64% of the total voting share. This concentration of power raised concerns about the integrity of the governance process.Moreover, governance tokens often faced a dilemma — either whales accumulate tokens at low prices or token prices remain low, potentially leading to token devaluation. This impacted liquidity pools, as high token prices attracted farmers while low prices led to liquidity drain.Innovating DeFi TokenomicsIn response to these challenges, DeFi protocols began exploring new tokenomics models. Some introduced rewards in other tokens, driving token price appreciation and farm APRs. Others implemented lock-up periods to reduce selling pressure, compelling stakers to commit to holding their tokens.Curve Finance took a unique approach by incentivizing the locking of governance tokens even more than farming for rewards. Stakers who locked their tokens received not only farming rewards but also governance rewards, creating a synergy that increased their incentives.Governance Tokens with EmissionsThis model gave rise to governance tokens with emissions. By locking their tokens, users gained voting power, directing governance tokens to specific LP pools. This concept spurred competition among protocols, with some resorting to bribes to secure more votes. Bribes, when compared to emissions, proved more capital-efficient.The Birth of DeFi 2.0Andre Cronje took inspiration from these developments and embarked on a quest to find a more equitable incentive structure for all participants in the DeFi ecosystem. He proposed a novel idea: what if locked tokens received a share of protocol swap fees only for the pools they voted for? This would encourage users to vote for productive pools, attracting liquidity and increasing swap volume.The (3,3) model, influenced by Olympus and its forks, introduced the concept of dilution, which refers to a user’s share of the protocol. To combat dilution, anti-dilution mechanisms were introduced, ensuring that users who locked their tokens maintained their relative share of the protocol as new tokens were minted.The Ve(3,3) ModelVe(3,3) combines the principles of vote escrow (ve) with the game theory of (3,3). When users lock tokens, they gain voting power and secure their share of the protocol. This model aligns incentives among farmers, stakers, and the DEX itself.Ve(3,3) DEXes have gained prominence in the DeFi landscape, offering attractive opportunities for users. Farmers can provide liquidity, farm tokens, and compound their earnings, capitalizing on these DEXes’ impressive token prices and high APRs.ICHI’s partnership with Ve(3,3) DEXesICHI has recently partnered with Retro, a Ve (3,3) style DEX. By combining Yield IQ’s innovative single-sided liquidity strategy with Retro’s Ve(3,3) model, users gain newfound simplicity, efficiency, and enhanced rewards in their liquidity provisioning journey.The ability to unlock $RETRO for Ve(3,3) participation, along with the introduction of Protocol Owned Liquidity (POL), positions Retro as a leader in sustainable and community-driven DeFi projects. With single-sided $RETRO pools now benefiting liquidity providers, users can enjoy boosted returns and voting rights without sacrificing valuable $RETRO tokens.You can earn yield on $RETRO pools without depositing $RETRO tokens. Instead, use your $RETRO tokens for voting and deposit major assets like wMATIC, wETH, wBTC, USDC, USDT, $CASH, agEUR, MAI, LINK, or stMATIC against $RETRO. Our unique single asset deposit algorithm allows you to supply the supplementary side and start earning rewards. The $RETRO tokens that were previously locked for liquidity provision can now be freed up and locked for veRETRO, where you’ll enjoy boosted returns and gain voting rights.Check out the available pools here.Besides the partnership with Retro, ICHI is also partnering with Ramses, allowing even more users to enjoy this smart liquidity provision strategy. Ramses is the native liquidity layer on Arbitrum, redefining ve(3,3) DEX infrastructure. By intertwining the concept of concentrated liquidity with a proprietary Bribe Infrastructure, Ramses aims to unlock new levels of capital efficiency. You’ll soon be able to provide liquidity to a number of Yield IQ vaults on Ramses and experience smart liquidity provision.Stay tuned.Final ThoughtsThe Ve(3,3) tokenomics model represents a significant step forward in DeFi by incentivizing liquidity provision and fee generation, reducing dependency on large liquidity providers. It aligns the interests of various stakeholders in the ecosystem, promoting long-term synergy. While playing the Ve(3,3) game may entail some risk, the potential for mid to long-term profitability and a healthier DeFi ecosystem makes it a game worth considering for DeFi enthusiasts and investors alike.Ve(3,3) DEXes: A Game-Changer in DeFi Tokenomics was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">ICHI, a Liquidity Management Protocol, Joins Chainlink BUILD</title>
    <published>2023-08-23T13:14:37+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-08-23T13:14:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-a-liquidity-management-protocol-joins-chainlink-build-c833be70f7e2?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/ichi-a-liquidity-management-protocol-joins-chainlink-build-c833be70f7e2?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We’re excited to announce that ICHI is officially joining the Chainlink BUILD program. As a part of BUILD, we aim to accelerate ecosystem growth and the long-term adoption of Yield IQ, an automated liquidity management protocol, by gaining enhanced access to Chainlink’s industry-leading oracle services and technical support, as well as incentivizing greater cryptoeconomic security, in exchange for a commitment to provide network fees and other benefits to the Chainlink community and service providers, including stakers.ICHI has long been an active participant and believer in Chainlink, currently using Chainlink Automation. Our participation in BUILD furthers our integration with Chainlink, with added benefits of priority support from the Chainlink ecosystem, increased access to dApps needing liquidity management, and stronger incentive alignment between the Chainlink and ICHI communities.We’re confident that through enhanced support, secure off-chain services, and the backing of Chainlink’s vibrant community, we can accelerate awareness of ICHI and realize the adoption of auto-liquidity management.ICHI: Powering Sustainable On-Chain Rewards and Deep LiquidityICHI’s mission is to revolutionize the DeFi space by offering an efficient and user-friendly platform for liquidity provision. Its ultimate goal is to help token holders accrue income, mitigating risks, and maximizing returns in an unpredictable and often volatile market. Through the easy-to-use platform, single-asset depositors can receive rewards as the liquidity provision algorithm generates yield on Uniswap v3. The dApp is currently deployed on Ethereum,Polygon and Arbitrum, with more chains on the horizon.Why We Joined Chainlink BUILDICHI joined BUILD to maximize the benefits of security and reliability that Chainlink’s oracle infrastructure provides. As part of BUILD, ICHI will receive key benefits, including access to and integration of Chainlink Price Feeds and access to new Chainlink product alpha and beta releases, among other benefits.In exchange for these services, ICHI will make a percentage of its native token supply available to Chainlink service providers, including stakers, over time. These mutually aligned economic incentives enable both communities to support one another.“We’re excited to join Chainlink BUILD to gain access to industry-standard oracle services, technical support, and a robust cryptoeconomic model that empowers us to build Yield IQ with greater security assurances. We look forward to continuing our collaboration together and we welcome the passionate Chainlink community into the ICHI ecosystem.” — Bryan Gross, Founder of ICHI.About ChainlinkChainlink is the industry-standard Web3 services platform. It has enabled trillions of dollars in transaction volume across DeFi, on-chain finance, gaming, NFTs, and other major industries. As the leading decentralized oracle network, Chainlink empowers developers to build feature-rich Web3 applications with seamless access to real-world data, off-chain computation, and cross-chain interoperability across any blockchain, providing global enterprises with a universal gateway to all blockchains.Learn more about Chainlink by visiting chain.link or reading the developer documentation at docs.chain.link. To discuss an integration, reach out to an expert.About ICHIICHI is a trustless market-making protocol that enables the use of sophisticated algorithmic strategies on Uniswap V3. Grow any token with low-slippage, on-chain liquidity using ICHI’s Yield IQ vaults.Learn more by visiting the ICHI website, Medium, Twitter, Telegram, or Discord.ICHI, a Liquidity Management Protocol, Joins Chainlink BUILD was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Layer2DAO Joins Forces with Yield IQ for Smart Liquidity Provision</title>
    <published>2023-08-10T15:01:39+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-08-10T15:01:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/layer2dao-joins-forces-with-yield-iq-for-smart-liquidity-provision-c6fb50587866?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/layer2dao-joins-forces-with-yield-iq-for-smart-liquidity-provision-c6fb50587866?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Layer2DAO leverages Yield IQ, bringing smarter liquidity provision strategies to its community.DAOs UniteYield IQ, the revolutionary tool offering new revenue streams for token holders has partnered with Layer2DAO, a dynamic community-driven decentralized organization in the Layer 2 ecosystem. This collaboration aims to provide the Layer2DAO community with an efficient, profitable, and user-friendly platform for liquidity provision. Let’s explore the key highlights of this partnership.Empowering Token Holders with New Revenue StreamsTo kick off this collaboration, Yield IQ has launched a dedicated vault on app.ichi.org — L2DAO/WETH. Users can now simply deposit their L2DAO tokens (single-sided) and benefit from optimized liquidity provision, earning trading fees while mitigating risks, all within the secure and transparent environment.As a testament to the commitment towards fostering this partnership, ICHI has further provided $1000 USD worth of ICHI tokens to Layer2DAO. These tokens will be utilized as staking rewards for L2DAO members over a four-week period. By doing so, Yield IQ is offering L2DAO users exposure to the ICHI token, enhancing their DeFi journey with access to additional opportunities.DAO to DAO Token SwapLayer2DAO and ICHI will facilitate a DAO token swap on Arbitrum with a value of $5,000 USD, locked for an impressive duration of 12 months via Hedgey. This allows both projects to diversify their treasuries and reduce vulnerability to sudden drops in token prices.As many DAO treasuries primarily consist of their native tokens, any significant decline in token value can jeopardize the project’s financial stability. By engaging in open and collaborative token swaps with other DeFi protocols, DAOs can build stronger partnerships, foster deeper ties between communities, and ensure mutual benefits while diversifying their assets. Token swaps enable DAOs to tap into the strengths and expertise of partner projects, creating a more cohesive and interconnected DeFi ecosystem.How Does Yield IQ Work?Yield IQ’s process is simple and efficient. Users deposit their preferred tokens into the platform, and Yield IQ allocates these tokens into concentrated liquidity AMMs, such as Uniswap V3, without initiating any swaps. In return, users receive LP tokens representing their share in the liquidity pool.The true magic unfolds as Yield IQ, powered by Chainlink Automation, dynamically adjusts the concentrated liquidity position based on token arrangements and real-time market conditions. Users earn trading fees when trades occur, supplementing potential token appreciation. With vigilant oversight of token composition, Yield IQ guards against harmful arbitrage and market shifts. Users can withdraw their initial deposit and earnings at any time by exchanging LP tokens for their share of assets in the vault.About Layer2DAOLayer2DAO is a decentralized autonomous organization dedicated to driving the widespread adoption of Layer 2 protocols within the Ethereum ecosystem. With the completion of the Ethereum merge, it has become increasingly clear that layer2 solutions are vital for the future growth and scalability of Ethereum.As the leading Ethereum L2 DAO, Layer2DAO is committed to expanding the L2 ecosystem by investing in and partnering with high-impact L2 protocols and ecosystem initiatives. The DAO utilizes its treasury strategically to support projects that show promise and contribute to the growth of the Layer 2 ecosystem. Moreover, Layer2DAO actively engages in liquidity provisioning, NFT creation, and various value-adding activities that reinvest proceeds back into the DAO.About Yield IQYield IQ is a fully automated, single sided concentrated liquidity provision strategy. By making rebalancing decisions based on token composition instead of token price, Yield IQ limits divergent loss and generates industry leading results. True to the spirit of DeFi, Yield IQ is governed by a self-executing smart contract, ensuring impartiality and decentralization. This ensures unrestricted, permissionless access and unalterable protocol behavior, serving as a truly decentralized financial tool.Learn more by visiting the ICHI website, Medium, Twitter, Telegram, or Discord.Layer2DAO Joins Forces with Yield IQ for Smart Liquidity Provision was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Stepping Up the Game: Yield IQ Supercharges Retro’s Ve(3,3) Model</title>
    <published>2023-08-01T13:45:39+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-08-01T13:45:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/stepping-up-the-game-yield-iq-supercharges-retros-ve-3-3-model-6e5fa945185e?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/stepping-up-the-game-yield-iq-supercharges-retros-ve-3-3-model-6e5fa945185e?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Retro and Yield IQ join forces to provide a more inclusive, efficient and rewarding DeFi experience.We are thrilled to unveil the groundbreaking combination of Yield IQ’s innovative single-sided liquidity strategy with Retro’s Ve(3,3) model. This powerful fusion leverages the force and finesse of Yield IQ and Retro, complemented by the Merkl reward system, to revolutionize liquidity provision and participation within Retro’s ecosystem.The introduction of a Ve(3,3) style DEX further enhances the voting experience. By locking your tokens, you gain influence over emission destinations, earning fees and rewards from the pools you support. This incentivizes users to thoughtfully consider their votes and helps steer the DEX in the right direction, promoting a community-driven ecosystem.Each RETRO token holds significant value as it becomes a voting power, redirecting cashflows — directly influencing the trading fee allocation. For example, you can deposit BTC, USDC or ETH and vote yourself into the income stream that yields the most returns, as you have the power to support the pool which you have deposited into. Yield IQ allows you to deposit single-sidedly — only the token that trades against RETRO and you’re able to use your RETRO for votes.Why Yield IQ? Simplicity and results. It offers:Single-token liquidity depositsAutomated management that grows deposits of this tokenVigilantly adjusts the liquidity composition between the two tokens, mitigating the risk of over-selling the deposited tokenDeposit major assets: You can earn yield on $RETRO pools without depositing $RETRO tokens. Instead, use your $RETRO tokens for voting and deposit major assets like wMATIC, wETH, wBTC, USDC, USDT, $CASH, agEUR, MAI, LINK, or stMATIC against $RETRO. Our unique single asset deposit algorithm allows you to supply the supplementary side and start earning rewards. The $RETRO tokens that were previously locked for liquidity provision can now be freed up and locked for veRETRO, where you’ll enjoy boosted returns and gain voting rights.This means you can use veRETRO in voting to drive more rewards to these major asset pools. Merkl’s reward system keeps track of LPs positions and seamlessly allocates the $oRETRO emissions for those who vote.Flip the coin, and you’ll find Retro as the exclusive provider of $RETRO in the liquidity pool — meaning it is building protocol owned liquidity. The best part? Voters are rewarded with all the trading fees from the pool for bringing in the major assets that trade against $RETRO.The strategy behind integrating Yield IQ and the Merkl reward setup is three-fold:Unlock $RETRO for Ve(3,3) Participation: Let’s not keep your $RETRO tokens tied up in liquidity pools. In Ve(3,3) models, the highest purpose of the token is to be locked for voting rights and benefits. Yield IQ ensures your tokens are put to their best use. Gain the upper hand in voting for trading fee allocation and enhancing returns.It has proven tricky to manage Uniswap V3 liquidity: Protect your deposits with an advanced strategy to avoid ending up with the least valuable token. Eliminate the complexity and time-consuming nature of swapping token mixes and setting price ranges. With Yield IQ, this intricate process is simplified and streamlined. Experience a deposit process as effortless as staking, where you can securely deposit your tokens and let our algorithm diligently manage and grow your deposited token.It introduces Protocol Owned Liquidity (POL): Many web3 projects falter once initial incentives dwindle. Retro aims to avert this by being the lone contributor of $RETRO liquidity in all $RETRO pools and seeding $250k worth of major assets. This approach increases the buy-side pressure for the $RETRO token through POL. The optimized Merkl reward mechanism ensures fair distribution of rewards, incentivizing the injection of major assets and aligning perfectly with the principles of automated market makers (AMMs). Retro’s strategy takes a long-term view and aims to sustain and enhance the project’s ecosystem.Single Sided $RETRO Pools Benefit Liquidity ProvidersLet’s walk through a hypothetical deposit to the wMATIC-$RETRO pool between a traditional 50/50 strategy and Yield IQ.Traditional 50/50 liquidity strategies require users to deposit their $RETRO tokens into the liquidity pool, resulting in missed opportunities for token locking and voting rights, as well as reduced returns. Moreover, users may experience higher permanent losses due to the absence of token over-sell protection.Yield IQ’s single-sided liquidity provision offers a game-changing alternative. Users can now save their $RETRO tokens and lock them for veRETRO, while still earning fees from the pool. This approach allows users to enjoy boosted returns and additional incentives on top of fee returns, while benefiting from deposit token over-sell protection, resulting in a smaller permanent loss.Recognizing the clear advantages, Retro has optimized its $RETRO pools and enabled single-sided liquidity provision exclusively via Yield IQ vaults. This means that every user now has the opportunity to safeguard their $RETRO tokens and maximize their payouts from liquidity provision.Table 2. Hypothetical Deposit &amp;amp; Return ComparisonFinal thoughtsThe collaboration between Yield IQ and Retro marks a significant step forward in revolutionizing liquidity provision and governance participation within Retro’s ecosystem. By combining Yield IQ’s innovative single-sided liquidity strategy with Retro’s Ve(3,3) model, users gain newfound simplicity, efficiency, and enhanced rewards in their liquidity provisioning journey.The ability to unlock $RETRO for Ve(3,3) participation, along with the introduction of Protocol Owned Liquidity (POL), positions Retro as a leader in sustainable and community-driven DeFi projects. With single-sided $RETRO pools now benefiting liquidity providers, users can enjoy boosted returns and voting rights without sacrificing valuable $RETRO tokens. Embracing this cutting-edge approach sets a new standard for decentralized finance and solidifies Retro’s commitment to creating a robust and prosperous ecosystem for its community. As we venture into this exciting new era, Yield IQ and Retro pave the way for a more inclusive, efficient, and rewarding DeFi experience.Can’t wait to get started?Yield IQ on Retro is available at retro.finance. Experience smarter liquidity provision.Learn more by visiting the ICHI website, Medium, Twitter, Telegram, or Discord.Stepping Up the Game: Yield IQ Supercharges Retro’s Ve(3,3) Model was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Retro Integrates Yield IQ: Unlocking Profitable Liquidity Provision Strategies</title>
    <published>2023-07-25T16:26:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-07-25T16:26:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ichifarm/retro-integrates-yield-iq-unlocking-profitable-liquidity-provision-strategies-a0fc171e4b8e?source=rss----85c80db45651---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ichifarm/retro-integrates-yield-iq-unlocking-profitable-liquidity-provision-strategies-a0fc171e4b8e?source=rss----85c80db45651---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>ICHI</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Retro partners with Yield IQ, unlocking new revenue streams for its users.We are thrilled to announce our partnership with Retro, a leading ve(3,3) decentralized exchange (DEX) and a new automated liquidity management marketplace on Polygon. Together, we are revolutionizing the world of liquidity provision and yield generation, creating an ecosystem that combines the power of Yield IQ’s strategy with Retro’s innovative platform. We’re super excited to collaborate with like-minded individuals and projects — working towards building a strong and sustainable DeFi ecosystem.Access Yield IQ on RetroOne of the key highlights of this partnership is the integration of the Yield IQ algorithm into the Retro front end. This integration ensures that Retro users can benefit from advanced yield optimization techniques while providing liquidity and earning trading fees. We’re here to support DEXs who wish to integrate our product and offer accessible and profitable liquidity management.The process is relatively straightforward. First, you deposit your preferred token. Yield IQ then allocates these tokens into a concentrated liquidity AMM, such as Uniswap V3, without any swap occurring prior to this deployment. In return, you receive LP tokens, a representation of your share in the liquidity pool.Here’s where the magic happens: Yield IQ, powered by Chainlink Automation, adjusts the concentrated liquidity position based on the token’s arrangement and market conditions. When trades occur, you earn trading fees, supplementing any appreciation of your token. Yield IQ consistently oversees token composition to guard against harmful arbitrage and drastic market shifts. When you’re ready, you can withdraw your initial deposit and earnings at any time by exchanging your LP tokens for your share of the assets in the vault.What Is Retro?Retro is not just another DEX. It is a solution designed specifically for protocols on Polygon, offering incentivized liquidity provision. Retro provides a unique blend of innovative ve(3,3) tokenomics, delivering higher yields and enhanced liquidity opportunities.Retro is a friendly fork of Thena (liquidity layer &amp;amp; AMM) and Uniswap V3 Concentrated Liquidity. Retro is collaborating closely with Thena to exchange ideas and features as they both work towards their respective visions. Just like Thena, Retro has introduced two pool types: concentrated liquidity pools for volatile asset pairs and Stableswap pools for stable asset pairs. Concentrated liquidity pools enhance swap efficiency, offering increased market depth, tighter spreads, and reduced slippage costs. This stability not only benefits individual traders but also contributes to a healthier and more vibrant swaps market, generating organic fees for veRETRO voters.Additionally, Retro is proud to integrate Stabl Labs’ $CASH yield-bearing stable index token into the protocol from launch. This integration will provide bribe revenue to veRETRO voters, enhancing the incentives and utility of the Retro ecosystem. Furthermore, their team plans to introduce unique elements that fully leverage the ve(3,3) model, benefitting all stakeholders and adding utility to the $CASH token.Retro stands out by incorporating multiple active liquidity managers into their app, such as Gamma and ICHI, to simplify and maximize liquidity provision on concentrated liquidity DEXs. This approach creates a one of a kind ALM marketplace enhancing decentralization, resilience, and efficiency, ensuring a dynamic and evolving ecosystem for liquidity providers.Leveraging Merkl for Customizable EmissionsRetro will leverage Merkl, developed by Angle Labs, to distribute emissions in a flexible and efficient manner. Merkl enables incentivizers to tailor their distribution strategies based on factors such as liquidity volume, price ranges, or specific token holders. LPs can earn rewards without additional risks or smart contract interactions, ensuring a seamless and rewarding experience.Looking AheadThe partnership between Yield IQ and Retro marks an exciting milestone in the world of decentralized finance. By integrating Yield IQ’s powerful strategy and algorithm into Retro’s frontend, LPs can enjoy efficient and profitable liquidity provision. Combined with the ability to earn trading fees, appreciate token values, and withdraw liquidity seamlessly, the Yield IQ and Retro partnership offers a compelling solution for LPs seeking maximum yield in the DeFi space.How Can I Access Yield IQ?Yield IQ is available on Uniswap V3 (Polygon) at app.ichi.org and will also be available on Retro, with plans for additional platforms on the horizon.Unleash the power of liquidity provision with Yield IQ.About Yield IQYield IQ is a fully automated, single sided concentrated liquidity provision strategy. By making rebalancing decisions based on token composition instead of token price, Yield IQ limits divergent loss and offers an efficient, profitable and user-friendly platform for liquidity provision. True to the spirit of DeFi, Yield IQ is governed by a self-executing smart contract, ensuring impartiality and decentralization. This ensures unrestricted, permissionless access and unalterable protocol behavior, serving as a truly decentralized financial tool.Learn more by visiting the ICHI website, Medium, Twitter, Telegram, or Discord.About RetroRetro is an upcoming ve(3,3) DEX on the Polygon blockchain. Retro will include battle tested value features for veRETRO holders, such as concentrated liquidity. Additionally, several key innovations will be introduced, such as gauge autobribes from $CASH yields, among others. Retro is scheduled to launch in the month of July.Join Retro community on Discord or visit their Twitter to learn more.Retro Integrates Yield IQ: Unlocking Profitable Liquidity Provision Strategies was originally published in ICHI on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
