<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Soroswap - Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/soroswap?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fsoroswap&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fsoroswap&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:09:59+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Monitor the Health of Soroswap on Alterscope</title>
    <published>2025-03-26T16:23:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-26T16:23:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/soroswap/monitor-the-health-of-soroswap-on-alterscope-adfc1f965667?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/soroswap/monitor-the-health-of-soroswap-on-alterscope-adfc1f965667?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Jenny T.</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Alterscope is a risk infrastructure that monitors the health of DeFi protocols like Soroswap Finance, evaluating key metrics such as liquidity, volume, security, and community reputation. It enables risk management by analyzing metrics and providing tools for informed decision-making.The decentralized finance (DeFi) ecosystem has experienced exponential growth in recent years, opening new opportunities for users and investors worldwide. However, this growth has also brought challenges, such as the need to manage risks and assess the strength of the protocols in which trust is placed. In this context, Alterscope positions itself as an innovative solution, offering users the ability to monitor the status of various DeFi protocols in real-time, including those integrated within the Stellar ecosystem.What Does Alterscope Do?It is a real-time infrastructure that helps people understand and manage risks in the world of decentralized finance (DeFi). It analyzes and processes risks across chains, protocols, and liquidity pools, reviewing key aspects such as security, price stability, and changes in rules. This enables users to make more informed and secure decisions about where to invest or how to protect their assets. Essentially, it simplifies the complex information of DeFi so that anyone can operate with greater confidence and clarity.What Information Does Alterscope Provide About Soroswap?The Score Chart visualizes the value of the aggregated score and its subscore values for the Soroswap protocol over a specific period, which can be 7 days or one month. The green represents development, the red reflects the overall evaluation, the orange indicates liquidity, and the brown refers to the social aspect.The General Security Parameters shows no reported hacks, a stable non-upgradable system, no bounty program for vulnerabilities, and team transparency with public information.This graph illustrates Development Activity by showing the proportion of contributions from the lead contributor compared to others. This is important because excessive reliance on a single person could pose a risk to the project’s sustainability.Soroswap has been audited by two independent entities to assess its security.- OtterSec: Conducted an audit on December 27, 2023.- Runtime Verification Inc: Performed an audit on August 31, 2024, identifying and categorizing issues based on their severity (critical, high, medium, low, and informational).In the liquidity section, the market dynamics of Soroswap are analyzed, focusing on asset price stability and the health of the liquidity pools. It includes the Total Value Locked (TVL), expressed in USD, which is updated daily at midnight. The TVL chart tracks changes over time, helping our users assess liquidity and market strength.The Markets section displays key metrics of Soroswap, such as the Total Value Locked (TVL), 24-hour volume, generated fees, and liquidity score. These metrics allow users to assess the activity and stability of the protocol.The Social section shows how the Soroswap community interacts and views the project. The Social Score measures engagement and reputation based on daily activity and messages.We invite you to try Soroswap Finance Make your first SWAP and discover a simple and reliable way to manage your digital assets.About Soroswap.Finance 🪐Soroswap.Finance is the first decentralized exchange (DEX) on the Soroban Blockchain, setting a new benchmark in cryptocurrency trading. As a trailblazer in the Stellar Development Foundation, provides an advanced platform for fast, cost-effective token swaps without intermediaries.Developed by Paltalabs 🥑, this open-source protocol ensures a secure and efficient trading experience, featuring minimal fees and a structure resistant to censorship. By using Soroswap.Finance, you gain access to an innovative solution in decentralized finance, optimizing both security and accessibility in managing your digital assets.Join Us!Website | GitHub | Twitter| Documentation | Discord |LinkedinPaltaLabs Website | PaltaLabs Twitter | PaltaLabs LinkedinMonitor the Health of Soroswap on Alterscope was originally published in Soroswap on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">USDX from the FxDAO protocol, is now available on Soroswap Finance</title>
    <published>2024-11-13T17:08:02+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-13T17:08:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/soroswap/usdx-from-the-fxdao-protocol-is-now-available-on-soroswap-finance-9ab8df222910?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/soroswap/usdx-from-the-fxdao-protocol-is-now-available-on-soroswap-finance-9ab8df222910?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Jenny T.</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">USDx from the FxDAO protocol is now available on Soroswap Finance! You can get USDx directly on Soroswap and swap it for any other token on our AMM. We have a $190,000 TVL liquidity pool for the XLM/USDx pair.Through the FxDAO protocol, you can issue stablecoins by locking Lumens as collateral in “Vaults” giving you access to liquidity without selling your Lumens.USDx from the FxDAO protocol, is now available on Soroswap Finance, and we’re thrilled to explore what makes USDx so captivating and revolutionary! Curious about how to get involved with the FxDAO protocol? Want to learn how to navigate Soroswap’s interface? And what does this development mean for the Stellar community? Let’s dive into all of this in this article!Soroswap Has a $190,000 Liquidity Pool in the XLM/USDx PairSoroswap has a liquidity pool of $190,000 for the XLM/USDx pair.Soroswap offers various liquidity pools with a total TVL (Total Value Locked) of $385.62k. Within the platform, the XLM/USDx pair stands out as the largest liquidity pool, with a total of $190,000 in locked value, provided by users who have deposited funds in the form of XLM and USDx.What Makes USDx So Revolutionary?USDx is an innovative stablecoin from the FxDAO protocol, a decentralised lending protocol that enables users to issue stablecoins by locking Lumens as collateral. This provides liquidity without the need to sell assets while allowing loans to be issued in multiple currencies (USD, EUR, GBP) with a minimum collateral ratio to prevent liquidation. FxDAO also empowers users by involving them in protocol governance.How Can I Get USDx?You can easily obtain USDx by purchasing it directly on Soroswap. Simply hold any token from our list, and swap it through our protocol. It’s that straightforward — get your USDx and start unlocking the potential of the Stellar ecosystem.What Can I Do with My USDx Now?With your USDx, you can do several things on Soroswap Finance:Swap it: Exchange your USDx for any other token available on Soroswap and take advantage of market opportunities.Maybe you can swap it for USDC and lend it on Blend.Capital to get a yield!Provide liquidity: Join the XLM/USDx pool and earn rewards through swap fees.Hold it as a stablecoin: Keep USDx as a stable option.or Participate in the FxDAO protocolHow to Participate in the FxDAO ProtocolAccess the Platform: Visit the FxDAO website at https://app.fxdao.io/ to start the process.Once you’re on the platform, connect your wallet. You have several options available: Lobstr, xBull, Freighter, and Albedo. If you’re unsure which to choose, check out our Guide to Choosing a Wallet for the Stellar Network.Select “Create USDx Vault” to use your Lumens as collateral and issue USDx. Specify the amount of Lumens to lock and the USDx you wish to receive. You’ll see the collateralization ratio (minimum 115%) and platform fees, allowing you to access liquidity without selling your assets.You need to confirm the transactions. The first is to establish the trustline, which adds the token to your wallet; the second is to approve the transaction. Make sure to review and approve both actions to proceed with the USDx issuance process.In this section, you can view the details of your USDx vault. Total Debt shows the issued amount (100 USDx), and Total Collateral indicates the locked collateral (1,215.4539438 XLM). The Collateral Rate is 115.58%. From here, you can Pay Debt to reduce your debt, Increase Collateral to add more Lumens, or Increase Debt to issue more USDx.You’re all set! You now have your USDx in your wallet. You can use your stablecoins to make transactions and take advantage of opportunities within the Stellar ecosystem. Here, we’ll show you how to use Soroswap to get the most out of your USDx.Now that you have your USDx, let’s do a SWAP on Soroswap.Finance 🪐With your USDx in hand, you’re ready to swap it for any token! Whether you want to convert back to XLM or trade it for USDC, the choice is yours.Set Protocol and Trustlines: Soroswap automatically selects the best protocol, but you can choose between SDEX, Soroswap AMM, or Phoenix AMM. Be sure to set a trustline for USDx to manage assets in your wallet.Congratulations! You have successfully completed your swap. Now you can verify and confirm your transaction on Stellar Explorer. Simply enter your wallet address or the transaction ID.We hope you can make your swaps and provide liquidity on Soroswap Finance, whether it’s with the XLM/USDx pair or any other you choose. Follow us to stay updated on the latest news and opportunities on our platform!About Soroswap.Finance 🪐Soroswap.Finance is the first decentralized exchange (DEX) on the Soroban Blockchain, setting a new benchmark in cryptocurrency trading. As a trailblazer in the Stellar Development Foundation, provides an advanced platform for fast, cost-effective token swaps without intermediaries.Developed by Paltalabs 🥑, this open-source protocol ensures a secure and efficient trading experience, featuring minimal fees and a structure resistant to censorship. By using Soroswap.Finance, you gain access to an innovative solution in decentralized finance, optimizing both security and accessibility in managing your digital assets.Join Us!Website | GitHub | Twitter| Documentation | Discord |LinkedinPaltaLabs Website | PaltaLabs Twitter | PaltaLabs LinkedinUSDX from the FxDAO protocol, is now available on Soroswap Finance was originally published in Soroswap on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Easily Swap Tokens on Soroswap from Your Mobile with Hana Wallet</title>
    <published>2024-10-30T19:42:06+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-30T19:42:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/soroswap/easily-swap-tokens-on-soroswap-from-your-mobile-with-hana-wallet-54e74f4b223a?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/soroswap/easily-swap-tokens-on-soroswap-from-your-mobile-with-hana-wallet-54e74f4b223a?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Jenny T.</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Swap tokens on Soroswap from your mobile, available in the Hana Wallet DApps directory. This integration makes ie easy to exchange ANY Stellar token like $XLM or $USDC. Discover how simple it is to manage your assets on the Stellar blockchain!Hana Wallet is a digital wallet designed for usability and security, enabling efficient management of Stellar blockchain assets across various devices. Its integrated browser facilitates seamless interaction with decentralized applications (dApps) within the Soroban ecosystem. Additionally, users can perform transactions without KYC, offering a streamlined and direct experience in decentralized finance.The combination of Hana Wallet and Soroswap enables users to quickly and securely exchange Stellar tokens, such as XLM or USDC, as well as other assets, right from their mobile device. With an intuitive interface, it’s easy for new users to make swaps without complications.Installing Hana Wallet on Your MobileHere’s a step-by-step guide to installing Hana Wallet on your mobile device:Download the App: Visit your device’s app store (App Store for iOS or Google Play for Android) and search for “Hana Wallet.” Download and install the app.2. Create an Account: Once the app is installed, open it and select the option to create a new account. Associate an email and follow the on-screen instructions to set up your wallet.Security: During the setup process, you’ll be prompted to establish security measures, such as a password or PIN. Be sure to choose something secure and easy to remember.3. Select the Stellar Network: Choose the Stellar network and ensure it is active. You can enable or disable it as needed.4. Access Soroswap Finance: Open the app directory in Hana Wallet, type “Soroswap Finance” in the search bar, and select it to access the platform. From there, you can start making swaps effortlessly!Video guide on using Soroswap with Hana WalletTo enhance your experience with Soroswap Finance, we encourage you to check out CriptoRoberto’s video tutorial. In this video, you’ll learn how to use the Hana Wallet app and easily swap $XLM and $USDC on Soroswap directly from your mobile device. This is a great way to simplify your token exchanges right at your fingertips. The tutorial is in Spanish and is designed to be intuitive, making it easy for you to follow along. Don’t miss out!https://medium.com/media/212eb85ebd732fb3ea5a96def6fa0927/hrefSwapping tokens on Soroswap.Finance through Hana Wallet is a quick and user-friendly experience. By following our simple installation guide and exploring the intuitive features of Hana Wallet, you can effortlessly manage your assets on the Stellar blockchain from your mobile device. Take advantage of the simplicity and security of decentralized finance with Soroswap and take control of your digital assets today!About Soroswap.Finance 🪐Soroswap.Finance is the first decentralized exchange (DEX) on the Soroban Blockchain, setting a new benchmark in cryptocurrency trading. As a trailblazer in the Stellar Development Foundation, provides an advanced platform for fast, cost-effective token swaps without intermediaries.Developed by Paltalabs 🥑, this open-source protocol ensures a secure and efficient trading experience, featuring minimal fees and a structure resistant to censorship. By using Soroswap.Finance, you gain access to an innovative solution in decentralized finance, optimizing both security and accessibility in managing your digital assets.Join Us!Website | GitHub | Twitter| Documentation | Discord |LinkedinPaltaLabs Website | PaltaLabs Twitter | PaltaLabs LinkedinEasily Swap Tokens on Soroswap from Your Mobile with Hana Wallet was originally published in Soroswap on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How Runtime Verification Helped Soroswap Transform Into an AMM Aggregator</title>
    <published>2024-10-03T16:20:15+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-03T16:20:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/soroswap/how-runtime-verification-helped-soroswap-transform-into-an-amm-aggregator-fb63aa41ac49?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/soroswap/how-runtime-verification-helped-soroswap-transform-into-an-amm-aggregator-fb63aa41ac49?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>esteblock</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Soroswap.Finance started as the first smart contract-based decentralized exchange (DEX) on the Stellar blockchain. We aimed to lead innovation on this new platform by allowing Stellar projects to provide liquidity and swap their Soroban-based tokens along with classic Stellar assets.However, as other Automated Market Makers (AMMs) began to emerge, liquidity across platforms became fragmented. This led to less efficiency and higher swap slippage for users. To tackle this, we decided to develop the Soroswap Aggregator — an AMM aggregator for the Soroban-Stellar blockchain that pools liquidity from various AMMs to improve user experience.The Soroswap Aggregator contracts were developed by the PaltaLabs 🥑 team and audited by Runtime Verification, a top-notch audit firm.In this post, I’ll share how this partnership helped us secure our protocol and what we learned along the way.The Stellar Audit Bank ProgramThe Stellar Audit Bank, by the Stellar Development Foundation (SDF), helps projects like Soroswap secure audits before launching on the Stellar Mainnet. It’s one of many SDF support initiatives. Another is the Stellar Community Fund, where teams can receive up to $150,000 in funding.Soroswap.Finance has received grants in XLM, valued at around $296.8k USD, from the Stellar Community Fund. This support has been crucial for our growth. For our latest Soroswap Aggregator protocol, SDF helped us partner with Runtime Verification, who audited the PaltaLabs team’s contracts to ensure top-notch security and performance.Working with Runtime VerificationCollaborating with Runtime Verification was a highly engaging and collaborative process. Over the course of three weeks, we had regular meetings where the team thoroughly analyzed every aspect of our code and protocol. Their expertise helped identify key areas of improvement, and their hands-on approach ensured that we understood the reasoning behind every suggestion.One aspect of the audit that stood out was how invested the Runtime Verification team was in fully understanding not only our code but also the logic and goals behind our protocol. They didn’t just identify potential vulnerabilities — they took the time to understand the business and technical logic behind Soroswap Aggregator. In fact, they even created detailed diagrams in the final audit report that explained how our protocol works, adding an extra layer of clarity and precision.Our weekly meetings, combined with a private Discord channel for quick communication, allowed us to maintain a steady flow of information. This open line of communication was crucial for addressing any questions or concerns in real-time, ensuring that we were always aligned and moving forward efficiently.Key Lessons LearnedWhile most of the findings in the audit were not critical, they provided us with valuable insights for future developments. One of the most important lessons we learned was the use of a deployer contract to avoid potential contract hijacking. This advice will be crucial for our smart contract deployments moving forward.The findings and suggestions from the audit process have helped shape the future of Soroswap’s smart contract architecture. For those curious, you can explore how we addressed each finding by checking the “audit” keyword in the closed Issues section of our GitHub repository.ConclusionOur experience with Runtime Verification has been incredibly rewarding. The team not only improved the security of our smart contracts but also helped us understand our protocol on a deeper level. If you’re building on the blockchain and are considering an audit, I highly recommend undergoing the process. It will elevate the security and reliability of your project, giving you and your users greater confidence.If you’re interested in learning more about Soroswap.Finance, make sure to follow our journey:GitHub: SoroswapTwitter (X): Soroswap.FinanceWebsite: soroswap.financeDocs: Soroswap DocumentationYoutube: SoroswapFinancePaltaLabs Website: paltalabs.ioPaltaLabs Twitter (X): PaltaLabsPaltaLabs Youtube: PaltaLabsMy Personal Twitter (X): @esteblock_devHow Runtime Verification Helped Soroswap Transform Into an AMM Aggregator was originally published in Soroswap on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Protocol Selection: Customize Your Swapping Experience</title>
    <published>2024-09-24T18:35:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-24T18:35:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/soroswap/protocol-selection-customize-your-swapping-experience-c1847ae44b8f?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/soroswap/protocol-selection-customize-your-swapping-experience-c1847ae44b8f?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Jenny T.</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Soroswap automatically choose the best protocol for your swaps, and you can also manually choose your preferred one.The New Feature: Protocol SelectionAt Soroswap Finance, we aim to provide you with the best swap experience by automatically choosing the optimal protocol based on current prices. Soroswap automatically chooses the best protocol available at the moment. Now, you also have the option to manually select your preferred protocol for trades. While we currently support Soroswap AMM and SDEX, this is temporary, as we plan to support more protocols in the future.What Protocols are currently supported?The Soroswap.Finance Protocol currenly supports both its own Liquidity Pools (The Soroswap AMM) and the Stellar Classic DEX (SDEX)SDEX: The Stellar Decentralized Exchange (SDEX) is the Classic Descentralized Exchange that existed even before the Soroban Smart Contract Platform. It currently has the biggest Liquidity Pools on Stellar, and its important to take this pools into consideration!Soroswap AMM: These are our own Soroban based Liquidity Pools. Currently we have more than 225k USD in Liquidity. You can check our pools hereHow to Use This New FeatureUtilizing the Protocol Selection feature is straightforward:Access Soroswap Finance: Visit the Soroswap Finance platform.2. Select a Token: Choose the token you wish to exchange from the dropdown menu .3. Explore the Protocol Options: Customize your transaction To optimize your swap, you can customize your protocol settings as follows:Access Protocol Settings: Go to the settings menu during the swap process.By default, both Soroswap AMM and SDEX protocols are activated, ensuring your swap is optimized for the best performance.To select only Soroswap AMM, simply toggle the switch next to it to turn it on, ensuring that the switch for SDEX is turned off. The button will display “On” for Soroswap and “Off” for SDEX, confirming your selection.To select only SDEX, toggle the switch next to it to turn it on, making sure the switch for Soroswap AMM is turned off. The button will display “On” for SDEX and “Off” for Soroswap, confirming your selection.This flexibility allows you to choose the protocol that best fits your trading strategy, ensuring optimal performance for your transaction.Example: How to Identify the Protocol in UseSoroswap automatically shows which protocol is being used for your swap. Below are two examples of how this appears:Swap Using Soroswap AMMIn this scenario, Soroswap automatically chooses the best protocol based on the prices available at the moment, selecting Soroswap AMM. You’ll see “Soroswap AMM” displayed in the “Platform” section, indicating that Soroswap’s liquidity pools are being utilized due to favorable pricing.Swap Using SDEXIn this case, Soroswap automatically chooses the best protocol based on the available prices, selecting SDEX. The “Platform” section will display “SDEX,” indicating that this protocol was chosen for its better rates at that moment.These examples illustrate how Soroswap automatically selects the best protocol based on real-time conditions. However, you can always choose your preferred protocol.Benefits of Controlling Your Swap ExperienceThe Protocol Selection feature offers several key benefits:Enhanced Flexibility: Adapt trading strategies in real-time by selecting the best protocols.Optimized Trading Conditions: Improve efficiency and effectiveness of trades with the right protocol.Increased Control: Make informed decisions based on personal criteria.These benefits contribute to a more rewarding and personalized trading experience.About Soroswap.Finance 🪐Soroswap.Finance is the first decentralized exchange (DEX) on the Soroban Blockchain, setting a new benchmark in cryptocurrency trading. As a trailblazer in the Stellar Development Foundation, provides an advanced platform for fast, cost-effective token swaps without intermediaries.Developed by Paltalabs 🥑, this open-source protocol ensures a secure and efficient trading experience, featuring minimal fees and a structure resistant to censorship. By using Soroswap.Finance, you gain access to an innovative solution in decentralized finance, optimizing both security and accessibility in managing your digital assets.Join Us!Website | GitHub | Twitter| Documentation | DiscordPaltaLabs Website | PaltaLabs TwitterProtocol Selection: Customize Your Swapping Experience was originally published in Soroswap on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">$NGNC Listing Announcement on Soroswap.Finance</title>
    <published>2024-09-03T14:42:52+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-03T14:42:52+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/soroswap/ngnc-listing-announcement-on-soroswap-finance-a0d1e654b5a7?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/soroswap/ngnc-listing-announcement-on-soroswap-finance-a0d1e654b5a7?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Jenny T.</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Soroswap.Finance X NGNCWe are thrilled to announce that $NGNC, a stablecoin pegged 1:1 to Nigeria’s official currency, the Naira, is now listed on Soroswap.Finance. This milestone marks a significant step forward for our platform, enhancing liquidity opportunities and asset exchange capabilities for our users.What is NGNC?NGNC, is a stablecoin pegged 1:1 to the Nigerian Naira, designed for cross-border payments and to support the future of internet value for the next billion Africans. By combining the stability of the Naira with the efficiency and security of blockchain technology, NGNC provides a reliable digital currency for both individuals and businesses seeking a dependable and efficient store of value.https://medium.com/media/a60fb522ae5b724cfe4d793878ea17b0/hrefNGNC is natively supported on Stellar as a native asset, leveraging Stellar’s fast, secure, and cost-effective blockchain network. This integration enhances its usability for cross-border payments and other digital transactions.Benefits of Listing $NGNCEnhancing FX Utility: By listing $NGNC on Soroswap.Finance🪐, Nigerian users gain direct access to FX, facilitating Forex transactions and providing deep liquidity on-chain. This supports global trade and investment in a secure and efficient environment.LINK’s Fiat Ramp Solution: LINK provides the primary fiat on/off ramp solution in Nigeria’s rapidly growing market, enabling Nigerian users to seamlessly purchase NGNC with their local fiat (NGN) and also withdraw it to their bank account.Legitimizing Foreign Stablecoins: NGNC establishes legitimacy for foreign stablecoins within the global cryptocurrency ecosystem, promoting stable and accessible financial solutions worldwide.How to Acquire NGNCTo acquire NGNC Coin, use the direct swap feature on Soroswap.Finance🪐 . You can swiftly exchange NGNC for a range of supported assets, including XLM, BTC, ETH, and USDC, among others. Additionally, you can purchase these tokens directly with NGNC. The platform ensures that transactions are processed quickly and seamlessly, often within seconds.Access stablecoin liquidity with a XLM/NGNC orderbook on the Stellar network.What You Can Do with NGNC on Soroswap.Finance:Add Liquidity: Participate in liquidity pools to earn fees proportional to your contribution. LP tokens can be redeemed at any time, providing continuous passive income.Trade and Exchange: Conduct direct trades between NGNC and other cryptocurrencies to diversify your portfolio and capitalize on market opportunities.Contribute to the Ecosystem: By using NGNC on Soroswap.Finance🪐, you support the expansion and adoption of decentralized financial technologies, fostering global financial inclusion.Why Soroswap.Finance is the Ideal Choice:Enhanced Liquidity: Our platform offers robust liquidity and efficient trading opportunities for all users, ensuring a seamless and reliable experience.Security and Transparency: With a focus on security and integrity in smart contracts, you can trust your NGNC transactions on Soroswap.Finance to be secure and transparent.Join Soroswap.Finance today to unlock the full potential of decentralized finance and transform your financial experience. Together, we’re revolutionizing digital economies in Africa with $NGNC — be part of the revolution now!About Soroswap.Finance 🪐Soroswap.Finance is the first decentralized exchange (DEX) on the Soroban Blockchain, setting a new benchmark in cryptocurrency trading. As a trailblazer in the Stellar ecosystem, provides an advanced platform for fast, cost-effective token swaps without intermediaries.Developed by Paltalabs 🥑, this open-source protocol ensures a secure and efficient trading experience, featuring minimal fees and a structure resistant to censorship. By using Soroswap.Finance, you gain access to an innovative solution in decentralized finance, optimizing both security and accessibility in managing your digital assets.Join Us!Website | GitHub | Twitter| Documentation | DiscordPaltaLabs Website | PaltaLabs Twitter$NGNC Listing Announcement on Soroswap.Finance 🪐 was originally published in Soroswap on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">xRF Token Now Available on Soroswap.Finance</title>
    <published>2024-08-23T18:17:04+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-23T18:17:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/soroswap/xrf-token-now-available-on-soroswap-finance-bbc1336cad62?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/soroswap/xrf-token-now-available-on-soroswap-finance-bbc1336cad62?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Jenny T.</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are pleased to announce the addition of the xRF token, a utility cryptocurrency essential to the Reflector oracle network. This launch provides access to a token specifically designed to enhance governance and optimize subscription services for decentralized oracles.The xRF token was added into the Soroswa.Finance token-list in commit c1d4927. Today you can get the xRF token at Soroswap.Finance!What is the xRF Token?The xRF token is a utility cryptocurrency specifically designed for the Reflector Oracle Network. This network is a decentralized system that provides reliable and secure price data by aggregating information from multiple on-chain and off-chain sources.Issued by a Decentralized Autonomous Organization (DAO), the xRF token plays a crucial role within the Reflector ecosystem. The DAO is composed of Reflector node operators who participate in the cluster consensus mechanism and in the overall governance of the network.Functions and Uses of the xRF TokenGovernance and VotingReflector DAO Governance: The xRF token is essential for the governance of the Reflector DAO. DAO members have equal voting power, and decisions are made by simple majority. DAO members can vote on the inclusion of new operators and changes to cluster configuration. Expulsion of members and the inclusion of new nodes are done through DAO votes.Proposals and Deposits: To submit proposals (such as inviting new operators or adding new price feeds), a deposit of xRF tokens is required. The standard deposit amounts are:2. Rewards and IncentivesConsensus Participation: Cluster operators who contribute resources to validate and publish price information receive xRF tokens as compensation. These tokens represent the amount of computational resources contributed. The rewards documentation and token distribution process provide details on how these rewards are managed.Ongoing Distributions: xRF tokens are distributed weekly to oracle node operators and the Reflector development team. Allocated tokens can be claimed from the DAO fund.3. Subscription ServicesPrice Feed Subscriptions: Subscription services allow DeFi developers to create subscriptions for price feeds with customizable update intervals. Creating and maintaining these subscriptions requires xRF token deposits, which are burned in the process. If the deposit falls below a specific threshold, the subscription becomes inactive. Details on managing subscriptions are available in the relevant documentation.Automation and Flexibility: Subscriptions provide webhook notifications for price updates, enabling DeFi applications to react immediately to price changes without the need for continuous polling.For more information on the xRF token and its role within the Reflector Oracle Network, please visit the following links:- Reflector Oracle Network: General information about the ecosystem and the services provided.- DAO and xRF Token Description: Details about the DAO structure and the functionality of the xRF token.- Reflector Twitter: Follow for the latest updates and news about Reflector and the xRF token.- Reflector Discord: Join the community to engage in discussions and receive support.The xRF token is integral to the functioning of the Reflector network and to the implementation of efficient and secure decentralized oracles.Integration with Soroswap.FinanceThe xRF token is integrated with Soroswap.Finance, a protocol built on the Soroban blockchain. This integration enables seamless trading of xRF, allowing users to trade it in pairs such as USD/xRF and XLM/xRF. Leveraging Soroban’s DeFi infrastructure, the xRF token benefits from efficient and secure transactions within the Stellar network.https://medium.com/media/65663fad87ebfb46a8aa525aafca03c1/hrefAbout Soroswap.Finance 🪐Soroswap.Finance is the first decentralized exchange (DEX) on the Soroban Blockchain, setting a new benchmark in cryptocurrency trading. As a trailblazer in the Stellar ecosystem, provides an advanced platform for fast, cost-effective token swaps without intermediaries.Developed by paltalabs, this open-source protocol ensures a secure and efficient trading experience, featuring minimal fees and a structure resistant to censorship. By using Soroswap.Finance, you gain access to an innovative solution in decentralized finance, optimizing both security and accessibility in managing your digital assets.Join Us!Website | GitHub | Twitter| Documentation | DiscordPaltaLabs Website | PaltaLabs TwitterxRF Token Now Available on Soroswap.Finance was originally published in Soroswap on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Soroswap.Finance Receives $50,000 Liquidity Award: A Major Milestone in the DeFi Ecosystem</title>
    <published>2024-08-23T13:39:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-23T13:39:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/soroswap/soroswap-finance-receives-50-000-liquidity-award-a-major-milestone-in-the-defi-ecosystem-7b977d6a9cc6?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/soroswap/soroswap-finance-receives-50-000-liquidity-award-a-major-milestone-in-the-defi-ecosystem-7b977d6a9cc6?source=rss----dc7099fa4b0e---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Jenny T.</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Soroswap.Finance, a pioneering protocol within the decentralized finance (DeFi) ecosystem, has reached a significant milestone by securing a $50,000 USD award in Stellar Lumens (XLM) to enhance its liquidity. This award, provided by the Stellar Development Foundation (SDF), was facilitated through the implementation of an advanced Liquidity Timelock Contract, marking a pivotal step in the protocol’s evolution and resilience.About Soroswap.FinanceSoroswap.Finance is a decentralized and cutting-edge protocol on the Soroban blockchain, designed to facilitate asset exchanges with high efficiency and security. Developed by PaltaLabs, Soroswap is distinguished by its focus on automation and decentralization, allowing users to trade tokens directly without intermediaries. With its open-source, censorship-resistant architecture, Soroswap provides a reliable and accessible solution in the DeFi ecosystem, maintaining a strong commitment to transparency and transaction integrity.What is the Liquidity Timelock Contract and Why is it Important?The Liquidity Timelock Contract is a crucial tool for maintaining stability and security within Soroswap.Finance. This contract ensures that liquidity pool tokens (LP tokens) remain locked until a specific date and time: August 5, 2025, at 5:52:09 PM, corresponding to the timestamp 1754416329. This measure not only safeguards the integrity and security of the funds but also strengthens user confidence in the protocol by preventing any premature withdrawals or manipulation of assets.The code and technical details of the Liquidity Timelock Contract are available for review on GitHub: Liquidity Timelock Contract. This contract plays a critical role in the operation of Soroswap.Finance, enabling secure and effective liquidity management.How Does it Work?Fund Locking: The contract ensures that liquidity tokens remain protected and cannot be withdrawn before the specified date. This process is crucial for maintaining the funds’ security and integrity.Technical Specifications: The contract uses a timestamp in epoch format to determine when funds can be unlocked. Its code includes essential functions to ensure that the locking and unlocking process is transparent and auditable.Impact on Trust: By securing the funds, the contract builds user trust in the platform, assuring that investments are protected and the protocol operates fairly and transparently.Transaction DetailsThe $50,000 USD award has been added to the XLM-USDC pair through two separate transactions, significantly boosting the pool’s total value locked (TVL). The specific transactions are:Transaction 1Transaction 2This achievement underscores Soroswap.Finance’s ongoing commitment to enhancing its liquidity and providing secure and reliable solutions within the DeFi space.Why Is This Important?This development not only strengthens Soroswap.Finance’s position within the DeFi ecosystem but also represents a significant advancement in the implementation of security and stability practices for decentralized exchange protocols. The use of timelock contracts enhances trust in the protocol by ensuring that funds remain secure during the lock period, thereby preventing manipulations or premature withdrawals.[August 8, 2024] — Soroswap.FinanceMore InformationFor more information on the current state of the XLM-USDC pool and other important updates, visit: Soroswap Pool InfoJoin Us!Website | GitHub | Twitter| Documentation | DiscordPaltalabs Website | Paltalabs TwitterSoroswap.Finance Receives $50,000 Liquidity Award: A Major Milestone in the DeFi Ecosystem was originally published in Soroswap on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
