<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.spatium.net/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.spatium.net%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=%5Brole%3D%22listitem%22%5D+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.article-content&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.created-data&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.spatium.net%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=%5Brole%3D%22listitem%22%5D+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.article-content&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.created-data&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:01+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Spatium Academy</title>
    <published>2024-07-16T22:10:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-16T22:10:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.spatium.net/blog/crypto-exchange-essentials</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.spatium.net/blog/crypto-exchange-essentials"/>
    <content type="html">This is the 4th article within Crypto guide for beginners. Read other ones:What is cryptocurrency and how does it work?, What is blockchain technology and how does it work?What is crypto exchange and how does it work?As we have already discussed, a crypto exchange is the place where crypto users get access to trading, selling, and buying crypto. Of course, this is not the only way to get crypto, there are also peer-to-peer (P2P) platforms, investment apps, and even crypto wallets. Let’s explore how crypto exchanges work and how crypto holders can trade there.How do crypto exchanges work?There are several types of crypto exchanges: central, decentralized, and hybrid. The most common type is centralized crypto exchanges though the growing rate of decentralized exchanges nowadays is high. When you go to the crypto exchange, you set up an account. Having an account with the exchange platform lets you buy Bitcoin, Ether, Polkadot, Litecoin, etc. There are some exchanges that let you buy crypto with fiat, for example US dollar, or euro. Usually, such exchanges allow users to withdraw crypto as well. Other exchanges are not connected to the financial world of web2 and are not connected to banks or other financial institutions. It means that on their platforms you can only trade crypto for crypto. Depending on the scale of the platform, the range of cryptocurrencies to trade differs. The bigger the exchange is, the more trading pairs it contains. Anyway, before setting up an account with the crypto exchange platform, check the availability of trading pairs as well as the options to move your crypto off the platform. Also, there are platforms that allow the withdrawal of crypto funds, but the platform fee for such an action can be very high. Another amazing feature of crypto exchanges is their availability. Unlike traditional exchanges, crypto exchanges are operating 24/7.How can one trade on a crypto exchange? Step 1. Set up an accountIt’s vital to set up an account to be able to trade at the crypto exchange. Depending on the type of exchange the verification checks might differ. Anyway, all centralized exchanges require KYC verification, which could be confirmation of identity through ID checks, utility bills with the home address, driving license, or passport. MInd that from region to region KYC regulations differ.Step 2. Fund your accountThere are several ways to fund a crypto exchange account. You can do it either with fiat money or crypto when you send crypto from your wallet to a crypto exchange wallet. The majority of crypto exchange platforms require a minimum deposit. ‍Step 3. Select a trading pairCryptocurrency exchanges offer the most common trading pairs. If none of the pairs matches your expectations, you can navigate the list of crypto assets and make a pair you want.Step 4. Come up with a trading strategyIf you are a newcomer to the crypto field, you can check a guide or two, listen to some bloggers, or follow the strategy offered by the exchange itself. Step 5. Start tradingAs soon as the crypto exchange account is funded and you are ready to employ the chosen trading strategy, cryptocurrency exchange transactions can be initiated. These can be done either through the desktop app on the computer or in your mobile phone app. The selling and buying transactions are put in the order book of the exchange. To proceed you have to pay crypto trading fees which differ from platform to platform. The fee may vary from 0.5% of the sum to 5% and even higher. It’s also important to remember that crypto exchanges do not set the prices for crypto, they are set by the market. The majority of crypto exchanges show up-to-the-minutes pricing. Summing uprading on the crypto exchange is not as easy as trading stocks and bonds in a traditional way. Though sometimes there is minimal identity check required, crypto exchanges are still unregulated. Moreover, centralized cryptocurrency exchanges are vulnerable to fraud, hacks, and theft. Also, if something happens to the exchange platform for example it goes down, users don’t get access to their crypto wallets. To be protected and trade safely you can either have an account with a decentralized currency exchange or use a crypto wallet with the trading features. One such wallet is the Spatium Feeless MPC wallet. It’s a multi-currency wallet enabling feeless transactions. Stay protected in web3 with Spatium Feeless Wallet. It’s easy to operate and securely to use. Spatium Feeless Wallet is free to download. It’s available on Android and iOS devices. Visit our website to learn more about the wallet. Get it on your phone, test it, and enjoy your financial freedom!You may also follow us on social media platforms, so you won’t miss a thing. Engage in earning points with Spatium Feeless Wallet and turn them into real world benefits!‍‍    ‍Keep a close eye on Spatium Feeless Wallet.Follow us on social platforms: X, LinkedIn, Discord, and Telegram.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/662fa7a197140a2171f13394/669a2bdb93e2c4cc6872ce3f_Crypto%20guide%20for%20beginners%20-%20Part%204%20-%20blog-min.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Spatium Academy</title>
    <published>2024-07-02T22:10:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-02T22:10:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://spatiumnet.webflow.io/blog/what-is-a-cryptocurrency-and-how-does-it-work</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://spatiumnet.webflow.io/blog/what-is-a-cryptocurrency-and-how-does-it-work"/>
    <content type="html">This is the first article within Crypto guide for beginners.Cryptocurrency is an important part of the web3 system. You may sometimes meet the shortened form of the word - crypto. It means that this digital currency is based on cryptography, advanced mathematical calculations, and equations. There are nowadays more than 20,000 different types of cryptocurrencies but all of them have one feature in common, they are decentralized. It means they are not governed by any centralized issuing authority (banks, governments, etc.).Cryptocurrency in a nutshellIf we take the US financial system as an example, then you will see that the body which is responsible for issuing dollars is the Federal Reserve. After that dollars go to banks and other financial institutions and are distributed among people. Any banking card from a bank can be canceled by the centralized authority. At the same time if a banking card is lost or stolen, the same centralized authority can block and then reissue it, thus protecting bank holder’s funds.Nothing like this is happening in web3. Cryptocurrency is created, exchanged, bought, and sold through peer-to-peer disturbed networks. Crypto is a completely digital means of payment, its value, with a couple of exceptions, is neither connected to any national currency nor to the price of gold or silver. It’s emitted or generated online and can be traded only digitally.Blockchains record cryptocurrency transactions and are built in a decentralized way. No one can trust anyone in web3, because the transactions are in the majority of cases fully anonymous. That’s why to protect cryptocurrency from being faked or stolen heavy cryptography is applied. According to CoinMarketCap, there are around 23,000 cryptocurrencies hosted on over 1000 blockchains worldwide. Each cryptocurrency is designed in its unique way and is supposed to bring new features to existing ecosystems. Payments in crypto are instant or near-instant, depending on the blockchain. Also, they are available 24/7 from anywhere. And the most important part is that there is no third-party verification of transactions. Blockchain networks are self-governed, implying a ‘trustless’ system of verification. The biggest crypto by market capitalization, as well as the most important cryptocurrencies in web3 are Bitcoin and Ethereum. The first crypto is Bitcoin and its exact date of creation is January 3, 2009. For the first year, its price was around 0$ and not many people believed in it. However, nowadays Bitcoin is over $60,000 and its price is constantly growing. To be able to perform transactions with cryptocurrencies you require a crypto wallet. Modern crypto wallets offer multi-featured interfaces, convenient private keys storage, and safe transactions.Spatium Feeless Wallet is a multi-currency crypto wallet. It makes crypto transactions affordable and cheap compared to many other crypto wallets. Spatium offers a revolutionary Feeless feature when transactions are paid in the crypto you send instead of the native crypto of the blockchain. Batched feeless transactions enable you to save up to 30%. Stay protected in web3 with Spatium Feeless Bitcoin Wallet. It’s easy to operate and securely to use. Spatium Feeless Wallet is free to download. It’s available on Android and iOS devices.  Visit our website to learn more about the wallet. Get it on your phone, test it, and enjoy your financial freedom!‍‍  ‍  Keep a close eye on Spatium Feeless Wallet.Follow us on social platforms: X, LinkedIn, Discord, and Telegram.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/662fa7a197140a2171f13394/668ff2f594e718573d069563_Crypto%20guide%20for%20beginners%20-%20Part%201%20-%20What%20is%20a%20cryptocurrency%20and%20how%20does%20it%20work_%20-%20blog-min.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Spatium Academy</title>
    <published>2024-07-08T22:10:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-08T22:10:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://spatiumnet.webflow.io/blog/what-is-blockchain-technology-and-how-does-it-work</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://spatiumnet.webflow.io/blog/what-is-blockchain-technology-and-how-does-it-work"/>
    <content type="html">This is the first article within Crypto guide for beginners. Read the first article.The two terms: blockchain and cryptocurrency are often used as synonyms, though they are not. The phrase ‘Bitcoin Blockchain’ means that Bitcoin blockchain is the platform enabling the launch of Bitcoin cryptocurrency. However, blockchain technology is very complicated, embracing not only the function of the underlying platform for cryptocurrencies but also has a wide range of other applications.Blockchain network characteristics1. TransparentOriginally, blockchain networks are public ledgers, meaning that all transactions are visible to anyone and accessible to anyone. Of course, nowadays there are private ledgers, but the amount of such networks in the global web3 ecosystem is very insignificant.2. PermanentOne of the properties of the Bitcoin blockchain is that starting from its creation in 2009 until nowadays it records and stores all transactions with digital assets. Digital assets are not only cryptocurrencies, these could be tokens that can hold data about real objects and services: property, goods, patents, smart contracts, etc.3. ImmutableBlockchain is an append-only ledger. Data about transactions enters it, and stays there permanently, with no option to be changed or corrected. Strong cryptographic protection prevents bad actors in web3 from meddling with blockchain transaction history. Why is a blockchain called so?The meaning of blockchain is quite clear if we cut the word into two parts: blocks that are chained. Taking the example of the Bitcoin blockchain, it’s true that all transactions to be put into the blockchain are organized in blocks. Each block records recent transactions before they get validated by the network. Once the data about the transactions are validated, the block is closed and permanently joins the blockchain. The Bitcoin blockchain adds six blocks each hour, which means that if someone wants to send a transaction to the Bitcoin blockchain, they will wait roughly 10 minutes for their transaction confirmation.Is blockchain technology secure?Blockchains are decentralized which means that they simultaneously run on a network of computers (nodes) scattered around the globe. There is no central node to control the transaction verification and block confirmation, nodes communicate with each other enabling peer-to-peer confirmation scenarios (consensus). The fact that blockchain is decentralized makes it safer compared to legacy record-keeping systems because blockchain doesn’t have a single point of failure. The fact that it is self-governing makes any duplication or fraud very difficult to achieve. Coming to life as an alternative financial system, the Bitcoin blockchain brought to life thousands of other blockchains with over 20,000 cryptocurrencies. Blockchain technology has outgrown the financial sphere and is actively exploring other industries as well.Spatium Feeless Wallet is a multi-currency crypto wallet. It makes crypto transactions affordable and cheap compared to many other crypto wallets. Spatium offers a revolutionary Feeless feature when transactions are paid in the crypto you send instead of the native crypto of the blockchain. Batched feeless transactions enable you to save up to 30%. Stay protected in web3 with Spatium Feeless Wallet. It’s easy to operate and securely to use. Spatium Feeless Wallet is free to download. It’s available on Android and iOS devices.  Visit our website to learn more about the wallet. Get it on your phone, test it, and enjoy your financial freedom! ‍‍   ‍‍Keep a close eye on Spatium Feeless Wallet.Follow us on social platforms: X, LinkedIn, Discord, and Telegram.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/662fa7a197140a2171f13394/668ff505d5e0d4a4247e0834_Crypto%20guide%20for%20beginners%20-%20Part%202.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
