<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">DFS Lab: Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfslab.net/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dfslab.net%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fpost%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.postcontent&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date-time&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dfslab.net%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fpost%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.postcontent&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date-time&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:05:34+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">DFS Lab New</title>
    <published>2024-12-09T22:05:34+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-09T22:05:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfslab.net/post/build-cyborgs-not-androids-in-africa</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfslab.net/post/build-cyborgs-not-androids-in-africa"/>
    <content type="html">Tides are shifting. As all boats rose in the last handful of years for African VC, the potential for a fall looks readily possible in 2022.‍We know that funds who are not-Africa or emerging market-focused have become less enthused about investing on the continent. At the same time, we have seen deterioration in the food, fuel, and fiscal systems in African countries. Even as software eats the world, the world needs to eat. All this is leading to a slowdown in the geometric growth that African VC has seen in the past couple of years.‍The Big Deal‍With the pullback of cheap capital, founders on the continent — like their peers around the world — are now faced with existential questions that have been oft-delayed during the days of uncapped SAFE notes and oversubscribed pre-seed rounds. Questions around unfettered, profitless growth that were previously suppressed by thoughts of twenty year timelines are suddenly much more visceral. No longer can we afford specious arguments about demographic trends or smartphone revolutions when spending runways end in weeks not years.‍We should be clear in our convictions and why we invest.‍Last October, we wrote about The B-Side of African Tech, an article that outlined what we at DFS Lab perceive as some of the greatest opportunities for African tech. In it, we broke down the tech opportunity under a framework from Wang Huiwen (王慧文), the founder of Meituan Dianping, one of the world’s largest on-demand delivery platforms.‍‍Wang looks at technology platforms and splits approaches between Side A, which favors digital ubiquity, and Side B, which favors physical ubiquity. If you were to apply this chart to most African economies, a snapshot of the addressable market for Side A would be a sliver while Side B would take up the majority. The reason is covered above, that fully digital experiences are either inaccessible, unaffordable, or don’t cover the primary consumption needs for those in the bottom 95%.‍The primary focus in ‘B-Side’ is to highlight the interconnectivity and opportunity in atoms-based businesses in Africa — those that source, supply, and sell the goods &amp;amp; services that make up the overwhelming majority of spending in African economies. ‘B-Side’ is also at the core of DFS Lab’s ever-evolving thesis.‍Since ‘B-Side’ was published, B1 has exploded in terms of funding — almost exclusively for B2B marketplaces that supply FMCG and food. B2B food restock marketplace Twiga raised $50M in fresh funding. B2B FMCG marketplace TradeDepot raised $110M in equity and debt. Wasoko (formerly Sokowatch) raised $125M. MarketForce raised $40M. And on, and on, and on. And on.‍B2, through a less mature sector in Africa, has also seen tremendous support across a variety of approaches: TeamApt raised $50M, Brimore raised $25M, The Food Lab raised $4.5M, Tushop raised $3M, Appetito raised $2M, Bumpa integrated with Meta, and YC took notice with bets on Chowdeck, Foodcourt, and Garage.‍The discussion around the atoms-based nature of Africa’s digital evolution is also being talked about more often. We’ve been one of the loudest voices around how digital ubiquity lags physical ubiquity on the continent and as such, startups and investors must adapt.‍Still, the hybrid reality of African tech is still less discussed than it should be, usually appearing only when startups run into challenges in the form of logistical nightmares, slow cash reconciliation, and higher than expected acquisition costs, among other barriers. While shifting, our ecosystem continues to be dominated by A-Side visionaries building for B-Side dominated markets.‍It makes sense to break down that hybrid reality further. Digital and physical processes can be mixed and matched in several different combinations, so how might a startup effectively approach the “African tech mullet?”‍To start, we can borrow a page from science fiction. Hear me out.Androids and cyborgs are commonplace concepts in science fiction where they are often used interchangeably but are actually quite different.An android is a robot made to look and act like a human being. On the other hand, a cyborg is a human with robotic or mechanical parts meant to extend their capabilities.‍As out of place as this analogy may seem at first, the difference between cyborgs and androids encapsulates the core choice that is made by every startup building a business in Africa’s hybrid marketplace: do you replace informal markets, or do you enhance them?Here are the two approaches:Create solutions that replace informal markets with digital, formalized parts and processes. Build an android.Create solutions that enhance informal markets by arming them with digital, formalized parts and processes. Build a cyborg.To be clear, most businesses evolve between the two approaches and many will have elements of both at different times. However, we do have several examples of each to draw from.We can start with e-commerce. Many e-commerce startups in Africa have been android approaches inspired by Amazon’s model of two-sided aggregation and direct-to-consumer sales. It’s a model that defines the opportunity as replacing the local market with an online option that is meant to be more convenient, have more options, and is fully digitized.‍However, these models have often floundered, partially because they are simply unable to fully replicate the benefits consumers enjoyed from informal markets. Benefits like in-person shopping advice, easy cash payments, and someone to go to for after sales support all proved to be difficult to replicate at scale. The long-term struggles of platforms like Konga, Jumia, and most recently Sky Garden are the result.‍Contrast that with more recent entrants in the ecommerce space building cyborg approaches. Bumpa in Nigeria is leaning into conversational commerce and building tools around the informal conversations that make sales happen for Nigeria’s newly digital shoppers. Tushop in Kenya empowers informal community sellers to be the spearhead of its last-mile marketing and fulfillment strategy, leveraging existing social connections to sell.In fintech, the difference is even more stark.The ‘digital bank for Africa’ has been a golden goose in African tech VC that has seen headlines dominated by android approaches. From the trials and tribulations of digital lenders Branch and Tala which tried to formalize unsecuritized consumer loans through a fully digital underwriting process, to the recent struggles of Nigeria’s neobank, Kuda, the fintech space is filled with examples of strong teams underestimating the difficulty of replacing offline, cash-based financial behavior with digital-only, online versions.‍But where have we seen success in fintech on the continent? It’s cyborg approaches that pair the flexibility of cash with agent networks that serve as conduits to digital transactions. These networks do not replace informal, largely cash-based financial lives — they simply supercharge it with digital optionality when the need arises. Cyborg businesses like TeamApt are proving the point-of-sale agent approach in Nigeria while M-Pesa is a veritable legend in financial inclusion success stories. Tyme Bank, in South Africa, started fully digital and then found much deeper success by leveraging kiosks at in-person retail access points.‍We believe in cyborg businesses because we know that informality is only partially programmable. The organic, human elements are often too complex to digitize without losing its benefits.‍We refer to programmable informality as the digitally-native portions of solutions which enhance the benefits of existing informal processes within a market.First, they aim to create network effects that deepen trust between buyers and sellers in fragmented markets.They also improve scalability in atoms-based value chains and come in the form of software that removes friction in the commerce stack from distribution to discovery.And perhaps most importantly, programmable informality is strongest when we know to leave informal processes alone, as opaque or “inefficient” as they may seem; to instead build and align around social capital, existing culture, community dynamics, and their often unmeasured benefits.‍Cyborg startups will earn a place at the competitive table with how well they operate their offline, non-programmable operations, but they will redefine industries and return venture funds with how far they can push programmable informality forward in Africa.‍At DFS Lab, our focus on cyborg startups means that there are several elements beyond the well-known trio of “strong team, big market, moving fast” that we’re focusing on as we partner with founders.B1 vs. B2 — we will continue to look for high-potential B1 startups in blue-ocean geographies and specialized verticals, but we also believe it’s a much more crowded field vs B2. However, it’s clear to us that there are sectors outside of FMCG which will likely see the B2B marketplace treatment but with much less competitive pressure — construction, automotive, raw materials, pharmaceuticals, etc. — and DFS Lab is excited to invest in those specialist platforms as they’re built. There’s just simply a lot of opportunity out there.‍In B2, we focus on startups that are even more convincingly cyborg-oriented given the hyperlocal nature of these businesses. Critically, we invest in teams who are building approaches to programmable informality that truly disrupt unit economics. This includes emerging strategies like dark fulfillment, conversion franchising, social selling, and more.Missionaries vs. mercenaries — we believe that the rigor required to build cyborg businesses, including the need to master physical operations alongside software-driven points of leverage means that nuance and authentic experience is critical. More often than not, we find industry missionaries who have shown conviction within a specific sector to hold significant advantages.‍This is not to say we believe all founders must be industry experts, but we do believe strong founders must be able to navigate the distinct challenges of specific industries with instincts honed through prior hands-on experience in some form.Scarcity vs. Abundance — almost all B-Side companies start with aggregating distribution in markets facing scarcity. However, as competition increases and supplies become more readily available, the market of scarcity they started in begins to evolve into a market of relative abundance (e.g. FMCG marketplaces).‍We aim to back founders who understand what it takes to navigate that shift from enabling commerce to expanding commerce — required for durable defensibility. This is often in the form of embedded digital services including finance, but ultimately will also take the shape of discovery services including advertising and sales support.‍For years, we’ve believed that startup profitability in Africa will be found within the friction of its informal markets. But for too long, the ecosystem has tried to brute-force android solutions onto the organic processes that drive our markets.‍DFS Lab is here to back the conviction-driven founders who aim to instead build within that nuance with cyborg startups that have the potential to grow into highly-profitable businesses across Africa, and that will show the world what the future of digital commerce looks like.‍Originally published 1 Nov 2022Download attachment</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">DFS Lab New</title>
    <published>2023-10-16T22:05:34+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-10-16T22:05:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfslab.net/post/dfs-lab-and-mojaloop-foundation-announce-4th-mojaloop-bootcamp</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfslab.net/post/dfs-lab-and-mojaloop-foundation-announce-4th-mojaloop-bootcamp"/>
    <content type="html">DFS Lab and the Mojaloop Foundation have announced their fourth joint bootcamp, aimed at fostering innovation in African payment solutions. The bootcamp, scheduled for May 23rd-26th, 2023, will bring together at least ten teams from across Africa to compete for a chance to win up to $5,000 in prize money. Each participating team will also receive $1,000.The overarching theme of this year’s bootcamp is “Developing Innovative African Payment Solutions.” Specifically, the bootcamp will explore how merchants can interact with and use payment solutions developed by merchant service companies on the Mojaloop platform, with a focus on low/high proximity, offline, and e-commerce payments.“We are excited to collaborate with DFS Lab on this bootcamp, as their financial inclusion mission has resonated loudly with the African fintech community. The bootcamp will help spur instant payments systems innovation to connect all financial services providers and customers within the digital economy,” said Mojaloop Foundation Executive Director Paula Hunter. “As a digital public good, Mojaloop enables the interoperability needed to drive innovation, and we believe this bootcamp will help identify new and exciting use cases.”Jake Kendall, Managing Director of DFS Lab, added, “We’re thrilled to continue our partnership with the Mojaloop Foundation and support the next generation of African fintech innovators. We look forward to seeing the creative solutions that emerge from the bootcamp and hope they will inspire other entrepreneurs and innovators across the continent.”During the guided design sprint, participating teams will have the opportunity to work with Mojaloop and DFS Lab experts to rapidly prototype next-generation features for their product roadmaps.Last year’s bootcamp was themed PISP (Payment Initiation Service Providers) and it featured nine teams building solutions on the PISP functionality of the Mojaloop platform.To apply for the bootcamp, visit bit.ly/Mojaloopbootcamp23.For more information, contact Gift Agboro, Head of Operations — DFS LabAbout the Mojaloop FoundationThe Mojaloop Foundation’s mission is to increase financial inclusion by empowering organizations creating interoperable payment systems to enable digital financial services for all. Sponsor-level members include the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, Coil, Google, MAS, Ripple, and The Rockefeller Foundation. To achieve its mission, Mojaloop Foundation operates as a 501(c)(3) charitable nonprofit organization, maintaining its free, open-source software, Mojaloop, and community as public goods in the service of financial inclusion. Merchants, banks, providers, government offices and other entities looking to build inclusive payments platforms can use Mojaloop — whole, adapted or as a real-time payments reference model. For more information about the Mojaloop Foundation, visit https://mojaloop.io/Download attachment</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">DFS Lab New</title>
    <published>2023-10-13T22:05:34+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-10-13T22:05:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.dfslab.net/post/the-frontier-blindspot</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.dfslab.net/post/the-frontier-blindspot"/>
    <content type="html">Sufficient Balance Two, Chapter 1This post was co-authored by the DFS Lab team.‍Marc Andreessen’s “Why Software Is Eating the World” is a cornerstone essay marking tech’s most recent golden age. In the piece, Marc makes the case that “With lower start-up costs and a vastly expanded market for online services, the result is a global economy that for the first time will be fully digitally wired.” And in the decade since, founders and investors around the world have rallied to build businesses to serve digitally connected populations. True to the prophecy, these startups have emerged leveraging standardized, scalable infrastructure to lower the cost of experimentation. A 2018 study found that startups “founded in sectors that benefited from the introduction of AWS raised much less capital in their first round of VC financing after AWS.” But how has this played out in African markets?‍In 2020, Paystack, the “Stripe for Africa,” was acquired by Stripe itself. In many ways, this was a success for the startup ecosystem, especially in Nigeria, that reinforced Marc’s paradigm above. Paystack creates the infrastructure for businesses to accept digital payments in Africa and was built through a startup journey that included global startup resources, methodologies, and experiences, including a stint through Y Combinator.‍Upon closer inspection however, one finds that Paystack’s journey was unique to Africa and that the team created value by solving for the gaps they experienced along the way. It is less that Paystack was identical to Stripe, but in a new geography. And more that Paystack through a combination of ingenuity, lived-in experiences, and luck, built the conditions for the Stripe model to succeed in Nigeria and Africa more broadly.‍This disconnect between the conditions that drove the growth of the digital economies in high income countries and on-the-ground reality in frontier markets creates what we call the frontier blindspot. As Western markets digitized their economies, the world developed intuitions about how technology markets are structured, what successful technology companies look like, and so on. This orthodoxy affects everyone, from founders to investors, driving strategy and informing investment decisions.‍One of the key drivers of this blindspot is our overestimation of digital progress. In 2011, Marc predicted 5 billion total smartphone users in the next ten years. As of 2019, we’re at about 3 to 3.5 billion smartphone users globally with sales slowing and even declining in some markets. However, beyond the disparity in smartphone penetration (a gap that will likely close at some point) there are other forces that imply that frontier markets will not mirror the development of digital economies in the global north.Relatively low connectivity — the GSMA estimates that mobile internet adoption in Sub-Saharan Africa in 2019 is about 26%Broken/non-existent infrastructure, especially around payments, credit, identity, last-mile logistics, etc.Limited income/small wallet sizesHighly fragmented value chainsUnderutilization of labor and resources‍These are, of course, not new observations. But while these factors act as barriers for “proven” business models, we believe they also represent immense opportunity for those who are able to see the present clearly and forge a future that accounts for it. Founders are building incredible companies in countries where infrastructure isn’t just stagnant, but completely broken. In Rwanda and Ghana, drones are delivering blood and medical supplies to remote areas. Kenya has one of the most successful mobile payments services in the world, but it’s just the tip of the iceberg. As we mentioned in Nigeria, the “Stripe of Africa” was acquired by Stripe itself, and the fundamental building blocks of modern ecommerce and financial services are being forged. There is also an important role for industry initiatives like the Mojaloop open source payment system funded by The Gates Foundation and its partners (Google, PhonePe, Omidyar Network, Rockefeller Foundation and a handful of other charitable and private sector organizations) that aim to create interoperable payments infrastructure and reduce costs at the industry level.‍The global pandemic has also reshaped consumer behavior in Africa. Despite limited digital infrastructure, commerce — formal and informal — has been forced to adapt to a contactless world. Key supply chains like those for food and FMCG are increasingly tech-enabled, where digitization must augment informal markets that are trusted, reliable, and adapted to local needs. On-demand delivery in particular has seen a large uptick in adoption in African urban centers like Nairobi, much like everywhere else. Africa’s startup ecosystems are maturing as well: M&amp;amp;A activity crossed $1 billion in 2020 — about at par with venture investments, according to Briter Bridges.‍If the frontier blindspot means we overestimate the speed of digital progress from a Western lens while underestimating the progress brought on by the continent’s builders, then the opportunity lies in identifying founders who can effectively apply the modern startup-stack to make life better for billions of digitally-limited consumers, the fastest growing population in the world. Furthermore, this persona goes beyond the African consumer, but reflects what the average global consumer looks like around the world such as in parts of Latin America, Eastern Europe, Southeast Asia, and the more remote regions of India and China. As much as we invest in founders building for Africa, we invest in African founders building for the world.‍More specifically, we believe there are several core areas that will flourish and underpin the future of digital commerce in Africa:Physical Logistics including tech-enabled mobility and delivery for B2C and B2B applications. We’re excited to see advancements along the value chain, including what we’ve already seen in freight, trucking, and imports. We’re also looking for founders willing to tackle more downstream logistics challenges that tap into and expand existing distribution value chains including in last-mile package, restaurant, and grocery delivery.An SME Solution Stack that aims to help smaller SMEs grow, including but not limited to new forms of social commerce. Importantly, we aren’t looking for solutions aiming to completely “disrupt” informal, offline markets but rather augment the efficiencies they create while increasing opportunities for both sellers and buyers. We are excited to work with founders who want to help smaller sellers save and make more money through tech-enabled O2O models that can reach more customers. We also want to back solutions that help sellers manage their businesses more efficiently, whether it’s removing barriers to getting started or helping with the working capital, infrastructure, and back-office functions needed to grow.Hustle Economy Platforms that provide on-demand services tailored for African businesses and consumers. Importantly, we are also excited to work with founders building products and services for platform workers themselves, helping to augment the otherwise lack of benefits and stability that comes with salaried jobs. We see strong potential in models that allow people to increase incomes with flexible work.Financial Building Blocks that support the digital commerce ecosystem partially created by everything we’ve already mentioned. For example, we are excited by responsible credit that removes the financial friction currently present in doing business. We are increasingly excited about advancements in low-cost, interoperable payments, and the new use cases they enable. As digital commerce evolves, we’re also looking for digital payment products that have been designed with this landscape in mind. Additionally, the continued growth of the hustle economy opens the door for financial services to serve an entirely new segment of workers.Agent Network products and services that improve network management as well as help agents make more money and do their jobs more easily. We see a world where agents expand beyond mobile money and opportunities to improve agent value remain largely untapped. We look forward to working with founders who want to help build more feature-rich O2O agent networks in Africa.‍Over the coming months, we plan to dig much deeper into the ideas outlined here. Undoubtedly, the entrepreneurs we partner with will surprise us with new combinations of, and exceptions to our hypotheses. As we stay in the trenches with them, building for the next billion in Africa, we will share what we learn with you. We hope you will share your thoughts and insights with us!‍Up NextChapter 2: Fortune at the middle of the pyramid: The contours of African consumer purchasing power and the opportunities for the tech industry.Chapter 3: Who is ‘The African Consumer’?: A follow-up to Fortune at the middle of the pyramidChapter 4: Physical Ubiquity Redux‍Download attachment</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
