<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by techFiesta on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40techFiesta&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*4nTp3EzAbRiXChMZx5rc4Q.jpeg</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*4nTp3EzAbRiXChMZx5rc4Q.jpeg</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40techFiesta&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:53+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">EBC Hackathon on techFiesta</title>
    <published>2024-05-30T09:43:05+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-30T09:43:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/ebc-hackathon-on-techfiesta-2da742c15c01?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/ebc-hackathon-on-techfiesta-2da742c15c01?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">EBC’s hackathon on techFiesta offered an unparalleled opportunity for hackers to network with industry peers, engage in lively sessions, develop innovative technical projects, and create lasting memories.Clients: The European Blockchain ConventionExecution: For 48 hours, developers were hacking in the EBC physical hackathon challenge. The hackathon focused on blockchain, crypto, DeFi, Web3, NFTs, Gaming, and the metaverse industry, presenting an opportunity for the 10 winning projects to win prizes of up to $60,000. As partners with EBC, techFiesta served as the infrastructure platform for the hackathon where the hackers viewed all hackathon details and submitted their projects.ResultOver 50 teams were formed.Over 200 developers learned how to build on a core infrastructure for the future of decentralized applications and Defi.20 mentors helped the developers all through the live eventThe top 10 winners invented projects like Web3 Smart Social App, Cross-chain DApp Migration, Crypto Telegram Bot, and XDC Wallet. These showcased the ingenuity and potential of emerging technologiesHackathon DetailsFormat: PhysicalDuration: 48 hoursHackathon Task and TracksHackers were asked to;Build a social media dApp that connects individuals and communities. Great their own better version of friend.tech by using smart tokens with their project (not a requirement)Create your version of a dApp that is on another chain and deploy your project on Coreum.Build a project in one of the following three streams: Xdc wallet with NFTS and tokens, decentralized perpetual dex or Crypto Telegram Bot for XDC/XRC-20/XRC-721​Hackathon Tracks — SocialFi Dapp | Cross-chain dApp migration | Xdc wallet with NFTS and tokens | Decentralized perpetual dex| Crypto Telegram Bot for XDC/XRC-20/XRC-721Hackathon BountiesHack’A’Thon yielded 21 diverse projects, with 10 standout winners sharing a prize pool of $60,000, sponsored by Coreum, XDC Foundation, European Blockchain Convention, and European Tech School. The winning projects showcased remarkable innovation, with five built on Coreum and five on the XDC Foundation, revolutionizing various domains from social apps to decentralized finance solutions.Winning Project DetailsCoreum winners:1. Best Web3 Smart Social App: GuildHub2. Best Cross-chain DApp Migration: Ulam Labs3. Completed Project Deployed on Coreum: DApp Squad4. Honorable Mention: Dmusic5. Pool Prizes: Web3 Wizards, Token TitansXDC winners:1. Best Decentralized Perpetual DEX: PROFIT PREDATORS2. Best XDC Wallet: Wall3t3. Best Crypto Telegram Bot: PUMPING PUMPKINS4. Honourable Mentions: Hunters, PAC_MAN, ALL TREND, Vottun Dojo, Maharaja &amp;amp; Agustin5. Participation Prizes: Gamium hackers, Hawk, Pikake, Universal PlasticEBC Hackathon: Driving Growth and Networking Opportunities Amongst DevelopersThe EBC hackathon proved pivotal for developers, providing them with a platform to innovate, win prizes, and explore grant opportunities. The quality of submissions was exceptional, impressing sponsors and establishing techFiesta as a robust infrastructure for hosting such events.Hosting events on techFiesta amplifies brand visibility, fosters thought leadership within the tech community and offers access to a vibrant network of developers and industry experts. Partnerships with techFiesta pave the way for innovation-driven solutions to real-world challenges while nurturing developer and user communities, crucial for sustainable growth and collaboration.About EBCThe European Blockchain Convention is the most influential blockchain event in Europe. It was founded with the mission to accelerate the blockchain ecosystem in Europe.Since its inaugural conference in 2018 in Barcelona, EBC has hosted thousands of attendees, hundreds of leading speakers, and the best startups in the blockchain &amp;amp; crypto space.Its global audience of founders, investors, regulators, developers, corporations, and many more come together every year to learn, get inspired, and connect.About techFiestatechFiesta is a talent platform for work distribution and online hackathons. We connect passionate professionals from all over the world with top companies and industry experts in the tech space. Our hackathons are designed to provide an engaging and collaborative experience for developers of all levels, as well as professionals from other fields who are interested in technology. Companies that participate in our hackathons have the opportunity to work with a diverse and talented group of tech innovators, harnessing their fresh and inventive ideas to fuel growth and success in their businesses.Follow us on our various social channels:LinkedIn: techFiestaTwitter: techFiestaDiscord: techFiestaTelegram: techFiesta</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How to Build a Strong Developer Community</title>
    <published>2024-05-30T09:10:58+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-30T09:10:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/how-to-build-a-strong-developer-community-61853531cc6f?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/how-to-build-a-strong-developer-community-61853531cc6f?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Developer communities remain fundamental to the success of numerous projects, playing a pivotal role in their evolution. This underscores the importance of building an active and engaged developer community. Every blockchain protocol needs a dedicated developer community and in this article, we shared strategies you can employ to grow your community.Source; FreepikThe role of a strong Web3 developer community cannot be overstated. By nurturing a vibrant community, you can gain valuable insights, enhance product development, and foster collaboration, and brand loyalty.How can you build and engage a developer community effectively? Let’s explore how you can implement what works to build a strong developer community.Why Build a Strong Developer Community?The Web3 market is anticipated to reach a valuation of $107.32 billion by 2025. — WiFi Talents. Thus, Web3 developers are needed to build projects that will cater to the needs of the masses and provide the best user experience (UX).A Web3 developer community comprises developers across all areas, from Rust, API specifications, artificial intelligence, smart contract auditing, and other Web3 development professionals who share knowledge, collaborate on projects, and learn from each other. These communities can exist online or offline and can be broad-focused or niche-focused, catering to specific areas.Many players in the Web3 ecosystem rely on developer communities to scale their projects.Community is indeed a powerful concept. It bonds people together, provides an arena to share ideas, and creates opportunities for collaboration. With the right setup, a community of like-minded people with shared interests and goals can become a surprisingly efficient and effective tool for exploring and solving problems together.A developer community serves a crucial role in helping newcomers learn the ropes and getting them excited about your product and — more to the point — excited about being part of the team behind your product. — Open ViewSome key characteristics of a Web3 developer community include:Collaboration: Developers can work together on hackathons, developer challenges, or open-source projects, and contribute code to existing projects. This collaborative spirit also leads to the creation of innovative new software products and tools for companies.Mutual support: Projects inevitably encounter roadblocks. Developer communities offer a built-in support network where you can ask questions, seek advice, and find solutions. Experienced members can troubleshoot issues, and offer guidance based on their experience.Learning and development: Developer communities act as continuous learning engines. Members share insights into the latest advancements, allowing you to keep your project at the forefront of technology. You can explore new libraries, frameworks, and approaches, ensuring your project utilizes the most relevant and powerful tools.Passion for software development: Let’s face it, building a project can be demanding. But with a strong developer community, you’re surrounded by people who share a passion for coding. This shared enthusiasm fuels the community’s growth and provides a source of motivation for your project.Building and maintaining a developer community requires lots of work and determination. However, the rewards usually justify the effort. Offering developers a common platform for interaction is vital for propelling the Web3 industry forward collectively.Benefits of Building a Strong Developer CommunitySource– 101 Blockchains1. Gain Invaluable Product Insights: Projects can gather deep insights into their Web3 products and services by actively engaging with the developer community. Through discussions, feedback, and user interactions, developers can uncover pain points, identify feature requests, and gain a better understanding of user needs. This firsthand knowledge enables teams to make informed decisions, prioritize development efforts, and continuously improve their offerings to serve their audience better.2. Enhance Engagement and Loyalty: A developer community fosters a sense of belonging and collaboration, increasing engagement and loyalty. Web3 projects can create a vibrant ecosystem where developers feel valued and supported by providing a platform for connecting. This sense of community encourages them to remain loyal to the project.3. Access to Top Developers: A thriving Developer community attracts skilled developers passionate about your project. This creates a talent pool you can tap into when seeking new team members. Additionally, the community can serve as a valuable feedback loop, allowing you to identify rising stars within your developer base.4. Enhanced Protocol Security: Security is paramount in the blockchain world. A large and active developer community contributes to a protocol’s security by identifying vulnerabilities and collaborating on solutions to mitigate them. The diversity within a community means that a protocol is tested against a wider range of attack vectors, ensuring a more robust system.5. Wider Adoption and Network Effects: Developers can evangelize a blockchain protocol to broader audiences. By building applications and solutions on top of a protocol, developers can drive user adoption. Each new application not only showcases the capabilities of the blockchain but also attracts non-developer users to the ecosystem, creating a network effect that enhances the value of the protocol.6. Better Developer Tools and Documentation: A strong community often develops its tools and improved documentation, which in turn attracts even more developers to the protocol. This self-reinforcing cycle leads to better development practices and makes the protocol more accessible to newcomers, thereby growing the community and the ecosystem even further.7. Feedback and Real-World Testing: Developers are instrumental in beta testing new features and updates in the blockchain protocol. Their feedback is crucial for understanding real-world usage and limitations, allowing for adjustments before a wider release. This feedback loop can significantly shorten development cycles and improve the quality of the final product.8. Sustainability and Longevity: By engaging a community of developers, blockchain protocols can ensure their sustainability and adaptability over time. A dedicated developer community can carry a project through market fluctuations and technological changes, ensuring its relevance and utility continue.How to Build a Strong Developer Community1. Organize Hackathons &amp;amp; Developer ChallengesHosting developer events is a great method to foster community engagement. These gatherings can take various forms, such as hackathons, developer challenges, workshops, in-person meetups, conferences, virtual seminars, or webinars. Invite knowledgeable speakers to delve into emerging trends, showcase their projects, or offer live coding tutorials. To resonate with programmers, content should be technical and devoid of vendor bias or overly promotional content from sponsors. Prioritize diversity and inclusivity when selecting speakers, as an all-male, homogenous lineup may limit perspectives.The format and level of formality for developer events should align with the community’s preferences. Some communities prefer an informal, democratic unconference format, characterized by spontaneous roundtable discussions and no set agenda. However, maintaining a consistent schedule of events — monthly for smaller gatherings or annually for larger conferences; is essential for building and sustaining community engagement.2. Grow with Content and IncentivesAs your community gains traction, shift your focus towards attracting developers beyond your immediate circle. Create compelling content that transcends technical documentation, offering insights, inspiration, and opportunities for discussion. Develop a content calendar that addresses your audience’s interests and pain points, providing valuable resources that drive engagement and foster community spirit. Consider implementing bug bounties, competitions, and developer grants to incentivize participation and reward contributions. Collaborate with other projects and organizations to expand your reach and attract new members.3. Provide Comprehensive Education and WorkshopsTo lower the entry barrier, blockchain protocols should invest in educational resources that are accessible to all skill levels. This includes detailed workshops, step-by-step tutorials, and interactive coding lessons. Offering free or subsidized courses on blockchain technology can also attract a broader audience.4. Create Incentive ProgramsIncentives can come in various forms such as financial rewards, recognition, or professional opportunities. Offering bounties for bug fixes, feature requests, and even community engagement can motivate developers to contribute consistently. Equity in projects or tokens can also be offered as long-term incentives.5. Building a Supportive Community EnvironmentA supportive environment includes responsive communication channels, regular community meetups (both virtual and physical), and active forums. These platforms should not only focus on the blockchain protocol but also foster discussions around best practices, career advice, and innovation.6. Showcasing Real-World ApplicationsDevelopers are often inspired by seeing the practical impact of their work. Blockchain protocols can facilitate this by partnering with industries that might benefit from blockchain solutions, thereby providing developers with real-world applications and case studies that highlight the effectiveness of the technology.7. Foster Diversity and InclusionA diverse developer community is a resilient one. Efforts should be made to make the community welcoming to developers from various backgrounds, skill levels, and perspectives. This can be achieved through targeted outreach, scholarships, and support groups for underrepresented developers in tech.5 Examples of Strong Developer CommunitiesSource; Freepik1. EkoLance: The EkoLance developer community is undeniably a strong one. We are building a strong developer community through techFiesta; our talent platform for work distribution and online hackathons. On techFiesta, developers participate in hackathons, developer challenges, and crowd tasks. This helps developers gain more hands-on experience and many opportunities for high-paying jobs and entrepreneurship. EkoLance boasts 3000+ trained Web3 developers, a talent pool of over 6000 professionals, and a community of over 8000.As a result of our strong developer community, over 9,000 users have built projects for blockchain protocols and infrastructure companies, 350 projects have been built, and $280K+ has been paid in bounties.2. GitHub community: GitHub is a popular platform for hosting software development projects using the Git version control system.They have a strong developer community. Besides offering a platform for hosting open-source software, GitHub follows many of the tenets of quality developer community building.3. The Aarnâ Protocol Community: Aarnâ protocol is revolutionizing DeFi asset management, decentralizing alpha access and autonomous discovery. It has a discord Server for Crypto Investors and Web3 Developers with roughly 6K members.4. Developer DAO: Developer DAO is a community of developers whose focus is to create a new and more productive version of the Internet. As it is decentralized, it is gated and lets you use the governance token $CODE to access the server anytime.‍The members of the community include those with diverse skills, such as creators, adventurers, explorers, and more.5. Web3 University: Web3 University brings together developers worldwide to teach them about Web3. Web3 University has a Discord channel where Developers are provided with various lesson tracks and a unique series of tutorials with diverse domains of Web3 development.Challenges of Building a Developer CommunityThere are several challenges associated with managing a developer community. They include:Risk of Community Backlash: One significant risk is the potential for a community backlash.Solution: Within any community, members will inevitably express dissatisfaction with the management approach. It’s crucial to anticipate this possibility and develop strategies for handling and moderating contentious discussions effectively.Time-Consuming Nature and Maintaining Engagement: Another challenge is the time-consuming and overwhelming nature of managing a community. Maintaining ongoing engagement can be challenging. Developers may lose interest if they don’t see regular updates or feel their contributions aren’t valued.Solution: This underscores the importance of appointing a dedicated community manager. Regular updates from community managers and transparent roadmaps can keep the community engaged. Also, actively involving community members in decision-making processes through governance tokens or committees can make developers feel more connected and valued.Complexity and Accessibility: Blockchain technology can be complex and intimidating, especially for developers who are new to the space. The steep learning curve can deter many potential community members.Solution: Simplifying the entry process is crucial. This can be achieved through comprehensive, easy-to-understand documentation, beginner-friendly tutorials, and active support channels like forums and real-time chat applications where newcomers can seek help. Regular webinars and workshops can also help demystify the technology.Incentivization: Attracting and retaining talented developers often requires more than just interest in the technology; it requires proper incentives.Solution: Implementing incentive mechanisms such as hackathons with prizes, grants for project development, and bounties for bug reporting can motivate developers. Additionally, offering recognition and career advancement opportunities within the community can serve as long-term incentives.Fragmentation and Competition: With the proliferation of blockchain protocols, developers are often split among numerous projects, which can lead to fragmentation and diluted efforts.Solution: Differentiating the protocol by clearly communicating its unique features and advantages is key. Building partnerships with educational institutions and other technology sectors can also draw a dedicated developer base.Scalability of Community Initiatives: As the community grows, scaling community support and initiatives can become a logistical challenge.Solution: Leveraging more than one community manager can help manage larger groups effectively. Structured mentorship programs can also ensure that knowledge and culture are passed down, maintaining the quality and cohesion of the community as it scales.ConclusionBuilding a strong Web3 developer community is a multifaceted endeavor that requires dedication, creativity, and strategic planning. By designing a compelling developer experience, your company can create the right conditions for attracting a sustainable and engaged community. Remember, the true measure of success lies both in numbers and depth of connections, the quality of contributions, and the collective impact achieved.Are you looking to attract the right developers or build yours? techFiesta is your best bet.Companies that partner with techFiesta have the opportunity to work with a diverse and talented group of tech innovators in our developer community, harnessing their fresh and inventive ideas to fuel growth and success for companies. Over 9,000 users are building projects for blockchain protocols and infrastructure companies, 350 projects have been built, and $280K+ has been paid in bounties. Our platform currently utilizes blockchain for transparent bounty distribution and identification of IDs and credentials during hackathons and developer challenges.To further help you make smarter hiring decisions, our new Soulbound tokens feature offers new possibilities for ownership, verification, and trust in the digital domain of CVs and credentials. Don’t miss out! Sign up on techFiesta now and let’s plan your first hackathon or developer challenge.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How To Mint Soulbound Tokens on Our Talent Platform, techFiesta</title>
    <published>2024-05-28T10:18:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-28T10:18:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/how-to-mint-soulbound-tokens-on-our-talent-platform-techfiesta-9acd7d2b0558?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/how-to-mint-soulbound-tokens-on-our-talent-platform-techfiesta-9acd7d2b0558?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Soulbound Tokens are a type of token that provides a digital reflection of a person’s identity, qualifications, and affiliations in a way that cannot be transferred or exchanged. These tokens are permanently attached to their owner, marking a significant departure from the conventional tokens or NFTs that can be bought, sold, or traded. As a result, they offer a unique and immutable record of an individual’s achievements, abilities, and experiences.Professionals participating in our training programs, hackathons, developer challenges, and crowd tasks earn Soulbound Tokens (SBTs) as undeniable evidence of their expertise and professional milestones. This approach makes it easier for employers to check qualifications while allowing professionals to display their skills and achievements transparently and confidently.A Step-by-Step Guide on How to Mint Soulbound Tokens on techFiestaProfessionals who have finished any training or participated in any hackathon, developer challenge, or crowd tasks on EkoLance or techFiesta can mint their soulbound tokens. Let’s go through a step-by-step guide on how to do this:Step 1: Open the email you received from techFiesta.Step 2: Click on ‘Mint Now’ in the email to be redirected to the minting page.Step 3: Choose ‘Click here to download’ if it’s your first time minting your SoulBound tokens and download the Concordium wallet.Step 4: Download the app on your phone or add the browser extension. Click ‘Yes, I consent’ to proceed.Step 5: Verify your identity using your international passport or ID Card. Wait for Concordium to process your verification.Step 6: Return to the tab asking to connect your Concordium wallet. Click ‘Connect Concordium Wallet.Step 7: Back on the minting page, click ‘Mint SBT,’ then ‘Mint Now.’ Sign and submit the signature request. After signing, you will see a notification that pops up that says “You have minted your SoulBound Tokens.”Step 8: Copy the contract index from the minting page. Go to ‘Manage’ on your wallet, add the contract index, and click ‘Look for tokens.’Step 9. Scroll to find the event you minted SBTs for, tick the box, and click ‘Update tokens.’ Your SoulBound Tokens will be labeled with ‘your balance = 1’ and ‘owned.’Step 10: Select your SoulBound Tokens and transfer them to your Concordium wallet collectibles.Step 11: Go to My Credentials on your techFiesta dashboard to access and share your SoulBound Tokens.🎉 Congratulations! You’ve successfully minted your SBTs and are ready to unlock endless opportunities!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SBTs And How to Build Onchain Reputation and Credential</title>
    <published>2024-03-22T13:42:34+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-03-22T13:42:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/sbts-and-how-to-build-onchain-reputation-and-credential-6d267024c516?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/sbts-and-how-to-build-onchain-reputation-and-credential-6d267024c516?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In the Web3 and digital economies, the challenge of authenticating professional achievements and experiences has never been more acute. Employers often face hurdles in verifying the training and work history claims of potential hires, while professionals grapple with the cumbersome process of proving their qualifications and experiences. The result? Missed opportunities on both ends, with talent and organizations struggling to connect in meaningful ways.We are bridging this existing gap in credential verification by utilizing the power of Soulbound Tokens (SBTs) to transform the way credentials are shared, verified, and valued in the Web3 ecosystem. Our unique SBT integration within EkoLance and our online hackathon platform, techFiesta, provide verifiable proof of educational and career achievements.By participating in our tailored training sessions, hackathons, developer challenges, and crowd tasks, professionals can earn SBTs that serve as irrefutable proof of their skills and career achievements. This not only simplifies the verification process for employers but also empowers professionals to showcase their skills and experiences confidently and transparently.What are Soulbound Tokens (SBTs)?Soulbound Tokens (SBTs) are a revolutionary concept introduced to the blockchain world, designed to represent an individual’s identity, credentials, and affiliations in a non-transferable and immutable manner. Unlike traditional tokens or NFTs that can be bought, sold, or traded, SBTs are “soulbound” to their owner, serving as a permanent record of achievements, skills, and experiences. This unique characteristic makes SBTs an ideal solution for creating a digital, tamper-proof CV that accurately reflects a professional’s journey and capabilities.It originated from a concept proposed by Ethereum co-founder, Vitalik Buterin and other thought leaders. They envisioned it as a means to encapsulate an individual’s social and professional identity in a decentralized context.How Valuable is SBTs to Professionals?For professionals navigating the competitive landscape of the Web3 sector, SBTs offer a multitude of advantages. Here are some of the key benefits:1. Immutable Proof of Achievement: Each SBT serves as an unforgeable record of a professional’s achievements and work experiences, directly linked to their digital identity. This eliminates the need for traditional verification methods, making it easier for professionals to prove their credentials. This digital ledger, or “Digital CV,” as we at EkoLance like to call it, provides a holistic and unforgeable account of an individual’s skills and experiences, accessible to potential employers at a glance.2. Enhanced Visibility to Employers: With SBTs, professionals can easily showcase their skills and experiences to potential employers, standing out in a sea of candidates. The digital CV dashboard will offer a comprehensive view of an individual’s professional journey.3. Streamlined Career Advancement: The ease of sharing verifiable credentials via SBTs simplifies the application process for new opportunities. Professionals can quickly and securely share their digital CVs with prospective employers, reducing the time and friction typically associated with job applications and talent scouting.4. Lifetime Portfolio: SBTs offer professionals a way to accumulate and curate a lifetime portfolio of their learning and achievements. This ongoing record not only aids in career advancement but also fosters a culture of continuous learning and development within the Web3 community.This SBT’s integration within the EkoLance ecosystem goes beyond mere token issuance. Professionals participating in any of our activities — be it training, hackathons, crowd tasks, or recruitment — are awarded SBTs that not only signify their accomplishments but also enrich their digital CVs with detailed metadata, including important details of the achievements, and even transaction hashes for verifiability.EkoLance is spearheading innovation by leveraging Soulbound Tokens (SBTs) to refine the processes of sharing, verifying, and valuing credentials within the digital realm. This strategic initiative directly addresses the industry’s critical challenge of credential verification.By embedding detailed information within SBTs, EkoLance significantly enhances the credibility of professional profiles, thereby streamlining the job application process. This innovation mitigates the traditionally cumbersome task of credential verification, facilitating a smoother interaction between applicants and employers. In an era where digital and physical identities increasingly intersect, SBTs stand as pillars of trust and authenticity.Let’s now delve deeper into the transformative impact of SBTs on Web3 companies seeking professionals to work for them.Are SBTs Important to Talent Seekers?Companies are always on the lookout for innovative methods to find and hire skilled talent. Soulbound Tokens (SBTs) present an effective solution to this challenge. They simplify the hiring process by giving employers access to verifiable, blockchain-based records of a candidate’s achievements and credentials. This shift to a more transparent, efficient, and reliable system moves us away from the traditional and often less dependable ways of checking professional backgrounds. SBTs help talent seekers in the following ways:1. Smarter Hiring Decisions: With SBTs, companies can access a candidate’s digital CV, a comprehensive record of their professional journey authenticated by blockchain technology. This not only speeds up the verification process but also ensures the integrity of the information presented, allowing for smarter, data-driven hiring decisions.2. Enhancing Employer Branding: By issuing SBTs and collaborating with EkoLance to host training or launch hackathons, companies position themselves at the forefront of innovation. This not only enhances their appeal to top-tier talent who value forward-thinking employers but also underscores their commitment to transparency and technological advancement in the hiring process.3. Building a Community of Talent: Through hosting events and issuing SBTs, companies can cultivate a vibrant community of engaged professionals. This ecosystem fosters loyalty and ongoing engagement, as participants are more likely to return for future training and networking opportunities, further enriching the talent pool available to the organization.What Makes EkoLance Stand Out?EkoLance represents a unique convergence of educational training, workshops, online hackathons, developer challenges, and job opportunities. These events are designed not just as avenues for learning and development but also as a way for professionals to accrue tangible, verifiable credentials of their skills and achievements.What sets us apart is the promise of a digital CV dashboard, a feature that goes beyond mere token collection. This dashboard provides a visual and interactive representation of all SBTs earned, offering a detailed overview of all credentials. Each credential includes specifics related to the event/workshop or job for more transparency and transaction hashes for authenticity.Another unique feature is the seamless integration of the Concordium wallet into our ecosystem. Upon completion of each event or training, participants receive an email prompt to mint their SBTs, which can then be viewed within their Concordium wallet, linked directly to our talent platform. This process not only ensures the security and integrity of the tokens but also enhances the user experience by making the management of SBTs easy and accessible.Looking ForwardThe upcoming launch of the digital CV dashboard and on-chain credentials is just the beginning. This functionality aims to revolutionize how professionals manage and present their on-chain reputations and credentials, offering a dynamic, interactive platform that brings the concept of a digital resume to life.Beyond the dashboard, our vision includes expanding the types of activities and events that can earn users SBTs, integrating with more blockchain platforms for wider accessibility, and partnering with an increasing number of organizations to enrich the ecosystem further. Our goal is to make SBTs a universal standard for professional credentials in the Web3 space, enhancing the value they provide to both individuals and companies.Join Us on This Journey: We invite both professionals and organizations to be part of this exciting evolution. Whether you’re looking to solidify your on-chain reputation, verify the credentials of potential hires, or collaborate on hosting transformative events, EkoLance offers the tools and community to achieve these goals.We’re not just revolutionizing the future of work; we’re shaping the future of professional identity in the digital age!About EkoLanceEkoLance revolutionizes the future of work by empowering professionals in Web2 and the blockchain industry. EkoLance has two products: an educational platform with training programs for upskilling in the blockchain space and a developer activation platform called techFiesta, where companies launch hackathons, developer challenges, and crowd tasks. EkoLance has a community of over 8,000 blockchain professionals.Follow us on our social channels:LinkedIn: EkoLanceTwitter: EkoLanceInstagram: EkoLanceFacebook: EkoLanceDiscord: EkoLance</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Swisstronik’s Developer Challenge on techFiesta</title>
    <published>2024-02-28T11:02:42+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-02-28T11:02:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/swisstroniks-developer-challenge-on-techfiesta-3ec86af6196c?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/swisstroniks-developer-challenge-on-techfiesta-3ec86af6196c?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The Swisstronik Developer Challenges on techFiesta, showcased innovation and coding expertise of global developers. These challenges played an instrumental role in fostering creativity and problem-solving through the techFiesta platformClient: SwissTronikExecution:The online challenges unfolded in two distinct phases, each lasting a week, with techFiesta handling promotions, community engagement, and seamless disbursement of rewards to the winners from a $800 prize pool.During the 2-week developer Challenge, developers were engaged with technical tasks, each designed to be resolved within an hour. The challenge was a series of quick, intensive problem-solving exercises.ResultAttracted over 120 hackers.62 developers built a basic smart contract for a voting system during the first developer challenge.For the second developer challenge, over 60+ built smart contracts, necessitating deployment, and scriptwriting to access specific variables across multiple testnets.Yielded 65 submissions from our thriving global Developer Community.Developer Challenge DetailsFormat: OnlineDuration: 1 week for each of the phases.Developer Challenge TasksFirst Challenge: Hackers were propelled into a rigorous 45-minute challenge to develop a basic smart contract for a voting system that allows only registered members to vote and deploy it on the Swisstronik testnet.Second Challenge: Hackers were tasked with crafting a sophisticated smart contract, necessitating deployment and scriptwriting to access specific variables across multiple testnets.The Winners and BountiesFirst Developer Challenge: The inaugural challenge focused on smart contract development, witnessing over 62 participants and 35 submissions. 10 winners were awarded $30 each, recognizing their remarkable skills and innovative solutions.Second Developer Challenge: With over 60 participants, the second challenge recorded 30 submissions. There were 5 winners and each got a $50 prize for their outstanding coding prowess and innovation.techFiesta: Driving the Tech Industry Forward Through Developer EventsThe Swisstronik Developer Challenges on techFiesta exemplified the fusion of innovation, skill, and collaborative spirit among developers. Hosting events on our platform offers a strategic advantage, positioning companies at the forefront of technological evolution and fostering an ecosystem of growth and innovation. This event did more than highlight the participants’ technical prowess; it demonstrated the profound impact that such concentrated innovation can have in driving the tech industry forward.Looking forward, techFiesta seeks to partner with many companies to host developer challenges and hackathons. The benefits are clear: grow your developer and user communities, access groundbreaking ideas, build innovative projects, and increase your brand visibility. Reach out to us today by clicking here.About SwisstronikSwisstronik is an identity-based blockchain ecosystem where regulatory compliance, decentralization, and user privacy meet to enable true blockchain adoption. It lets Web 3.0 and traditional companies build KYC-, AML-, and DPR-compliant decentralized applications (dApps) with enhanced data privacy.To enable this, the Swisstronik blockchain leverages programmable and cryptographic privacy protection methods to keep user data private. At the same time, the Swisstronik Web3 Compliance Suite gathers international KYC issuers and other legal service providers to keep the Swisstronik system and the dApps powered by it regulatory compliant at all times.About techFiestatechFiesta is a developer activation platform where companies launch hackathons and developer challenges. Our developer events are designed to provide an engaging and rewarding experience for developers of all levels, as well as professionals from other fields who are interested in technology. Protocols that host developer events on techFiesta have the opportunity to work with a diverse and talented group of developers, harnessing their fresh and inventive ideas to fuel growth and success in their businesses.Follow us on our various social channels:LinkedIn: techFiestaTwitter: techFiestaDiscord: techFiestaTelegram: techFiesta</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Gnosis Chain Hackathon on techFiesta</title>
    <published>2024-02-22T14:03:41+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-02-22T14:03:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/gnosis-chain-hackathon-on-techfiesta-e30be776f89e?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/gnosis-chain-hackathon-on-techfiesta-e30be776f89e?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The Gnosis Chain Hackathon on techFiesta marked a significant convergence of global developers. This event fostered collaboration and technological advancement within the developer community.Client: Gnosis ChianExecution: The 21-day intensive online hackathon was all about empowering developers to build projects on the Gnosis chain ecosystem. Developers competed for rewards totaling $2,000 by building innovative solutions on the Gnosis chain, an EVM-compatible Layer-1 blockchain. Developers had the exciting opportunity to immerse themselves in educational workshops.Workshops: The Gnosis Chain Hackathon Kick-Off Session and How to Build a Startup out of Your Hackathon Project were a goldmine of learning experiences, arming participants with the essential knowledge and tools needed to navigate the intricacies of project development.ResultOver 5000 hackers learned how to build a startup out of their hackathon project through the workshops.18 participants submitted the demo videos of their projects.The top 3 winners created real-world solutions. They are Rainfy (Decentralized savings app), Verxio Protocol (Privacy protection solution), and Event Connect (Event management).Hackathon DetailsFormat: OnlineDuration: 4 weeksHackathon Task and TracksHackers were asked to build anything they liked on the Gnosis Chain.Tracks — AI | Games &amp;amp; NFT Infrastructure | Mech NFTs | POAP | Euro Ramp AppHackathon BountiesThe Gnosis Chain hackathon ended with a Demo session held via Zoom, showcasing 18 innovative projects through 1-minute video submissions, highlighting an environment of creativity and ingenuity.Winning Project DetailsRainfy — Rainfy’s decentralized savings application collaborates with Monerium, enabling effortless conversion of fiat currencies into stablecoins on the Gnosis chain. The platform incentivizes savings through gamified earning models and empowers users with insightful financial management features.Verxio Protocol — Addressing privacy concerns, Verxio Protocol ensures anonymous transactions on the Gnosis Blockchain, safeguarding user identities and financial confidentiality through stealth addresses.Event Connect — An integral part of EduConnect, Event Connect manages educational events effectively, offering comprehensive event administration and promotion, along with POAP Certifications for attendees.Impact of this techFiestaThe Gnosis Chain hackathon on techFiesta served as an opportunity for diverse developers to build innovative projects on the Gnosis chain. Developers also had the opportunity to elevate their skills significantly, leveraging insightful workshops and real-time support to navigate project development intricacies.Organizing a techFiesta allows you to benefit from fresh ideas and valuable feedback, essential for driving your business growth. Most importantly, it helps you build and nurture your developer and user communities, laying the foundation for success through shared efforts and collaboration.About GnosisGnosis Chain is an EVM-compatible Layer-1 blockchain for software engineers, targeting top-notch security, resilience, and credible neutrality, backed by a deeply decentralized network secured by over 100K validators. The Gnosis mission has always been centered on experimentation and building decentralized infrastructure for the Ethereum ecosystem. When Gnosis was founded in 2015, it focused on building prediction markets to enable worldwide access to accurate information. To learn more about Gnosis, click here!About techFiestatechFiesta is a blockchain-powered hackathon platform that connects passionate professionals from all over the world with top companies and industry experts in the tech space. Our hackathons are designed to provide an engaging and collaborative experience for developers of all levels, as well as professionals from other fields who are interested in technology. Companies that participate in our hackathons have the opportunity to work with a diverse and talented group of tech innovators, harnessing their fresh and inventive ideas to fuel growth and success in their businesses.Follow us on our various social channels:LinkedIn: techFiestaTwitter: techFiestaDiscord: techFiestaTelegram: techFiestaMedium: techFiesta</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">TóróNet Hackathon on techFiesta</title>
    <published>2024-02-14T09:43:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-02-14T09:43:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/t%C3%B3r%C3%B3net-hackathon-on-techfiesta-1812783926aa?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/t%C3%B3r%C3%B3net-hackathon-on-techfiesta-1812783926aa?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The TóróNet hackathon, organised on techFiesta offered developers an opportunity to create real-world applications on the TóróNet chain.Clients: TóróNetExecution: The 27- day online hackathon focused on developers designing a draft concept of an application that solves a problem in communities. Technical sessions and workshops organized by the TóróNet team facilitated a deeper understanding of the blockchain and the specific challenges presented. The closing ceremony was held virtually on December 7, 2023, and the purpose was to celebrate the achievements of the 56 participants and unveil the hackathon winners.Workshops: “Toronet Hackathon Kick-off Session” and “Toronet Hackathon Technical Session” provided comprehensive details about the hackathon and delved deeply into the complexities of the Toronet Hackathon.ResultOver 500 developers participated in the online workshops organized by the ToroNet team.56 participants created applications with real-world applicability as tangible smart contracts on the TóróNet chain.The applications built by the 5 winners impacted local communities with limited access to financial services. These projects addressed financial insecurities, invented renewable energy solutions, and provided a secure, transparent, and efficient way for users to save, contribute, and work towards achieving financial and lifestyle goals.Hackathon DetailsFormat: OnlineDuration: 4 weeksHackathon Task and TracksHackers were asked to;Design a draft concept of an application that solves a problem in their community.Develop the concept into smart contracts on Toronet and illustrate basically how the application would function to solve the problem.​Hackathon Tracks — Finance | Operations | Environmental | Social | Cooperative &amp;amp; Community | TechnologyHackathon BountiesOut of the 56 talented developers who participated in the hackathon, five were announced as winners, each distinguished by their innovative and practical solutions. The top five winning projects showed how blockchain can impact communities for the better. They shared $18,000 in prizes.Winning Project DetailsCoffer City is a Web3 solution addressing financial insecurities, promoting economic resilience, and fostering transparent savings and contributions within Nigerian communities.Groverse is revolutionizing renewable energy access with affordable and user-friendly solutions, incentivizing users through daily token mining.ThriftChain is a blockchain-based financial management tool facilitating individual and group savings, contributions, and thrift activities, addressing challenges in acquiring assets.Eco4reward is a decentralized solution incentivizing eco-friendly actions to address environmental degradation and rising unemployment in Nigeria.Nyé is a secure and transparent ecosystem connecting donors with NGOs, redefining the donation landscape with Toro tokens to ensure transparency and tangible impact.techFiesta Events: Fostering Community-Driven InnovationsThe ToroNet hackathon significantly advanced community-focused innovation and inclusive financial solutions. Developers demonstrated exceptional creativity by developing applications tailored to meet the needs of underserved communities.At techFiesta, our commitment lies in nurturing innovation, inclusivity, and impactful technological advancements. Collaborating with techFiesta offers companies an opportunity to engage with a dynamic developer community, enhance their brand visibility, and contribute to the development of transformative technologies.About TóróNetThe TóróNet is the world’s first layer 1 blockchain designed to power the tokenized economies of the Global South. They’re a pioneering organization dedicated to transforming lives and empowering underserved communities through innovative solutions. With a strong commitment to humanitarian values, they harness cutting-edge technologies to overcome the limitations of modern infrastructure and bridge the gap in access to essential services. TóróNet’s mission is to improve the well-being of individuals and communities left behind in the fast-paced world by providing increased access to education, healthcare, financial services, and economic opportunities.About techFiestatechFiesta is an online hackathon platform where companies launch hackathons, developer challenges, and crowd tasks. Our techFiestas are designed to provide an engaging and rewarding experience for developers of all levels, as well as professionals from other fields who are interested in technology. Protocols that host techFiestas have the opportunity to work with a diverse and talented group of professionals, harnessing their fresh and inventive ideas to fuel growth and success in their businesses.Follow us on our various social channels:LinkedIn: techFiestaTwitter: techFiestaDiscord: techFiestaTelegram: techFiesta</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Highlights from the Aleph Zero Hackathon on techFiesta</title>
    <published>2024-01-25T15:31:16+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-01-25T15:31:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/highlights-from-the-aleph-zero-hackathon-on-techfiesta-bef9ca24b0e6?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/highlights-from-the-aleph-zero-hackathon-on-techfiesta-bef9ca24b0e6?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Recently, the Aleph Zero hackathon ended successfully on techFiesta. It started on the 27th of November and ended on the 15th of December 2023. With over 20 participants, this hackathon was a beacon for creators seeking to solve real-world challenges and redefine the development landscape within the Aleph Zero ecosystem.techFiesta was the primary hub for participants to see hackathon details, submit their projects, and distribute rewards to deserving winners from a prize pool of $3500. We played a crucial role in promoting the hackathon, engaging with the developer community, and organizing events attracting diverse hackers. Thanks to the Aleph Zero team for hosting this hackathon on techFiesta.Developer Training SessionPreceding the hackathon kickoff, the Aleph Zero team curated an immersive developer training, delving deep into an important topic tailored to their platform. This intensive training session offers participants a detailed exploration of Aleh Zero, offering insights into smart contract development with Ink and harnessing its full potential. The training entails the following:How to Develop Smart Contracts With Ink: To prepare for the hackathon, Aleph Zero took proactive steps by offering participants comprehensive guidance and mentorship through specialized training sessions focusing on creating smart contracts using Ink, the language fundamental to their smart contract ecosystem. The training was led by Uladzislau Savenia, the Developer Relations Specialist at Aleph Zero. Through these sessions, participants were provided with an in-depth understanding of Ink, empowering them with invaluable insights into leveraging this language for crafting efficient and secure smart contracts.The Hackathon ProcessThis hackathon aims to make the Aleph Zero platform as developer-friendly as possible, building tools that empower developers to create innovative solutions that solve real-world challenges and streamline the development process. Aleph Zero upholds rigorous standards for data privacy and transaction security while aiming for genuine decentralization over time.Participants were tasked with crafting ingenious solutions ranging from IDE integrations for Ink! to pioneering platforms for smart contract deployment and lifecycle management. Its canvas extended to innovations in wallets and user adoption integrations, all to facilitate the creation of groundbreaking solutions. They benefited from two insightful workshops that helped improve their skills and knowledge, making the competition intense and innovative.The educational workshops entailed the following:Aleph Zero Hackathon Kick-off Session: In this virtual kick-off session, Aleph Zero Developer Relations Specialist, Uladzislau Savenia introduced Aleph Zero and the expectations of the hackathon participants. Maria Eneva-Olms from techFiesta shared the key details about the hackathon and showed how the participants can register on techFiesta and submit their projects.Aleph Zero Hackathon Information Session: In this information session, Piotr Moczurad, the Ecosystem Tech Lead and Blockchain Developer at Aleph Zero, provided an insightful introduction to Aleph Zero and elaborated on the hackathon’s expectations. He navigates through the core principles of Aleph Zero, offering participants a deeper understanding of the platform’s functionalities. Additionally, he sets the stage for the hackathon, sharing valuable insights, anticipated outcomes, and essential guidelines, laying a robust foundation for participants to embark on their creative journeys to hackathon success.The Winning Projects are:1st Place: Zedar Aleph Zero notifications — $2000This project is a notification service that sends notifications about events on the Aleph Zero chain to subscribed on-chain accounts. Notifications are sent to various channels, including Telegram. The on-chain smart contract manages subscriptions, while an off-chain service manages notifications.In summary, this mechanism allows users on the blockchain to autonomously create and validate subscriptions through the execution of smart contracts. The smart contract not only facilitates the registration of these subscriptions but also ensures that the corresponding fees are reserved according to the specified duration of the subscription, providing a transparent and automated process within the blockchain network.2nd Place: Inkly — $1500Inkly is designed to provide comprehensive support for ink! smart contract development, testing, and deployment. This innovative tool aims to facilitate a seamless transition for Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM) developers into the thriving ink! ecosystem by offering a rich set of functionalities.In essence, Inkly is a pivotal tool in the Aleph Zero ecosystem to foster innovation and provide developers with the resources they need to excel in the rapidly evolving landscape of blockchain technology. With its seamless integration into the ink! ecosystem, Inkly not only simplifies development processes but also contributes to the growth and accessibility of decentralized applications on the Aleph Zero blockchain.Impact of Aleph Zero HackathonAleph Zero hackathon marks another chapter of innovation, collaboration, and breakthroughs. Guided by the pursuit of solving real-world challenges and streamlining the development process, this hackathon showcased a multitude of visionary solutions.The synergy between Aleph Zero and techFiesta acted as a catalyst, inspiring participants to push the boundaries of what’s possible in blockchain development. Each contribution not only aimed at making Aleph Zero more developer-friendly but also paved the way for a more inclusive and innovative blockchain ecosystem.As the curtains draw on this collaborative journey, the legacy of the Aleph Zero hackathon remains — a testament to the power of collaboration, creativity, and the shared vision of empowering developers to craft transformative solutions on a platform that continually strives for excellence and accessibility.ConclusionAleph Zero’s recent hackathon has proven to be a pivotal event in empowering developers globally, serving as a nexus for the convergence and exchange of innovative ideas. In collaboration with techFiesta, this event has significantly enhanced the platform’s accessibility to developers, fostering an environment ripe for technological breakthroughs. The winning entries from this hackathon were exemplary in their innovation, and there is considerable anticipation regarding their potential impact, particularly in Africa and other regions.For developers, participation in hackathons is an invaluable opportunity. These events not only provide a platform to demonstrate technical prowess but also offer chances to secure bounties, access funding, and grants, and establish partnerships with other builders and innovators in the field. Register on the techFiesta platform now and begin your hacking journey.About Aleph ZeroAleph Zero is a privacy-enhancing layer 1 blockchain, engineered for speed, achieving efficiencies akin to conventional web2 systems. It upholds rigorous standards for data privacy and transaction security while aiming for genuine decentralization over time. Aleph Zero’s versatility is highlighted by over 40 use cases being actively developed, showcasing its adaptability across various sectors and applications.About techFiestatechFiesta is a developer activation platform where companies launch hackathons and developer challenges. Our developer events are designed to provide an engaging and rewarding experience for developers of all levels, as well as professionals from other fields who are interested in technology. Protocols that host developer events on techFiesta have the opportunity to work with a diverse and talented group of developers, harnessing their fresh and inventive ideas to fuel growth and success in their businesses.Follow us on our various social channels:LinkedIn: techFiestaTwitter: techFiestaDiscord: techFiestaTelegram: techFiesta</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Celo X Bunzz Hackathon on techFiesta</title>
    <published>2024-01-25T15:05:40+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-01-25T15:05:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/celo-x-bunzz-hackathon-on-techfiesta-bb249cc05a0c?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/celo-x-bunzz-hackathon-on-techfiesta-bb249cc05a0c?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The Celo X Bunzz hackathon on techFiesta was held to promote technological growth and cooperative innovation among the African developer community.Clients: The Celo Foundation Africa DAO and BunzzExecution: Over four weeks, a hybrid hackathon took place. It began with teams submitting their ideas online. All ideas were accepted by The Celo Foundation Africa DAO and Bunzz, leading every team into the second stage which is the development phase. This phase included online practical workshops to help them in the building process.The event ended with an in-person, showcase of the top 11 projects. This mix of online and in-person elements created a well-rounded learning experience. It showed a successful model for innovative and inclusive events.Workshops: “Bunzz Ecosystem and Celo Deployment” and “Introduction to Celo Composer” gave the hackers the necessary skills to build their projects.Result21 projects were built.Over 500 developers learned how to build on Celo and deploy smart contracts to the Celo Network through Bunzz.The projects were built across diverse sectors such as document security (TIỌWỌ̀BỌ́), decentralized platforms (Solvre), collaborative marketing (Chainwise), music industry rights management (Yoshka), and digital literature preservation (Akwụkwọ), all harnessing blockchain technology for enhanced efficiency and transparency.Hackathon DetailsFormat: Hybrid (online and in-person)Duration: 4 weeksHackathon Task and TracksHackers were expected to build on Celo and deploy smart contracts to the Celo Network through Bunzz.​Hackathon Tracks — DeFi | NFT/Art/Gaming | Social Good | E-commerce | All Things Blockchain &amp;amp; CryptocurrenciesHackathon BountiesThe top five winners received USDC transfers directly to their digital wallets through the techFiesta platform. The participant with the highest score was awarded $2,000. The second and third-place participants received $1,500 and $1,000, respectively. The fourth and fifth-place finishers each received $250. To acknowledge the effort of all participants, each was granted an NFT representing their contribution. This method of offering financial rewards and NFTs serves to recognize the commitment and innovation of the participants in the hackathon.Winning Project DetailsTIỌWỌ̀BỌ́ offers a solution for document sharing and signature appending, utilizing technology for secure and efficient processes.Chainwise enables collaborative campaigns by connecting product creators, influencers, and communities to achieve specific goals.Solvre introduces a new approach to bounty platforms, focusing on decentralization to ensure reward fairness and transparency.Yoshka provides a method for song ownership through tokenization, aiming for equitable royalties and clear value management in the music industry.Akwụkwọ introduces the concept of NFT-based book libraries, digitizing literature for preservation and access.techFiesta Events: Driving Growth and Community EngagementHosting events with techFiesta helps you tap into a powerful marketing channel that boosts your project’s visibility and establishes your brand as a thought leader in the tech community. The platform connects you with a dynamic network of developers and blockchain professionals, creating opportunities for innovation to solve real-world challenges.Organizing a techFiesta allows you to benefit from fresh ideas and valuable feedback, essential for driving your business growth. Most importantly, it helps you build and nurture your developer and user communities, laying the foundation for success through shared efforts and collaboration.About Celo FoundationThe Celo Foundation was founded in 2017 to support the growth and development of the decentralized, open-source, and mobile-first Celo platforms. Its platform helps build a carbon-negative financial system that creates conditions of prosperity for all. The Foundation is guided by the Celo community tenets. It contributes to education, technical research, environmental health, community engagement, and ecosystem outreach — activities that support and encourage an inclusive financial system.About BunzzBunzz is the largest DApp development platform in the Asian region, and supplies modules for the most frequently used smart contracts, allowing it to deploy them on all EVM networks with a GUI. This reduces development time for smart contracts by 99%. The modules are audited, allowing users to avoid the great expense of security checks. Smart contract modules can be uploaded to the repository and published by the users themselves. Bunzz has the potential to become a Docker Hub in the Web3 space.About techFiestatechFiesta is a blockchain-powered hackathon platform that connects passionate professionals from all over the world with top companies and industry experts in the tech space. Our hackathons are designed to provide an engaging and collaborative experience for developers of all levels, as well as professionals from other fields who are interested in technology. Companies that participate in our hackathons have the opportunity to work with a diverse and talented group of tech innovators, harnessing their fresh and inventive ideas to fuel growth and success in their businesses.Follow us on our various social channels:LinkedIn: techFiestaTwitter: techFiestaDiscord: techFiestaTelegram: techFiesta</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Haven1 Developer Challenge: Empowering Innovation Through Identity Solutions</title>
    <published>2023-12-18T10:49:34+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-18T10:49:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@techFiesta/haven1-developer-challenge-empowering-innovation-through-identity-solutions-4559f36cab01?source=rss-13b36675db09------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@techFiesta/haven1-developer-challenge-empowering-innovation-through-identity-solutions-4559f36cab01?source=rss-13b36675db09------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>techFiesta</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Haven1 Developer Challenge on techFiesta was a dynamic and innovative event that spanned from November 22nd to December 4th, 2023, attracting 41 developers. This challenge provided an opportunity for developers to showcase their skills, collaborate, and compete for prizes from a pool worth $500.techFiesta served as a central hub where developers saw all the details of the challenges and submitted their projects. At the same time, the Haven1 team utilized their techFiesta dashboard to evaluate the submissions and monitor all hackathon Key Performance Indicators (KPIs). techFiesta also offered an integrated payment processing feature to facilitate the on-chain disbursement of bounties.We are grateful for the trust placed in us to manage this exceptional event. Our role involved promoting the challenge, fostering a vibrant developer community, and coordinating events that attracted a diverse array of developers from around the globe.During the challenge, participants were given a task to create a simple smart contract that imports Haven1’s `Proof of Identity.sol` contract. It was an opportunity to innovate applications with the potential to transform tangible smart contracts on the Haven1 chain. Through this challenge, Haven1 aimed to harness blockchain solutions to foster groundbreaking solutions in the realm of decentralized identity verification.At the end of the intense development period, 10 winners emerged, each exemplifying outstanding skill, creativity, and a deep understanding of creating smart contracts on Haven 1.The Impact of Haven1 Developer ChallengeHaven1 is dedicated to ensuring top-notch security, reliability, and adherence to regulations, all while offering an easy-to-use interface. This innovative approach has led to a robust and scalable system that supports fast and secure transactions, paving the way for a new era in decentralized finance.This developer challenge is a testament to innovation. It encouraged developers to explore the potential of integrating verifiable identities within smart contracts. The aim is to develop smart contracts that maintain the high standards of security and regulatory compliance that Haven1 is known for.In line with this, our role in hosting such challenges on techFiesta reflects our commitment to driving technological innovation. We organize events that inspire developers to delve into blockchain technologies. Our goal with this challenge aligns with our mission to empower developers, promote collaboration, and spur the creation of practical applications.“The Haven1 developer challenge showcases our commitment to advancing technological expertise, inspiring innovation, and enabling developers to create solutions on innovative blockchain protocols.”. — Maria Eneva-Olms, CEO and Founder of techFiesta.For developers, events like this offer a platform to display talents, win rewards, secure grants and funding, and forge valuable connections with fellow builders and innovators. By joining the techFiesta community, you’re not only participating in developer events; you’re igniting a journey of endless exploration in the tech landscape. Register on the techFiesta platform now and begin your hacking journey.Looking forward, techFiesta seeks to partner with many protocols to host developer challenges and hackathons. The benefits are clear: grow your developer and user communities, access groundbreaking ideas, build innovative projects, and increase your brand visibility. Contact us today by clicking here.About Haven1Haven1 is an EVM-compatible Layer 1 blockchain that brings key principles of traditional finance to Web3. Built-in verifiable identity at the wallet level facilitates recourse mechanisms and security guardrails which allow Haven1 to unlock previously unattainable decentralized finance use cases. Purpose-built for secure and regulated financial transactions, Haven1 is the destination for a new generation of on-chain finance. With a focus on security, reliability, regulatory compliance, and an intuitive user experience, Haven1 offers a robust and scalable infrastructure for lightning-fast, safe, and secure transactions.About techFiestatechFiesta is a developer activation platform where companies launch hackathons and developer challenges. Our developer events are designed to provide an engaging and rewarding experience for developers of all levels, as well as professionals from other fields who are interested in technology. Protocols that host developer events on techFiesta have the opportunity to work with a diverse and talented group of developers, harnessing their fresh and inventive ideas to fuel growth and success in their businesses.Follow us on our various social channels:LinkedIn: techFiestaTwitter: techFiestaDiscord: techFiestaTelegram: techFiesta</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
