<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">StellarX - Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/stellarxhq?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fstellarxhq&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fstellarxhq&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:29+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">AMMs on StellarX</title>
    <published>2021-11-12T21:45:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T21:45:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/stellarxhq/amms-on-stellarx-b0f9c493936c?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/stellarxhq/amms-on-stellarx-b0f9c493936c?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Dima</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">What are AMMs and how to use them with StellarXAutomated Market MakersJust a week ago the upgrade of the Stellar network introduced the support for native AMMs (Automated Market Makers). AMM is an interesting concept that allows users to provide liquidity to the markets and earn fees in the process.Here’s a short summary of how AMMs work on Stellar. Anyone can deposit two Stellar assets they own into a liquidity pool. If someone converts funds through the liquidity pool using assets swap (path payments), contributors to the liquidity pools will earn a share of the 0.3% fees paid by traders.AMMs might be a familiar concept if you have used products like Uniswap to provide liquidity to market pairs on the Ethereum blockchain.We are happy to announce that StellarX now provides a simple interface to explore how AMMs work on Stellar and interact with them.Stellar AMMs are in a class of their ownCompared to other AMMs in the crypto universe, Stellar AMMs are massively different. They are native to the Stellar blockchain.Having native AMMs makes Stellar the first blockchain to provide liquidity solutions at the protocol level, allowing users of AMMs to take advantage of the near-zero fees on Stellar. There is no need to pay hundreds of dollars in fees to deposit and withdraw with AMM liquidity pools. It also allows all Stellar projects to use the same liquidity. This increases volume and benefits everyone from developers to network users.Another advantage of AMMs is the improvement they bring to swap functionality on the network. Any Stellar project that has a swap interface automatically started to benefit from better liquidity after the AMM launch. As liquidity pools continue to fill, swaps become more useable and provide improved exchange rates giving users a better trading experience.It’s easy to get excited about this new functionality. Liquidity providers can keep more of their assets thanks to reduced fees, and due to the inclusive nature of Stellar, anyone can take part whether they have assets worth a few dollars or millions.Getting started with AMMs on StellarXToday anyone can participate in AMMs on Stellar by going to stellarx.com.AMM overviewYou can view all activity across Stellar AMM Liquidity Pools from this page. The option to browse top AMM pairs and search for individual pairs enables you to see each pool’s performance, as well as access their Individual Pool Analytics page. Explore top liquidity pools to help you make decisions on where is best to provide liquidity.Individual Pool AnalyticsOn the pool’s analytics page you can view transactions and check out the exchange rates of both assets in the pool. Total Tokens Locked section allows you to see the total amount of locked assets in this liquidity pool.XLM/USDC AMM pool details pageAdd LiquidityTo start, log in to StellarX with your preferred method (StellarX account, a Ledger device, or WalletConnect via the LOBSTR app). Once in, head over to the AMM section to access your AMM dashboard.To start providing liquidity, select Add Liquidity option.You can use the dropdown menus to select the two assets you would like to use to provide liquidity. Using the input sections, you can enter how much of each asset you would like to provide to the pool. StellarX will automatically balance the other asset as both need to have roughly the same $ value (50%/50%) to be sent to the liquidity pool.StellarX will then present you with the summary page for the transaction. If you’re happy, click Add Liquidity to finish the process.Liquidity Pool OverviewAny pools you provide liquidity towards will show in the overview section. From here, you can increase and remove liquidity to each of the pools you’re in and view each pool’s statistics using the graph icon.Remove LiquidityIn this section, you can select how much liquidity you would like to remove from a pool. The network uses your pool shares to calculate how much of each asset to return to your wallet.With AMM access enabled for your wallets in StellarX, there has never been more opportunity to decide what to do with your assets on Stellar. We hope you take advantage of these new options and discover what else Stellar can provide for you.You can follow us on Twitter for updates and use our Reddit to find out more about StellarX.For more information on AMMs, please follow the links bellow:Introducing Automated Market Makers on StellarFast Forwarding Stellar AMMsProtocol 18 Upgrade GuideAMMs in the Stellar EcosystemAMMs on StellarX was originally published in StellarX on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The New Age of Financial Transactions</title>
    <published>2019-09-19T20:08:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-19T20:08:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/stellarxhq/the-new-age-of-financial-transactions-aec715f9d730?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/stellarxhq/the-new-age-of-financial-transactions-aec715f9d730?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ari Diamond</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In this article we will shed some light on how StellarX helps to power the future of global payments using the Stellar network.As you know, Stellar is an open-source decentralized protocol that allows transactions between ANY currencies on the Stellar network — essentially, it’s a place to move assets of many types in fast, easy and cheap ways.The Stellar network is able to fulfill its function as a universal payment system through StellarX. The beauty of StellarX is its ability to act as a platform that bridges and connects different economies and currencies in a way that was not possible in traditional financial services.Anchors Are The Key — But How Do They Work?Anchors are truly incredible mechanisms that can power innovative financial possibilities across the Stellar ecosystem. They’re what define Stellar as a blockchain that’s not rooted in moving a specific asset type, but a functional blockchain that harnesses moving any type of asset. In short, Anchors provide a pivotal bridge into the Stellar ecosystem by allowing any off-chain asset to be deposited or withdrawn on StellarX.What’s even better? They’re cheap, fast, and frankly more powerful than traditional money transmitter options.Let’s consider the following scenario:I’m a user living in New York City that wants to send Nigerian Naira to a user in Lagos, Nigeria.Traditionally: the user could use a money transmitter like a Western Union, and be subject to the crazy world of money transmitter restrictions such as: delayed timelines, fees related to transmission costs, foreign exchange costs, delayed delivery options, amount sent, destination country, currency availability, agent location hours, and differences in time zones.But why would you do that if you have a more cost efficient and faster alternative?StellarX: the user can use Anchors to deposit USD using AnchorUSD. Once you receive AnchorUSD, you can exchange your currency for Nigerian Naira using Cowrie’s Anchor (NGNT) and send it to the recipient user’s wallet. Once the recipient user receives NGNT, they can withdraw it directly to their Nigerian Naira bank account.Why is this important?Because it’s cheaper and faster for two parties to deposit, send, receive, and withdraw fiat currencies. We believe that Anchors will be the key players for financial inclusiveness (and ease) and one of the most important growth factors for the adoption of the platform and ecosystem.Based on that vision, StellarX is constantly looking to integrate new Anchors to our platform. Our goal is to have an ecosystem of strong off-chain assets, represented as both fiat and crypto Anchors. The more we have integrated, the higher the likelihood Stellar can make traditional payment systems obsolete.So far we have integrated 2 fiat and 10+ crypto Anchors but this is just the beginning. Through our partners like AnchorUSD, Cowrie Exchange, and aPay, now our users can deposit, send, receive, and withdraw USD, NGNT, BTC, ETH, LTC, SALT, OMG, ZRX, BCH, KIN, MTL, REP, XEL, BAT, and LINK.For more updates on future Anchor launches, please follow us on Twitter. We have several Anchors in the pipeline that we will be adding between now and the end of 2019. Stay tuned!New Anchor Deposit and Withdrawal ExperienceSince we are hyper-focused on our Anchor experience, we have also invested in a UX overhaul of our deposit and withdraw journeys for both fiat and crypto. Now it’s even easier to add off-chain assets on StellarX!Path Payments and How They Tie to AnchorsAs you might have heard, we recently released path payments on StellarX. Huh? Path payments? Allow me to explain…The Stellar Network allows payments to be made across assets using the path payments feature. A path payment specifies a series of assets to route a payment through, from source asset (the asset debited from the payer) to destination asset (the asset credited to the payee).The magic of a path payment is that you do not need to hold the asset that the other party wants to receive. StellarX users are now able to send the tokens they own and it will immediately convert to the desired destination token they want to send to the recipient.So how does this tie to Anchors? Let’s go back to our example:I’m a user living in New York City that wants to send Nigerian Naira to a user in Lagos, Nigeria.Let’s say the user in Nigeria doesn’t hold any USD on Stellar, and wants to receive Nigerian Naira. In order to send USD from my wallet to a peer in Nigeria, I can send it by way of a path payment — all I need to do is select the recipient and the amount of USD that equates to the amount of NGN the recipient wants to (or is asking to) receive. Now I can send USD to them via StellarX and they will receive NGN…in seconds!New and Upcoming Features by PlatformIn our July Medium article we talked about what we were building on web and mobile, here’s what’s been delivered since then and what we plan on delivering in the future.What’s New On Web?Path Payments: specify a series of assets to route a payment through, from source asset (the asset debited from the payer) to destination asset (the asset credited to the payee).Anchors: we recently announced Cowrie’s NGNT Anchor! You can now deposit and withdrawal Nigerian Naira on StellarX!More Markets: adding more high demand currencies and tokens in our market listings. Stellar is THE blockchain for digitizing any off-chain asset, so we are focused on continuing to improve our ability to unify disjoint economies and blockchains on Stellar.Export Transactions: the ability to download your transaction history. Simple and often requested by our users.Anchor Deposit and Withdrawal UX Improvement: we touched on this above, but decided to highlight it again :)What’s Coming Up On Web?Merge Accounts: the ability for users to close out balances from one Stellar account to another.Funding Option on Sign Up: for new users, we’re going to be adding deposit options right in the sign up flow.Additional Information on Issuers: we’re going to surface more information about each issuer you’re trading with so you know more about the asset you’re trading!Portfolio View: we’re going to be overhauling the wallet &amp;amp; balance experience so it’s more of a portfolio-style view that makes it easier to understand your holdings, balances, and trading history across multiple asset types.What’s New On Mobile?Path Payments: specify a series of assets to route a payment through, from source asset (the asset debited from the payer) to destination asset (the asset credited to the payee).Token Lookup: the ability to look up and add tokens by domain, code, or name instead of by issuer address.What’s Coming Up On Mobile?Market Listings &amp;amp; Trading: buy and sell any token listed on StellarX. Easily execute trades with one touch.Deposit &amp;amp; Withdrawals: we’re bringing deposit and withdrawal options to mobile, Anchors for off-chain assets, XLM deposits, and more!Filter By Transaction: the ability to filer recent activity by different transaction types (i.e. payments, trades).Export Transactions: the ability to download your transaction history. Simple and often requested by our users.Base Currency Selector Enhancement: an improved version from viewing base currencies only by text to viewing by text, icon, label and code!Android10 Light / Dark Theme Support: the ability to view your screen in light mode and dark mode.Video Feature from Stellar Development FoundationCheck out the recent feature on the “StellarX Mission” from Stellar Development Foundation!https://medium.com/media/88446cf0694f78a61d1e72b5f585c50d/href“A developer in any part of the world can build a wallet, you don’t have to be apart of a big bank, or a big company, it really is all there…that’s the magic, it’s a global order book on chain…talent doesn’t have to stay in the borders of North America, it’s beyond those borders.”To learn more about StellarX visit StellarX.comFor the latest updates, follow us on Twitter @StellarXhq and LinkedInThe New Age of Financial Transactions was originally published in StellarX on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">StellarX Mobile, A New Frontier</title>
    <published>2019-07-22T18:42:10+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-22T18:42:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/stellarxhq/stellarx-mobile-launch-832916505f1?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/stellarxhq/stellarx-mobile-launch-832916505f1?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ari Diamond</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Finally! We are excited to announce StellarX mobile on Android and iOS as well as provide an update on our upcoming roadmap on both web and mobile!“This is another step toward making StellarX accessible to everyone and increasing adoption and usage. By becoming a multi-platform DEX, we are excited by the possibility of offering a mobile experience to users in ‘mobile-first’ regions around the world.” — StellarX Engineering Team.StellarX’s native mobile apps are designed and developed by the team behind BlockEQ (acquired by Coinsquare), the first Stellar mobile wallet application. Our goal is to make transacting on the Stellar network accessible and as easy as downloading an app on your mobile phone.OS Support:Our decisions on OS support centred around keeping our global user base in mind.The Android StellarX mobile app targets the last 7 OS versions — this provides users with wider coverage by allowing users with older Android devices to use the app. Our iOS app targets back to iOS 11. We did not elect to target back further as 85% of the current iPhone market is on iOS 12.0 or later.Mobile Features:We have released our apps in multiple deployments, starting on Android at the end of June and then releasing iOS in mid-July.Below is a list of the v1 functionality.Sign Up: you can register now on all 3 platforms (web, Android, iOS), but always remember your passphrase and store it safely!StellarX Authentication: login using the same credentials and restore accounts and settingsWallet Capabilities: view balance by currency, protocol minimum balance requirements, send and receive any token on the networkActivity &amp;amp; Transactions: view recent activity and transactionsInflation: set Inflation destinationsAdd Tokens: add any token on the networkMultiple Accounts: for multiple account holders, there’s the ability to switch between accountsThemes: light and dark theme switching for AndroidToggle between Light &amp;amp; Dark Mode on iOS or AndroidWhat’s Next on Mobile?We are already working on improving our mobile products and we have exciting features coming up in future releases.Path Payments: specify a series of assets to route a payment through, from source asset (the asset debited from the payer) to destination asset (the asset credited to the payee).Market Listings &amp;amp; Trading: buy and sell any token listed on StellarX. Easily execute trades with one touch.Look Up By Domain: the ability to look up tokens by domain instead of by issuer address.Contact List Integration stellar addresses can become associated with personal contacts for easy sending and receiving transactions between friends.Filter By Transactions: the ability to filer recent activity by different transaction types (i.e. payments, trades).We are looking forward to continuing to offer feature rich products to the Stellar community as we continue to build Stellar’s leading decentralized exchange. StellarX’s Android and iOS mobile apps are a step toward making StellarX accessible to everyone and increasing adoption and usage.Now you might be wondering, what is coming to our web app? We have additional existing feature improvements and new features to announce too!What’s next for web?Path Payments: specify a series of assets to route a payment through, from source asset (the asset debited from the payer) to destination asset (the asset credited to the payee).Anchors: more crypto and fiat anchors for deposits and withdrawals on and off StellarX as well as improvements to our user experience for deposits and withdrawals. Our goal is to continue to offer more options for deposits and withdrawals as we know on and off ramping is key to the growth of the Stellar ecosystem.More markets: adding more high demand currencies and tokens in our market listings. Stellar is THE blockchain for digitizing any off-chain asset, so we are focused on continuing to improve our ability to unify disjoint economies and blockchains on Stellar.Export Transactions: The ability to download your transaction history. Simple and often requested by our users. We’re listening! :)Dynamic Fees: the ability for users to choose their own transaction fees.Merge Accounts: the ability for users to close out balances from one Stellar account to another.Recently Added Crypto Anchors on StellarX include BTC, ETH, and more!What’s Beyond All Of This?While we are excited to highlight some of what we have accomplished and what’s coming) since acquiring StellarX, the buck doesn’t stop here.“Our goal is to mold StellarX into not just an exchange, but a destination for moving assets in new and innovative ways in, out, and within the Stellar ecosystem. It’s not only about trading, it’s also about releasing features with real-life use cases. The only way to do that is to think beyond traditional exchange features, and look to bridge the gaps that can allow us to cross the chasm into the mainstream — think cross border payments and remittances, peer to peer trading and lending, FX settlement. The possibilities are endless, and we’re sitting in a privileged position having StellarX as our jumping point.”— Ari Diamond: General Manager, StellarXTo learn more about StellarX visit StellarX.comFor the latest updates, follow us on Twitter @StellarXhq and LinkedInStellarX Mobile, A New Frontier was originally published in StellarX on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">StellarX Is Acquired By Coinsquare</title>
    <published>2019-02-14T14:14:41+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-14T14:14:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/stellarxhq/stellarx-is-acquired-by-coinsquare-85beadaaaa0e?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/stellarxhq/stellarx-is-acquired-by-coinsquare-85beadaaaa0e?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Team Member</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Today, we’re happy to announce that Coinsquare, the biggest crypto exchange in Canada, has acquired StellarX.From here, StellarX will continue along the roadmap we announced last Fall, led by a dedicated team at Coinsquare of developers and designers who will make StellarX into the product we know it can be. StellarX will continue to operate and grow under its own brand.The Reason for the AcquisitionStellarX has awesome potential. By dollar-equivalent volume, we were a top-3 decentralized marketplace just weeks after launch. Today, even in a down market, there are tens of millions of dollars of value held by StellarX account holders. Given marketing and continued development, StellarX’s future is extremely bright.To fulfill its potential, StellarX needs a home with regulatory experience and with a full-scope plan to build around the app.Coinsquare is the perfect fit. They are already the leading Canadian cryptocurrency platform. They have very close relationships with regulators in the U.S., Europe, and Canada. The Bank of Montreal is their banking partner. They have experience with Stellar, having acquired BlockEQ a few months before. And, in Megha Bambra — the BlockEQ cofounder who will now lead StellarX — they have an extremely capable entrepreneur excited to grow StellarX and the Stellar ecosystem as a whole.Megha BambraWhat’s NextStellarX is out of the limbo that a deal like this necessarily entails while it closes. After a transition period, Megha and her team will continue building out the exchange.They are a particularly strong mobile team, and we expect greatness from the coming StellarX mobile app.In time, they will also add many things that weren’t possible under StellarX’s previous regime: new fiat tethers and securities tokens.Almost all the original StellarX team will be moving to SDF. There, they will build new products on Stellar and improve Stellar’s developer experience. SDF will work with Coinsquare to ensure that StellarX continues to prioritize the full scope of the network’s interests over the interests of any one particular stakeholder.We all see StellarX as a cornerstone utility for the network, and we’re excited to watch Stellar, Coinsquare, and StellarX grow together in 2019 and beyond.StellarX Is Acquired By Coinsquare was originally published in StellarX on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How StellarX Will Take Over The World</title>
    <published>2018-09-28T18:53:46+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-09-28T18:53:46+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/stellarxhq/how-stellarx-will-take-over-the-world-119e280e09fc?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/stellarxhq/how-stellarx-will-take-over-the-world-119e280e09fc?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Team Member</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">This week, we’re happy to say that StellarX is fully open. There’s a lot we still need to do (and I’ve listed some of that at the end of this post.) But we’re excited about what we’ve built — been up just 24 hours and DonaldTrump is talking to SatoshiNakamoto in the trollbox, why not, and JesseLivermore shrewdly came back from the dead to trade our fat spreads. Bullish!So we’ve got this thing started. We’re methodically positioning StellarX to be the most popular place to trade in the world. We know it’s a big, dumb goal. But we think it’s achievable, starting with a few basic values:StellarX is freeWe’re a totally free trading platform, almost certainly the only one.Legacy exchanges charge per trade. A “free” custodial platform, like Robinhood, profits from its customers’ idle funds. Decentralization offers a more user-friendly experience, but users of any Ethereum DEX — IDEX, EtherDelta, and so on — have to pay for gas, which, as we’ve already shown, is too expensive today and will be even more expensive in the future.Using StellarX, on the other hand, costs you nothing. We take no fees and, even above that, we refund all network costs, something no other decentralized exchange can match. All the while, you have sole control over your assets, so whenever there’s interest, it’s yours. We’ve even written our own fee out of our agreements with deposit partners, who, we’ve found, often put in a percentage by default. We aren’t here for a cut. We’re here to redefine how assets move around the world.How can we afford to do this? In short, we chose the right tech. Trades and orders are native to Stellar, not a layer that has to be superimposed via relayers and smart contracts. And Stellar’s consensus mechanism requires neither “work” nor “stake” — that is, it doesn’t use your capital to function. Thus, we don’t need your capital to function either.We let you trade anythingToday, StellarX has a real fiat onramp, a first for a decentralized platform. If you have a U.S. bank account, you can deposit dollars directly, via ACH, right inside our app.We also, today, show tokens for Euros, Philippine Pesos, Nigerian Naira, Chinese Yuan, Hong Kong Dollar, and the British Pound, and we’ll add in-app deposits/withdrawals for these as soon as their issuers support our standards. We anticipate a full suite of forex stablecoins in the coming months: we will be a “local” exchange for many countries that currently have nothing.On the crypto side, the most important coins are already in place, BTC, ETH, and so on, and we’ll be adding deep into the coinmarketcap top n very soon. We have listings comparable to many legacy exchanges, and we’ll far exceed them in the near future. The “X” in StellarX might seem like a nod to “exchange”, but we see it as the algebraic x. Anything. Anyone. Anywhere. That’s the platform we’ve got.Our full potential, however, is so far unrealized: StellarX will one day have bonds, stocks, real estate, commodities, and so on all side-by-side with essential currencies, but these new assets take time and the right protocol to digitize. This leads me to our final founding value, a subtle and little-understood one, but really the most important thing that StellarX offers, because without it no exchange can become the world’s marketplace:Our market is transparentEverything meaningful that happens on StellarX is on-chain, and so yeah the world can see it. But here I mean “transparent” in a larger sense, both for users and, crucially, for token issuers. Because both must be informed for a market to flourish.transparency for traders: Our tokens behave in an expected manner. There are no smart contracts to unravel ownership, or to catastrophically fail. Tokenization is handled at the protocol layer from simple templates. Important features are set as flags, not in custom code.transparency for issuers: if you so choose, you can see who your customers are and confirm their identity before they interact with your token.We realize nobody really wants to think about compliance — it’s probably blockchain’s least sexy word — but how a platform enables or discourages it has massive effects, especially as newer and more interesting types of assets get digitized. Whether you find it wrong or not, it’s just a legal fact that banks, corporations, and municipalities have to know who holds their credit, their stock, and their bonds.Yet almost every other platform defies this basic truth. Thus Gemini, in order to launch their big dollar stablecoin, had to write the underlying Ethereum contract to allow them to:generate an infinite amount of tokens, and every 48 hours…totally change the implementation, making all tokens non-transferable or pretty much anything elseThis is blockchain fine-print that hurts both the token holders and the issuer. It’s unfair to traders to have to sort out ownership risk via a code review.Stellar has a better way. We get that KYC is a thing in the world. We also understand that smart contracts are the wrong place to bury fundamental information. We allow issuers — if they so require — to impose KYC requirements before a person can trade their token. And we give holders human-readable information about what they own, so they can make decisions for themselves.To fulfill the promise of a universal platform, information has to flow freely between holders and issuers. No one is going to issue stock or whatever to the blockchain otherwise.So…yeah: free, flexible, functional. That’s why we think we’ll win. Like I said, we have a long way to go, but we’re off to a running start. To the Stellar community: thank you so much for all your feedback over the summer. You’ve made StellarX so much better already.Here’s a summary of our product priorities over the next few months. And as new assets and new deposit partners come online, we’ll let you know.Coming soon to StellarX, in no particular order:Night modeA mobile site, for great justiceContinued improvement to signup, onboarding, and visual designImproved token stats and infoPortfolio performance reporting &amp;amp; summariesImproved charting libraryFungible path-payment support (i.e. allowing a sender to send token A and specify that the recipient receives it as token B)A market maker rewards programMulti-sig supportSEP 0007 support for airdrops, etc.Non-XLM markets supportIn-app deposit/withdrawal support for all tokens via SEP 0006Universal (optional) KYC via SEP 0009 &amp;amp; 0010Self-serve platform for issuers to submit more token detailBitcoin.tax support for Stellar tradesOriginally published at blog.stellarx.com on September 28, 2018.How StellarX Will Take Over The World was originally published in StellarX on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Great Filter: Why You Shouldn't ICO on Ethereum</title>
    <published>2018-08-14T17:12:58+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-08-14T17:12:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/stellarxhq/the-great-filter-why-you-shouldnt-ico-on-ethereum-6fe696a35873?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/stellarxhq/the-great-filter-why-you-shouldnt-ico-on-ethereum-6fe696a35873?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Team Member</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The Great Filter: Why You Shouldn’t ICO on EthereumWhile we finish up StellarX, I wanted to share a research project on Ethereum we did earlier in the year. It’s an open secret that it’s simply the wrong platform for most of the stuff being built on it — it’s not, of itself, a bad technology, but entrepreneurs have applied Ethereum to the wrong uses.A reckoning is coming, something like the Great Filter:…where high costs and slow performance cull almost the entire ecosystem, and unless your project is specifically adapted to Ethereum’s strengths, it will die alongside so many others.I’m pretty tired of people debating cryptocurrency using stuff they either made up or copied, fingers-crossed, from some untested whitepaper. So here I use actual data from actual tests that cost us an actual thirteen thousand dollars. My team and I spent that money running an “at-scale” app for a total of ten hours on the Ethereum network, when gas prices were low, so it’s a mere pittance compared to what your blockchain company will pay to learn these same lessons in a real deployment.Ethereum’s Strengths and WeaknessesEthereum is a distributed programming platform — scripting software for autonomous organizations and ownerless apps. Vitalik himself put it like this, in his original announcement on bitcointalk:Ethereum is a modular, stateful, Turing-complete contract scripting system…our goal is to provide a platform for decentralized applications.Today, as in 2014, if you’re building a distributed computer program, something with no sole owner and no centralized decision-making apparatus, Ethereum is a great choice. For the perfect use case, think something like Augur — they needed a fully automated, ownerless way to make truth-decisions about real world events…so they could circumvent regulatory enforcement for what is basically a gambling platform.But most blockchain companies don’t need smart contracts to execute their core business logic or want to dodge some legal or jurisdictional problem. They just want to issue digital assets and process transactions. That’s exactly where Ethereum will let you down. If you’re building something where:you issue a tokenthat users will trade back and forth, andyou want those trades to happen cheaply and in real-timeEthereum is the wrong choice. It’s slow and it’s really f’ing expensive, and it fails to act like you want in both the “one account doing a lot” and the “many accounts doing a little” cases.Let’s get to the data. Our testing was based on a third-party load test, designed by Kik, and we tweaked the spec wherever possible to make Ethereum perform better. As you can see, it stubbornly defied our efforts. Our results and methodology are in our GitHub, and we encourage you to check our work.Problem 1: Your most enthusiastic users will have the worst experience.Ethereum queues transactions on a per-account basis, and yet miners don’t prioritize transactions by wait time. In fact, given transactions with equal gas prices, miners are assigned them at random. So an active account builds up a transaction queue, and the network has no mechanism to clear it. The result, for high-volume accounts, is an ever-increasing transaction lag.Ethereum processes transactions using two numbers, a transaction nonce (what we’ll call the “nonce”) and an account nonce that, for clarity, we’ll sometimes call the “count”. The transaction nonce puts an account’s transactions in order; the account nonce counts whenever one of them is mined. When a new transaction, with its nonce, is submitted, Ethereum compares that nonce to the current count to decide what to do. If the transaction’s nonce is lower than the count, the transaction is ignored. If it’s higher, the transaction is delayed. Only if/when the nonce matches the count can the transaction move into a block. Here’s a simplified diagram of how it works:This is actually very similar to the “please take a number” systems you see at a deli or at a government office like the DMV, and it’s a fairly common way to prevent replay attacks. Lots of other chains do something similar. However, Ethereum’s transaction-to-block algorithm (or, really, lack thereof) adds the wrinkle that the people working your DMV window here — the miners — aren’t necessarily accountable to the next number in line.Miners often have their own criteria for the transactions they’ll accept. Many only accept high-gas-price transactions. Some only accept their own transactions. Miners like these will let block space go unused before filling it with something from your queue. So now imagine a DMV where certain windows are telling people “sorry can’t help you,” while more people file into the waiting room every second and you have all these jokers in front of you who have to get helped before you can even talk to someone — and, voila, you have some idea of how Ethereum handles transactions.We weren’t aware it worked like this until after we tried to implement Kik’s load spec: 480 accounts each submitting 1 txn/minute on average for 3 hours. That’s 86,400 total transactions, an average of 8 per second.We spun up the test, using ETH Gas Station’s “standard” estimates for gas, expecting a median confirmation time of about 30 seconds, and, lo and behold, 13 hours later, more than half of our transactions still hadn’t made it into a block. We stopped the test at 13h and 50m, and 50.1% of our transactions were missing. (Reminder: the raw data is in our GitHub, if you want to check our work.) We thought we’d messed up somehow, but, no. We had just created a bunch of long lines, and some jabroni transactions had stood there all day doing nothing.When you read elsewhere about “Ethereum transaction times”, the posted numbers almost always suppose a single, one-off event. They do not pertain in an application-level environment. We ran the Kik test again just to really make sure we were doing everything right, spending another 6.9 ETH, and we got essentially the same result.Here’s a typical experience from that run — this is just the account that happened to be first alpha-numerically. You can see the wait times grow as transactions pile up.It’s one thing to talk about “settlement time” in the abstract. But think about the above data in terms of actual user experience. The more someone uses your Ethereum app, the slower it goes. After just three hours, their transactions are taking 8 hours to confirm.Of course Kik’s test spec said we should submit transactions for three hours and then stop, so that’s what we did. In the real world, you can’t build in downtime to allow the count to catch up — so in theory transaction queues just get worse and worse. In practice, of course, as your Ethereum app becomes unresponsive, users will help it catch up, by leaving.Here’s the performance distribution from that second test. I trimmed the slowest 5% so the long-tail doesn’t skew the overall picture.For comparison, this is what Kik measured running the same spec (on Stellar.)I just grabbed this plot from their post, and I don’t have the original data, so I can’t show my results on the same chart. But using the magic of computers, I can at least overlay the curves:Everything looks comparable until you notice the x-axes. The waits we measured on Ethereum are 3,000 times longer. That’s the queuing problem in a nutshell.This performance issue is currently a fundamental part of Ethereum. Improvements like sharding or Casper are promising in theory, but those will be complex fixes layered over Ethereum’s almost maximal complexity. Something like lightning can rely on Bitcoin’s inherent simplicity; whereas there’s nothing basic to fall back on here. A skyscraper is usually built on bedrock, not on top of another skyscraper, yet that is what a lot of Ethereum scaling solutions propose to do.The only certain performance improvement is to spend more on gas and hope to plow through each account queue faster. We in fact did that in a third three-hour trial — which we ran because of our “we should do what we can to make this work” commitment.The previous two tests had used the “standard” ETH Gas Station recommendation. We used the “fast” tier (≈4 Gwei at the time) for the third and spent 11.8 ETH on our 480 accounts.Performance improves — to only 500 times slower than Kik’s results on Stellar — but it’s still not fast enough. The backlog builds and payments hang around with nothing to do.https://medium.com/media/7b5b7aab730124d481f7b8995458709e/hrefProblem 2: Very High Cost of Wide AdoptionEver thus to power users. But Ethereum is also unsuitable for the other kind of adoption, what you might see with an app like, I dunno, Etsy, where instead of a few people going deep, you have lots of people checking in every once in a while. That’s because an Ethereum app’s per-user costs go up quickly as it adds users, and that’s why you see stuff like 70x price spikes whenever anyone tries using the network across many accounts.We captured this data incidentally, looking for a workaround to the queueing problem. To keep transactions from piling up, we refactored the Kik spec as follows: instead of a few accounts submitting a bunch of transactions, we spun up a bunch of accounts (28,800) and had each of them just do a single transaction. To stick to the original test’s guideline of 8 total txn/s we submitted the transactions over the course of an hour.Curiously, this didn’t actually help performance very much. The median confirmation time was 23 minutes — actually slower than the “fast” test above. Even weirder, some of the first transactions we submitted were the last to confirm:We knew account queues couldn’t be the issue. It turned out that as soon as our transactions started hitting the network, miners’ fees soared. So our earliest transactions, submitted with pre-test “standard” pricing, were quickly priced-out. They lingered in low priority for hours.We had discovered another of Ethereum’s negative reinforcement loops. Adding users immediately scales cost. In the real world, increasing the number of units implies lower per-unit costs. Basically the whole private sector is built on this idea — “economy of scale”. But here: each incremental user immediately increases the per-user cost. It’s like bizarro economics.You can see prices climbing ≈6x over the short 1-hour run of our test.Again, the built-in time limit of the test makes everything look more sustainable than it actually is. Extrapolate this chart out and drop the needle somewhere in the middle. What do your per-user costs look like after two weeks of steady usage? Two years?The above test cost us $1,445 for a single hour. It ran when gas prices were low, just ≈1 Gwei for standard speed, and it puttered along at just 8 transactions a second. To run a basic test, that’s $12.6m a year.If you apply that cost structure to a real business, you see that Ethereum’s fees are already unsustainably high. For example, PayPal does about 240 transactions a second. Put aside the performance fixes it would take to make that happen and put aside the rising-price dynamic I just documented. If PayPal had been built on Ethereum and paid our observed rate, they would’ve laid out $380m in network fees last year. That would’ve been 21% of their net income, and, again, that’s pretending that you could somehow freeze prices.An idealized version of Ethereum won’t work for one of the most profitable transactional businesses in the world. How is the real version going to work for the rest of us?Now what?“If you want to build a decentralized Uber and Lyft on top of an unscalable Ethereum, you are screwed. Full stop.” — Vitalik ButerinI encourage you to watch the full panel this quote came from — it shows four of the most important members of the Ethereum team saying a lot of what I’ve been saying here. When today’s high-profile ICO becomes tomorrow’s cautionary tale, it will only be bad for everyone in the ecosystem, and they know it.There’s no doubt that the Ethereum community is the strongest in blockchain, and there very likely wouldn’t be token economies at all without Vitalik’s vision. It’s not Ethereum’s fault that developers are asking from the tech what it was never meant to deliver. It’s the people chasing last year’s ICO dollars, regardless of what’s actually the right tool. Ethereum’s problems all start with misguided entrepreneurs. Don’t become another one of them.If you’re building a transactional app, the protocol will not support the behavior your users will expect. I have immense respect for the ambition and the complexity of Ethereum, but I’ve come to see it as blockchain haute couture. Beautiful, intricate, high-concept, high-minded. And not what you wanna wear to work.another young developer regrets his choicesIf you want trustless, distributed computation — if that’s really what you’re building — definitely use it. If you never plan to actually launch anything, Ethereum’s great for that, too — just ask the over 50% of ICO projects who disappear after their token sales, if you can find them. They’ve already hit the Great Filter. And likely some beach in Puerto Rico.But if you want to build a business that sticks around — if you plan a typical user-to-user service and don’t need to tie up your business logic in a smart contract — if you plan to issue a digital asset and you plan to transact at high volumes as a core part of your strategy, pick a platform that is optimized for that. Do what we did, and build on Stellar.Tomer Weller designed and ran the load tests and provided technical guidance for this post. Originally published at blog.stellarx.com on August 14, 2018.The Great Filter: Why You Shouldn&amp;#39;t ICO on Ethereum was originally published in StellarX on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Announcing StellarX</title>
    <published>2018-07-05T16:19:12+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-07-05T16:19:12+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/stellarxhq/announcing-stellarx-7dd62c168c2f?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/stellarxhq/announcing-stellarx-7dd62c168c2f?source=rss----7dbbb8f1bc24---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Team Member</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Today, we’re very pleased to announce StellarX, the first full-featured trading app for Stellar’s universal marketplace.StellarX is a user-friendly way to trade all types of assets cheaply and quickly while maintaining sole control of your keys. You can request an invite here, and we’ll open to the public this summer.What’s special about StellarX?First of all, StellarX lets you live the inter-chain dream of swapping your Philippine Pesos for Litecoin for municipal bonds for lumens, and all of those trades settle in seconds.We let you trade directly from your own wallet, and you can deposit and redeem off-chain assets, like BTC or EUR. We also help you manage your secret keys, though of course we never have access to them or your assets.Because we’re built on the open Stellar order book, *no one* — no exchange, no miners, no middleman of any kind — takes a cut of your transactions. In a world of a thousand DEXs, we’re one of the few true peer-to-peer, trader-to-trader platforms.Trading on StellarX is completely free because the Stellar network fees are so low we can refund them out-of-pocket. And we also give Stellar’s automatic 1% APR inflation back to our users, keeping none of the weekly airdrops for ourselves. If you hold funds on StellarX, you will get your pro rata lumens every Tuesday.Why should you care?Stellar’s universal marketplace is greenfield for experienced, adventurous traders — the order books are raw and underexplored. StellarX is designed to reveal every asset possible, every order book, every trade.For example, right now we show five bitcoin markets asking five different prices for the same thing;arbitrage possibilities like this are not only common on Stellar,we’ll pay you, through our market makers’ awards, to take advantage of them;of course compared to charna token, bitcoin is for pensioners and cowards,let’s just all agree on that,but my point is,there’s clearly opportunity here.Who are we?We’ve made apps like Kickstarter, Headspace, and OkCupid. StellarX’s creators have a great deal of building experience outside the crypto space, and we know how to make popular, user-friendly tools.Why did we build on Stellar?Stellar is a fantastic settlement backend that has, until today, had a very basic frontend. The technology is solid. It’s just, historically, been hard to understand and use. Compared to over-valued, under-built technologies, (stuff like, I dunno, 95% of the things listed on coinmarketcap), we believe Stellar is actually underappreciated, even among people familiar with crypto. Here’s what we like about it:Stellar enables arbitrary extensions of the “tether” idea, meaning you can digitize any off-chain asset — pork futures or Zcash or SkyMiles or USD or whatever — and the protocol itself will handle redemption and compliance. Stellar therefore unifies disjoint economies (and blockchains) into a single market.Stellar supports native ICOs, and because it’s actually a payment technology (and not an attempt to build a “distributed computer”), it’s better than Ethereum for most ICO use cases.Stellar has a built-in order book. It’s not just a ledger system; it’s a transaction system. Markets and settlement are built directly into the platform. Stellar itself matches buyers and sellers. Stellar itself is a DEX. So an app like StellarX can natively expose the entire trading ecosystem, without partitioning.Stellar doesn’t rely on proof-of-work, meaning it’s both energy- and cost-conservative. Transaction fees are, as of today, two ten-thousandths of a penny ($0.000002) — so low we can afford to redeem them for our users. Plus, since Stellar bypasses miners and their ASIC farms, we can use it knowing we’re not paying some dudes to drown our grandchildren.Broad adoption hasn’t happened yet for Stellar. But in putting this thing together we’ve dug deeper into the technology than any team beyond the core developers, and we know it works. We decided we’d rather build now and wait for the world to catch up than have it the other way around.You can request an invite here, and we’ll begin opening up the platform soon. Watch this space for more news and just the most pithy, most insightful analysis imaginable.Our founding principle is to always show you the most diverse, most open marketplace on earth. StellarX. Have at it.Announcing StellarX was originally published in StellarX on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
