<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.streamingfast.io/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.streamingfast.io%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.collection-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;discard_thumbnail=on&amp;date_selector=.uui-blogpost04_author-text-2&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSDateSelectorBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.streamingfast.io%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.collection-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;discard_thumbnail=on&amp;date_selector=.uui-blogpost04_author-text-2&amp;date_format=F+j%2C+Y&amp;author_selector=&amp;limit=3&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:35+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">StreamingFast | Unlocking the Power of Substreams for Solana Developers</title>
    <published>2025-01-03T22:10:35+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-03T22:10:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.streamingfast.io/blog/unlocking-the-power-of-substreams-for-solana-developers</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.streamingfast.io/blog/unlocking-the-power-of-substreams-for-solana-developers"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div title="" class="uui-text-rich-text-4 w-richtext"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlocking the Power of Substreams for Solana Developers: New Features and Enhancements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine unlocking Solana&amp;#x27;s blockchain data with just a few lines of code. What if you could stream real-time account changes, decode complex on-chain interactions, and build next-generation dapps with unprecedented ease? The Graph&amp;#x27;s latest Substreams update is about to revolutionize how Solana developers access, interpret, and leverage blockchain data. It’s not just offering a tool—it’s providing a data revolution that will transform your approach to building on Solana, breaking down the barriers that have long frustrated developers and limited blockchain innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Improvements for Substreams on Solana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our recent updates focus on a couple transformative areas:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Historical and Real-Time Account Changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Solana ecosystem has long lacked a reliable source for pulling historical account changes. To address this, Substreams now has a powerful &lt;a href="https://substreams.dev/packages/solana-accounts-foundational/v0.1.0"&gt;new endpoint&lt;/a&gt; that enables developers to stream account changes block by block, unlocking unprecedented insights and enabling more robust application logic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of the Historical Account Changes Feature:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cursor Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Seamlessly resume data extraction from the last processed block, ensuring continuity and preventing data loss during interruptions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimized Data Model&lt;/strong&gt;: For each block, only the latest update per account is recorded. Deleted accounts are flagged with &lt;code&gt;deleted == true.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noise Reduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Low-importance events, such as changes by the &amp;quot;Vote11111111...&amp;quot; account or lamport-only updates, are omitted for cleaner data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Filtering&lt;/strong&gt;: Stream account changes by specifying any account or owner as input.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Historical Back-Processing (as of January 2025)&lt;/strong&gt;: Substreams accumulate historical data over time, allowing back-processing for comprehensive insights.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible Data Sinks&lt;/strong&gt;: Export account change data to any storage destination or interface directly through Rust, JS, or Go programs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this service, developers can analyze account data with unprecedented precision, unlocking new possibilities for dapps and infrastructure on Solana.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Anchor IDL Integration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solana data can appear as arbitrary bytes, making it challenging for developers to interpret and extract meaningful insights. Anchor, the most widely adopted data standard on Solana, provides an Interface Definition Languages (IDLs) that define the structure and meaning of on-chain data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re simplifying this process by enabling developers to create Substreams projects directly from an Anchor IDL in JSON format within the &lt;a href="https://github.com/streamingfast/substreams-starter"&gt;Dev Container&lt;/a&gt;. This feature streamlines data extraction, giving dapp developers a faster and more intuitive way to build applications on Solana.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why This Matters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Anchor IDLs provide a shared understanding of encoded blockchain data, much like ABIs in the EVM ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Developers can easily decode and extract relevant data, reducing complexity and saving time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Developers don’t need to interact with both the Anchor Library and Substreams, the Dev Container fetches existing IDLs automatically. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This integration positions Substreams as a must-have tool for any Anchor-based Solana project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empowering the Solana Ecosystem with Substreams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;These updates represent a significant leap forward in indexing capabilities for Solana developers. Whether you’re building dapps, managing infrastructure, or conducting in-depth analytics, Substreams is designed to meet your needs with unparalleled efficiency and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.substreams.dev/tutorials/intro-to-tutorials/on-solana/account-changes"&gt;Get started&lt;/a&gt; with the new features or explore how Substreams can transform your Solana project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to push the boundaries of blockchain data indexing!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">StreamingFast | Substreams Support for MANTRA Chain</title>
    <published>2024-12-06T22:10:35+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T22:10:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.streamingfast.io/blog/substreams-support-for-mantra-chain</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.streamingfast.io/blog/substreams-support-for-mantra-chain"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div title="" class="uui-text-rich-text-4 w-richtext"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Substreams, developed for The Graph, has added another non-EVM blockchain: MANTRA!  Now devs building on MANTRA can use Substreams and Substreams-powered Subgraphs on The Graph!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="w-richtext-align-center w-richtext-figure-type-image"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/671a5c4f3b43d0eb07ad1d7f/674f64d323940c40c88e575c_AD_4nXd7YOx3XODNmdSIpBA9E7qv5fhgILiN5hxrmQxxP5XwFDlEWovi3GvffboBNNQnQ1d1yOwlzaRtGoMbswOZE2HqBYvajf6Fo1qeLjUOgZ9Rn_gXbQ5f2gHKqpcO6stCC79koi4JpQ.png" loading="lazy" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing MANTRA Chain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MANTRA Chain is a purpose-built layer 1 blockchain for tokenized Real-World Assets. Fully interoperable with the other Cosmos blockchains through the IBC module, MANTRA is both Cosmos- and Ethereum-compatible, providing developers from across the blockchain stack with ease of use, great speed, full transparency, and now the most performant data indexing stack available. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MANTRA Chain’s mission is to provide a permissionless blockchain for permissioned applications. With a focus on the Real World Asset market, MANTRA offers users a compliant and frictionless method to transfer full or fractional ownership of diverse assets across various jurisdictions and blockchain ecosystems. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Substreams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Built by StreamingFast, a core developer of &lt;a href="https://thegraph.com/"&gt;The Graph&lt;/a&gt;, Substreams are a programmable data stream offering high-throughput and sink-agnostic features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stream Reliably in Real-Time: &lt;/strong&gt;Low-latency gRPC stream (backed by the &lt;a href="https://thegraph.com/docs/en/firehose/"&gt;Firehose&lt;/a&gt;) that is cursor managed to handle reorgs and eliminate the unreliability of RPCs. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallelized Back-Process&lt;/strong&gt;: Significantly reduces indexing times, enabling the processing of entire blockchains within just a few hours.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extract Complex Insights: &lt;/strong&gt;With native filtering, aggregation, and composability both historical and in real-time, easily extract insights at scale. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sink Anywhere&lt;/strong&gt;: Substreams enable seamless integration of data with any storage or interface environment, including &lt;strong&gt;subgraphs&lt;/strong&gt;, SQL databases, or direct gRPC streaming.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DevEx: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://streamingfastio.medium.com/substreams-codegen-no-code-tool-to-bootstrap-your-project-a11efe0378c6"&gt;Codegen&lt;/a&gt; tools, all dependencies installed, integrated decodings, a GUI, and Studio or local Graph Node deployments.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Substreams and its sinks can be easily developed and tested within the &lt;a href="https://docs.substreams.dev/reference-and-specs/devcontainer-ref"&gt;Dev Container&lt;/a&gt;. To get started with Substreams, follow the MANTRA events path. It will walk you through using code-generation tools to initialize a Substreams project within the Dev Container.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="w-richtext-align-center w-richtext-figure-type-image"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/671a5c4f3b43d0eb07ad1d7f/674f64d3d888078d9e00f94b_AD_4nXd0aFQXjCUh_1dK_QCq6s6hy3JIh1ddnqisQceiliV7C7Q1SX83fr42WLyMf2IRoqTsxFo49WNZzkwVQJXZMWl6-XGW7kIEIRG0iO0nSY5pRam4raYh8NEWHYDYTvltpxxfl8Aj.png" loading="lazy" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Started Using MANTRA Subgraphs On The Graph&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Graph provides a decentralized protocol for indexing and querying blockchain data, making it an ideal choice for developers who want to build scalable applications without managing their own data infrastructure. Here’s how to get started building your first MANTRA Subgraph:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Codegen your first Substreams using &lt;code&gt;substreams init&lt;/code&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;substreams codegen&lt;/code&gt; subgraph&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;within the Dev Container.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;strong&gt;AssemblyScript&lt;/strong&gt; to create the data transformations (as any other subgraph).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Define the API schema through &lt;strong&gt;GraphQL.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Once complete, follow the on-screen steps to deploy to &lt;a href="https://thegraph.com/networks/"&gt;The Graph&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Adding support for MANTRA Chain is another important step toward decentralizing access to indexed web3 data. By combining the interoperability of MANTRA with the power of Substreams and Subgraphs, developers can now leverage The Graph to build performant and reliable dapps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to reach out to us on our &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/mYPcRAzeVN"&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/graphprotocol"&gt;The Graph Discord&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">StreamingFast | Earn GRT For Building, Publishing and Using Substreams</title>
    <published>2024-12-20T22:10:35+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-20T22:10:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.streamingfast.io/blog/earn-grt-for-building-publishing-and-using-substreams</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.streamingfast.io/blog/earn-grt-for-building-publishing-and-using-substreams"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div title="" class="uui-text-rich-text-4 w-richtext"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Substreams, developed for The Graph, has experienced incredible growth in developer adoption over &lt;a href="https://x.com/PropellerSwap/status/1854434127073992988"&gt;recent months&lt;/a&gt;. To further support the core principles of decentralization and composability, StreamingFast is proud to introduce the freshly-updated Substreams Registry: &lt;a href="https://substreams.dev/blog/earn-grt-for-building-publishing-and-using-substreams"&gt;substreams.dev&lt;/a&gt;. This platform allows developers to share and discover Substreams packages, enabling rapid innovation, eliminating redundant efforts, and unlocking powerful composability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Celebrate the Registry Launch with Our Contest!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To mark this milestone, we’re launching an &lt;strong&gt;exciting contest with 24,000 GRT in prizes up for grabs&lt;/strong&gt; over eight weeks! Participation is simple: publish a Substreams package on &lt;a href="https://substreams.dev/blog/earn-grt-for-building-publishing-and-using-substreams"&gt;substreams.dev&lt;/a&gt;, and track your ranking on the &lt;a href="https://substreams.dev/bounties"&gt;weekly leaderboard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How It Works&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contest is divided into two seasons, each lasting four weeks. This format ensures opportunities for everyone, whether you&amp;#x27;re joining late or need more time to develop your package. Each time a unique user calls a Substreams package within a day that you published through StreamingFast’s Substreams endpoints, you will receive one usage point. The prizes will be rewarded based on the amount of usage points each Substreams package receives during each unique week of the contest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Season 1 Details&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration:&lt;/strong&gt; Each week will run Monday through Sunday, beginning on December 9, 2024, and running until January 5, 2025.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prizes:&lt;/strong&gt; Weekly, there will be prizes for the three most-used packages:&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;1st Place - 1000 GRT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;2nd Place - 750 GRT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;3rd Place - 500 GRT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ranking: &lt;/strong&gt;Whenever a unique developer requests data from the StreamingFast API within a day, that will count as one use of your package.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus Prizes: &lt;/strong&gt;At the end of Season 1, we’ll award an extra 1000 GRT to the package that is used the most times &lt;em&gt;by other Substreams packages.&lt;/em&gt; The power of composability means you can do more, quicker, and we want to reward developers that build great building blocks!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward Distribution:&lt;/strong&gt; Prizes for all four weeks of Season 1 will be sent after Season 1 has finished. You’ll need to reach out to us over Discord so that we can arrange payment.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Season 2 Details&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration:&lt;/strong&gt; Each week will run Monday through Sunday, beginning on January 6, 2025, and running until February 2, 2025. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prizes:&lt;/strong&gt; Weekly, there will be prizes for the three most-used packages:&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;1st Place - 1000 GRT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;2nd Place - 750 GRT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;3rd Place - 500 GRT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;4th Place - 500 GRT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;5th Place - 500 GRT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ranking: &lt;/strong&gt;Whenever a unique developer requests data from the StreamingFast API within a day, that will count as one use of your package.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus Prizes: &lt;/strong&gt;At the end of Season 2, we’ll award an extra 1000 GRT to the package that is used the most times &lt;em&gt;by other Substreams packages.&lt;/em&gt; The power of composability means you can do more, quicker, and we want to reward developers that build great building blocks!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward Distribution:&lt;/strong&gt; Prizes for all four weeks of Season 2 will be sent after Season 2 has finished. You’ll need to reach out to us over Discord so that we can arrange payment.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why Substreams?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t dug into the tech yet, &lt;a href="https://substreams.streamingfast.io/blog/earn-grt-for-building-publishing-and-using-substreams"&gt;Substreams&lt;/a&gt; are a programmable data stream offering high-throughput and sink-agnostic features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;‍&lt;strong&gt;Stream Reliably in Real-Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Low-latency gRPC stream (backed by the &lt;a href="https://firehose.streamingfast.io/blog/earn-grt-for-building-publishing-and-using-substreams"&gt;Firehose&lt;/a&gt;) that is cursor managed to handle reorgs and eliminate the unreliability of RPCs. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;‍&lt;strong&gt;Parallelized Back-Process:&lt;/strong&gt; Significantly reduces indexing times, enabling the processing of entire blockchains within just a few hours.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Composability:&lt;/strong&gt; Enables the creation of aggregated streams in a modular way, simplifying the extraction of complex insights from raw data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sink Anywhere:&lt;/strong&gt; Substreams enable seamless integration of data with any storage or interface environment, including subgraphs, SQL databases, or direct gRPC streaming.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started With Substreams&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few resources you’ll need if you are new to Substreams:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;We have &lt;a href="https://docs.substreams.dev/"&gt;extensive documentation&lt;/a&gt; available to help you when building a Substreams, including chain-specific docs if you’re working on &lt;a href="https://docs.substreams.dev/tutorials/evm"&gt;EVM chains&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://docs.substreams.dev/tutorials/solana"&gt;Solana&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://docs.substreams.dev/tutorials/cosmos"&gt;Cosmos&lt;/a&gt;, as well as for pushing into a &lt;a href="https://docs.substreams.dev/tutorials/graph-node"&gt;Substreams-powered Subgraph on The Graph Network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prefer a quick video? &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gVqGCqKVM08"&gt;Here’s a short summary of how Substreams works&lt;/a&gt;, and how the data flows from the initial request, to once it’s in your database.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://discord.gg/jZwqxJAvRs"&gt;Join us on Discord&lt;/a&gt; to chat live with our developers &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; our incredibly helpful community.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.substreams.dev/reference-and-specs/chains-and-endpoints"&gt;Click here for a full list of chains&lt;/a&gt; that are currently supported for Substreams.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publishing to the Registry&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul role="list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;The easiest way to get started with Substreams is by using our code-generation tool, &lt;code&gt;substreams init&lt;/code&gt;. Want to see just how quickly you can get started? &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RmKi-Nq9E_A"&gt;Check out this video&lt;/a&gt; showing how quickly you can start piping out data using &lt;code&gt;substreams init&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can then modify and adapt the Substreams code to suit your needs – craft the custom output to shape the data as you require, and select where you’d like the data to sink into. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build and run your Substreams and ensure everything works as expected.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Publish your Substreams to the registry using &lt;code&gt;substreams publish&lt;/code&gt; within the Substreams CLI.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This can all be easily done within &lt;a href="https://github.com/streamingfast/substreams-starter"&gt;our GitHub DevContainer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Don’t Miss Out – Start Building Today!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sooner you publish your Substreams package, the greater your chances of earning! If you have any questions or need assistance, our community and team are here to help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
