<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Pure JSON Bridge</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://example.com"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=PureJsonBridge&amp;context=Main&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsubquery.ghost.io%2Fghost%2Fapi%2Fcontent%2Fposts%2F%3Fkey%3Dbf3ce175b25567ba18844bb26a%26limit%3D10&amp;items_path=posts&amp;article_field=slug&amp;title_field=title&amp;prefix=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.subquery.network%2F&amp;author_field=&amp;pubdate_field=created_at&amp;date_format=&amp;content_field=html&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://example.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://example.com/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=PureJsonBridge&amp;context=Main&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsubquery.ghost.io%2Fghost%2Fapi%2Fcontent%2Fposts%2F%3Fkey%3Dbf3ce175b25567ba18844bb26a%26limit%3D10&amp;items_path=posts&amp;article_field=slug&amp;title_field=title&amp;prefix=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.subquery.network%2F&amp;author_field=&amp;pubdate_field=created_at&amp;date_format=&amp;content_field=html&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:36+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SubQuery Powers DuckChain with Advanced Data Indexing Solutions</title>
    <published>2025-04-07T03:09:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-07T03:09:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/subquery-powers-duckchain-with-advanced-data-indexing-solutions</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/subquery-powers-duckchain-with-advanced-data-indexing-solutions"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce full integration with DuckChain — the Telegram AI Chain empowering Telegram users to enter crypto through AI, EVM, and beyond.making waves with lightning-fast speeds, ultra-low fees, and next-level scalability. SubQuery is now powering DuckChain with seamless, decentralised data indexing to supercharge development across the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DuckChain is built for the future: a performance-first blockchain optimised for real-world usage and mass adoption. Developers now have access to SubQuery’s powerful data infrastructure to rapidly build, test, and deploy dApps that scale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="why-this-matters-for-duckchain-builders"&gt;Why This Matters for DuckChain Builders&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With SubQuery, devs on DuckChain can skip the hassle of managing custom data infrastructure. Our flexible indexing solution provides instant access to high-performance APIs tailored for querying on-chain data—so you can spend less time wrestling with backend tasks and more time crafting game-changing applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="tools-that-just-work"&gt;Tools That Just Work&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery brings a full suite of open-source SDKs, comprehensive docs, and community-driven tooling to streamline the indexing process. Whether you're building wallets, explorers, DeFi apps, or games, our managed service ensures you're supported at scale—handling hundreds of millions of daily queries without breaking a sweat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re proud to bring SubQuery’s infrastructure to the DuckChain ecosystem. It’s all about helping devs ship faster and smarter.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— Ian He, Co-Founder &amp;amp; CTO, SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="let%E2%80%99s-build-the-future%E2%80%94one-quack-at-a-time"&gt;Let’s Build the Future—One Quack at a Time&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DuckChain–SubQuery integration unlocks endless possibilities. As we continue expanding multi-chain support, we remain committed to empowering developers with the tools they need to build boldly and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="why-use-subquery"&gt;Why Use SubQuery?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery simplifies the creation of custom APIs for dApps or smart contracts in minutes, providing clean, indexed data for any service. The platform is flexible, allowing external API calls and imported libraries, while also offering robust DOS (denial of service) mitigation controls. With SubQuery, developers have the option to run projects on personal infrastructure or rely on the managed service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery is designed to be fast. By optimising the store with multi-threading and reducing costly database writes, SubQuery significantly reduces sync times. Faster syncing enables quicker iterations and faster delivery of features to market.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="subquery%E2%80%99s-support-for-duckchain"&gt;SubQuery’s Support for DuckChain&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Advanced Indexing of blocks, transactions, and logs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/subquery/ethereum-subql-starter/tree/main/DuckChain?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Example Project&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Full support for DuckChain in our &lt;a href="https://managedservice.subquery.network/login?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;free enterprise-level managed service&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord community&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (including technical support)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-duckchain"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About DuckChain&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DuckChain is defined as Telegram AI Chain, a blockchain platform uniquely designed for the Telegram ecosystem. It combines AI-driven tools with EVM technology to serve Telegram’s extensive global audience of over 1 billion users. As the largest EVM-based chain in this ecosystem, DuckChain emphasizes seamless integration, user-friendly solutions, and operational efficiency. Focused on advancing cryptocurrency adoption, DuckChain bridges sophisticated blockchain capabilities with the simplicity and accessibility tailored to Telegram's community needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://duckchain.io/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/DuckChainAnn?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://x.com/Duck_Chain?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DuckChain-io?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SubQuery Announces 60 Million SQT Consumer Rewards Programme to Supercharge Network Growth</title>
    <published>2025-04-02T04:33:49+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-02T04:33:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/60-million-sqt-consumer-rewards-programme</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/60-million-sqt-consumer-rewards-programme"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At SubQuery, we’re committed to building the most efficient, developer-friendly data indexing network in Web3. To accelerate adoption and empower developers, we’re announcing our biggest campaign ever - the &lt;strong&gt;60 million SQT Consumer Rewards Programme&lt;/strong&gt;, a 12-month initiative starting 1st of May, designed to incentivise projects that actively utilise the SubQuery Network as their primary data API.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Consumer Rewards Programme will be the highest rewards programme in SubQuery history so far.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="why-we%E2%80%99re-launching-this-programme"&gt;Why We’re Launching This Programme&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strength of the SubQuery Network lies in its users. As we continue to grow, our focus is on &lt;strong&gt;onboarding more developers and applications&lt;/strong&gt; onto the decentralised network. While SubQuery’s indexing technology already provides a seamless experience, we want to engage the community and drive further adoption.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SQT Consumer Rewards Programme is designed to recognise and reward &lt;strong&gt;top project owners&lt;/strong&gt; who use the SubQuery Network, ensuring that early adopters and active consumers benefit as the ecosystem expands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="subgraphs-and-subquery-projects-rewards"&gt;Subgraphs and SubQuery Projects Rewards&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rewards apply not only to &lt;strong&gt;native SubQuery Projects&lt;/strong&gt; but also to &lt;strong&gt;Subgraphs that migrate to the SubQuery Network&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a developer running a Subgraph today, you can seamlessly transition your indexing to SubQuery and earn rewards while benefiting from our more cost-efficient, and highly scalable network. This programme provides a financial incentive to make the switch, while also ensuring there is no interruption to your application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="how-it-works"&gt;How It Works&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from 1st May 2025, every month we will reward project owners based on their &lt;strong&gt;SQT spending&lt;/strong&gt; on the SubQuery Network. Here’s what you need to know:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leaderboard transparency&lt;/strong&gt; – A ranking system will track SQT spending by project owners (based on total sum of SQT spending across verified indexer projects)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial rollout with five rewarded projects&lt;/strong&gt; – At the end of month 1, the top 5 projects on the leaderboard will receive rewards! Later in the programme with more projects flowing in, the number of rewarded projects will grow.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rewards are calculated monthly&lt;/strong&gt; – top projects at the end of the month will receive rewards based on spending from the previous month.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proportional distribution&lt;/strong&gt; – The more SQT spent, the higher the reward share.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capped rewards&lt;/strong&gt; – Receive up to 900% APY! You could well and truly cover costs with the rewards received in this programme, we’ll only cap the rewards at 10x a project’s SQT spend.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To maintain integrity, all rewarded projects must be verified. Our team will validate projects by checking data usage, websites, social presence, and query sources. We encourage participants to introduce themselves on the SubQuery Discord, ensuring seamless communication with node operators and the broader community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="a-growing-reward-pool"&gt;A Growing Reward Pool&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first reward pool will be distributed at the end of May (month 1) and with fewer projects competing early on, participants have a greater chance of receiving significant rewards. As more developers join, the pool will expand to match the growing network adoption.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By rewarding early adopters and &lt;strong&gt;encouraging developers to migrate from centralised and competing solutions&lt;/strong&gt;, we’re ensuring long-term growth for the SubQuery Network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is just the beginning—join us as we shape the future of web3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="getting-started"&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ready to start earning rewards with the SubQuery Network? Here’s how to get involved:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://academy.subquery.network/subquery_network/architects/publish-subgraph.html?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Learn how to deploy your Subgraph&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://academy.subquery.network/subquery_network/architects/publish.html?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Learn how to deploy your SubQuery Project&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Acquire some SQT from &lt;a href="https://www.bybit.com/en/trade/spot/SQT/USDT?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bybit&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gate.io/trade/SQT_USDT?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Gate.io&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://crypto.com/price/subquery-network?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Crypto.com&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://app.uniswap.org/explore/tokens/base/0x858c50c3af1913b0e849afdb74617388a1a5340d?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Uniswap&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Join our Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and head to the #network-general channel for any questions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keen to make the switch but don’t have time? Use our team of experts, email us at professionalservices@subquery.network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">New Roadmap Released: SubQuery’s Year of AI</title>
    <published>2025-03-31T07:56:27+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-31T07:56:27+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/new-roadmap-2025</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/new-roadmap-2025"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new SubQuery Network roadmap, &lt;strong&gt;"2025 - SubQuery’s Year of AI,"&lt;/strong&gt; has just been launched on our website. The roadmap outlines an ambitious vision for scaling our decentralised network, integrating AI deeply into Web3, and expanding our world-class indexing capabilities. While &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/roadmap?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;our website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides the full breakdown of the three categories and key milestones, this article explores the philosophy driving our decisions and why these steps are crucial for the future of decentralised data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🚀 Read the full roadmap here: &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/roadmap?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;subquery.network/roadmap&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="scaling-the-subquery-network-a-stronger-fairer-economy"&gt;Scaling the SubQuery Network: A Stronger, Fairer Economy&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decentralisation is about more than just technology—it’s about community-driven economies. To ensure the sustainability and fairness of the SubQuery Network, we are refining our SQT token economic model. The importance of SQT would be further emphasised, by allowing more places to be able to govern by the token, we are creating a more robust and participatory ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We recognise the importance of market efficiency. Our planned improvements in &lt;strong&gt;price discovery mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt; will allow for more accurate pricing of indexing and RPC services, removing guesswork and inefficiencies for both Node Operators and Consumers. This, coupled with a user-friendly overhaul of our &lt;strong&gt;Closed Agreement system&lt;/strong&gt;, will make SubQuery more accessible and practical for Web3 businesses of all sizes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new dRPC token economy will be in place early this year, formalising the process of dRPC listing to be more &lt;strong&gt;community-driven&lt;/strong&gt;, only limited RPC would be listed annually, and the token would play a more important role in the listing decision.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most importantly, we are taking another major step towards decentralisation with the &lt;strong&gt;first election for the SubQuery Council&lt;/strong&gt;. Governance matters, and by placing decision-making into the hands of our community, we are reinforcing our commitment to the eventual SubQuery DAO.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="accelerating-web3-growth-with-ai-intelligence-meets-decentralisation"&gt;Accelerating Web3 Growth with AI: Intelligence Meets Decentralisation&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI is revolutionising every industry, and Web3 is no exception. In 2025, we are doubling down on AI integration to enhance community engagement, governance, and developer efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A major focus is &lt;strong&gt;incorporating AI in everything we do for the community&lt;/strong&gt;. One exciting aspect of this is the introduction of &lt;strong&gt;AI Agent Roles in DAO governance&lt;/strong&gt;. These AI-driven agents will help users navigate complex governance proposals, distilling key points into digestible insights so that community members can make informed decisions. Beyond that, AI agents will be designed to represent specific user groups—such as Delegators or Node Operators—ensuring their interests are effectively voiced in governance processes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, we are making significant &lt;strong&gt;AI App improvements&lt;/strong&gt; to enhance functionality and accessibility. Our &lt;strong&gt;SubQuery AI App framewor&lt;/strong&gt;k enhances LLMs' understanding of indexed on-chain data. We’ll make improvements on the framework integration with the SubQuery SDK to reduce the need for human-defined inputs and prior knowledge. The ultimate goal is to enable AI-driven applications to operate securely on the decentralised SubQuery Network, paving the way for fully autonomous AI agents in Web3. We are developing &lt;strong&gt;AI App integrations with Telegram and Discord&lt;/strong&gt;, ensuring that AI-driven insights and assistance are available in the platforms where Web3 communities naturally engage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A co-developed platform with our partner will be launched, to empower our community with the AI capability we have built.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="bringing-the-best-indexing-support-to-all-unmatched-scalability"&gt;Bringing the Best Indexing Support to All: Unmatched Scalability&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the heart of SubQuery’s mission is our commitment to delivering the best indexing solutions to developers, no matter where they build. In 2025, we aim to support &lt;strong&gt;300 networks, including Solana&lt;/strong&gt;, reinforcing our position as the most comprehensive Web3 indexing solution available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re also enhancing our technology stack to make multi-chain indexing more powerful. By improving our multi-chain project hosting capabilities, developers will be able to deploy robust, cross-chain applications with ease.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another game-changer is the introduction of &lt;strong&gt;Immutable Mode&lt;/strong&gt;, which unlocks massive performance improvements by enabling parallel and reverse indexing. This will significantly benefit use cases that only require immutable data, such as blockchain analytics and historical tracking. Additionally, we’re upgrading our &lt;strong&gt;Query Service to Postgraphile v5&lt;/strong&gt;, bringing advanced historical range queries that make analysing on-chain data even more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="read-the-full-roadmap"&gt;Read the Full Roadmap&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SubQuery Network 2025 roadmap is a reflection of our belief in a &lt;strong&gt;decentralised, AI-enhanced, and developer-friendly future&lt;/strong&gt;. While the milestones we have set will be worked on simultaneously, their impact will collectively transform how Web3 communities access, analyse, and leverage data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We invite you to explore the full roadmap on our website and join us in making &lt;strong&gt;2025 the Year of AI&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether you’re a developer, a community member, or a data enthusiast, your participation is key to building the next generation of decentralised intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🚀 Read the full roadmap here: &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/roadmap?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;subquery.network/roadmap&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Unlocking Cross-Chain Lending Insights with SubQuery: A Case Study on Folks Finance</title>
    <published>2025-03-25T02:40:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-25T02:40:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/unlocking-cross-chain-lending-insights-with-subquery-a-case-study-on-folks-finance</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/unlocking-cross-chain-lending-insights-with-subquery-a-case-study-on-folks-finance"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://folks.finance/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Folks Finance&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a non-custodial DeFi protocol offering a comprehensive suite of tools for managing digital assets. Its ecosystem includes multiple protocols designed to maximise asset efficiency and yield generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Folks’ &lt;em&gt;xChain App&lt;/em&gt; delivers seamless cross-chain lending and borrowing, enabling unified liquidity and access across multiple blockchains. The &lt;em&gt;Algorand App&lt;/em&gt; features a lending protocol where users can deposit assets to earn yield or use them as collateral for loans. The integration of the &lt;a href="https://folksrouter.io/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Folks Router&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; DEX aggregator ensures the best prices and most efficient routes through DEX aggregation. Additionally, &lt;em&gt;xALGO&lt;/em&gt; is a Liquid Staking Token (LST) that allows users to earn yield by participating in Algorand Consensus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To optimise data indexing and analytics, Folks Finance has integrated SubQuery, a leading Web3 data indexing solution, enabling real-time insights into swaps, lending operations, and overall protocol performance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-at-a-glance"&gt;Key Metrics at a Glance&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;More than 85,000 users have accessed Folks Finance, powered by the SubQuery API.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Total Transactions Processed: 500,000&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Traders, researchers and developers using Folks Router benefit from faster decision-making while receiving accurate and reliable data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="the-challenge"&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before integrating SubQuery, Folks Finance faced significant challenges in data indexing and retrieval. The decentralised nature of their ecosystem meant that tracking swaps, user activity, and liquidity flow required complex and inefficient querying processes. Without a robust data solution, it was difficult to provide real-time insights into swap trends, token performance, and user behavior. This lack of efficient data indexing limited transparency and decision-making capabilities for both users and developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="the-role-of-subquery-in-folks-finance"&gt;The Role of SubQuery in Folks Finance&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery plays a critical role in two key areas of Folks Finance’s ecosystem:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Folks Router&lt;/strong&gt; – The DEX aggregator benefits from SubQuery’s data indexing capabilities to track token swap activities, user volumes, and overall protocol performance.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Folks xChain&lt;/strong&gt; – The cross-chain lending protocol integrates SubQuery to enhance data visibility and provide real-time insights to users and developers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This case study will focus on how SubQuery has been used to power &lt;a href="https://folksrouter.io/metrics?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Folks Router&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="how-folks-router-leverages-subquery"&gt;How Folks Router Leverages SubQuery&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Enhanced Swap Tracking and Analytics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Folks Router aggregates liquidity from multiple decentralised exchanges (DEXs), allowing users to swap tokens at optimal rates. By integrating SubQuery, Folks Finance can efficiently track and analyse:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Monthly swap activity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Token-specific metrics&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;User-specific volume contributions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This data is critical for assessing trading behavior, liquidity trends, and DEX aggregator performance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Real-Time Data for the Metrics Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery powers the &lt;strong&gt;Folks Router &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://folksrouter.io/metrics/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Metrics Dashboard&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a transparent view of all swaps that have occurred. The indexed data ensures that users and developers can monitor transaction patterns, total volumes, and liquidity movement across the ecosystem in real time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfmuIv02pfsHcHFFB0CI1XpPe7iDBZk1orWDjGJXUS1cqN0oWU4n7n7Fgk8fgEuvK97l12nCzhJsE8n3Ez7hcTjTo_ZNchaZ5xqJMs95DH2AFs4tEusRCfUB1W_hYVSBrZDqCiiRQ?key=FRlMcSjiCbnt9ZVe7DSR2Et0" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="676" height="1171"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id="subquery%E2%80%99s-indexing-capabilities-for-folks-router"&gt;SubQuery’s Indexing Capabilities for Folks Router&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate the power of SubQuery, we examined two key datasets within the Folks Router indexer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Router Insights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This dataset provides an overview of swap activities on a monthly basis, including:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Total swap and fees volume&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Number of unique traders&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Transaction count&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXe7w4XI2aFpzdjp3nE2cKAmYSFLHblhF5COYtF6O-fiXGDDu4T_KvVDBo1jDRssR5RqsWx-uPHdgvm6EnUT7kcJakYRqB-P9Z9HnWWsh6oA47npAnpgHKePi40jadxJnpBRST8-cw?key=FRlMcSjiCbnt9ZVe7DSR2Et0" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="796" height="400"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; Month is just one of the available time slices. The same data can be retrieved for other slices (day and hour) by simply changing the queried entity to &lt;strong&gt;FolksRouterDayData&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;FolksRouterHourData&lt;/strong&gt; without modifying the objects being queried.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the metrics can be further broken down to individual users, enabling insights such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Volume per individual sender&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Frequency of swaps per sender&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Top traders within a specific timeframe&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For instance, to calculate the total volume associated with an individual address, the following query can be used:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXeIcT-bpWRMdqBxRMgmiLS4d3cVTrgeIMeLM4obGej0mAPkZgpYmLnmfzV_pp7dADQlv7mY5G1u2qCeioxHZ3PJMvHubobOz1i_8x7g2uUKbsSnVBNu1IIkvxgwodYBt_JOkbESOg?key=FRlMcSjiCbnt9ZVe7DSR2Et0" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="796" height="396"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id="token-level-data"&gt;Token-Level Data&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To gain deeper insights, the FolksRouterTokensInfo dataset tracks each token’s swap activity. The following information can be retrieved for tokens and, if needed, for the previously mentioned time slices as well:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Total swap volume&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Number of transactions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unique traders&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, the query below simultaneously provides aggregated information across all indexed tokens and details about a specific token:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcJZbkafCYv4sqya5z-2Wdzr0JQ0JsqJlVF9jbjrKZzaRATdG2_5s0wg4VOG-4lV21hCTK67bIS707rBn22KWPmNIXXUC7Zv76gSXAtlyeQDNNFKRChyltvcMVIXmE6vKZIzDt53Q?key=FRlMcSjiCbnt9ZVe7DSR2Et0" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="795" height="401"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id="benefits-of-using-subquery-for-folks-finance"&gt;Benefits of Using SubQuery for Folks Finance&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time Data Processing&lt;/strong&gt; – SubQuery enables rapid indexing of swap data, ensuring up-to-date analytics on Folks Router and Folks xChain.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability&lt;/strong&gt; – As Folks Finance expands its DeFi offerings, SubQuery’s indexing capabilities scale seamlessly with increasing transaction volumes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Transparency&lt;/strong&gt; – Users and developers gain better visibility into protocol activity, fostering trust and engagement.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Performance Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; – SubQuery-powered dashboards allow Folks Finance to track key performance metrics across different facets of its ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id="the-road-ahead"&gt;The Road Ahead&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking forward, Folks Finance will continue to leverage SubQuery’s powerful indexing capabilities to enhance its ecosystem. As new assets are added to the platform, Folks will update the existing indexers to incorporate these assets, ensuring that data remains comprehensive and up-to-date. Furthermore, with the expansion of the Folks xChain protocol to new chains, additional indexers will be introduced to support the seamless aggregation of cross-chain data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By integrating SubQuery, Folks Finance has unlocked a new level of data transparency and efficiency across its ecosystem. Whether powering the Folks Router Metrics Dashboard or providing granular insights into token swaps and user behavior, SubQuery ensures that Folks Finance users and developers have access to the real-time data they need. As DeFi continues to evolve, the partnership between Folks Finance and SubQuery highlights the critical role of advanced data indexing in driving innovation and cross-chain interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://subquery.network/indexer?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Start building your SubQuery indexer&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Behind the Node: Meet liveraven-subquery.eth</title>
    <published>2025-03-24T02:17:52+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-24T02:17:52+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/behind-the-node-meet-liveraven-subquery-eth</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/behind-the-node-meet-liveraven-subquery-eth"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re introducing liveraven-subquery.eth (‘LiveRaveN’), a standalone individual validator for crypto projects. With 17 years of experience in quality assurance for various IT products—primarily embedded software at a world-renowned company— he brings a wealth of expertise to the space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dive in to explore LiveRaveN’s insights, experiences, and advice for the next wave of node operators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="introduction-to-liveraven-subqueryeth"&gt;Introduction to liveraven-subquery.eth&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;LiveRaveN currently has 17 years of experience in quality assurance for IT products—primarily embedded software at a world-renowned company—and he has spent his career ensuring systems run flawlessly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly three years ago, he ventured into crypto, drawn by a deep interest in project testing and a desire to contribute to building stronger, more resilient networks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="why-did-you-choose-to-become-a-node-operator"&gt;Why did you choose to become a Node Operator?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the beginning when he first started running nodes across various projects, LiveRaveN discovered that being a node operator isn’t just a technical role—it’s a way to shape the future of decentralised infrastructure while continuously learning and growing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, he’s bringing this expertise to SubQuery, helping to strengthen Web3 one block at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="joining-the-subquery-network"&gt;Joining the SubQuery Network&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;LiveRaveN first came across SubQuery by chance while browsing the internet. Intrigued, he joined the early testnets and quickly found the experience technically fascinating. Working with a project of this scale and innovation sparked his interest, setting him on a path to deeper involvement in the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="a-day-in-the-life"&gt;A Day in the Life&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A typical day for LiveRaveN depends on the state of the network. If everything is running smoothly—which is usually the case—he will focus on fine-tuning and optimising his service, always looking for ways to improve efficiency and reliability.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, when issues arise, he quickly shifts gears, troubleshooting and ensuring his node remains stable and secure. It’s a balance of proactive monitoring and continuous improvement, driven by a passion for maintaining high-performance infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="why-delegators-should-choose-liveraven-subqueryeth"&gt;Why Delegators Should Choose liveraven-subquery.eth&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"I take pride in being one of the most stable and consistent indexers, delivering top APY for both myself and my delegators. My focus is on reliability, performance, and continuous optimisation, ensuring the best possible rewards. With a growing stake and a commitment to long-term success, I’m always open to discussions and easily reachable."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;– liveraven-subquery.eth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="advice-for-new-node-operators"&gt;Advice for New Node Operators&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best insights come from those with hands-on experience. That’s why we ask our Node Operators to share their advice—so newcomers can learn from real-world challenges and best practices. Liveraven-subquery.eth shares their insights &lt;em&gt;“be passionate to the project, learn the project, and it will reward you.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After reading this article, you might be feeling inspired! Depending who you are, the below resources will be a great help:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you’re interested in being a Node Operator on the SubQuery Network: &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/mastery-series-how-to-get-started-as-a-node-runner-on-the-subquery-network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Read this blog article&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you want to delegate to liveraven-subquery.eth: &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/sqt-staking-everything-you-need-to-know-to-be-a-delegator-on-the-subquery-network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Read this blog article&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and delegate to &lt;a href="https://app.subquery.network/indexer/0xa8ddFCf5b5aC088d4d9DaA76fE8b743351578399?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;liveraven-subquery.eth here&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you’re an existing Node Operator who wants to have your own “Behind the Node” feature: &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/9AnqEg3jTV8J7WcN8?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Fill out the form&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SubQuery Powers Sonic with Seamless Data Indexing</title>
    <published>2025-03-18T16:14:20+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-18T16:14:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/subquery-powers-sonic-with-seamless-data-indexing</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/subquery-powers-sonic-with-seamless-data-indexing"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sonic, the rebranded Fantom blockchain, brings faster transactions, better scalability, and lower fees. We’re proud to support developers who are building on Sonic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sonic Blockchain is a Layer 1 blockchain compatible with Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM), created to meet the growing demand for faster and more affordable networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery's indexing capabilities empower Sonic builders to efficiently manage and query on-chain data, expediting development processes and facilitating rapid iterations. This advances the goal of onboarding the next billion users to the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With SubQuery, developers on Sonic gain access to a high-speed, decentralised data indexing solution that simplifies managing on-chain data. Subquery’s tailor-made API eliminates the need to build custom indexing solutions, allowing developers to focus on what matters most—building products and enhancing user experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Sonic devs now have top-tier data indexing with SubQuery, making on-chain queries seamless. Excited for this integration.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— Seg, Developer Relations, Sonic Labs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery’s open-source SDK, tools, and extensive &lt;a href="https://academy.subquery.network/indexer/quickstart/quickstart_chains/bsc.html?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;documentation&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; offer a comprehensive indexing experience. Developers also benefit from our &lt;a href="https://managedservice.subquery.network/login?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;enterprise-level managed service&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which hosts infrastructure capable of handling hundreds of millions of daily requests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We're thrilled to equip Sonic developers with advanced APIs and tools to supercharge their builds. Can't wait to see what they create next!”&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— Ian He, Co-Founder &amp;amp; CTO of SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="why-use-subquery"&gt;Why Use SubQuery?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery simplifies the creation of custom APIs for dApps or smart contracts in minutes, providing clean indexed data for any service. The platform is flexible, allowing external API calls and imported libraries, while also offering robust DOS (denial of service) mitigation controls. With SubQuery, developers have the option to run projects on personal infrastructure or rely on the managed service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery is designed to be fast. By optimising the store with multi-threading and reducing costly database writes, SubQuery significantly reduces sync times. Faster syncing enables quicker iterations and faster delivery of features to market.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="subquery%E2%80%99s-support-for-sonic"&gt;SubQuery’s Support for Sonic&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Advanced Indexing of blocks, transactions, and logs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/subquery/ethereum-subql-starter/tree/main/Sonic?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Example Project&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Full support for Sonic in our &lt;a href="https://managedservice.subquery.network/login?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;free enterprise-level managed service&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord community&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (including technical support)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-sonic"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Sonic&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sonic is the highest-performing EVM L1, combining speed, incentives, and world-class infrastructure, powering the next generation of DeFi applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The S token is Sonic's native token, used for paying transaction fees, staking, running validators, and participating in governance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://soniclabs.com/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://docs.soniclabs.com/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Docs&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/Sonic_English?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://x.com/SonicLabs?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/3Ynr2QDSnB?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.soniclabs.com/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SubQuery is Powering Solana with Decentralised Infrastructure</title>
    <published>2025-03-17T02:12:34+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-17T02:12:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/subquery-is-powering-solana-with-decentralised-infrastructure</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/subquery-is-powering-solana-with-decentralised-infrastructure"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After much anticipation and overwhelming demand from our community and numerous web3 developers we’ve met at conventions and events, we’re beyond excited to announce a game-changing milestone—SubQuery’s Decentralised Solana RPC is now live!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Builders on Solana can now leverage a fully decentralised RPC endpoint on the SubQuery Network. With our global network of node operators, you can expect no bottlenecks, no limits—just pure performance. But this is just the beginning— &lt;strong&gt;data indexing is also coming &lt;/strong&gt;soon to Solana, making decentralised data access easier and more seamless for developers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="you-voted-we-built"&gt;You Voted, We Built&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This achievement isn’t just ours—it belongs to you, our community. From day one, we’ve shaped SubQuery by actively listening to our community, believing that the best product decisions come from its users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It all began with an open call for &lt;a href="https://forum.subquery.network/t/help-us-decide-our-next-public-rpc/582/9?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;suggestions on our Forum&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, followed by a &lt;a href="https://snapshot.box/?ref=blog.subquery.network#/s:subquerynetwork.eth/proposal/0x0e28500afe7644c73d99688c018f4211b89074b5b794ac57e825565541364a7f/votes"&gt;&lt;u&gt;vote&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to determine which network deserved our focus next. The verdict? Solana rose to the top with 77% of the votes—a clear testament to its passionate builders and growing ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a community-driven project, we didn’t waste time. The results were in, and we got to work. Solana has a different RPC API, which we needed to integrate into our gateway, and now we’re thrilled to have launched our decentralised Solana RPC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="a-new-era-for-solana-developers"&gt;A New Era for Solana Developers&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;RPC reliability is a significant challenge for Web3 developers, as it can impact the performance and availability of their applications. Many developers currently rely on multiple or centralised RPC providers to ensure their applications stay up and running.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With SubQuery’s decentralised Solana RPCs, we’re eliminating the barriers that have held builders back. No more single points of failure. No more excessive costs. Just seamless, scalable, and community-powered access to the Solana network—exactly as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our globally distributed network of node operators is already handling tens of millions of RPC requests daily across major EVM and Substrate chains. Now, we’re bringing that same power, performance, and unstoppable decentralisation to Solana—not just for RPCs but also for indexing. Soon, SubQuery will roll out indexing support for Solana, making it even easier for developers to query and organize on-chain data with speed and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="indexing-coming-soon"&gt;Indexing Coming Soon&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Solana integration is coming very soon. Projects can expect the same speed and flexibility that we’ve come to be known for across our other 280+ supported networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re working closely with a few select customers to test and optimise this integration — if you would like to join SubQuery as an Solana launch partner, please reach out to us at &lt;a href="mailto:sales@subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;sales@subquery.network&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="get-started-today"&gt;Get Started Today&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Access your free decentralised Solana RPC endpoint now by visiting our &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/rpc/list?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;RPC list page &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;and selecting &lt;em&gt;Get Endpoint&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Need enterprise-grade performance? Opt for unlimited decentralised RPCs with no rate limitations by purchasing a plan from our globally distributed node operators via the &lt;a href="https://app.subquery.network/explorer/home?category=rpc&amp;ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;SubQuery Network Explorer&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;For indexing, start exploring our &lt;a href="https://academy.subquery.network/indexer/welcome.html?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;detailed documentation&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve also prepared a step-by-step guide to help you integrate your RPC seamlessly—check it out &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/mastery-series-how-to-access-decentralised-rpcs-on-the-subquery-network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;here&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXffVspssi19FS6WURfAFblojgJiMenQCeNV_YGgNRLLvA-aqOHTUsiKaLatGZMz2XTURYvKUAOcd8iAgNAi1XNWWO6phR0ouT5nxpjAdN8Da3ml_TLUCfmj1MZHiEGP0vJY3SPy?key=nELgQIA7FGXcTPQ0UzBsvTO3" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="602" height="567"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id="data-indexing-is-next"&gt;Data Indexing is Next&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the launch of our Solana RPC, we’re taking the first step in supporting the Solana ecosystem—but we’re not stopping there. Next, we’ll (finally) introduce indexing support for Solana, making it easier for developers to efficiently query and organize on-chain data. Stay tuned as we continue expanding our solutions for Solana builders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-solana"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Solana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solana is a fast, scalable blockchain for decentralised applications (dApps) and crypto transactions. Launched in 2020, it processes thousands of transactions per second (TPS) with low fees, making it a top choice for DeFi, NFTs, and gaming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powered by its native token, SOL, Solana offers high-speed, cost-effective solutions compared to Ethereum. Backed by the Solana Foundation in Geneva and developed by Solana Labs in San Francisco, it is a leading blockchain for next-generation Web3 innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://solana.com/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://x.com/solana?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://solana.com/telegram?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://solana.com/discord?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://solana.com/youtube?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://solana.com/github?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;GitHub&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://solana.com/reddit?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reddit&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Meet SUBastian our AI Assistant Bot - Ask Any Questions about SubQuery</title>
    <published>2025-03-13T09:56:34+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-13T09:56:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/meet-subastian-our-ai-assistant-bot-ask-any-questions-about-subquery</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/meet-subastian-our-ai-assistant-bot-ask-any-questions-about-subquery"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our community has frequently requested a comprehensive database of everything happening at SubQuery. Today, we’re excited to introduce the perfect solution that answers your questions, satisfies your curiosity, and provides a complete historical record of the SubQuery Network from its inception to today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meet SUBastian, the &lt;strong&gt;SubQuery AI Assistant Bot&lt;/strong&gt; on Discord! In this article, we’ll explore its capabilities and how it can enhance your experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="what-is-subastian"&gt;What is SUBastian?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SUBastian is an AI Assistant Bot, an intelligent assistant designed to enhance community engagement by providing real-time responses, insightful data, and interactive experiences.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional bots that follow pre-set commands, this AI-driven solution leverages natural language processing (NLP) and machine learning to understand context, generate meaningful replies, and even assist in complex tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="built-using-the-subquery-ai-app-framework"&gt;Built Using the SubQuery AI App Framework&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The open-source AI Assistant Bot was built using the SubQuery AI App Framework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designed to assist users with queries on SubQuery’s SDK, decentralised network, and staking rewards, it also demonstrates our function tooling for real-time wallet balance and network analytics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Built with a robust RAG model trained on SubQuery’s documentation, it delivers accurate, context-aware responses. This chatbot is a prime example of how developers can leverage the &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/subquery-ai-app-framework-a-new-way-to-build-decentralised-intelligent-applications/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;SubQuery AI App Framework&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to seamlessly integrate AI into decentralised applications—securely, efficiently, and with minimal effort&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="key-features-that-set-it-apart"&gt;Key Features That Set It Apart&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instant, Smart Responses&lt;/strong&gt; – Say goodbye to delayed replies or repetitive FAQs. The AI bot can handle a range of queries, from explaining project updates to guiding new users on how to participate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data &amp;amp; Analytics at Your Fingertips&lt;/strong&gt; – Need the latest SubQuery Network stats or governance proposals? The bot can fetch and summarise data, making it easier for community members to stay informed without leaving Discord.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seamless AI Assistance&lt;/strong&gt; – Whether it's helping users navigate the SubQuery Network, or breaking down complex concepts that can also be found in our &lt;a href="https://academy.subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;docs&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the bot acts as a knowledgeable assistant available 24/7.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="how-to-use-subastian"&gt;How to use SUBastian&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using our assistant bot couldn’t be easier. No complicated setup, no waiting—just instant answers at your fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join Our Discord&lt;/strong&gt; – If you haven’t already, hop into the &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;SubQuery Discord server&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask Your Question &lt;/strong&gt;– Simply type your query in&lt;strong&gt; #general channe&lt;/strong&gt;l of our Dsicord. Whether it’s about SubQuery’s history, network updates, or technical details, the bot is ready.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Instant Answers&lt;/strong&gt; – Within seconds, the bot will fetch and display the most relevant information, saving you time and effort.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.subquery.network/content/images/2025/03/image.png" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="1400" height="921" srcset="https://blog.subquery.network/content/images/size/w600/2025/03/image.png 600w, https://blog.subquery.network/content/images/size/w1000/2025/03/image.png 1000w, https://blog.subquery.network/content/images/2025/03/image.png 1400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;em class="italic" style="white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;Ask. Receive. Done! Here’s a sneak peek at the SubQuery AI Assistant Bot (now names SUBAstian in action—instant answers at your fingertips!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s it! No more searching through docs or scrolling through past announcements—just ask, and SUBastian delivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="the-future-for-subastian"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Future for SUBastian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is just the beginning for SUBastian. As our ecosystem grows, so will its capabilities—expect continuous upgrades, smarter responses, and even deeper integrations with the SubQuery Network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will explore more about AI-driven governance, and SubQuery will continue to be a key component of that, providing on-chain data for AI agents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI-powered assistants aren’t just a convenience; they’re shaping the future of community engagement—making interactions faster, smarter, and more intuitive than ever. Stay tuned for what’s next!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="start-using-subastian-now"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start using SUBastian now&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t experienced the power of an AI Discord bot yet, now’s the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get ready for smarter, more interactive, and more efficient conversations—right within Discord. Access it &lt;a href="https://discord.com/channels/796198414798028831/1174402964484526120?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;here&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">February 2025 Monthly Recap</title>
    <published>2025-03-10T08:51:38+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-10T08:51:38+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/february-2025-monthly-recap</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/february-2025-monthly-recap"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;February brought unexpected challenges, but also major milestones for SubQuery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The start of February brought an unexpected hurdle when our X account was hacked—an unfortunate and unforeseen incident that had never happened before in SubQuery’s history. We acted swiftly, reaching out to X’s support team and enlisting the help of our partners. Thanks to a direct connection provided by one of our partners who faced a similar issue, we started on the recovery process. We’re now very close to regaining full control of our account. We apologise for any inconvenience or concern this may have caused and want to assure everyone that SubQuery is here for the long run, and nothing has changed to stop our momentum.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite this setback, February was also a month of great progress and firsts. We proudly launched day-one indexing support for Unichain mainnet, delivering unparalleled speed and efficiency to developers building on the Layer 2 Superchain. This marks the beginning of an exciting collaboration, and we’re confident that even more opportunities will emerge as we continue to work together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another massive milestone for SubQuery was bringing our global team together in one place for a few days in Guangzhou. This in-person meetup was a rare opportunity for team members—many of whom work remotely across different time zones—to connect face-to-face, share insights, and align on key initiatives. From deep-dive workshops to team-building activities, this was the first time we’ve all come together in real life, but it won’t be the last!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Marketing &amp;amp; BD team was also on the ground at Consensus Hong Kong, making the most of our first-ever participation in an Asian Consensus event. Our co-sponsored side event, Hack Seasons, was a huge success, drawing a packed house of builders, innovators, and industry leaders. Throughout the conference, we connected with investors, ecosystem partners, and top projects actively shaping the future of crypto—strengthening relationships that will fuel SubQuery’s next phase of growth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s dive into the details!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="consensus-hk-2025-a-milestone-for-web3-in-asia"&gt;Consensus HK 2025: A Milestone for Web3 in Asia&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdGaByabLtCgqE1eLBMcmUl_T3LrODllt3jBzuRweHKPb_5Z7jZj9PrsG2wqiJSHtWekMNrFYgXj7wPTlERVCXNRvRsF1EziVq902CQQh_ZENZP00gCE_d_FnTS0Gxw6yIV_O-8QQ?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="737" height="387"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consensus Hong Kong 2025 marked a new era for blockchain innovation, bringing together industry leaders, builders, and investors to shape the future of Web3. With over 8,000 attendees, the event signaled a clear shift—institutional players are stepping in, with major TradFi names like Standard Chartered Bank making moves in the space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfSufk4zhMoS4RsHDfWBVcIWQFJEJnXS-DzSm7lrqkGJvfBWHPdJp5AdqlodzlF5gMLUxKJK6YX-ndy7qksJPgYAYICGMJu1TcouV4BvL6NUTLhSJYW71KNnyxXhDw8W4xUJfxEfg?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="433" height="578"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;em class="italic" style="white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;Marta Adamczyk (Head of Business Development at SubQuery) and Brittany Seales (Head of Marketing at SubQuery) at the Main Event&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI and Web3 took center stage, with discussions on how AI-powered agents could transform blockchain by automating smart contracts, payments, and transactions. This trend aligns perfectly with our SubQuery AI App framework, which is poised to drive next-gen decentralisation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="hack-seasons-a-huge-success"&gt;Hack Seasons: A Huge Success&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our co-sponsored side event, Hack Seasons, was a highlight of Consensus HK, packed with builders, innovators, and thought leaders. With three stages of insightful talks, it fostered deep discussions on indexing, data infrastructure, and the future of dApps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdpj90hLaDz8Ugxq0F_ltUoC8vUJefgS0hg8OQoThWWq-3INPcQ-xu916k-R11Gi21Oi0WElHryhpptDNEEKqvE8K9YmArUzPg_n-qlKGoUCXUgSb0_H-AtRzHhq2AMEpgqZ8oJ_A?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="853"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;em class="italic" style="white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;Our booth at Hack Seasons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id="expanding-our-network"&gt;Expanding Our Network&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consensus HK was the perfect opportunity to reconnect with partners, investors, and customers while forging new relationships. We engaged in high-value meetings with investors like Crypto.com Capital, DCG, and Taisu Ventures, reinforcing confidence in SubQuery’s vision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdRWsqG6TwbEWgPnE_hkNi8aYSMlKej-qTC9sdZIRyVbjR9cFtxkF4nO5XdbTjuiG12leP64-O31cvintOvZbV0lBoViCgn3trpoBtadCrpb2uTEvqRHQdZ8WCmreQG_dIHRdjvFg?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="358" height="477"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;em class="italic" style="white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;Brittany and Marta with Lucas Leong from Crypto.com Capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also had key discussions with PowerPool Finance, which is successfully using our SubQuery indexer SDK and is eager to expand its integration. Conversations like these highlight the growing demand for decentralised data solutions across the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="a-nostalgic-moment"&gt;A Nostalgic Moment&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At our booth, our classic SubQuery merch was a hit—a final farewell to our old branding as we look ahead to an exciting future. With six team members on the ground, we maximised engagement and made meaningful connections that will shape what’s next for SubQuery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXen4nVNHOESikEBm7EiCEyM0nsN6Nnf_POIgXzUjRJM61trCf2UvInlVm4YBc0n9h0tLTJffga7PprpKtM6D18Vd9wj1dWN-DDCiIZh-u7Q2TfIWnVohURXhk_9DtbzeIgkKsQ9Yg?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="720" height="540"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;em class="italic" style="white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;The SubQuery team - reunited!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id="special-integration-powering-unichain-from-day-one"&gt;Special Integration: Powering Unichain from Day One&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXf0rdzkSSJqnwvjDOMpUjdjdUlGS1gBfm1olTtGNWwVc8oySZyYfKEyVTNmKrsDiWK2TgZKxaJ8lXbndeevwzy5DIMZr7D_d2_2sCVWtU5lP7zs1l5OXcfvWD8ynDmLdgum2QOs?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="641" height="360"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery is proud to provide day-one indexing support for Unichain mainnet, bringing unparalleled speed and efficiency to developers building on this revolutionary Layer 2 Superchain—designed for DeFi by the very best in DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unichain is a next-gen Layer 2 solution, built on deep expertise from one of the most widely used protocols in DeFi. It advances Ethereum’s rollup-centric vision with enhanced scalability while remaining open, accessible, and optimized for DeFi innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With SubQuery, developers on Unichain gain:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Custom APIs in minutes – Rapidly build tailored APIs for dApps and smart contracts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Flexibility &amp;amp; control – External API calls, custom libraries, and self-hosted options with automated security measures.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lightning-fast performance – Optimized multi-threading and reduced database writes for faster indexing and sync times.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Comprehensive support – From open-source SDKs to enterprise-grade managed services handling millions of daily requests.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="decentralised-gnosis-rpc-initiated-by-the-community"&gt;Decentralised Gnosis RPC: Initiated by the Community&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXd6PtxWzoXYYlMtxseJlQ6TQv-2gVARGqUfJASjYbmKvKLAjD1fuH5OHdLD2OXsY1M07kyk1zOleIsk6c_DzNJwDxDPxSfdbEqFEaE-MTrCA_hkacppDi7xHoIs5okQd1wWRd4MuQ?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="582" height="306"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers on Gnosis now have access to a fully decentralised (and free!) RPC endpoint on the SubQuery Network—eliminating reliance on centralised providers while ensuring scalability and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This launch was driven by our community. After gathering votes, Gnosis and Solana emerged as the top priorities, and we moved swiftly to deploy Gnosis RPCs. Work is already underway to bring Solana RPC support to the network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reliable RPCs are critical for blockchain development, yet too often require costly infrastructure or centralized services. SubQuery’s globally distributed node operators now handle millions of RPC requests daily, making blockchain access more open, resilient, and cost-effective for developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Started Today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try out your free decentralised Gnosis RPC endpoint now via our &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/rpc/list?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;RPC list page&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—or explore enterprise-grade, unlimited RPCs through the &lt;a href="https://app.subquery.network/explorer/home?category=rpc&amp;ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;SubQuery Network Explorer&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXd0klDCguZvH9Unnygoa82hColKW9yGL_y0wckwTsKELP3tzxJPX_7ydaY7PO_5UGS0D4WbZJPs1lZYVHjkp8nKYNPhr_8I53AZr957pP7aEuYYPRSnGpcA9-m_AP7xLkI4fXkpiw?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="832" height="519"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id="strengthening-bonds-subquery%E2%80%99s-first-global-team-meetup"&gt;Strengthening Bonds: SubQuery’s First Global Team Meetup &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A major milestone for SubQuery was bringing our global team together for the first time. As a company with a distributed workforce spanning multiple time zones, this in-person gathering was a rare and invaluable opportunity for collaboration, alignment, and camaraderie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfLOQdr48eCjnPhmkypTSEst52O0h4pX2AHU6KA0bSvXMzdySghPsRYHKDCHgpl3DzJHp9ddOmJ1Q3q1IZ7Xe-NbSvxTZ4C3U8aKPkYlOgIEAoGmcPMo3LnnnHQsH7YKPW0lNpxXw?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="587" height="390"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the course of several days, our team engaged in deep-dive workshops, strategic discussions, and hands-on sessions to refine our vision and roadmap. Beyond work, we strengthened connections through team-building activities, shared meals, and lively conversations—experiences that reinforced the spirit of unity and innovation at SubQuery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was our first-ever full team meetup, but it certainly won’t be the last. As we continue to scale, fostering strong relationships and maintaining a culture of collaboration will remain a priority!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfMXn46tePn9SovXW35kUVJlVfzXNHrPj89L3cwfmLaI5-j2ovZRo0WFU45JZW_C2F8RN8-MnWAp7tGT1xitYac6AUYI_LZYYCW0gyCJTRcKfA6epOej_0mpNA-gE4WWUcwNV1Nmg?key=ZnjZJpJlE80uNZW09s9-6WDl" class="kg-image" alt="" loading="lazy" width="629" height="471"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coming Soon: The SubQuery 2025 Roadmap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Big things are on the horizon! We’ll unveil our 2025 roadmap in March, showcasing the next phase of SubQuery’s evolution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Expect some exciting things - some you’ve been waiting for and others might surprise you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for what’s next!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S.&lt;/strong&gt; Remember to join our &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt; &lt;u&gt;our social channels&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to stay updated on our latest news and announcements!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">SubQuery Provides Flawless Data Indexing Support to the Monad Network</title>
    <published>2025-03-06T09:20:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-06T09:20:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.subquery.network/subquery-provides-flawless-data-indexing-support-to-the-monad-network</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.subquery.network/subquery-provides-flawless-data-indexing-support-to-the-monad-network"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.monad.xyz/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Monad&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ecosystem has seen one of the fastest expansions in the blockchain industry since Solana’s rise. We’re proud to support developers building on the Monad testnet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monad is a high-performance blockchain platform designed as an Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM)-compatible Layer 1 (L1) scaling solution. The smart contract platform offers full compatibility with the EVM while focusing on scalability and decentralisation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery's indexing capabilities empower Monad builders to efficiently manage and query on-chain data, expediting development processes and facilitating rapid iterations. This advances the goal of onboarding the next billion users to the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With SubQuery, developers on Monad gain access to a high-speed, decentralised data indexing solution that simplifies the process of managing on-chain data. Subquery’s tailor-made API eliminates the need to build custom indexing solutions, allowing developers to focus on what matters most—building products and enhancing user experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;gt; “Developers building on Monad now have access to one of the best data indexers, making it easier than ever to manage and query on-chain data. This integration empowers builders to focus on innovation, and we’re thrilled to have SubQuery onboard.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— Keone Hon, Co-Founder, Monad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery’s open-source SDK, tools, and extensive &lt;a href="https://academy.subquery.network/indexer/quickstart/quickstart_chains/bsc.html?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;documentation&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; offer a comprehensive indexing experience. Developers also benefit from our &lt;a href="https://managedservice.subquery.network/login?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;enterprise-level managed service&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which hosts infrastructure capable of handling hundreds of millions of daily requests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;gt; “We're excited to provide developers on Monad with advanced APIs and tools to enhance their building experience. Monad's EVM-compatible L1, boasting speeds 1,000x faster than Ethereum, opens the door for groundbreaking innovation. We look forward to seeing what developers create next.”&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— James Bayly, Co-Founder &amp;amp; COO of SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="why-use-subquery"&gt;Why Use SubQuery?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery simplifies the creation of custom APIs for dApps or smart contracts in minutes, providing clean indexed data for any service. The platform is flexible, allowing external API calls and imported libraries, while also offering robust DOS (denial of service) mitigation controls. With SubQuery, developers have the option to run projects on personal infrastructure or rely on the managed service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery is designed to be fast. By optimising the store with multi-threading and reducing costly database writes, SubQuery significantly reduces sync times. Faster syncing enables quicker iterations and faster delivery of features to market.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="subquery%E2%80%99s-support-for-monad"&gt;SubQuery’s Support for Monad&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Advanced Indexing of blocks, transactions, and logs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://academy.subquery.network/indexer/quickstart/quickstart_chains/monad.html?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;An excellent Quick Start Guide&amp;nbsp;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/subquery/ethereum-subql-starter/tree/main/Monad/monad-testnet-starter?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Example Project&amp;nbsp;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Full support for Monad in our &lt;a href="https://managedservice.subquery.network/login?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;free enterprise-level managed service&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord community&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (including technical support)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-monad"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Monad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monad is a high-performance Ethereum-compatible L1. Monad materially advances the efficient frontier in the tradeoff between decentralization and scalability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monad introduces optimizations in four major areas, resulting in a blockchain with throughput of 10,000 transactions per second (tps).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.monad.xyz/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://docs.monad.xyz/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Docs&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/monad_xyz?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/monad_xyz?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Main X&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://x.com/monad_eco?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ecosystem X&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://x.com/monad_dev?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Dev X&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://x.com/pipeline_xyz?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Pipeline X&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/monad?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Community Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://discord.gg/monaddev?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Dev Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://monadxyz.substack.com/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="about-subquery"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SubQuery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SubQuery Network is innovating in web3 infrastructure with tools that empower builders to decentralise without compromise. SubQuery’s infrastructure network offers everything from data indexers, RPCs and AI agents - all fully decentralised and production ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our fast, flexible, and open data indexer supercharges thousands of dApps on nearly 300 networks. Our Sharded Data Node will provide breakthroughs in the RPC industry and our AI App framework makes building AI apps easier than ever before. We pioneer the web3 revolution for visionaries and forward-thinkers. We’re not just a company — we’re a movement driving an inclusive and decentralised web3 era, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​​​&lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Linktree&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://subquery.network/?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Discord&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://t.me/subquerynetworkcommunity?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Telegram&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/subquerynetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Twitter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://blog.subquery.network/?lng=en"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Blog&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/subquery?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SubQueryNetwork?ref=blog.subquery.network"&gt;&lt;u&gt;YouTube&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
