<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Subs on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@subsprotocol?source=rss-a2e4032e12fa------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40subsprotocol&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*m3ddqQORmcUhQz3sCEI8iQ.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*m3ddqQORmcUhQz3sCEI8iQ.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40subsprotocol&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:19+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Revolutionizing SaaS Subscriptions: Etherspot Integrates Subs for Blockchain-Based Subscription.</title>
    <published>2024-04-30T14:53:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-04-30T14:53:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://subsprotocol.medium.com/revolutionizing-saas-subscriptions-etherspot-integrates-subs-for-blockchain-based-subscription-2eacef72b6b8?source=rss-a2e4032e12fa------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://subsprotocol.medium.com/revolutionizing-saas-subscriptions-etherspot-integrates-subs-for-blockchain-based-subscription-2eacef72b6b8?source=rss-a2e4032e12fa------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Subs</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Subs x EtherspotWe are excited to announce a new partnership with Etherspot. Through this collaboration, Etherspot just integrated Subs to allow developers to easily pay their subscription with Cryptos.Introduction to EtherspotEtherspot is an innovative Account Abstraction development platform that simplifies onboarding users across EVM-compatible blockchains. By simplifying the complexities of blockchain interactions, Etherspot empowers developers to create more efficient and user-friendly decentralized applications. Their platform offers robust functionalities, including multi-chain support, Web2-like onboarding, gasless transactions, transaction batching, recovery guardians, and more…Implementing Subs for SaaS subscriptionsRecognizing the potential for decentralized financial solutions in the SaaS industry, Etherspot has adopted Subs to manage their subscriptions. Subs, known for its seamless integration of recurring payments on blockchain, offers Etherspot a unique edge. By leveraging Subs, Etherspot can now offer builders subscription plans that are not only secure due to its blockchain backbone but also flexible and easily adaptable to various payment structures and frequencies. Developers can now pay their Etherspot subscriptions with stablecoins.“The integration went very smoothly and Subs team is always open to suggestions.” — Blooda, Etherspot’s DevSecOps Engineer.Custom Adaptations of Subs for EtherspotTo meet specific needs, Subs was customized to integrate smoothly with Etherspot’s existing services. These adaptations included:Redirection after subscriptionWebhooks featuresEnhanced UI/UX elements ensuring clear instructions and a frictionless user experience and moreA Step Towards Decentralized SaaS SolutionsThe partnership between Etherspot and Subs is a testament to the versatility and potential of blockchain technologies in transforming traditional business models. By integrating Subs, Etherspot not only improves its service offerings. But also make them pioneers in the adoption of decentralized subscription services in the SaaS industry. This collaboration marks a significant step forward in realizing the full potential of blockchain for business and sets a precedent for future innovations.The partnership aligns perfectly with the Subs mission of enabling customizable subscriptions without users having to lock funds or platforms to write complex smart contracts.“Our aim at Etherspot is not only to deliver a frictionless Web3 experience for users but also to simplify the process of dApp development,” said Michael Messele, CEO of Etherspot. “By teaming up with Subs, we enable Web3 developers to seamlessly access our services using stablecoins and leverage account abstraction technology for their dApps.”The partnership kicks off on the Polygon network, with plans to expand to other EVM-compatible chains based on developer demand. All developers can start now through Etherspot’s developer portal.You can take a look or subscribe here.This is just the beginning for the Subs-Etherspot collaboration. Both teams are committed to continuously improving the subscription payment experience through additional features. The goal is to make subscriptions as seamless and user-friendly as their Web2 counterparts, while unlocking the decentralization benefits of Web3.For more details on using Subs Protocol subscriptions within the Etherspot ecosystem, check out the integration guide here.About Subs ProtocolSubs Protocol is a decentralized subscription protocol that enables businesses to create recurring payments on-chain. With a user-friendly interface, Subs allows anyone to define custom subscription models, accepted tokens and payment frequencies without requiring coding.About EtherspotEtherspot provides Account Abstraction blockchain development tools to simplify building multi-chain dApps and improving the Web3 user experience.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing Subs : A New Crypto Subscription Solution</title>
    <published>2024-04-23T16:22:27+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-04-23T16:22:27+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://subsprotocol.medium.com/introducing-subs-a-new-crypto-subscription-solution-14f133687909?source=rss-a2e4032e12fa------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://subsprotocol.medium.com/introducing-subs-a-new-crypto-subscription-solution-14f133687909?source=rss-a2e4032e12fa------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Subs</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Introducing Subs : A New Crypto Subscription SolutionCryptocurrency Subscriptions Unlocked: Subs Forges a New PathIn the ever-evolving world of digital payments, a new frontier is emerging — the convergence of the booming subscription economy and the rapid growth of cryptocurrency. Enter Subs, an innovative solution that is poised to revolutionize the way we think about recurring payments in the Web3 ecosystem.The subscription economy has been on a remarkable trajectory, with global revenue estimated to reach a staggering $900 billion by 2026, up from $73 billion in 2021. This meteoric rise has been fuelled in part by the increasing adoption of AI-powered services, suggesting a potential shift toward a subscription-based hegemony in the years to come.At the same time, the cryptocurrency market has been experiencing its own exponential growth, with a compound annual growth rate of 56% over the past five years. This surge in popularity has led to a significant increase in the demand for crypto payment gateways, with the global market projected to reach $5.4 billion by 2031, growing at a CAGR of 18.7%.However, the adoption of recurring payment capabilities in the Web3 space has been historically limited, despite the clear need for such solutions in a market largely dominated by digital content. The unique technical challenges posed by implementing subscription-based models on blockchain networks, such as a lack of native support, transaction costs, and network congestion issues, have hindered the progress of this critical innovation.This is where Subs comes in, offering a game-changing solution that bridges the gap between the subscription economy and the world of cryptocurrency. Subs is a fully functional, live-on-mainnet solution that provides a seamless and secure way for Web3 companies and users to manage recurring payments.A revolution for every companyFor Web2 companies and users, Subs offers a range of benefits, including reduced fees, fewer intermediaries, enhanced privacy, and greater flexibility. Conversely, for Web3 companies and users, Subs provides a fast and intuitive user interface, high security, enhanced control, and scalability — all of which are crucial for the success and adoption of subscription-based models in the decentralized ecosystem.Subs’ comprehensive solution includes a set of smart contracts for on-chain subscriptions, a “no-code” button for easy implementation on any project, and a personal Subs platform for small businesses to host their subscription pages. Additionally, the Subs dashboard provides an all-in-one app for managing crypto subscriptions, including invoicing and other essential features.By leveraging the power of blockchain technology, Subs is poised to unlock new opportunities for content monetization, group monetization, and donations — all while empowering both Web2 and Web3 businesses to capitalize on the rapidly growing subscription economy.We’re passionate and ambitiousThe team behind Subs, composed of seasoned blockchain engineers, DevOps experts, and seasoned marketing professionals, brings a wealth of experience and a deep understanding of the challenges faced in the Web3 space. Their commitment to innovation and their dedication to solving the technical hurdles associated with crypto-based subscriptions make them uniquely positioned to drive the adoption of this groundbreaking solution.As the subscription economy and the cryptocurrency market continue to converge, Subs stands as a beacon of innovation, offering a transformative solution that could redefine the way we think about recurring payments in the decentralized future. With its comprehensive set of features, robust security, and user-friendly interface, Subs is poised to become the go-to platform for Web3 companies and users seeking to capitalize on the vast potential of the subscription economy.Try Subs now : https://app.subsprotocol.com/</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
