<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog - Tala</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://tala.co/blog/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Ftala.co%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_selector=.entry-title+a&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Ftala.co%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.entry-content&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_noproxy=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Ftala.co%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_selector=.entry-title+a&amp;url_pattern=https%3A%2F%2Ftala.co%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.entry-content&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_noproxy=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:39+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Resilience and creativity in the face of inflation - Tala</title>
    <published>2024-01-18T15:26:10+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-01-18T15:26:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://tala.co/blog/2024/01/18/resilience-and-creativity-in-the-face-of-inflation/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://tala.co/blog/2024/01/18/resilience-and-creativity-in-the-face-of-inflation/"/>
    <author>
      <name>Tala</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html"> 		 Post-pandemic, economies around the world are struggling to recuperate. As part of our 2023 Customer Barometer, Tala surveyed over 2,000 customers from Africa, Latin America, and Southeast Asia to understand their perceived impact of inflation and how they cope with these changes. Maintaining their previous standard of living has become more challenging for people as costs for essential goods rise. Still, the ways customers navigate the current economic landscape are multifaceted. From adaptive budgeting strategies to new side hustles, this report sheds light on the resilience and resourcefulness exhibited by consumers in the face of inflationary pressures.    Inflation affects the Global Majority personally&amp;nbsp;    Our customers are acutely impacted by inflation as nearly 1 in 2 customers surveyed indicated they had no rise in pay in 2023. This makes it challenging for customers to keep up with daily expenses. In fact, 90% of respondents agree that inflation impacts their family budgets, and most note groceries as the most common pain point. Across the board, our customers around the world are feeling financial pressures.    Inflation has implications for both essential spending as well as leisure. Thirty-five percent of global respondents feel they rarely or never have anything left for leisure or enjoyment. However, this varies slightly by market. Filipino and Kenyan customers are cutting back on non-critical expenses to meet basic needs, more so than in Mexico.     Customers find ways to cope via entrepreneurship    Despite the complications of inflation on customers, they’ve identified a variety of methods to cope with increasing costs and manage difficult times. Globally, 59% report starting business, side hustles, or part-time roles as a means to cope. Although a global behavior, we see slight variances. In Kenya and Mexico, there is a preference for starting a business or a side hustle (40% and 42%, respectively). In the Philippines, 34% report picking up a second or part-time job, and 36% report starting a business or side hustle.&amp;nbsp;    As customers develop other avenues for income, we also see signs of resilience. Across our markets, 48% occasionally experience stress related to inflation, but not constantly. In fact, 19% rarely experience stress. Reports of high financial stress were seen most notably in Kenya. There, 17% reported almost always feeling stress about their financial situation — nearly three times that of our other markets.&amp;nbsp;    The majority feel supported to navigate financial headwinds&amp;nbsp;    When asked how Tala has impacted their finances, we see high reports of peace of mind. Generally, our customers feel they have the right financial resources — the majority of respondents agree they have the right tools to manage their money how they want to, and 26% strongly agree. Customers worldwide have been able to handle financial shocks, manage household expenses, and leverage Tala loans to start and grow businesses.&amp;nbsp;    This report illuminates the remarkable resilience and resourcefulness demonstrated by our customers grappling with the challenges of inflation. As we navigate economic uncertainties, it is evident that the Global Majority are not just passive observers but proactive participants in shaping their financial destinies. From disciplined budgeting to embracing supplementary income streams, the diverse strategies employed by our customers underscore the dynamic nature of economic progress. Learning from these behavioral shifts is crucial in developing effective solutions to support individuals in maintaining their desired quality of life despite ongoing inflationary pressures.&amp;nbsp;    Notes on methodology    Tala conducted an online survey among 2,173 Tala customers living in Kenya, the Philippines, and Mexico to understand perceptions of inflation and how people are managing their financial lives accordingly. The sample is representative of our active customer populations with a 95% and higher confidence level across each sample set.     	</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://tala.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Blog_Customer-barometer-3.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Accelerating Action for Women’s Equality with Tala’s Leaders - Tala</title>
    <published>2025-03-06T19:16:43+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-06T19:16:43+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://tala.co/blog/2025/03/06/iwd-2025/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://tala.co/blog/2025/03/06/iwd-2025/"/>
    <author>
      <name>christian</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html"> 		 At Tala, we’re proud to say that 70% of our senior leadership team is women-led. In line with this year’s theme for International Women’s Day, we asked them how they accelerate action for women’s equality outside of the workplace.    From advocating for equitable funding and mentorship to reshaping leadership in tech, law, and finance, these leaders prove that change starts with bold steps forward.    Shivani Siroya, Founder &amp;amp; CEO    Grace Hopper once said, “The most dangerous phrase in the language is: &amp;#8216;It&amp;#8217;s always been done that way.’” To accelerate action, we cannot settle for systems that limit anyone’s potential. Instead, our work should, both professionally and personally, prove another way is possible.&amp;nbsp;    It’s not about the barriers we may face, though we must also acknowledge them as women, but concentrate more on the problems we’re solving. By charging ahead after our goals and towards a better, more equitable future, we can rewrite the rules and open doors to opportunities that were once out of reach.    My journey has taught me that changing the status quo starts with action. Whether it’s helping other women access funding, advocating for policy change, or building systems that support women in leadership, every step counts. There is no progress without change!    Kelly Uphoff, CTO    I have been very lucky in my career to work for some very successful women leaders who were extraordinary not because of their gender, but because of their authenticity. In different ways, they showed me that you can be yourself AND succeed, even if “yourself” doesn’t fit the mold of what a traditional leader might have looked like. I also saw them struggle in different ways that seemed unfair and that still motivates me to make sure I’m now an authentic voice for the newest generation of women leaders coming up today.&amp;nbsp;    Damier Xandrine, CLO    I am the granddaughter of Cecile Marie Broussard, a very &amp;#8220;light-skinned&amp;#8221; Black woman who lost her job once her employer learned that she was Black. Keep in mind––this happened in Los Angeles, California, not the Jim Crow south. The realities of how inequality can impact opportunity are literally part of my DNA, so advocating for fairness and access for underrepresented communities has always been important to me.&amp;nbsp;    The legal profession is an area where women have been underrepresented, especially at the highest levels of leadership. One organization that prepares girls and women to excel in their legal career is Ms. JD. I support the organization&amp;#8217;s programs and also serve as a mentor and coach for early-career lawyers. Investing in these young women and helping them advance, in a profession where they can be under-valued, is my way of accelerating their success and growth. And also—I get to honor my grandmother who made the same investment in me.    Lauren Pruneski, SVP of Global Brand &amp;amp; Communications    I make it a priority to mentor women who are earlier in their careers, especially those navigating work-life balance and the challenges of being a working parent with young kids. Early in my career, I benefited tremendously from the guidance and example of others, and I try to pay that forward. Many women are starting families at the same time they’re rising in their careers. While every path is different, and there’s no one-size-fits-all approach, I’ve found that simply seeing how others manage the journey, or having someone to talk to who understands the challenges, can be incredibly valuable.    Beyond mentorship, I’m passionate about advocating for greater paid family leave—not just for birth mothers, but for all parents and caregivers. Equally important, we need to encourage dads and non-birth parents to take their full leave, helping to normalize and equalize caregiving responsibilities.    Mumbi Annstella, General Manager of Tala Kenya    I am a big believer in the saying, “you can’t be what you haven’t seen”. In my personal life, I have been lucky to have had multiple&amp;nbsp; women mentors who have supported me in my career, showed me what was possible, and pushed me into the right rooms and roles to enable my growth––from my first senior roles in growth and expansion to my current role at Tala today.&amp;nbsp;    I have since modeled my career and personal initiatives on what I have seen and learned from these women in leadership. Following this same mantra, I am very intentional about spending personal time with groups such as Women Who Build Africa (WWBA) which allows for women at all career levels in tech to meet, discuss technologies, and share experiences to build confidence in a safe space. They also help women founders work on their pitches and build fundraising networks.&amp;nbsp;    I believe that the learning journey never ends and it is on us to share our learnings as mentors with those behind us even as we advance and discover more mentees.    Zoe McKiness, SVP of Data &amp;amp; Platform    I was fortunate to have strong women mentors in the sciences starting in high school who always pushed me to achieve my full potential and dismiss self-doubt. Professionally, I have benefitted from amazing mentors who have helped me “get out of my own way” and not shy away from continuously pushing the boundaries for myself and the teams I have been lucky to be a part of.&amp;nbsp;    This generosity and support inspired me to contribute and sponsor various women in science, tech, and data science organizations across my career. Equally, if not more rewarding, have been the individual coaching relationships I have had the privilege to experience over the years. I strongly believe these personal connections help both the mentor and mentee grow and develop.&amp;nbsp; 	</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://tala.co/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GL_IWD_blog.png"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Books That Changed the Way Talazens Think in 2024 - Tala</title>
    <published>2024-12-20T21:34:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-20T21:34:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://tala.co/blog/2024/12/20/books-that-changed-the-way-talazens-think-in-2024/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://tala.co/blog/2024/12/20/books-that-changed-the-way-talazens-think-in-2024/"/>
    <author>
      <name>christian</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html"> 		 As we round out the year, we’re celebrating the stories and ideas that inspired Talazens in 2024 by spotlighting the books that have shaped our thinking about humanity, impact, technology and the world around us.&amp;nbsp;    From thought-provoking reads to new perspectives, these recommendations reflect the values that unite us and fuel our shared mission of unleashing the economic power of the Global Majority.    Take a look at the books that have influenced our journey in 2024, and maybe discover your next great read along the way!         &amp;#8220;Nexus is a grounding exploration of how far human connection and information networks have come. It was interesting to read this in the foreground of all the recent technological breakthroughs we’re seeing with AI and blockchain, especially given what we&amp;#8217;re working on at Tala.      The book serves as a good reminder that humanity, communication, and collaboration are all interconnected drivers of progress, and encourages a deeper appreciation for the evolving networks — both human and technological — that define our lives.&amp;#8220;            &amp;#8220;This book weaves a storyline about racial and ethnic inequality in various permutations across the globe, while also exploring the human response to it. In reading it, I gained a new understanding that technology and the legal system, while tools to combat these issues, do not solve the problems themselves. To do so, we need dedicated, passionate people driving these tools in order to effect change.    It also taught me a good lesson––helping individual people won&amp;#8217;t always bring about systemic change, but that doesn&amp;#8217;t make it any less meaningful to the people you have helped. I recommend the book for those who like historical and modern fiction rooted in reality. Isabel Allende always writes in a way that puts you in the middle of the story which I also appreciate.&amp;#8221;            &amp;#8220;James&amp;#8221; is a reimagining of Mark Twain&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn&amp;#8221; from the perspective of Jim, the enslaved person who accompanies Huck along the Mississippi. Seeing the world through James&amp;#8217; point of view is revelatory—a journey through the many ways that racial identity is constructed and lived, and a reminder that every person has a story.    I&amp;#8217;ve been recommending this book to everyone this year, but especially to people who say they don&amp;#8217;t read &amp;#8220;literary fiction&amp;#8221;—it&amp;#8217;s a page-turning plot that also challenges you to think, and the humanity will break your heart open if you let it!&amp;#8220;            &amp;#8220;There are several themes that I’ve taken to heart from this 500+ page memoir, like focusing on solutions rather than “admiring” the problem, and giving oneself permission to choose joy despite the perceived futility of one’s individual actions. That said, I keep coming back to this last line that encapsulates the essence of Power’s story and message: “People who care, act, and refuse to give up may not change THE world, but they can change many individual worlds.”    When I feel overwhelmed and ask myself, &amp;#8220;Will all my efforts have been worth it?&amp;#8221; I ground myself by reflecting on the stories of real people I&amp;#8217;ve had the privilege to hear. In those moments, the answer is always a simple and resounding yes.    For anyone who is passionate about social impact, I highly recommend this book. Fighting the good fight, at work and in life, is hard and exhausting, but reading Power’s stories and reflections made me feel less alone and injected some much-needed fuel to keep me going.&amp;#8220;            &amp;#8220;This book is all about the intersection of creativity, business, and leadership. The insights on cultivating the right balance between processes that provide stability, while simultaneously embracing ambiguity that fosters innovation deeply resonate with Tala&amp;#8217;s culture. I’d strongly recommend this to anyone interested in understanding and unlocking creative thinking.&amp;#8220;            &amp;#8220;This autobiographical graphic novel and coming-of-age story provides a powerful perspective on events—both personal and historical—that challenge how we perceive life, education, and freedom. Each time I revisit it, I’m reminded not to take anything in life for granted and that everyone deserves a second chance.    Not only is the book visually stunning and funny, but also deeply insightful. It taught me valuable lessons about empathy, the importance of community, and perseverance. I’d recommend it to anyone in need of a little direction. It offers the chance to walk in others’ shoes and listen to their stories, allowing empathy to flourish.&amp;#8220; 	</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/png" href="https://tala.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MX_TalazensBooks_blog.png"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
