<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Softr Bridge</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://example.com"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=SoftrBridge&amp;context=Main&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tap4change.org%2Fv1%2Fdatasource%2Fairtable%2F71cd0c38-3991-41bf-a0e0-3b4b1cfe0eeb%2Fe9bf56ad-3356-4136-8c6b-d06dc001510c%2F1c852182-070e-4921-9b09-702c377e7323%2F890a5379-fb60-4026-b6ca-211c2683f2f4%2Fdata&amp;items_path=records&amp;article_field=fields.url&amp;title_field=fields.Title&amp;prefix=&amp;author_field=&amp;pubdate_field=createdTime&amp;date_format=&amp;content_field=fields.Body+Text&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://example.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://example.com/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=SoftrBridge&amp;context=Main&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tap4change.org%2Fv1%2Fdatasource%2Fairtable%2F71cd0c38-3991-41bf-a0e0-3b4b1cfe0eeb%2Fe9bf56ad-3356-4136-8c6b-d06dc001510c%2F1c852182-070e-4921-9b09-702c377e7323%2F890a5379-fb60-4026-b6ca-211c2683f2f4%2Fdata&amp;items_path=records&amp;article_field=fields.url&amp;title_field=fields.Title&amp;prefix=&amp;author_field=&amp;pubdate_field=createdTime&amp;date_format=&amp;content_field=fields.Body+Text&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:45+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How Gen Z and Millennials Can Make Strategic Donations to the Causes They Support</title>
    <published>2024-08-03T10:04:21+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-03T10:04:21+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tap4change.org/blog/How-Gen-Z-and-Millennials-Can-Make-Strategic-Donations</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tap4change.org/blog/How-Gen-Z-and-Millennials-Can-Make-Strategic-Donations"/>
    <content type="html">When it comes to charitable giving, Gen Z and Millennials are increasingly playing an important role. According to a survey conducted by the National Philanthropic Trust, in 2020, young people aged 24 to 39 gave an average of 8.2% of their annual income to charities. Whether you’re a young professional, a student, or simply someone who wants to make an impact, here are some tips to help you make strategic donations to the causes you care about.

## **What is Charitable Giving?**
Charitable giving is the practice of donating money, goods, or services to a nonprofit organization. It’s an important part of philanthropy and can be extremely rewarding for those who take part in it. 

Charitable giving can take many forms, from donating money to participating in fundraising events, volunteering your time and skills, or buying items for those in need.

## **Who Donates Most?**
The oldest the generation, the more they seem to give. Tradition donors (GenX, Boomers, Traditionalists) have more disposable income and tend to give more as individuals and in total.

But Modern donors, or Next-gen donors (Millenials &amp; Gen-Z), are showing a huge appetite to give back and help others, sometimes in less conventional ways, supporting causes rather than institutions, grassroots-type movements, and looking for more direct impact. 

When engaged through the right channels, these generations show incredible generosity and donate on average to 3.3 charities. [Z Event](https://zevent.fr/), a video game streaming marathon, showcases that very well.

[TAP4CHANGE](https://studio.softr.io/TAP4CHANGE.ORG) will provide the right channel to these generations and older ones, by delivering a much-needed convenient, transparent, and uplifiting donation experience.

## **How Much Should You Give?**
The right amount to give depends on your personal circumstances. However, there are certain advantages to giving generously. 

For example, donations to registered charities are tax-deductible, so you can reduce your taxable income and save money on taxes. It’s also possible to donate items instead of money. If you’re in a position to do so, consider donating clothes, furniture, books, or other items to organizations or people in need.

## **Reputable Charities**
To ensure you’re donating to a reputable charity, it’s important to do your research. Check if the charity is registered with the government, read their reviews online, and learn more about their mission, activities, and impact. Additionally, it’s important to know where your money is going. 

Ask the organization how exactly it will use your donation, and keep an eye out for charities that are transparent about their finances.

## **Conclusion**
Charitable giving can be an extremely rewarding experience for those who choose to participate. Generosity doesn’t always have to come in the form of money; it can also take the shape of volunteering, spreading awareness, or donating items. 

However, it’s important to make sure you’re donating to reputable charities by doing your research and making sure your money goes to the right place. Through thoughtful and strategic donations, Gen Z and Millennials can make a difference and contribute to the causes they support.

## **Quick tips:**
For those looking to donate to charity, it’s important to know that your money is going to the right place. To ensure you’re donating to a reputable charity, it’s important to do your research. Check if the charity is registered with the government, read their reviews online, and look up their mission, activities, and impact. 

Additionally, ask the organization how exactly it will use your donation, and keep an eye out for charities that are transparent about their finances. By conducting a thorough donor's lookup, you are taking steps to ensure your money is going where it’s needed.

## **=&gt; In 2024, WE WILL MAKE THAT SIMPLE! pre-register now for [Tap4C](https://www.tap4change.org/how-it-works)**[hange](https://www.tap4change.org/how-it-works)

**References:**
[1][ A Look at Generational Giving Donor Trends and Influences](https://www.nonprofitpro.com/post/a-look-at-generational-giving-donor-trends-and-influences/)
[2][ Understanding the Next Generation of Donors and How They Will Change The World](https://www.changingourworld.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Next-Gen-Report_FINAL-1.pdf)
[3] [80+ Charitable Giving Statistics &amp; Demographics (2023)](https://www.definefinancial.com/blog/charitable-giving-statistics/)
[4] [Four Generations For Charity: Who Really Gives a Buck?](https://www.generations.com/insights/four-generations-for-charity-who-really-gives-a-buck)
[5][ A Look at Generational Giving Donor Trends and Influences](https://www.nonprofitpro.com/post/a-look-at-generational-giving-donor-trends-and-influences/)
[6] [Why Gen Z Might Become One Of The Most Charitable …](https://www.forbes.com/sites/markcperna/2022/11/29/why-gen-z-might-become-one-of-the-most-charitable-generations-yet/)
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How Millennials and Gen Z are Changing the Face of Charitable Giving</title>
    <published>2024-08-03T10:04:21+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-03T10:04:21+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tap4change.org/blog/How-Millennials-and-Gen-Z-are-Changing-the-Face-of-Charitable-Giving</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tap4change.org/blog/How-Millennials-and-Gen-Z-are-Changing-the-Face-of-Charitable-Giving"/>
    <content type="html">Millennials and Gen Z, known as the "digital natives," have grown up with technology at their fingertips. With social media playing a big role in their lives, they can connect online, share information, and mobilise around causes they care about. 

While these generations are eager to help, charities lack the tools to attract and engage them. This leads to a growing perception that they are not as engaged with charities as previous generations. In this article, we’ll explore why this is the case and what it means for the future of charitable giving.

## **Summary:**
&lt;ol type="1"&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Skepticism of Large Organizations and Lack of Trust&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Desire for Direct Impact and Measurable Results&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Wrong Communication Channels and Lack of Personal Connection&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Preference for Direct Forms of Activism and Continuous Engagement&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Advocacy and Activism for Systemic and Political Solutions&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Financial Constraints&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Digital Natives and Online Activism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt; 
## **Skepticism of Large Organizations and Lack of Trust**
One of the main reasons for the trend is skepticism of large organizations and a lack of trust in how donations are used. 

Millennials and Gen Z are more skeptical of traditional institutions and want more transparency and accountability in how their money is spent. They want to know that their donations are making a real impact and that the charity is using their funds effectively.

## **Desire for Direct Impact and Measurable Results**
Another reason for the trend of lower engagement with charities among millennials and Gen Z is their desire for a direct impact and measurable results. This generation wants to know that their efforts and donations are making a tangible difference and want to see the results of their efforts firsthand.

Charities need to find ways to demonstrate the impact of their work and show the results of their efforts continuously. This can be done through data and metrics, as well as through stories and testimonials from people who have been directly impacted by their work. By demonstrating the direct impact of their efforts, charities can engage this generation and inspire them to take action.

## **Wrong Communication Channels and Lack of Personal Connection**
This generation values authenticity and wants to support causes that align with their values and beliefs. They are more likely to get involved with a cause if they have a personal connection to it, such as through friends or family, or if they have had a personal experience with the issue.

Charities need to find ways to build personal connections with this generation using the right communication channels and create a sense of community around their cause. This can be done through social media, community events, and other forms of outreach that allow people to connect with the cause on a personal level. 

Building a strong sense of community and personal connection is key to this generation's engagement.

## **Preference for Direct Forms of Activism and Continuous Engagement**
Another factor is their preference for more hands-on, direct forms of activism and community service. This generation wants to make a direct impact in their communities and they want to make it last. They are more likely to volunteer their time. They want to be part of the solution and see the results of their efforts firsthand.

## **Advocacy and Activism for Systemic and Political Solutions**
Millennials and Gen Z are also increasingly focused on systemic and political solutions to social issues. They understand that many of society's problems are deeply rooted in systemic issues and that lasting change requires political action. 

This has led to a growing interest in advocacy and activism and a desire to use their voices to bring about change.

## **Financial Constraints**
Financial constraints, such as student loan debt and low wages, also play a role in why millennials and Gen Z may not seem as engaged with charities. 

This generation is facing financial challenges that previous generations did not and may not have the same level of disposable income to donate. Despite this, they are still looking for ways to give back and make a difference in their communities.

## **Digital Natives and Online Activism**
Finally, as digital natives, millennials and Gen Z prefer to support causes through social media campaigns and online activism. They are more likely to share information about a cause on social media and sign online petitions than to make a financial donation. 

This shows that they are very engaged with causes, but are looking for new and innovative ways to make a difference.

In conclusion, while it may look like millennials and Gen Z aren't as engaged with charities as previous generations, they are more interested in making a difference than ever. They will advocate for the causes they care about. 

Charities need to adapt to their needs and preferences, such as more transparency, accountability, and hands-on ways to make an impact, to continue to engage this new generation of donors. 
Making it easy to support a cause via digital channels and within their financial means is of paramount importance. And so is continuous engagement to create personal connections.

The future of charitable giving is changing, and it's important for organizations to stay ahead of the curve.

This is what TAP4CHANGE.ORG is about.
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Essential Checklist for First-Time Donors: Making Charitable Decisions</title>
    <published>2024-10-11T03:46:54+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-11T03:46:54+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tap4change.org/blog/the-essential-checklist-for-first-time-donors</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tap4change.org/blog/the-essential-checklist-for-first-time-donors"/>
    <content type="html">_“There is more happiness in giving than there is in receiving.”_

A wise teacher once noted that true joy comes not from receiving gifts but from giving them from the heart. This sentiment beautifully captures the essence of charitable giving: it’s a positive way to make a meaningful difference in both your life and the lives of others. 

Whether you're moved by a cause close to your heart or simply want to contribute to your community, the act of donating can be deeply fulfilling. 

However, as a first-time donor, you might find it hard to choose from the various ways of donating, or choosing the right charity and non-profit organisation that you want to help like _“Who can I donate to, who to trust?,” “How can I get started?”, Where is my money going”, or How can I make a difference or impact?”_

Good thing is, we’re here to guide you every step of the way, ensuring that your charitable journey is both smooth and impactful.
### **Understanding Your Motivation for Donating**
There’s no question behind your full intent in donating or giving back to the community. But it’s important to reflect on why you want to do it, or to whom you want to give it to.

Are you passionate about a particular cause, such as education, mental health, or the environment? Or maybe you're driven by a desire to give back.

Donating is not just about giving money; it's about aligning your contributions with your values and passions. It’s about what you stand for! When you find a cause that resonates with you, your donation becomes more meaningful, and you're more likely to continue supporting it in the future. 

So take a moment to think about what matters most to you and how you want your donation to make a difference.

### **Different Types of Donations**
There are many ways to contribute to a cause, and your donation doesn't always have to be in the form of money. Here are the different types of donations to consider:
- **Monetary Donations:** Financial contributions are the most common way to give. The money you donate can provide immediate support to a charity's programs and services.
- **In-Kind Donations:** This involves donating goods or services instead of money. For example, you could donate clothing, food, or even your professional expertise.
- **Volunteering:** If you're not in a position to give money, donating your time and skills can be just as valuable. Many charities rely on volunteers to help them carry out their work.
- **Planned Giving:** This is a way to leave a legacy by including a charity in your will or estate plans. It's a thoughtful way to ensure your support continues long into the future.

### **Avoiding Charity Scams**
Unfortunately, not every organisation claiming to be a charity is genuine. So as pure as your heart can be, you also have to be wise in this industry.

Scammers often take advantage of generous individuals, especially in times of crisis or during the holidays. To avoid falling victim to a charity scam, watch out for the following red flags:
- **Pressure to Donate Quickly:** Scammers often create a sense of urgency to prevent you from doing your research. A legitimate charity will appreciate your donation whenever you choose to give.
- **Lack of Transparency:** Be wary of organisations that aren't transparent with information about their mission, how they use donations, or their financial records. 
- **Vague or Suspicious Contact Information:** Legitimate charities will have clear and accessible contact details. If you can't find a physical address or phone number, consider it a warning sign.

If something feels off, trust your instincts. It's better to take the time to research and verify a charity than to rush into a decision and risk losing your donation to a scam.

In case that you ever did encounter such issues, report them to appropriate authorities or watchdog organisations.

### **What Else to Know About Making Donations?**
To maximize the impact of your donation and enhance your giving experience, keep these tips in mind:
**Tax Benefits**
Did you know that your donation could come with financial benefits for you as well? In many countries including Australia, charitable donations can be tax-deductible, which means you can reduce your taxable income by the amount you donate. 

For instance, in Australia, you can claim a tax deduction for your donations if the organisation has a [deductible gift recipient (DGR)](https://www.ato.gov.au/individuals-and-families/income-deductions-offsets-and-records/deductions-you-can-claim/gifts-and-donations#:~:text=You%20can%20only%20claim%20a,be%20made%20to%20a%20DGR.) status. To take advantage of this, make sure you donate to a registered charity and keep a record of your donation. When tax season rolls around, you’ll have the necessary documentation to claim your deduction.

**Recurring Donations**
If you want to make an ongoing impact, consider setting up recurring donations. These are automatic payments that you make regularly, such as monthly or annually, to your chosen charity.
 
Recurring donations are a great way to provide consistent support to a cause, helping the charity plan and sustain its programs more effectively. Plus, spreading out your donation over time can make it easier on your budget while adding up to a useful amount for the charity. 

Think of it as an Afterpay for charities. This large Australian company allows its customers to buy the products or services they want in fashion,automotive, entertainment, &amp; more, and spread payments over time (pay in instalments). Likewise, a subscription lets you have the impact you want, and contribute over time. 

Tap4Change lets you do exactly that: allocate your total monthly budget for charitable causes, create a portfolio of charities you choose to support, and let your donation get split between these non-profit organisations. Follow your impact by watching out for the next update from these charities! 

## **Choosing the Right Donation Platform**
As we mentioned earlier, it’s crucial to make a safe and secure donation. So if you plan on donating through online platforms, here are some tips you can consider:
- **Direct Donations vs. Third-Party Platforms:** Donating directly through a charity’s official website is often a good option. This way, you’re sure your funds go straight to the organisation. 

Unfortunately, out of 60,000 Australian charities, [less than 60%](https://www.acnc.gov.au/tools/reports/australian-charities-report-10th-edition) have a website and only a fraction of them have online donation capabilities. In this case, third-party platforms are very useful, especially if they offer to split donations to multiple causes and charities.

Our platform [Tap4Change](https://www.tap4change.org/) is a good example. We are an Australia-based charity finder dedicated to solving the challenges of giving back by helping individuals like you easily discover and support organisations that align with your values and causes you stand for. It even allows you to search by area.

With Tap4Change, you can allocate your total monthly budget for charitable causes, create a portfolio of charities you choose to support, and let your donations be split among these non-profit organisations. So if you have $50 and want them to go to separate causes and charities, the platform lets you set your budget and spread it among the charities of your choice. 

By building this portfolio of charities, you can easily donate whenever you like, to whoever you like, in any amount of your choice. This way, you can stay in control of your donation budget, while helping the different charities you care about.

- **Secure Websites:** Always look for secure websites when making donations online. A secure site will have "https://" at the beginning of the URL, and you should see a padlock icon in your browser’s address bar. These indicators mean the site uses encryption to protect your data during transmission.

- **Trusted Payment Methods:** Use well-known and trusted payment methods such as credit cards or secure payment services. These options often come with built-in fraud protection and can be tracked more easily if issues arise.

- **Privacy Policies and Data Security:** Before making a donation, review the charity’s privacy policy to understand how your data will be used and protected. A reputable charity will have a clear privacy policy outlining how they handle and secure your personal information.

Typically, Tap4Change [won’t share your data](https://www.tap4change.org/privacy-policy) with third parties unless absolutely necessary, not even to the charities that you support, to ensure that you won’t be receiving unwanted fundraising emails, letters and calls. 

By carefully selecting a secure donation platform and protecting your personal information, you can make your charitable contributions with confidence.

## **What to Expect or Do After Making a Donation?**
Congratulations on your first donation! Most charities will send you a thank-you note or email acknowledging your generosity. This often includes information about the impact of your gift.

You can also ask how your contributions are allocated and request updates on how your donations are making a difference. This engagement can keep you informed about the impact of your support.

Then you can always spread your wings and spread the word! Share your donation experience with friends and family. Encouraging others to support the cause and make a difference.

Lastly, take a moment to reflect on your donation experience. Did the charity meet your expectations? Was the donation process smooth? Who knows? You might find yourself getting involved in other volunteering ideas like spending your time and skills to help others free of cost!

## **Are You Ready to Donate?**
Giving to charity is a powerful way to contribute to the world around you, and as a first-time donor, you’re about to embark on a rewarding journey. 

Stay smart by choosing trustworthy charities (that you know, that are reputable, recommended by others etc) and secure donation methods. After making your donation, celebrate the positive impact of your generosity. 

Engage with the charity to see how your gift is being used, share your experience with others, and reflect on how this act of giving has enriched your life. Who knows? Your first donation could be the start of a lifelong commitment to making the world a better place.
So, take that first step—your kindness can change lives! Here’s a great place to [start](https://www.tap4change.org/)!
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Why Should You Donate?</title>
    <published>2024-10-18T08:41:16+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-18T08:41:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tap4change.org/blog/the-essential-checklist-for-first-time-donors</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tap4change.org/blog/the-essential-checklist-for-first-time-donors"/>
    <content type="html">Have you ever found yourself with a little extra cash at the end of the month, wondering what to do with it? Maybe you’re dreaming about that fancy dinner or a new gadget. But have you ever thought about how much better you might feel by donating that money to a worthy cause?

Research shows that giving can actually boost your happiness more than spending it on yourself. Not only can your contribution help others, but it can also improve your mental wellness. 

So why not start today?

## **The Joy of Giving**
Let’s face it: we all love the feeling of making a difference. Even the smallest donation can lead to significant change. You don’t have to be a millionaire to make an impact. Whether it’s skipping a morning coffee to donate that few dollars or setting aside a little each month, every bit counts. 

Knowing that your contribution is helping someone in need brings a sense of fulfillment that a new gadget just can’t match.

When you find a cause that resonates with you, it’s like hitting the jackpot of happiness. Imagine knowing that your support is making a real difference in the lives of those who need it most. It’s a win-win! So why wait? Dive in and start giving!

## **Benefits of Donating**
Donating offers several benefits for yourself, those around you, and the community. Here’s how giving can make a difference:
1\. **Boosts Your Mood**: Studies show that giving triggers the brain’s reward system, leading to feelings of happiness and satisfaction. It’s true what they say: it feels good to give!

2\. **Creates a Sense of Community**: When you donate, you’re joining a community of like-minded individuals who share your passion for making a difference. This connection can lead to new friendships and a deeper understanding of the issues at hand.

3\. **Promotes Personal Growth**: Giving can open your eyes to the challenges others face, fostering empathy and compassion. This perspective can lead to personal growth and a greater appreciation for what you have.

4\. **Makes a Real Impact**: Your donation helps fund programs and initiatives that support the most vulnerable in society. When you give, you are directly contributing to positive change and the betterment of your community.

5\. T**ax Benefits**: Depending on where you live, donations to registered charities can be tax-deductible (e.g, in Australia and the US). This means that not only are you helping others, but you might also be able to save on your taxes! 

In Australia, donations to charities with [Deductible Gift Recipients (DGR) status](https://www.acnc.gov.au/tools/factsheets/deductible-gift-recipients-dgr-and-acnc) are tax deductible. But of course, the fact that a donation isn’t tax deductible shouldn't stop you from helping a cause that you stand for.

## **Finding Your Cause**
Now that you’re convinced that donating is a good idea, how do you figure out where to send your hard-earned money? With so many nonprofits out there, it can feel overwhelming. But don’t let that paralyze you! Think about what matters most to you.

Ask yourself:
\- What cause are you most passionate about? Is it animal rights, homelessness, or maybe education for underprivileged children or mental health?
\- Do you want to make a local impact, or are you interested in supporting international efforts?
\- What type of organizations do you feel drawn to—big nonprofits or smaller grassroot community groups?

Different charities have different capabilities, and therefore they have different impacts. As a metaphoric example, a smaller grassroot charity can quickly administer first aid, a medium sized charity will provide the crutches, and a large international organisation will help with rehabilitation.

Finding the right match will ensure that your donations bring you joy and create a positive impact in the world. Remember, there are countless charities out there doing incredible work, so you’re sure to find one that aligns with your values.

## **Making a Difference Together**
One of the most beautiful things about donating is that together, we can do so much more than we can alone. Charities have the structure and resources to help those in need on a larger scale. When you donate, you’re joining a community of like-minded individuals who want to see positive change in the world.

It’s easy to think that your individual contribution won’t matter, but that couldn’t be further from the truth. Every donation, no matter how big or small, adds up. Imagine if everyone skipped just one coffee a month and donated that money instead. The impact would be monumental!

And if you’re ever worried about where your money is going, most charities provide annual reports detailing how funds are used. This transparency can give you the reassurance that your donations are making a real difference.

## **How Can Tap4Change Help?**
Ready to make a difference? We’re here to help you every step of the way! Our [online charity platform](https://www.tap4change.org/) is designed to make donating seamless and enjoyable. 

With personalized donation allocation via your “donation portfolio”, you can support multiple causes with a single contribution, ensuring your generosity creates maximum impact.

Let’s come together and create the change we want to see in the world. It all starts with you! Show what you stand for and share it with your mates!


</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
