<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Unlock the Potential of Digital Assets: Insights from Taurus SA</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.taurushq.com/blog/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.taurushq.com%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_selector=.portfolio-card+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.blog-content-info&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date&amp;date_format=d.m.Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_noproxy=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.taurushq.com%2Fblog%2F&amp;url_selector=.portfolio-card+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.blog-content-info&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=.date&amp;date_format=d.m.Y&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_noproxy=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:48+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Taurus Blog - Taurus Launches First Interbank Network for Digital Asset Collaboration</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:10:48+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.taurushq.com/blog/taurus-launches-first-interbank-network-for-digital-asset-collaboration/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.taurushq.com/blog/taurus-launches-first-interbank-network-for-digital-asset-collaboration/"/>
    <author>
      <name>@taurus_hq</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html"> Geneva, 09.04.2025 — Taurus, a leading European provider of digital asset infrastructure for banks, is pleased to announce the launch of Taurus-NETWORKTM (TN), a groundbreaking technology solution connecting Taurus-PROTECT clients to enhance collaboration at a time when financial institutions are accelerating digital asset adoption. By unlocking new use cases such as collateralized lending, radically streamlining costly onchain operational processes, and strengthening regulatory compliance, TN is expected to have a significant market impact, particularly in capital and liquidity management.  Taurus-PROTECT is a secure, institutional-grade custody solution designed to enable banks and financial institutions to safeguard their digital assets while maintaining full sovereignty over their operations. Taurus-NETWORK creates a connected ecosystem of primarily regulated institutions that radically streamlines operations and enhances collaboration between members. Its built-in collateral management system minimizes counterparty risk, making cross-institutional interactions more secure and efficient than other alternatives. Vassili Lavrov, Head of Product Infrastructure, said: “We have been building Taurus-NETWORKTM step by step, and I wanted to thank our engineers for their hard work and our clients for their regular feedback. Network participants retain control of their assets and never rely on Taurus to enter or unwind transactions. Taurus-NETWORKTM creates an ecosystem covering public and permissioned DLTs, as well as all types of assets whether cryptocurrencies, tokenised securities, and digital currencies." Taurus-NETWORKTM ecosystem includes the following benefits for Taurus’ clients:   Access to the largest interbank digital asset network: with a focus on regulated and financial institutions, participants access more than 35 banking institutions (at the time of writing) covering 4 continents and 10 countries, all digital assets ready. TN allows ecosystem participants to select the jurisdictions they want to do business with, offering flexibility and control over their counterparties. This ensures that participants and financial institutions can align their activities with their own specific regulatory requirements and strategic objectives.   Banking-grade collateral management: TN introduces the most advanced collateral management platform in the industry, leveraging Taurus’ roots in banking and feedback from sophisticated financial institutions. As part of TN collateral management platform, participants can pledge funds or assets for instant credit to other participants. Banks can use their balance sheet to participate in syndicated loans originated by other members of the network, secured by the TN collateral management platform. Exchanges can implement seamlessly “off-exchange trading” processes with the counterparty and risk limits of their choice without moving funds from Taurus-PROTECT.   Real-time settlement: TN optimizes the speed of settlement across on-chain and fiat railways while minimizing settlement risks through an advanced orchestration engine.   Embedded compliance: Travel rule compliance and proof of reserves are embedded by design, and TN reduces to zero necessary manual compliance work such as proof of ownership controls or cumbersome Satoshi tests, as they are automatically and cryptographically embedded into the system;   Automation of operations and interactions: TN reduces by &amp;gt;90% the operational burden of transaction management, such as identity management and whitelisting processes. TN allows network participants to have an irrevocable proof of identity as well as exchange and verify digital asset addresses automatically. Instant transfer confirmation is also possible.   New standard in security and counterparty risk management: TN participants interact directly and electronically with each other through their Taurus-PROTECT custody instance, regardless of their set-up (on-premises, hybrid, or SaaS). TN participants can pledge collateral bilaterally without intervention from a third party, including Taurus. This makes TN collateral and liquidity management solutions the gold standard in the industry.   Rapid adoption by industry leaders Taurus-NETWORK launches with the participation of Arab Bank Switzerland, Capital Union Bank, Flowdesk, ISP Group, Misyon Bank, and Swissquote. Additional major financial institutions are expected to join in the first semester of 2025.&amp;nbsp; "Joining Taurus-NETWORK aligns perfectly with our commitment to innovation and operational excellence in the digital asset space. It empowers us to securely collaborate with other leading financial institutions while retaining full control over our operations. Taurus-NETWORK sets a new standard for efficiency and trust in the industry, and we’re excited to be part of it,” said Rani Jabban, Managing Director and ExCo member at Arab Bank Switzerland. “We are excited to combine the capabilities of CUBNET, Taurus-PROTECT and Taurus-NETWORK to deliver a market-leading solution for the seamless settlement of digital assets amongst institutional players,” Patrick Zbinden, CEO at Capital Union Bank, commented. Thomas Jeulin, Head of Sales EMEA of Flowdesk, said: “Joining Taurus-NETWORK is a natural step for us as digital assets and traditional finance continue to converge. Providing liquidity to the largest financial institutions while unlocking new use cases in collateral management and derivatives aligns perfectly with our mission." “As the first neobank of Türkiye, which is among the largest crypto markets in the world, joining Taurus-NETWORK alongside leading global financial institutions is a major step forward for us, expanding our tokenization and custody solutions to global networks through top-tier partners in the ecosystem. We are eager to continue growing together,” said Dr. Önder Halisdemir, CEO of Misyon Bank. “We are pleased to join Taurus-NETWORK. As COO, I recognize the value of technology in enabling collaboration, enhancing competitive advantage, and unlocking new business opportunities for our clients. Taurus-NETWORK fosters seamless interaction among members and builds a trusted ecosystem for digital asset activities, which continue to evolve rapidly and drive sustained growth. Leveraging the latest market innovations is essential for scaling, automating, and optimizing our operations, ensuring long-term resilience and future-proofing our business through technology-enabled strategies,” Nestor Verrier, Chief Operating Officer at Swissquote, commented. Roy Tal, the Chairman of ISP Group, said: “Taurus-NETWORK is addressing one of the biggest challenges in digital asset markets—counterparty risk. We are proud to be part of the network, providing our clients with a seamless, secure, and transparent way to manage their liquidity and collateral.” "Taurus-NETWORK is a pivotal milestone in Taurus' mission to reshape the digital asset industry," said Yann Isola, Head of Product Financial Services. "By bringing together institutions and facilitating secure, efficient, and automated operations, we are unlocking new opportunities for growth and innovation. This is just the beginning as we are planning to release innovative solutions on a regular basis.” The network leverages Taurus' robust relationships with global banks and market makers to create an ecosystem where regulated financial institutions retain control over their assets, while interacting electronically directly with each other. The current announcement highlights some features and participants included at the launch of Taurus-NETWORKTM. More evolutions and solutions will be announced soon.&amp;nbsp; About Taurus&amp;nbsp; Founded in 2018, Taurus is a Switzerland-based financial technology company providing enterprise-grade digital asset infrastructure solutions. It offers products and services for issuing, storing, and trading all types of digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, tokenized assets, NFTs, and digital currencies. Additionally, Taurus operates a marketplace for private assets and tokenized securities and is a securities firm regulated and supervised by FINMA. For more information, visit: https://www.taurushq.com       Taurus News  Technology        Share on          </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Unlock the Potential of Digital Assets: Insights from Taurus SA</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:10:48+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.taurushq.com/blog/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.taurushq.com/blog/"/>
    <author>
      <name>@taurus_hq</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Uncover the potential of digital assets with Taurus insights and blog posts.Could not extract full content, selector may need to be updated.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Taurus Blog - Taurus Recognized as World’s Best Custody Provider by Euromoney</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:10:48+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.taurushq.com/blog/taurus-recognized-as-worlds-best-custody-provider-by-euromoney/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.taurushq.com/blog/taurus-recognized-as-worlds-best-custody-provider-by-euromoney/"/>
    <author>
      <name>@taurus_hq</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html"> 28.03.2025, Geneva — Taurus, a leading digital asset infrastructure provider, has been named World’s Best for Custody Services by Euromoney. This prestigious recognition reflects not only the technical sophistication of Taurus’ solutions but also its strategic role in helping financial institutions integrate digital assets into their operations.&amp;nbsp; Founded in 2018, Taurus delivers the industry’s most comprehensive platform, combining enterprise-grade technology with unmatched regulatory compliance in a single, unified solution. The world’s most stringent financial institutions trust Taurus to securely store, tokenize, issue, and trade digital assets with ease.&amp;nbsp; Taurus’ platform includes:&amp;nbsp;  Taurus-PROTECT: Multi-layered custody solution that supports different storage types (hot, warm, cold) to meet the needs of institutions looking for banking-grade security.&amp;nbsp;   Taurus-CAPITAL: Tokenization solution that allows financial institutions to issue and manage any digital securities&amp;nbsp;   Taurus-EXPLORER: Real-time connectivity to over 25 blockchain protocols, enabling seamless integration across both public and permissioned blockchains.&amp;nbsp;   TDX: Regulated marketplace for tokenized private assets, providing liquidity to previously illiquid markets.&amp;nbsp;  By combining these capabilities in one platform, Taurus makes it easier for institutions to adopt digital assets without compromising security, flexibility, or compliance.&amp;nbsp; “We’re honored to be named 'The World's Best for Custody Services' by Euromoney,” said Lamine Brahimi, co-founder and managing partner at Taurus. “It’s a clear signal that Taurus is setting the standard in institutional digital asset infrastructure and delivering the most complete, future-ready platform on the market.”&amp;nbsp; “This recognition from one of the most respected voices in global banking reinforces our position as a trusted partner for financial institutions worldwide. As digital assets continue to create new opportunities in global finance, we remain dedicated to providing secure, compliant, and innovative custody solutions that enable institutions to participate in this economy."&amp;nbsp; With ten offices across Europe, North America and the Middle East, and more than 30 institutional clients, including State Street, CACEIS, Deutsche Bank, Zand Bank, and Misyon Bank, Taurus has rapidly established itself as the leader in the digital asset space.&amp;nbsp; As demand for secure, regulated access to digital assets increases, Taurus is positioned as a key infrastructure partner for institutional adoption.&amp;nbsp; About Taurus&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Founded in 2018, Taurus is a Switzerland-based financial technology company providing enterprise-grade digital asset infrastructure. It offers services for issuing, storing, and trading all types of digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, tokenized assets, NFTs, and digital currencies. Additionally, Taurus operates a marketplace for private assets and tokenized securities and is a securities firm regulated and supervised by FINMA. For more information, visit https://www.taurushq.com/&amp;nbsp;       Taurus News        Share on          </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
