<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by THE HUB on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40THEHUB_DAO&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*UY7ive_L4TsRHrFsUraQNQ.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*UY7ive_L4TsRHrFsUraQNQ.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40THEHUB_DAO&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:10:59+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">THE HUB for Gaming, Metaverse and Mixed Realities Joins Chainlink BUILD</title>
    <published>2023-09-08T14:02:55+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-09-08T14:02:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/the-hub-for-gaming-metaverse-and-mixed-realities-joins-chainlink-build-67f03cf66ef4?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/the-hub-for-gaming-metaverse-and-mixed-realities-joins-chainlink-build-67f03cf66ef4?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>THE HUB</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We’re excited to announce that THE HUB is officially joining the Chainlink BUILD program. THE HUB is building tools for Gaming, Metaverse and Mixed Realities. This ranges from the Metaverse Explorer — an AI-powered data analytics platform with over 400,000 monthly requests to the go-to builder tool for developers with over 7,000 users to an interoperable 3D avatar generator with NFT ownership and adoption amongst others in esports with partners such as Fitchin an esports platform by Sergio “Kun” Aguero and tier 1 esports teams like Krü, Giants, Furious Gaming and more. Partners and investors include Polygon, PwC, Google Cloud, Detecon, The Sandbox, Brinc, Ocean Protocol and more.As a part of BUILD, THE HUB aims to accelerate ecosystem growth and adoption of our tools by gaining enhanced access to Chainlink’s industry-leading oracle services and technical support, as well as incentivizing greater cryptoeconomic security, in exchange for a commitment to provide network fees and other benefits to the Chainlink community and service providers, including stakers. Furthermore, as THE HUB Founder Nicolas Weber states: “The recently launched CCIP is super interesting for us as it perfectly complements our strategy of chain and world agnostic tooling. We are actively exploring opportunities to integrate this into our product stack. We are excited to shape adoption together with the amazing Chainlink ecosystem!”Written by Cristina Vargas and Nicolas WeberTHE HUB: The Engine of the MetaverseIn the “Information Age”, data is as valuable as oil. It helps users make better decisions, plan long-term, and gain a deep understanding of any topic or subject. However, in the current status of Mixed Realities, data is very siloed and thus adoption is very slow. “The paradox of new technologies is always that the backend needs to become more sophisticated, while the UX is becoming much simpler,” states Nicolas Weber. In order to achieve this, THE HUB is following a two-layered approach: 1) Aggregating data standards within a network and 2) providing the picks and shovels for creators and businesses to invest, build and experience — all in one place and interoperable. Of course, this vision cannot be achieved alone and therefore THE HUB — which is operating as a DAO — teamed up with the top players in web2 and web3 in the spirit of building bridges, not walls. And whether it is called Metaverse, Gaming, Mixed Realities, 3D — internet — at the end we are all describing the same worlds.Initially THE HUB started with the idea of collectively acquiring and populating Metaverse assets. To achieve this mission, the three founders Nicolas Weber, Camilo Echeverri and Youssef Gabsi — who know each other from back in university in Frankfurt, teamed up. However it was quickly evident that there is an omnipresent lack of 1) price transparency, 2) builder standards where each developer was limited to just one world and 3) a lack of tokenization and interoperability of assets. As paradoxical as this sounds, the Metaverse itself still needed to be tokenized. This eventually led to the launch of the three verticals of investing, building and experiencing, whose tools can be checked out here: https://thehubdao.xyz/Fast-forward 2 years, THE HUB is at the forefront of adoption and is working with top companies, universities, institutions and more to make the mission of true adoption a reality.Why We Joined Chainlink BUILDTHE HUB joined BUILD to partner up with the leading oracle and interoperability provider in web3. As part of BUILD, we will receive key benefits, including access to and integration of secure smart contract automation through Chainlink Automation, provably fair randomness for user-facing events through Chainlink VRF, and access to new Chainlink product alpha and beta releases, among other benefits.In exchange for these services, THE HUB will make up to 3% of its native token supply available to Chainlink service providers, including stakers, over time. These mutually aligned economic incentives enable both communities to support one another.“Any Web3 project that wants to provide a seamless and interoperable service to their users gravitates towards Chainlink, and THE HUB is no exception. We look forward to continuing our collaboration together, and we’re very excited to welcome the passionate Chainlink community into THE HUB ecosystem.” — Nicolas Weber, Founder of THE HUBAbout ChainlinkChainlink is the industry-standard Web3 services platform and has enabled trillions of dollars in transaction volume across DeFi, insurance, gaming, NFTs, and other major industries. As the leading decentralized oracle network, Chainlink enables developers to build feature-rich Web3 applications with seamless access to real-world data and off-chain computation across any blockchain and provides global enterprises with a universal gateway to all blockchains.Learn more about Chainlink by visiting chain.link or reading the developer documentation at docs.chain.link. To discuss an integration, reach out to an expert.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Part 2: How THE HUB Excels in Capital Efficiency and Sets New Standards in the Metaverse</title>
    <published>2023-07-05T11:28:39+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-07-05T11:28:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/part-2-how-the-hub-excels-in-capital-efficiency-and-sets-new-standards-in-the-metaverse-703c33949508?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/part-2-how-the-hub-excels-in-capital-efficiency-and-sets-new-standards-in-the-metaverse-703c33949508?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>THE HUB</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In Part 1 of this blog series, we explored the concept of capital efficiency and its significance in the metaverse ecosystem. In this second installment, we’ll take a closer look at how THE HUB is demonstrating exceptional capital efficiency and setting new standards in the metaverse market.Capital Efficiency Strategies of THE HUBTHE HUB employs several strategies to ensure capital efficiency:Leveraging Network Effects: By creating a vibrant and interconnected ecosystem, THE HUB benefits from network effects that drive user engagement and growth. As more users join the platform, the value of the network increases, leading to higher demand for THE HUB’s offerings and greater returns on investment.Diversified Revenue Streams: THE HUB has designed a diverse range of monetization opportunities, including virtual land sales, in-world transactions, and partnerships. This diversification helps THE HUB generate revenue from multiple sources, ensuring financial stability and reducing reliance on external funding.Strategic Partnerships: THE HUB collaborates with industry partners to co-create and enhance the metaverse experience. These partnerships enable THE HUB to access valuable resources and expertise without incurring significant costs, further improving capital efficiency.Continuous Innovation: By staying at the forefront of metaverse technology and innovation, THE HUB maximizes the value of its investments and ensures long-term relevance in the market. This focus on innovation also helps THE HUB attract and retain users, driving further growth and revenue generation.Community-Driven Development: THE HUB’s decentralized structure empowers the community to drive development and decision-making. This approach not only ensures that the platform’s features and services align with user needs but also reduces the burden of development costs, as community members contribute their skills and expertise.Capital Efficiency in Action: THE HUB’s SuccessesTHE HUB’s commitment to capital efficiency is evident in its many successes:Rapid Growth: THE HUB has experienced impressive user growth and engagement, driven by its innovative offerings, diverse revenue streams, and network effects. This rapid growth demonstrates the effectiveness of THE HUB’s capital-efficient strategies.Financial Sustainability: THE HUB’s diversified revenue model and strategic partnerships have contributed to its financial sustainability. This stability reduces the project’s reliance on external funding, ensuring that THE HUB can continue to grow and evolve without sacrificing its vision or independence.Positive User Feedback: THE HUB’s community-driven approach has resulted in overwhelmingly positive feedback from users, validating the project’s focus on capital efficiency and its ability to deliver value to its community.Capital efficiency is a critical factor for investment funds and VCs when evaluating metaverse projects. THE HUB’s exceptional capital efficiency, driven by its diverse revenue streams, strategic partnerships, and commitment to innovation, sets it apart from its competitors and positions it for continued success in the burgeoning metaverse market. By understanding and embracing the principles of capital efficiency, THE HUB is creating a sustainable and thriving platform that delivers value to both its users and investors alike.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Understanding Capital Efficiency in the Metaverse and Why it Matters</title>
    <published>2023-06-22T09:03:25+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-22T09:03:25+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/understanding-capital-efficiency-in-the-metaverse-and-why-it-matters-3d8c32a11e13?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/understanding-capital-efficiency-in-the-metaverse-and-why-it-matters-3d8c32a11e13?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>THE HUB</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">As the metaverse market continues to grow exponentially, investment funds and VCs are constantly on the lookout for projects with high capital efficiency. But what does capital efficiency mean, and why is it essential for metaverse projects? In this two-part blog series, we’ll explore the concept of capital efficiency, its significance in the metaverse ecosystem, and how THE HUB is excelling in this critical area.What is Capital Efficiency?Capital efficiency refers to a company’s ability to generate returns on invested capital while minimizing investment costs. In simpler terms, it’s about getting the most bang for your buck. A capital-efficient company can achieve growth and success with minimal capital investment, reducing the risk for investors and increasing the likelihood of long-term profitability.Why Capital Efficiency Matters in the MetaverseIn the fast-paced and highly competitive world of the metaverse, capital efficiency plays a crucial role for several reasons:Limited Resources: The metaverse market is still in its infancy, with many projects vying for a share of limited investment funds. Capital efficiency enables projects to allocate resources wisely, maximizing returns for investors and ensuring sustainable growth.Rapidly Evolving Market: The metaverse landscape is continually changing, with new technologies and trends emerging at breakneck speed. Capital-efficient projects can adapt and pivot more easily, ensuring they remain competitive and relevant.Risk Mitigation: With numerous unknowns in the metaverse market, capital efficiency helps mitigate risk by ensuring that projects can achieve growth without relying heavily on external funding.Examples of Capital Efficiency in the MetaverseTo better understand capital efficiency in action, let’s examine a few examples:Virtual Land Sales: One of the most lucrative revenue streams in the metaverse is virtual land sales. Capital-efficient projects can generate substantial income from these sales, reinvesting the profits to develop and expand their metaverse offerings.In-World Transactions: As users engage in various activities within the metaverse, in-world transactions generate additional revenue. Capital-efficient projects can capitalize on these transactions by offering attractive and diverse virtual goods, services, and experiences, driving user engagement and monetization.Stay tuned for Part 2 of this blog series, where we’ll dive deep into how THE HUB is achieving capital efficiency and setting new standards in the metaverse market.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">THE HUB’s Vision and Mission: Bridging the Gaps and Driving the Future of the Metaverse</title>
    <published>2023-06-07T12:46:14+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T12:46:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/the-hubs-vision-and-mission-bridging-the-gaps-and-driving-the-future-of-the-metaverse-17a39d157473?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/the-hubs-vision-and-mission-bridging-the-gaps-and-driving-the-future-of-the-metaverse-17a39d157473?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>THE HUB</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In the first part of our blog series, we discussed the current metaverse landscape, highlighting the market standards and gaps that need to be addressed. As investment funds navigate this complex ecosystem, it is essential to identify projects that demonstrate a clear commitment to addressing these gaps and realize their potential. In this second part, we will explore how THE HUB, with its vision and mission, is filling these gaps and positioning itself as a key player in the metaverse ecosystem.THE HUB’s Approach: Addressing the Gaps and Realizing its Vision and MissionFostering Interoperability: THE HUB is committed to promoting interoperable standards and creating a cohesive ecosystem. By collaborating with other metaverse platforms and industry stakeholders, THE HUB aims to enable seamless interactions, improving user experience and driving growth for businesses and investors. This focus on interoperability aligns with the preferences of 68% of metaverse users who desire seamless cross-platform experiences.Ensuring Scalability: THE HUB’s robust and scalable infrastructure is designed to accommodate the increasing demands of the metaverse. By focusing on efficient solutions, THE HUB ensures that it remains well-equipped to support the rapid growth of the digital landscape. With the global metaverse market projected to reach a staggering $800 billion by 2025, scalability will be a critical factor for success in this space.Leveraging AI-Based Analytics: THE HUB’s advanced analytics platform utilizes AI to provide valuable insights to investors and businesses alike. This commitment to data-driven decision-making enables THE HUB to stay ahead of the curve and identify high-potential projects and opportunities within the metaverse. By tapping into the power of AI, THE HUB helps investment funds navigate the complexities of the metaverse market and make informed decisions.Developing Sustainable Monetization Models: THE HUB’s focus on creating sustainable and scalable revenue models ensures the long-term viability of the platform. By offering a diverse range of monetization opportunities, THE HUB caters to the evolving needs of users, businesses, and investors in the metaverse. A recent report suggests that sustainable revenue models will be a key differentiator for metaverse projects, with 60% of investment funds prioritizing projects that demonstrate long-term profitability.Customizability and Personalization: THE HUB recognizes the importance of providing users and businesses with unique and tailored experiences within the metaverse. By offering customizable solutions and catering to the distinct requirements of various stakeholders, THE HUB is well-positioned to capture a significant share of the metaverse market. In a recent survey, 84% of metaverse businesses expressed a preference for platforms that support customization and personalization.Conclusion:THE HUB’s vision and mission demonstrate a clear commitment to addressing the gaps and challenges that currently exist within the metaverse landscape. By focusing on interoperability, scalability, data-driven insights, sustainable monetization models, and customizability, THE HUB is carving out a unique niche within the metaverse ecosystem. As investment funds continue to explore opportunities in this rapidly growing market, THE HUB’s approach and dedication to bridging these gaps make it a compelling choice for those looking to invest in the future of the metaverse.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Understanding the Metaverse Landscape: Market Standards and Emerging Opportunities for Investment…</title>
    <published>2023-05-03T09:01:36+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-03T09:01:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/understanding-the-metaverse-landscape-market-standards-and-emerging-opportunities-for-investment-ab1197223a26?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/understanding-the-metaverse-landscape-market-standards-and-emerging-opportunities-for-investment-ab1197223a26?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>THE HUB</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Understanding the Metaverse Landscape: Market Standards and Emerging Opportunities for Investment FundsThe metaverse, a rapidly evolving digital frontier, has become a hotbed for innovation and investment. In 2021 alone, over $12 billion was invested in metaverse-related projects, reflecting the immense potential of this market. As VCs and other investment funds strive to capitalize on this expanding market, it is crucial to understand the current landscape, identify gaps, and explore potential opportunities. In this first part of our two-part blog series, we delve into the market standards, assess the present scenario of metaverse projects, and examine the emerging opportunities for investment funds.The Current Metaverse Landscape: Market Standards and GapsFragmented Ecosystem: The metaverse is currently a highly fragmented space, with numerous platforms operating independently. A recent report by DappRadar revealed that the top 5 metaverse platforms account for only 40% of the total market capitalization, indicating the lack of interoperability in the space. This disjointed ecosystem creates barriers for users, businesses, and investors. The need for a more cohesive and unified ecosystem is apparent, and investment funds should look for projects that promote interoperability and collaboration.Limited Scalability: Many existing metaverse platforms face scalability issues as they struggle to accommodate the growing number of users, transactions, and digital assets. For instance, during the CryptoKitties craze in 2017, the Ethereum network faced severe congestion, leading to slow transaction times and increased fees. For investment funds, identifying projects with robust and scalable solutions is critical for long-term success.Insufficient Analytics and Data: In a rapidly evolving market, access to accurate and up-to-date information is essential for informed decision-making. However, the metaverse space currently lacks comprehensive analytics and data tools, creating a need for projects that can provide valuable insights to investors and businesses. A recent study found that only 16% of metaverse projects provide adequate analytics and data, demonstrating the significant gap in this area.Inadequate Monetization Models: While the metaverse offers numerous opportunities for revenue generation, many platforms have yet to establish effective monetization models. For example, despite the booming NFT market, which reached a staggering $25 billion in sales in 2021, many platforms struggle to convert this growth into sustainable revenue streams. Investment funds should look for projects that have a sustainable and scalable revenue model, ensuring the long-term viability of their investments.Customizability and Personalization: The metaverse is a diverse and expansive digital world, where users and businesses seek unique experiences tailored to their specific needs. Projects that offer customizable solutions and cater to the distinct requirements of various stakeholders will have a competitive advantage in this market. According to a survey, 72% of metaverse users prefer platforms that provide customization and personalization options.Understanding the current metaverse landscape, market standards, and gaps is crucial for investment funds looking to capitalize on the immense potential of this digital frontier. In the next part of this blog series, we will explore how MGH DAO, with its vision and mission, is filling these gaps and positioning itself as a key player in the metaverse ecosystem.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Multiverse Graffiti Contest</title>
    <published>2023-04-21T10:01:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-04-21T10:01:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/multiverse-graffiti-contest-452d5a9432e8?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@THEHUB_DAO/multiverse-graffiti-contest-452d5a9432e8?source=rss-46b394cdc675------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>THE HUB</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Celebrating Metaverse Adoption: Exploring the Exciting Graffiti Contest at Espacio Creador x METAGAMEHUB DAOGraffiti has long been a vibrant form of self-expression and urban art, and now, it’s making its way into the metaverse! Espacio Creador, a leading creative hub, is hosting an exciting graffiti contest that combines the physical world with virtual reality to celebrate the growing adoption of the metaverse. Set to kick off on Monday, April 17th, and run for one month, this contest promises to be a unique and innovative showcase of artistic talent across multiple platforms.One of the unique aspects of this contest is that participants have the option to create their graffiti art in three different ways:In-person: Create your graffiti artwork using traditional techniques and materials in the physical world.Digital Art: Explore digital creativity by creating your graffiti artwork as a digital piece using various digital art tools and software.Virtual Reality: Unleash your creativity using the Oculus platform at the Espacio Creador office, creating graffiti art in a three-dimensional virtual space.This multi-dimensional approach allows artists to push the boundaries of their creativity and explore new avenues of expression in the ever-evolving world of digital art.The contest is open to artists from all walks of life, whether they are experienced graffiti artists, digital artists, or simply passionate about exploring the intersection of art and technology. Participants can choose their preferred medium and platform, and are encouraged to let their imaginations run wild to create truly unique and captivating graffiti art.One of the highlights of this contest is the opportunity for the three winners to have their artwork displayed in both the real world and the metaverse. The winning graffitis or art pieces will be featured in the gallery of Espacio Creador, a prominent physical art space, as well as in their Decentraland art gallery (coordinates -61,45), where it will be transformed into a virtual NFT that can be bought, sold, and traded among collectors. This unique blend of physical and virtual art showcases the growing adoption of the metaverse as a legitimate and exciting art platform.Here are some ideas for participants to consider as they create their graffiti art for the contest:Blending the physical and virtual worlds: Participants can explore the idea of merging physical graffiti with digital elements, such as incorporating augmented reality (AR) or virtual reality (VR) elements into their artwork. This could create a dynamic and interactive experience for viewers, as they can appreciate the art in both the real world and the metaverse.Metaverse-inspired themes: Participants can draw inspiration from the metaverse itself and create graffiti art that reflects the virtual world, with futuristic and otherworldly elements. This could include depictions of virtual landscapes, avatars, or futuristic cityscapes, showcasing the unique aesthetics and possibilities of the metaverse.Social commentary: Graffiti has a long history of serving as a form of social commentary, and participants can use this contest as an opportunity to explore relevant issues in the context of the metaverse. This could include exploring topics such as identity, privacy, surveillance, and the impact of technology on society, among others.Interactive and immersive experiences: Participants creating graffiti art in the virtual reality platform, Oculus, can take advantage of the immersive nature of VR to create interactive and dynamic experiences for viewers. This could include creating 3D graffiti that viewers can explore and interact with in the virtual environment, creating a unique and engaging experience.In conclusion, the graffiti contest at Espacio Creador is an exciting celebration of metaverse adoption, offering artists a unique opportunity to showcase their talent in a multi-dimensional way. By combining physical graffiti with virtual reality and NFTs.As part of the contest submission, participants are required to create a 30-second video showcasing the process of creating their graffiti or art piece. This video can capture the artist’s creative process, techniques, and inspiration behind the artwork. It adds an interactive element to the contest, allowing participants to share their artistic journey with the audience and provide insights into their creative process. The video requirement adds an exciting dimension to the contest, offering a glimpse into the artistic process and enhancing the overall experience for participants and viewers alike.To participate, the Video has to be submitted to the official Instagram account of Espacio Creador!Don’t miss out on this exciting graffiti contest of Espacio Creador x MGH, where you can explore new horizons of artistic expression in the metaverse. Get ready to unleash your creativity and join the contest to be a part of this cutting-edge artistic journey!</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
