<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by FinTech Cameroon on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@fintechcm?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40fintechcm&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*MK3JvRNYWtd_NCvYkuFxDw.jpeg</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*MK3JvRNYWtd_NCvYkuFxDw.jpeg</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40fintechcm&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:06:56+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Interstellar v4.0 (Voyager Update) is out!</title>
    <published>2019-11-05T16:21:59+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-11-05T16:21:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-v4-0-voyager-update-is-out-8fc09513440e?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-v4-0-voyager-update-is-out-8fc09513440e?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>FinTech Cameroon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">PreludeThe spacecraft, named Voyager 1 and Voyager 2, were launched in September and August of 1977. They were instrumental in accumulating the vast amount of knowledge we have on our solar system which we take for granted today.Even though the Voyager mission was meant to explore our solar system, something groundbreaking happened decades after.Voyager became the first — and indeed the only — mission to take humanity into Interstellar space and became known as the Voyager Interstellar Mission.In August of 2012, 35 years after it was launched, Voyager 1 passed though the heliopause and entered Interstellar space.In December of 2018, Voyager 2 joined its sibling in Interstellar space, around 11 billion miles (18 billion km) from Earth.Stuff like this inspires our team at Interstellar and we see parallels between the Voyager programme and what we constantly try to achieve with our Interstellar app — pushing boundaries and going beyond our comfort zones. We launched the Interstellar app two years ago in October 2017, as a decentralised payment platform, and since then we’ve gone above and beyond our original mission with Proxima Centauri, Sirius, Pathfinder, Vega, and our latest Interstellar v4.0 release, codenamed VOYAGER in honour of the Voyager Interstellar Mission.Press ReleaseToday, we release Interstellar v4.0 (codenamed Voyager) to the general public. The Interstellar app provides a complete digital currency experience for individuals, professionals, organisations and even IoT devices. Using Stellar blockchain technology, Interstellar allows anyone to easily create, send, receive, swap, secure, and trade Digital Currencies and other Tokenised Assets at the speed of light. Available on all major platforms, at home, at work or on the go.According to the CEO, Ernest Mbenkum,“The best way to predict the future is to invent it. Interstellar v4.0 (Voyager update), is our team’s latest effort in building blockchain tools and services for the future where everything will be tokenised not just for humans, but also for IoT devices and AI analytical purposes. We are getting ready for the Fourth Industrial Revolution”According to the CTO, Fritz Ekwoge,“Interstellar v4.0 (Voyager update) is our most ambitious release yet, without sacrificing security, and the decentralised nature of our platform. We are getting closer to one our goals of providing decentralised financial inclusion tools for the underbanked and unbanked. &amp;quot;Other than major UX and performance improvements, Interstellar v4.0 achieved two other major milestones.Firstly, our all new All-Spark is the best new way for Interstellar users to transfer assets between themselves, without the need for trustlines and funded accounts. This is an issue which had long plagued many Stellar users. Secondly, our SEP6/SEP24 integration now empowers Interstellar users to have easier access to even more third party non-Stellar asset gateways (anchors), and allows users to interact with those non-stellar asset gateways without leaving the app!This is all very powerful and liberating stuff, and we are making this major Interstellar update available to the public today.Interstellar v4.0 is immediately available on the web at https://interstellar.exchange. Mobile versions are also available on the Apple iOS and Google Play stores. Windows and Mac desktop app updates will follow shortly.New Features in Interstellar v4.0 (Voyager Update)Interstellar v4.0 (Voyager update) comes with a lot of new features including:New Languages. Our Interstellar app now supports 11 new languages. (Chinese, Russian, Hindi, Spanish, Filipino, Italian, Turkish, Japanese, German, Korean, and Portuguese). Our app has been downloaded and used in 166 different countries, so these translations will help to improve the overall user experience. We now support 14 different languages and more will be added in future.All new All-Spark feature. Any Interstellar wallet owner can now send any non-XLM asset to anyone else on the Interstellar platform even without a trustline. The receiving account doesn’t even need to be funded! As a security measure, both sender and receiver need to sign the generated transaction for the transaction to go through.Extra Security Measures. Wallet owners now need to sign every outbound transaction with their session passwords. Additional security options are available under our settings menu.Most comprehensive SEP6/24 Integration. Wallet owners can now deposit and withdraw any SEP6/24 compliant digital asset without leaving their Interstellar wallet! SEP6 (SEP0006) and SEP24(SEP0024) are Stellar blockchain enhancement proposals to allow deposits and withdrawals of assets from third party anchors (asset providers).Most comprehensive SEP10 Integration. Wallet owners can now sign the necessary transactions needed to grant them access to SEP0010 access restricted tokens. SEP10 (SEP0010) is a Stellar blockchain enhancement proposal to verify ownership of a Stellar account.New Asset Focused Wallet UI/UX. In this brave new world where everything will be tokenised, digital assets are king. That’s why our brand new wallet layout puts emphasis on assets for rapid access to your most used assets. You do not even need a trustline to include any Stellar tokenised asset into your portfolio.New Trader Focused Exchange UI. We revamped our trading UI to make it easier for advanced traders to quickly perform their trades. Just like on other centralised trading platforms. There’s also a new feature that allows you to delete multiple pending orders in a single transaction.Multiple Accounts. Interstellar has always supported multiple wallet accounts. This time around, the app remembers your last used wallet account so that you can quickly access the account even when you log out, and login again.SEP6/SEP24/SEP10SEP6/24We are very pleased with the level of SEP6/24 support we’ve integrated into our Interstellar app. SEP6/24 permits users to deposit and withdraw asset-backed tokens without leaving the wallet!True to our decentralization mantra, any anchor that properly implements SEP6/24 gets to see their anchored assets immediately available for deposits and withdrawals within the Interstellar wallet! No permissions required.See the screenshots below demonstrating deposit and withdrawals options for the BAT asset (from Apay.io’s anchor service), without leaving the Interstellar wallet.apay.io&amp;#39;s BAT SEP6 integration within InterstellarSee screenshots below demonstrating deposit and withdrawal options for the BCH cryptocurrency asset (from Interstellar.exchange&amp;#39;s anchor service), without leaving the Interstellar wallet (duh).BCH SEP6 integration within InterstellarOur Interstellar SEP6/24 integration also means that you can now directly withdraw from Apay.io’s BTC anchor service, and deposit directly into Interstellar.Exchange’s BTC anchor service without leaving the Interstellar app! You can also directly withdraw from Interstellar’s BTC anchor service and deposit directly into NaoBTC’s BTC anchor service! This is a great way to move BTC-backed assets between the main BTC anchors within the Stellar network. Traders who rely on arbitrage may also find this feature quite useful.It should be noted that our new SEP6/24 anchor integration isn’t limited to just crypto-backed assets. Compatible fiat anchors are supported as well! Take a look below at the new Cowrie NGNT (Nigerian Naira) fiat integration within Interstellar.Nigerian Naira SEP6/24 integration within InterstellarSEP6/24 experts will be pleased to know we do accept markdown input for deposit instructions. Markdown support allows anchors to produce more presentable and detailed deposit instructions for their custom assets, including the use of logos for extra brand recognition. Notice how the logos of MTN and Orange get displayed below on the SEP6/24 deposit instructions for Interstellar’s FCFA fiat anchor (XAF). FCFA is the official fiat currency used within 6 countries in Central Africa. MTN and Orange are two very popular mobile money operators in Cameroon.SEP10SEP6/24 is cool and all, but inherently lacks any form of authentication. Anyone can see anyone’s anchor transaction history if they know their Stellar public key. This might be OK for cryptocurrency tokens given their semi-anonymous nature, but might not be OK for fiat assets. Fiat transaction history may expose bank details, location, phone numbers and emails.SEP10 was created to provide some form of authentication between stellar wallets and stellar anchors. Stellar wallet accounts sign a specially crafted transaction to prove to anchors they control the stellar wallet account, and only then does the anchor show the stellar wallet owner sensitive information like their deposit and withdrawal history.We are pleased to announce that Interstellar v4.0 (Voyager update) now supports anchors with SEP10 authentication enabled, which keeps the user’s transaction details private and only visible to the stellar wallet owner.One good example of an SEP10 enabled token on the Stellar network is Interstellar&amp;#39;s XAF token, a fiat asset-backed token which pegs 1:1 to the FCFA fiat currency used in Central Africa. Interstellar&amp;#39;s XAF anchor does not require authentication for deposit and withdrawal instructions… but it does require SEP10 authentication for deposit and withdrawal transaction history.SEP10 in action for Interstellar&amp;#39;s XAF anchor service.The All New All-SparkThere are two major issues new users face when they start using the Stellar network.Funding their accounts.Setting up trustlines for custom assets.We created the All-Spark to help Interstellar users send custom tokens to other Interstellar users, even when the recipient doesn’t have a trustline setup for the custom token being sent. But what about sending custom tokens to unfunded accounts, you may ask? All-Spark covers that too!Interstellar&amp;#39;s All-Spark in action. Sending custom asset to an unfunded account.The way the All-Spark works is quite simple. All-Spark is actually transparently integrated into Interstellar&amp;#39;s new asset send workflow.Send Asset Workflow — Receiving account is funded and trusts custom asset.Sender selects the asset they want to send.Sender enters receiver&amp;#39;s address and amount they wish to send.If the receiver’s wallet address is funded, and has the appropriate trustline set up, the Interstellar app sends funds directly from the sender to the receiver’s wallet account.Send Asset Workflow — Receiving account is not funded, or does not trust custom asset.Sender selects the asset they want to send.Sender enters receiver’s address and amount they wish to send.If the receiver doesn’t yet have a trustline set up for the asset being sent, Interstellar&amp;#39;s All-Spark feature automatically kicks in. Here’s where it gets interesting.If the receiver’s wallet account isn’t yet funded, 1.5 XLM will be deducted from the sender’s account to fund the receiver’s wallet account.If the receiver’s wallet account doesn’t yet have a trustline for the asset you are trying to send, an additional 0.5 XLM will be deducted from the sender’s account to fund the receiver account’s new asset trustline reserve.A specially crafted multisig smart contract is created with the signatories of both sender and receiver accounts.If sender and receiver approve the multisig transaction, the receiver account gets funded (if unfunded). The receiver account also gets a trustline setup for the asset being sent. Finally the receiver account gets the full amount of the custom tokens the sender sent. All-Spark/Interstellar does all these operations for you without needing you to share your secret keys.If either sender or receiver cancel the multisig transaction, the receiver receives nothing. This is useful for end users in that users now get the chance to reject incoming assets they have no interest in keeping.Exchange UpdatesBeing traders ourselves, we constantly look for ways to improve our Interstellar decentralized trading platform.Here’s the new look:Interstellar v4.0: New Trading UI.The new look features the following improvements over previous iterations:Buy and sell forms are now on separate panels. No need to switch tabs to be in either buy or sell mode.The orderbook now appears below the orderform, making interactions between the orderbook and orderform much easier.You can now delete multiple existing offers at once in the same transaction.By default, all trade transactions now need to be signed with a session password. You can disable this extra security feature in the settings.i18nAfter noticing the increased use of our Interstellar wallet in 166 countries and all continents, we believed it was very important we increased our support for more languages to better serve our local communities. Our Interstellar app has been translated into the following languages: Chinese, English, French, German, Hindu, Italian, Indonesian, Japanese, Korean, Pilipino, Portuguese, Russian, Spanish, and Turkish. More will be added in the months ahead.Interstellar is now available in 14 languages.You can get the new Interstellar v4.0 (Voyager) right now at https://interstellar.exchange</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Interstellar v3.6.0 (Vega)</title>
    <published>2019-03-29T21:00:55+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-29T21:00:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-v3-6-0-vega-634c68e6fe71?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-v3-6-0-vega-634c68e6fe71?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>FinTech Cameroon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">A Complete Digital Currency ExperienceAs spring rolls in, FINTECH Ltd will like to announce our newly refreshed website for the Interstellar wallet and decentralized exchange, including the release of Interstellar version 3.6.0 code-named Vega (The brightest star in the constellation of Lyra).The Interstellar.exchange website has been redesigned to provide more helpful information about our app and its unique features for our users both new and old.With over 100,000 user wallets created through the Interstellar web app and over 15,000 mobile and desktop Interstellar app downloads, we will like to thank our users and fans for continuing to support our app since our humble beginnings in September, 2017.We have listened to your feedback, reviews and comments, and we have some new and exciting updates and features to share with you. Without further ado, here’s what we’ve introduced with Interstellar v3.6.0.Showing Desktop Some More LoveEven though our Interstellar wallet has undergone multiple facelifts since September 2017, our engineering and design teams have always focused on a mobile first strategy. This changes today.We are happy to announce that Interstellar v3.6.0 introduces many UI/UX improvements specially targeted for desktop users with larger screens. This is particularly useful for professional users with multiple wallets and trusted assets.Interstellar on large monitors now displays an always-on left side bar for easier access to menu items. It also includes a right side bar with real-time recent wallet history, which allows you to quickly glance through any changes occurring on your wallet.New Interstellar Wallet For Desktop. Now includes a Left Side Menu, and a Recent Activity Panel on the right.Our Dashboard and Wallet History sections have also been redesigned with a new grid layout which takes advantage of desktops with large monitors. You get to see a lot more, and scroll less.New Interstellar Dashboard For Desktop. Overview of all imported wallets.New Interstellar Dashboard For Desktop. Overview of all assets across all imported wallets.Professional Interstellar users with multiple wallets and large screens will love what we’ve done to our new Dashboard and Wallet History sections.Here’s a short video of what to expect:https://medium.com/media/81dd46659f5c7d29c2e7d7ef5bab1fe4/hrefMultisig PlusInterstellar v3.6.0 also introduces the most advanced multiple signatory coordinator on the Stellar blockchain, which is now exclusively available on our app.We call it Multisig Plus.Here’s why Multisig Plus is cool. Traditionally, multiple signers on the Stellar network could only sign one transaction at a time, in the order in which they were submitted. This doesn’t work well in practice especially when the decision makers have different levels of availability, or when transactions require varying levels of time-consuming procedures before they can be signed. With Multisig Plus, decision makers can sign any pending transactions any time, and in any order. They get to have a bird’s-eye view of all pending transactions they have to sign, see who else has accepted or rejected the pending transaction, and get to work on any of the pending transactions in any order as they see fit. This is true freedom and control.According to Fritz Ekwoge, CTO at Fintech Ltd:Multisig Plus required us to go back to the drawing board and challenge everything we knew about multisig coordination on Stellar. Our team devised a novel approach which fits more naturally into the real-life workflow of our users.Multisig Plus on InterstellarMultisig Plus has tremendously helped organizations like GiveDirect, where decision makers are spread across multiple cities and continents.Miscellaneous Updates &amp;amp; Road MapInterstellar v3.6.0 comes bundled with other miscellaneous updates, including:1. Toggle memos to hide transaction memo spams and scams.2. Custom Stellar Network Operation Fees. (You can now choose between Low, Medium and High priority fees).3. A new landing page for our website.4. The new Stellar logo.All these updates are available right now on https://interstellar.exchange. Our desktop web and mobile web versions all run the latest Interstellar v3.6.0.Our Android, iOS, Windows, and Mac apps will be updated in the near future.Talking about the future… What’s next after Interstellar v3.6.0?There are a thousand and one things in our roadmap, but the most relevant item we wish to share right now is GodSpeed.GodSpeedOur team has studied the bidirectional payment designs of the Lighting Network as-well-as the current Starlight implementation for the Stellar blockchain which are both designed to help address some major scalability challenges including security, privacy, instant payments and zero fee transactions.According to Ernest Mbenkum, the CEO of Fintech Ltd:“We have been looking at the Lightning Network from a fresh and slightly different perspective and to this end, our Skunk Works Division at FINTECH Ltd, has been working on what we refer to internally as project “GodSpeed” which we will share with the community in the fall of 2019.”Image Source: https://www.behance.net/SpencerS95Stay tuned. Even better, follow us on twitter or join our telegram group to stay up to date.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Interstellar.Exchange releases a Stellar Wallet and Decentralized Exchange UI on the iOS AppStore.</title>
    <published>2019-02-01T18:35:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-01T18:35:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-exchange-releases-a-stellar-wallet-and-decentralized-exchange-ui-on-the-ios-appstore-eb4abafc0f8f?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-exchange-releases-a-stellar-wallet-and-decentralized-exchange-ui-on-the-ios-appstore-eb4abafc0f8f?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>FinTech Cameroon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Here at Fintech Ltd, we are pleased to officially announce the release of our award-winning and popular Interstellar.Exchange Stellar wallet and decentralized exchange UI on the iOS AppStore. The app was released on the iOS AppStore on Thursday, January 17, 2019. This means our Interstellar wallet is now arguably the most complete Stellar wallet and decentralized exchange experience on the iOS AppStore. You can download Interstellar for iOS here.Why this release matters to you, the iOS Stellar user.iOS users have always been able to access our Interstellar wallet through https://interstellar.exchange on any iOS browser. However, this was not an optimal experience for many of our iOS users. Using the browser to access our Stellar wallet and exchange UI meant slower startup times and jumping through a lot of hoops to use our app while offline. Using mobile browsers also meant using less available screen space.The iOS app version of Interstellar.Exchange loads faster than the web version, and can also be easily used offline to view previous snapshots of asset balances or SDEX markets. The iOS app version of Interstellar.Exchange also maximizes screen space on iPhones, better than on mobile browsers.While there are iOS users who will always prefer a mobile web experience over an app experience, it was important to give users a choice, and discover for themselves what works best for them.Below, we’ll list a fraction of the reasons why Interstellar for iOS is the most complete Stellar experience on the iOS AppStore.A complete Stellar experience on the iOS AppStore.Our Interstellar platform offers users both a complete Stellar wallet, and a complete Stellar decentralized exchange UI.A Complete Stellar Wallet on the iOS AppStoreAs a Stellar wallet, users of the Interstellar iOS app can expect the following benefits:Support for multiple accounts.Support for any stellar asset.Fiat price estimates for any stellar asset on the SDEX.Private keys are stored locally on your device, securely encrypted with a password of your choice.Fund accounts with BTC, ETH, LTC, and XRP.Integrated UI for the deposit and withdrawal of BTC, ETH, LTC and XRP, including some fiat assets like WSD and XAF.Support for N/M multisig setups for extra security.Light/Dark themes.Notification sounds.Swap from one asset to any other asset.One click setup for inflation destinations.Merge accounts.Support for Stellar Federation addresses (e.g. lambo*interstellar.exchange).Automatic checks for missing memos when sending XLM to popular exchanges like Binance.Dashboard overview for all of your accounts and asset balances.… and many other essential Stellar wallet features.A Complete Stellar SDEX UI on the iOS AppStoreAs a Stellar SDEX UI, our Interstellar iOS offers users the following benefits:Markets overview which can be sorted by price, volume or %price difference. This also includes non-XLM markets.Semi-advanced market search features where you can search by asset code (btc), market (xlmusd), by asset name (bitcoin), or even by anchor (apay).Trade between any two Stellar tokens (even between any two non-XLM tokens).Standard trading buy and sell forms.Daily and hourly candlesticks.Orderbooks.Wallet trading history.Market trading history.Candlesticks, RSI charts and MACD charts24hr Open, High, Low, Close data... and a lot more features you’ll discover once you use the app.Not a trader? Not a problem.With such a full-featured trading UI, one would assume only power users would use Interstellar. Our Interstellar wallet enables novices too to join the fun of trading. If you are already very comfortable with trading UIs and terminology, you’ll find yourself at home on our iOS Stellar Decentralized Exchange UI. That said, traditional trading UIs can be very intimidating for first time users. Also, some users just want to swap tokens using the best rates and routes available. That’s why we launched our Stellar Swap feature. You can read more about our dummy-proof stellar asset swap feature in our previous blog post.Enjoy Interstellar for iOSFollow us on Twitter at: https://twitter.com/interstellardexJoin our Keybase group at: https://keybase.io/team/interstellarJoin our Telegram group at: https://t.me/joinchat/FL6DLBBSUA0izq32wWPBQw</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Interstellar v3.5 (PathFinder) Update.</title>
    <published>2018-12-29T23:16:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-29T23:16:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-v3-5-pathfinder-update-9268d40c7027?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-v3-5-pathfinder-update-9268d40c7027?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>FinTech Cameroon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">2018 has been a great year for us here at Fintech Ltd. Our Stellar wallet and decentralized exchange frontend won the 5th Stellar Build Challenge earlier this year; we integrated BTC, LTC, ETH, XRP anchors using our Warp Drive Technology and we were also the first to integrate fully backed USD, Naira and XAF fiat anchors on the Stellar blockchain. We were also nominated for best Digital Innovation in Africa at the 2018 Africa Excellence awards, and we were also finalists for Best Blockchain Technology in Africa. Our Interstellar app has become more popular and useful to many novice and power users who care about the Stellar ecosystem as a whole. The continuous support we’ve received from the Stellar community has pushed us to continue working even harder to improve our product. That’s why we are honored to announce the release of Interstellar version 3.5, codenamed PathFinder.A Little Bit Of HistoryBut first… a bit of “stellar” exploration history. On December 4, 1996 NASA launched the Mars Pathfinder aboard a Delta II booster, which landed on July 4, 1997 on Mars’s Ares Vallis, in a region called Chryse Planitia. It carried a lightweight robotic Mars rover named Sojourner, which became the first rover to operate outside the Earth–Moon system.In addition to scientific objectives, the Mars Pathfinder mission was also a “proof-of-concept” for various technologies, such as airbag-mediated touchdown and automated obstacle avoidance.Now, coming back to earth, our dev team in Cameroon that brought you Interstellar.Exchange continues to “launch” new features in order to evolve the Stellar ecosystem. Like the Mars Pathfinder we continue to push beyond the boundaries of what is possible within the Stellar blockchain technology stack by releasing new “proof-of-concept” ideas with each update to Interstellar.New Stellar Asset Swaps: Powered by PathFinderWith Interstellar v3.5, we took our most unique feature, the crypto asset swap, and transformed it from something good to something insanely great. It now allows anyone to swap between any two crypto assets on the SDEX (Stellar Decentralized Exchange), even without a direct market between those two crypto assets. We achieve this feat by FINDING the best PATH between any two assets and use only the best path to swap one crypto asset for another. Hence the internal codename: PathFinder.Our primary motivation for this PathFinder update was to address some shortcomings that our previous crypto asset swap feature had. One of the flaws our previous model had was that it only handled crypto asset swaps for the absolute best current offers on the SDEX without considering liquidity and depth of the orderbook. It was also limited to direct markets between any two crypto assets, i.e. you couldn’t swap from Interstellar’s BTC to Tempo’s EUR on the SDEX because there wasn’t any direct market between both crypto assets. Users who also used our advanced multisig feature experienced difficulties making swaps work for them because by the time all the signers signed the crypto asset swap transaction, the orderbook would most likely have already changed, transforming their market order into a limit order. This wasn’t a good user experience. Our new crypto asset swap feature solves all the above-mentioned issues beautifully, by finding the best path between any two crypto assets in real time.As a recap, our new PathFinder swap feature allows you to swap one crypto asset for another, even when a direct market between both coins doesn’t exist, i.e. to swap from BTC to ETH, PathFinder might swap from BTC to XLM first, and then from XLM to ETH. It does this automatically. How cool is that? Even if a direct market existed between BTC to ETH, PathFinder might still go from BTC through XLM to ETH in a scenario where there isn’t enough liquidity for your swap from BTC to ETH, or if the spread in the direct BTC to ETH market is too high. The best part is, we didn’t hardcode Stellar lumens (XLM) to always be used as fallback in case there isn’t any direct market. The PathFinder works in real time to always find the best path in the SDEX from one crypto asset to another. That’s why at the time of writing this piece, the most profitable way to swap 1000 XLM for EUR, is to first swap 1000 XLM to WSD, and then swap the WSD to EUR.According to Fintech Ltd’s CEO, Ernest Mbenkum:Fintech Ltd’s new PathFinder swap feature will make trading on the Stellar SDEX a lot easier for novices.*We at Fintech Ltd, loved the way the PathFinder crypto asset swap feature worked so much that we decided to build its own dedicated website. You can check it out at swap.st. The most integrated way to use swap, however, is through our Interstellar app. Nonetheless, https://swap.st allows you to use our new PathFinder Swap feature via any Stellar wallet of your choice.But wait!The PathFinder isn’t the only feature we launched in Interstellar v3.5. We improved our wallet UX, our market views, our trading views and we also have an iOS beta version, waiting to be approved by Apple.Stellar Wallet UpdatesOur wallet dashboard UI now has improved support for multiple accounts. Accounts are now listed in alphabetical order for easier access. You can also see which accounts lack inflation destinations directly in our new dashboard, and with a click, you can set it to the lumenauts inflation pool. Our new wallet dashboard also includes a fiat approximation for your current account balance in various currencies.Another important change we added to our wallet UI was a new settings page. The new settings page now allows you to add/remove trustlines, switch themes from dark to light (or vice versa), change your preferred fiat currency, and many other settings.Finally we are super excited to share with you our new method for selecting assets. You can search assets by name, code, url of the issuer, and sometimes, even the currency the asset represents.SDEX Frontend UpdatesWe also significantly improved the exchange side of our Interstellar app. We now have a new markets view with the ability to sort by volume, and percentage price change. Sorting via any criteria was something we initially objected to in a decentralized exchange since it gives scammers an excuse to game the system to rank higher. We’ve mitigated this risk slightly by having our own list of recommended markets to trade on, in the SDEX. Novices are encouraged to only trade our picks. Experts can still trade any assets they want.One of the coolest things we’ve included on our SDEX frontend is a semi-advanced search engine. With so many trading pairs on the SDEX, there had to be a better way to find what you want. You can now search for a specific market by simply typing the base and quote currencies (e.g. XLM/BTC or XLMUSD), you can search for a specific anchor (e.g. interstellar or apay), and in some cases, you can search by the name of the coin (e.g. Bitcoin).Finally, our charts were taking some time to load due to the higher amount of traffic we were getting. We fixed our slow loading candlestick charts with this new Interstellar v3.5 update.According to Fintech Ltd’s CTO, Fritz Ekwoge:Here at Fintech Ltd, we’ve always believed the SDEX will be used beyond XLM trading pairs. As an example, it is very foreseeable that major FOREX markets will be traded on the SDEX. Our goal is to make it easy and transparent for both XLM and non-XLM markets to trade on the SDEX. Our latest update, Interstellar v3.5, drives us closer to our goal of building an SDEX, not just an XLMDEX.This and countless mini bug fixes and UX improvements are why we are happy we could provide this update to you, Stellar fans, before the end of 2018. Enjoy, and send us feedback at interstellar@fintech.cm.Wishing you all a happy new year.PS: This update is immediately available at https://interstellar.exchange (for mainnet), and https://testnet.interstellar.exchange (for testnet)If you are already an android user, please subscribe to our beta android app, which already has this update.Desktop versions (Mac, Linux and Windows) for Interstellar v3.5 will be available soon. You can still download previous versions on our homepage (https://interstellar.exchange).If you wish to join our iOS beta, please use the following link: https://testflight.apple.com/join/sblcJ5sC.Footnotes* Note that our PathFinder technology has nothing to do with Atomic Swaps and it is not decentralized. You simply send the crypto asset you want to swap to our PathFinder service, and then it looks for the best path with the most liquidity and smallest spread, converts it for you to your desired crypto asset, and sends the crypto asset back to you. Making this work in a decentralized way would involve a lot more hurdles for the end user than necessary. If you want to go full decentralized, please use the trading UI within Interstellar.exchange. That works 100% decentralized. Our PathFinder crypto asset swap is meant to be a more approachable alternative for users who are intimidated by complexity of traditional trading user interfaces.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing the Interstellar v3.0 update codenamed Sirius. Yes, seriously.</title>
    <published>2018-09-04T21:27:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-09-04T21:27:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@fintechcm/introducing-the-interstellar-v3-0-update-codenamed-sirius-yes-seriously-50816646f68a?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@fintechcm/introducing-the-interstellar-v3-0-update-codenamed-sirius-yes-seriously-50816646f68a?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>FinTech Cameroon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Sirius is a star system and the brightest star in the Earth’s night sky with a visual apparent magnitude of −1.46.On a more “Sirius” note, we at Fintech Ltd, believe that the Stellar Decentralized Exchange (SDEX) is too powerful a beast to be tamed. If everyone is busy building UI/UX tools for newbies, who will build tools for the pros and the wild ones?Fintech Ltd is proud to announce the release of Interstellar v3.0, the most powerful and untamed SDEX frontend out there.Although we launched Interstellar 2.0 (Proxima Centauri) just a few months ago, this new major update is so cool and important that we resisted the urge to tag it v2.5 (Tau Ceti) and decided to tag it Interstellar v3.0 (Sirius), because it’s our most brilliant release yet.With the introduction of KYC, fiat anchors and our advanced SDEX frontend UI, we hope you’ll enjoy this new update.Introducing Interstellar KYCHere at Fintech Ltd, we believe a lot in the use cases of blockchain technology that go beyond cryptocurrencies, and one very important use case of blockchain technology is asset tokenization.Whether we like it or not, one of the important requirements and white elephants in the room for most asset backed tokens (ABT) is regulation, and when you talk about regulation, you can’t leave out KYC (Know Your Customer) and AML (Anti-Money Laundering).According to the CEO of Fintech Ltd, Mr. Ernest Mbenkum:When ABTs become ubiquitous and they will, we are going to have a very serious issue of KYC fatigue because users will be required to submit the same KYC info and documents across different companies, financial institutions, governments and jurisdictions.Wouldn’t it be great if you could have a secure place to store all your KYC data and grant or revoke access to your KYC info for each ABT on a need to know basis and on demand?That’s exactly what we did with Interstellar. An in-built KYC platform built with Stellar technology where you can securely store all of your KYC info and related documents.Your KYC documents are encrypted locally on your device using your Stellar public key and can ONLY be accessed on your local devices via Interstellar using your Stellar private key.Even though your KYC data is encrypted locally on your browser, we also store your encrypted data on our remote servers for backup. This is mainly for your convenience in case your device gets stolen, or you need to sync across multiple devices. Your encrypted data isn’t at risk on our servers because we do not know your private key(s).The best part about our KYC implementation is that you get to pick and choose what you share with third parties like an à la carte menu. You will be able to see the specific data a third party is requesting from you, and only you have the power to share that specific info with the third party. If the third party only needs your email address and not your phone number, you will have the possibility to only share your email and exclude your phone number or other info.KYC management is so important because we know it will be required in the most popular asset backed tokens category i.e. tokens tethered to fiat. Let’s call them fiat anchors for now.Introducing Fiat AnchorsCrypto to crypto trading is cool. But do you know what’s even cooler? Fiat to crypto, and we’ve made it super easy to do just that within the Interstellar app.Historically, Interstellar was only focused on anchoring other cryptocurrencies. We successfully anchored BTC, ETH, LTC and even XRP. Our deposit/withdrawal experience has always been so cool because you could deposit and withdraw any of our anchored crypto-currencies without leaving the app or relying on third parties. Interstellar has helped thousands of users with their crypto to crypto transfers. Coincidentally, we received a 5-star review from one of our fans on Google Play just as we were writing this blog post. Screenshot below:In April 2018 we successfully integrated our very first fiat anchor, the NGNT token from Cowrie, which is pegged 1–1 to the Nigerian Naira. It had the same seamless experience where users could trade Naira fiat to crypto instantly, without leaving the Interstellar app.We are now super excited to announce the integration of four new fiat currencies with the Interstellar platform. The first three fiat currencies are USD, GBP and EUR, anchored by The White Company . The White Company offers a stable, transparent, and secure ecosystem for cryptocurrency asset management, payments and enables consumers and companies, alike, to harness the many benefits of digital currency without any of the risk, expense or market volatility.You can now prepare your KYC info, deposit, withdraw and trade USD, GBP, and EUR without leaving the Interstellar app.   The following three tokens from White Standard are already integrated into Interstellar:WSD (pegged 1–1 to the USD),WSP (pegged 1–1 to the British Pound) andWSE (pegged 1–1 to the Euro).The fourth fiat currency integration we are excited to announce is the XAF token, anchored by Fintech Ltd, which is pegged 1–1 to the Central African CFA Franc (XAF) which is the official currency of six independent states in Central Africa or CEMAC region. The Bank of Central African States (BEAC) manages and issues the currency. Members of the Central African currency union, known as the Economic and Monetary Union of Central Africa include Cameroon, Central African Republic, Chad, Republic of the Congo, Equatorial Guinea, and Gabon. CFA stands for “Communauté Financière d’Afrique,” which translates to the African Financial Community in English.Selected users can now deposit and withdraw their XAF tokens using mobile money in Cameroon. More on this in a separate blog post.We believe the introduction of fiat anchors will increase liquidity in the SDEX from institutional investors. These investors will want to trade their fiat for crypto, Stellar backed ICOs or maybe just plain FOREX. Whatever the case, our trading UI/UX had to be useful enough for these professional traders. We needed to step up our game.Introducing The New Interstellar SDEX UI for the pros.Before talking about the new features in our latest SDEX frontend, let’s get something out of the way quickly.We’ve built an SDEX, not an XLMDEXThere’s a big difference between Stellar the blockchain technology, and Stellar Lumens (XLM) the cryptocurrency. If the SDEX was only meant to trade XLM, it would be called XLMDEX, not SDEX. Many of the changes we’ve implemented on our new SDEX frontend have been to emphasize that the SDEX can be used beyond XLM trading pairs.Let’s start with our market overview feature. It is powerful. We show you all popular trading pairs in the past 24 hours, with 24hour volume and 24hr price change percentages. We didn’t want to dumb down concepts like base and counter currencies which we believe any entry level trader should know about. You will even see popular trading pairs like BTC/CNY, because we believe the SDEX is a crypto and asset backed token exchange, not just an XLM exchange.We also included an intelligent coin search feature so you can now search for full coin names, or just the asset code name. You can even search all assets from any anchor (Try it. Search for apay).To avoid constantly searching for the same pairs while trading, the new Interstellar market overview panel allows you to star/tag a trading pair for easier access next time.Finally, we decided to add more advanced trading charts and features. We included EMA12 and EMA26 indicators on our candlesticks and we also added separate RSI and MACD charts for the more serious traders amongst us. Other charts are in the pipeline like Bollinger Bands.According to the CTO of Fintech Ltd, Mr. Fritz Ekwoge,The Interstellar 3.0 Sirius update is available right now on all modern browsers at https://interstellar.exchange. We will soon release this important update on all other major mobile and desktop platforms.Expect more from us soon!About FinTech LtdFounded in March 2017, FinTech Ltd is a Cameroon-based technology company that develops innovative Blockchain Applications for the global banking and financial services sector. With our extensive experience in cryptocurrency development and a highly experienced team of Blockchain Developers, we aim to deliver the best Blockchain solutions at affordable market rates. For more, visit www.fintech.cm.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">GiveDirect chooses the Interstellar Stellar wallet for its Global Direct Charity Programme</title>
    <published>2018-06-26T12:53:19+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-26T12:53:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@fintechcm/givedirect-chooses-the-interstellar-stellar-wallet-for-its-global-direct-charity-programme-f00115e08613?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@fintechcm/givedirect-chooses-the-interstellar-stellar-wallet-for-its-global-direct-charity-programme-f00115e08613?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>FinTech Cameroon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Fintech Ltd announces today its popular Stellar wallet and decentralized exchange, Interstellar, has been selected by GiveDirect as its goto blockchain platform for transparent, secure charitable donations.Total giving to charitable organizations was $410.02 billion in 2017 (2.1% of GDP). This is an increase of 5.2% in current dollars and 3.0% in inflation-adjusted dollars from 2016. As in previous years, the majority of that giving came from individuals. Specifically, individuals gave $286.65 billion, accounting for 70% of all giving and representing a 3.0% increase over 2016.GiveDirect, a global charity project, holds the vision of eradicating extreme poverty worldwide. Set up in 2017, GiveDirect is an innovative charity that uses blockchain technology to solve the number one issue plaguing all charities: transparency. In 2017, after a year piloting their blockchain charity solution in Ghana, it became apparent to GiveDirect that they needed a faster, more scalable blockchain solution, with better tools.Early 2018, GiveDirect switched from its previous blockchain solution to the Stellar platform. GiveDirect chose Stellar principally because of Stellar’s speed, multi-asset paradigm, decentralized exchange, multi-sig, and vibrant ecosystem of tools built on top of Stellar. In particular, their move to Stellar was cemented with the discovery of the Interstellar. Interstellar is a Stellar wallet and decentralized exchange, which takes most of what Stellar has to offer and packages it into one neat coherent user-experience. The ready-made Interstellar platform from Fintech Ltd freed GiveDirect from re-inventing the wheel, and instead allowed GiveDirect’s team to focus on their own tech, notably, an NFC wrist-band to make storing crypto-currencies very painless for their target audience.According to GiveDirect’s CEO, Kevin Colussi,Interstellar cemented our choice of Stellar. Particularly, we loved the way Interstellar implemented Stellar’s multi-sig (multiple signatures), which was very important to me as a CEO to reduce the risk of fraud, misuse of funds and to ensure continuity. Secondly, we loved the way Interstellar made it very easy for us to accept multiple crypto-currencies, and exchange them all to Stellar Lumens within the Stellar Decentralized Exchange (SDEX). Our previous blockchain solution only accepted a single cryptocurrency for donations, which limited the amount of donations we could receive. Finally, Fintech Ltd’s support team has been excellent, even going out of their way to provide us with custom code to ease our work. We’ve already successfully rolled-out Phase One of our direct charity giving programme in Ghana using cryptocurrencies and blockchain technology. We plan to expand soon in other regions of the world which are experiencing extreme poverty.According to GiveDirect’s champion in Ghana,We love how Interstellar was built to be mobile first. Here in Ghana, this is a life-saver. The ease of use of Interstellar, coupled with our dead-simple NFC enabled wrist-bands, has made managing charitable donations a lot less stressful, and fully transparent.According to Fintech’s CEO, Mr Ernest Mbenkum,When we learned about GiveDirect, and what they were trying to do, we jumped right in to provide a helping hand. Families living in extreme poverty world-wide deserve better, and if our tech can help them live a more comfortable life, we won’t hesitate to provide assistance. We view technology as a means to end, and not an end goal by itself. And one of the worthy end goals technology can help with is the complete eradication of extreme poverty world-wide.According to Fintech’s CTO, Fritz Ekwoge,It’s always very interesting to see practical life-saving use cases for blockchain, especially using tech we built.To get more info on how Interstellar is being used at GiveDirect, check out the following blog post from GiveDirect: https://givedirect.io/2018/05/19/interstellar-wallet-brings-security-and-ease-to-givedirect/For more information on Fintech Ltd and its blockchain solutions, please visit the links below:Website: www.fintech.cmEmail: info@fintech.cmTwitter: https://twitter.com/fintechcmLinkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/company/fintechcm/For more information on GiveDirect, please visit the links below:Website: https://givedirect.io/Email:info@givedirect.io</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Interstellar and Cowrie Announce Partnership on Naira-Crypto Decentralized Exchange.</title>
    <published>2018-06-14T01:21:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-14T01:21:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-and-cowrie-announce-partnership-on-naira-crypto-decentralized-exchange-2685f44307fb?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@fintechcm/interstellar-and-cowrie-announce-partnership-on-naira-crypto-decentralized-exchange-2685f44307fb?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>FinTech Cameroon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Fintech Ltd (creators of the popular Interstellar wallet and decentralized exchange), and Cowrie Integrated Systems Limited (a Nigerian based fiat to crypto gateway), today announce a new streamlined Naira to Crypto trading experience.Cowrie Integrated Systems Limited is an NCC (Nigerian Communications Commission) licensed VAS (Value Added Service) provider. Cowrie launched NGNT earlier in the first quarter of 2018 as an asset backed digital token built on the Stellar decentralized exchange. The NGNT Stellar token is pegged to the Nigerian Naira (NGN) on a 1:1 ratio and it digitizes the Naira giving it the benefits of a decentralized token and traditional fiat.Fintech Limited launched Interstellar in the last quarter of 2017 as a one-stop secure crypto wallet and decentralized exchange. Amongst other features, Interstellar enabled users to securely deposit, withdraw and trade Bitcoin, Stellar Lumens, Litecoin, Ethereum and Ripple. The Naira backed NGNT token, from Cowrie, is the first fiat gateway integrated directly into the Interstellar wallet and decentralized exchange. Nigerians now have an easy to use user experience to buy and sell cryptocurrencies in exchange for Naira instantly, straight to and from one’s bank account.Nigeria is a middle-income, mixed economy and emerging market, with expanding manufacturing, financial, service, communications, technology and entertainment sectors. Nigeria is ranked as the 30th-largest economy in the world in terms of nominal GDP, and the 23rd-largest in terms of purchasing power parity. It is the largest economy in Africa; its re-emergent manufacturing sector became the largest on the continent in 2013, and it produces a large proportion of goods and services for the West African subcontinent.In recent years, Nigerian youth have embraced the growing world of crypto, despite the Nigerian government’s hesitation to fully embrace cryptocurrencies. According to multiple sources, Nigerian youths are trading more than 4.8 Million US Dollars in bitcoin every week! To encourage even more Nigerian youths to participate in the blockchain revolution, Fintech LTD has performed stellar lumen airdrops to hundreds Nigerian teens.Interstellar has always provided instant, near feeless transactions for all. Now this process is easier for everyone to embrace crypto, opening the market to two hundred million new users.Naira Deposit And Deposit on the Interstellar Decentralized ExchangeAccording to Fintech Ltd’s CEO, Mr. Ernest Mbenkum:“Integrating the NGNT token inside our Interstellar exchange was simply responding to increasing demand from Nigerians using our popular Interstellar platform. We are happy to help introduce millions of Nigerian to the beautiful world of cryptocurrency and blockchains; introducing them to a world that could change the Nigerian economy forever”.According to Fintech Ltd’s CTO, Mr. Fritz Ekwoge:“Interstellar was built from day one to be mobile-first and offline-first, which is a huge deal in Nigeria and neighboring African countries. We are happy to be pioneers in this space.”According to Ladi Okorodudu, Operations Director at Cowrie Integrated Systems Limited:“We selected Interstellar because of the quality and intuitiveness of their wallet and decentralized exchange. The integration happened smoothly between both teams and we are happy with the outcome thus far. This is one step forward in our goal to radically change the way Nigerians trade cryptocurrencies.”For more information on Fintech Ltd and its blockchain solutions, please visit the links belowWebsite: www.fintech.cm Email: info@fintech.cm Twitter: https://twitter.com/fintechcmLinkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/company/fintechcm/For more information on Cowrie Integrated Systems Limited, please visit the links below: Website: http://cowriesys.azurewebsites.net/ Email:info@cowriesys.com</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing Interstellar v2.0 (Proxima Centauri Update); re-inventing the ecosystem.</title>
    <published>2018-05-27T19:42:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-27T19:42:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@fintechcm/introducing-interstellar-v2-0-proxima-centauri-update-re-inventing-the-ecosystem-a17efeecf5a3?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@fintechcm/introducing-interstellar-v2-0-proxima-centauri-update-re-inventing-the-ecosystem-a17efeecf5a3?source=rss-aba414eb2e6e------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>FinTech Cameroon</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Crypto’s fastest and most reliable decentralized wallet and exchange just got better. For the past few months, Fintech Ltd, the team behind Interstellar, has been hard at work creating its largest ever update to the popular crypto platform. Interstellar v2.0 introduces new features our users will love, including semi-automatic asset/token verification, price conversions for any token into all the major fiat currencies in the world, and a whole new set of desktop applications for increased security of a user’s precious assets.What is Interstellar?Interstellar is a fast secure crypto wallet and decentralized exchange, powered by the Stellar network. Users can directly deposit, withdraw and trade Stellar Lumens (XLM), Ripple (XRP), Bitcoin (BTC), Ethereum (ETH), and Litecoin (LTC). Users can also send, receive or trade any other Stellar based token including Mobius (MOBI), Smartlands (SLT), SureRemit (RMT), Tempo (EURT).Interstellar takes security very seriously by never storing secret keys on any server. Instead keys are stored locally, encrypted with a password only known to the user. Interstellar now also includes advanced security features like multisig support and support for ledger hardware wallets.For power users, Interstellar also makes it super easy to work with multiple accounts in the same session.What’s new in Interstellar v2.0 (Proxima Centauri Update)?Desktop AppsFintech Ltd announced Interstellar for Android a few months ago with a lot of positive reviews and feedback. Today, Fintech Ltd is pleased to introduce Interstellar’s new set of desktop apps. Users can now download and use Interstellar for Windows Desktop, Interstellar For Mac OSX, and an HTLM5 version of Interstellar. Interstellar for Android and desktop were designed from day one to be the fastest, most secure, and most reliable way to access the Stellar network to date.  Even though users can access Interstellar from any modern browser on any operating system, using the android and desktop apps gives users better protection against man-in-the-middle DNS attacks. The desktop and android versions of Interstellar also makes the Interstellar wallet more decentralized and less reliant on Interstellar’s web servers running 24/7. The flagship of the Proxima Centauri Update, our new desktop program allows users to access our decentralized exchange faster than ever before.Asset VerificationInterstellar provides one of the finest UI and full access to the Stellar Decentralized Exchange. Fintech Ltd is pleased to introduce Interstellar’s new verification system for coins and tokens on the Stellar decentralized exchange. The main entry point into the Interstellar decentralized exchange experience is a list of manually curated trusted assets, which protects users from fraudulent and predatory scams common on other decentralized exchanges. While users can still trade the full spectrum of coins and tokens that the Stellar network has to offer (via our search feature), assets on the Interstellar recommended list are guaranteed to be entirely safe from fraud. Curated by experts and always updated, the Interstellar curated token list serves to help new users stay safe when trading, as well as lowering the level of effort for all users, experienced or not.Automatic Price ConversionsFintech is pleased to announce its Interstellar v2.0 (Proxima Centauri update) comes with automatic price conversion to your choice of fiat or crypto. The most interesting thing to note about this feature is that it works on any Stellar based token. This feature is perfect for both high sum investors and casual users alike, providing an instant summary of your holdings into a familiar, intuitive value. With the introduction of this feature, Interstellar users will never have to leave the app to figure out a token’s price again!Expect more updates soon.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
