<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Blog - Tribal</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tribal.credit/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tribal.credit%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://github.com/RSS-Bridge/rss-bridge/favicon.ico</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=CSSLostDateBridge&amp;home_page=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tribal.credit%2Fblog&amp;url_selector=.w-dyn-item+a&amp;url_pattern=%2Fblog%2F.*&amp;content_selector=.w-richtext&amp;content_cleanup=&amp;title_cleanup=&amp;date_selector=&amp;date_format=&amp;date_selector_index=&amp;author_selector=&amp;remove_styling=on&amp;remove_markup=on&amp;limit=3&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:11:07+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Unlocking opportunities: MENA&amp;#x27;s central role in global B2B transactions - Tribal</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:11:07+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:11:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tribal.credit/blog/menas-central-role-in-global-b2b-transactions</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tribal.credit/blog/menas-central-role-in-global-b2b-transactions"/>
    <author>
      <name>https://facebook.com/tribalhq</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The global B2B payments landscape is rapidly evolving, and one region taking center stage in this transformation is the Middle East and North Africa (MENA). With a market valued at USD 994.20 Billion in 2022 and a projected value of USD 2146.70 Billion by 2030, the MENA region is set to play a pivotal role in shaping the future of B2B transactions.Talking specifically about the region, in 2021, the B2B Payments Market in the Middle East and Africa was estimated to be worth USD 54 billion. By 2030, it is anticipated to reach USD 122 billion, expanding at a CAGR of 9.6% from 2022 to 2030, according to data from Straits Research.The growth of the global B2B payments market can be attributed to several factors, including increased international trade, digitalization, and partnerships between B2B payment providers and FinTech giants. As we delve into the significant trends emerging from MENA in the world of international trade, it becomes evident that this region is a key player.At Tribal, we recognize MENA&amp;#x27;s pivotal role in shaping the global B2B payments ecosystem. Through our innovative international payments solution, Tribal Pay, we empower businesses across MENA to engage in seamless cross-border transactions.‍Tribal Pay, has emerged as a powerhouse in redefining global B2B transactions for SMBs and companies. With remarkable expertise, the platform recently achieved the milestone of —processing over USD 150 million in international transfers.‍Our commitment to providing transparent and equitable dealings, along with a credit-based cost structure, eliminates hidden fees and ensures a level playing field for businesses. All these is reflected in the following data:‍MENA - A hub of B2B activity: The MENA region stands as a central hub for commerce. The UAE and Egypt surpass other markets  in terms of money transfer activity within the region. It initiates four times more regional payments than any other market, highlighting its significance in intra-regional trade.‍Global commerce partnerships: MENA&amp;#x27;s influence in the global B2B landscape extends beyond its borders. It leads in commercial activity with markets outside of MENA, including Europe, Latin America, and even Hong Kong. MENA&amp;#x27;s strategic position makes it a preferred partner for global economies.‍Realizing the potential: With the rising trend of real-time payments, increased smartphone penetration, and a growing B2B e-commerce industry, MENA is poised to harness its potential fully. Moreover, initiatives by various governments in the region to promote B2B payments are creating new opportunities for businesses.‍As pioneers in the B2B payments and financing solutions landscape, our mission is to continue fostering innovation and agility to empower businesses and their leaders. With a major milestone in international payments, Tribal Pay reaffirms its commitment to lead the evolution of B2B payment solutions globally. As we move forward, Tribal Pay will set the benchmark for excellence in global commerce.‍Unlock the potential of MENA in B2B transactions with Tribal Pay and join us in shaping the future of international trade.‍‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/651bc5e67ed7eae78184be52/651bc5e67ed7eae78184c0fe_Pagos%20internacionalesOK.webp"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">6 steps to achieve an efficient supply chain - Tribal</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:11:07+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:11:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tribal.credit/blog/6-steps-to-an-efficient-supply-chain</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tribal.credit/blog/6-steps-to-an-efficient-supply-chain"/>
    <author>
      <name>https://facebook.com/tribalhq</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">When it comes to your supply chain, complacency is the enemy of growth. No matter how well it&amp;#x27;s working, you should always should seek ways to improve it.In fact, according to a Deloitte study, 79% of companies with high-performing supply chains achieve above-average revenue growth in their sectors.The challenge lies in knowing how to enhance and optimize your supply chain, which can be daunting for both small brands and established e-commerce businesses.Here, we present the best practices to enhance your supply chain efficiency and take your business to the next level.What does efficiency in the supply chain mean?Efficiency in the supply chain refers to a company&amp;#x27;s ability to use resources, technology, and expertise to minimize logistics costs and maximize profits. The goal of an efficient supply chain is to save money and maximize revenue by optimizing processes and stages within the supply chain.Efficiency vs. Effectiveness in the supply chainEfficiency in the supply chain is defined as the internal performance standard of an organization, whereas effectiveness in the supply chain is the external performance standard.In other words, effectiveness in the supply chain focuses on meeting demands from external groups to your organization, while efficiency in the supply chain is about fulfilling those demands quickly and cost-effectively.What is responsiveness in the supply chain?Responsiveness in the supply chain refers to the ability to react swiftly to sudden changes in the environment that affect processes.A good example could be the ability to scale during the COVID-19 pandemic, such as meeting over double the usual online orders due to lockdowns, or swiftly sending inventory during a period when some of the world&amp;#x27;s busiest ports were congested with container ships.Responsiveness in the supply chain: key to tackling current challengesWhat sets typical supply chains apart from responsive ones? While luck could arguably favor responsive supply chains, there&amp;#x27;s much more behind the scenes, from diversifying suppliers and carriers to implementing connected technology that enables real-time tracking across the supply chain.Flexibility is at the core of a responsive supply chain, implying not only reacting to changes but also being proactive.The goals of a responsive supply chain include:Meeting customer demand (timely delivery at expected costs).Scaling up or down when demand forecasts go wrong.Managing costs during challenging times.Continuously improving processes and workflows to fit current needs.Reducing risk through diversification, planning, and establishing the right partnerships.Several stakeholders are involved in ensuring a smooth-running responsive supply chain, including:The company&amp;#x27;s leaders.Manufacturers and suppliers.Your fulfillment center(s) and external logistics service providers.Technology providers.Your carriers.Your customers.All these stakeholders must be responsive communicators and engage in two-way communication.Efficiency + Responsiveness in the supply chainEfficiency in the supply chain focuses on achieving more with less, while responsiveness centers on agility and keeping the business afloat when things don&amp;#x27;t go as planned. However, in reality, efficiency in the supply chain and responsiveness work hand in hand to handle continuous chaos, as supply chains are among the most volatile and delicate elements in business.At the end of the day, it&amp;#x27;s not about having an efficient supply chain versus a responsive one, but about having a cohesive supply chain that can move quickly and adapt without losing money. Efficient and responsive supply chains share common metrics to monitor, such as on-time fulfillment, profit margins, shipping speed, and delivery times, among others.Together, they pursue the same ultimate goal: meeting customer expectations.How to enhance supply chain efficiency in 6 stepsWhether you&amp;#x27;re just starting your eCommerce business or already established, improving supply chain efficiencies can seem like a monumental task. If you don&amp;#x27;t know where to start, here are seven steps to greater supply chain efficiency:Step 1: Expand supply chain visibilityThe first step to enhancing supply chain efficiency is increasing visibility into your logistical operations.The best way to do this is by implementing inventory management strategies that allow you and your team to track inventory levels as they progress through stages, from reception to storage, packaging, picking, and shipping to customers.Modern inventory management software (IMS) can offer greater visibility as well as access to real-time inventory tracking, helping you avoid stockouts, pending orders, and excessive storage costs.By implementing an IMS, you&amp;#x27;ll also gain access to data and analytics that aid informed business decisions, such as inventory forecasting.Step 2: Build strong partnerships. The importance of supplier relationships in the supply chainCommunication with your suppliers is key! When you have a good relationship with them, you can plan better and avoid shortages, delays, or issues from the outset.A reliable supplier is responsible for tracking the inventory-in-process phase (i.e., the movement of raw materials processed into finished products), which impacts the quality of the products you sell and how quickly you can get more inventory.Suppliers that aren&amp;#x27;t consistent in delivering a quality product can slow down your supply chain from the start, so it&amp;#x27;s important to be selective and weed out those consistently causing problems or delays in your purchases.Once you&amp;#x27;ve found responsible and flexible suppliers, you should continually nurture those relationships through clear and open communication, as well as effectively resolving conflicts.Step 3: Optimize your supply chain with intelligent automationIf you want to enhance supply chain efficiency, one of the best strategies is automating your processes. Automation allows you to reduce human errors, boost performance and speed, and save time and money in the long run.By automating time-consuming tasks like order processing and automated shipping, you can optimize operations and increase productivity. Imagine having an automated warehouse that cuts down time, effort, and common logistics errors. You might even consider investing in your own technology and tools to automate your warehouse.However, we acknowledge that automation technology can be expensive. This is why many e-commerce companies rely on technologically advanced third-party logistics partners (3PLs) that have already made investments in automation. This way, you can reap automation benefits without incurring high costs. It allows you to focus your resources on product development, marketing strategies, and other critical initiatives for business growth.Step 4: Implement supply chain softwareWith numerous operations taking place in your supply chain at the same time, it&amp;#x27;s critical to adopt the correct software and technology to allow your team to work as efficiently as possible.‍If you manage warehouse inventories in different locations, consider using a warehouse management system (WMS) that connects to your IMS. This will help you automate order processing, get real-time inventory tracking, have order management tools, and access data reports and analysis.Of course, implementing a solid technology infrastructure can be costly. Fortunately, many direct-to-consumer firms collaborate with a 3PL that already has the technologies in place to maximize supply chain efficiency.Step 5: Cultivate supply chain expertsOnce you&amp;#x27;ve decided to implement all the aforementioned changes, the next step is to create a training plan for your employees.Remember that your supply chain is only as good as the people in charge of it. To ensure consistency, efficiency, and correctness in decision-making, warehouse employees, order fulfillers, and logistics managers should be trained on standard operating procedures.If an employee has been with the company for a long time, seek their input on how to improve warehouse operations. If you lack a logistics team, a 3PL can provide the necessary expertise to manage your supply chain.Step 6: Get funds to improve your supply chainImplementing efficient technology and software in your supply chain can represent a significant investment. Don&amp;#x27;t worry though, because there are financial solutions like Tribal that can help you obtain the necessary financing to acquire the systems and tools that will allow you to achieve an efficient supply chain.With Tribal, you can access financing options that allow you to maintain your company&amp;#x27;s operational liquidity and cover the expenses needed to optimize your supply chain. From paying your suppliers to obtaining working capital credit, Tribal provides you with financial tools to boost your supply chain without compromising cash flow.Don&amp;#x27;t let financial constraints stop you from improving your supply chain. With Tribal, you can get the financial support you need to implement the best practices and technologies in your business, and thus achieve a more efficient and profitable supply chain.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/651bc5e67ed7eae78184be52/651bc5e67ed7eae78184c09a_64e68098c70070c769944e7b_%255BHEADER%255D%2520Estrategias%2520para%2520eficientar%2520cadena%2520de%2520suministroOK.webp"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Sustaining a Steady Cash Flow: Enhancing your invoicing and accelerating payment receipts - Tribal</title>
    <published>2025-04-11T22:11:07+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T22:11:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tribal.credit/blog/cash-flow</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tribal.credit/blog/cash-flow"/>
    <author>
      <name>https://facebook.com/tribalhq</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Are you the CFO of a company and aiming to ensure a consistent cash flow? You&amp;#x27;re not alone! One of the most crucial keys to achieving this lies in optimizing your invoicing process. By receiving payments from your clients faster and more effectively, you&amp;#x27;ll enhance your cash flow and secure your company&amp;#x27;s prosperity.‍Invoicing is an essential process in any business. It&amp;#x27;s how you pay for what you need to operate your business and how you get paid for your products or services. Establishing accurate and efficient invoicing processes keeps the cash flow moving and ensures not a cent goes to waste.‍However, we all know how important it is to receive payments on time to keep our business running. Yet, this can sometimes become a headache if you lack an efficient invoicing process. This efficiency can be achieved through automation.‍And while automation can streamline workflows, according to a global study by Webexpenses, only 5% of accounts payable teams have fully automated invoice and payment processing. Teams could significantly cut labor costs by using software to automate these tasks. In fact, the same study indicates that 26% of companies are working towards having a fully automated invoice processing system by 2024.‍If you find yourself in this statistic, don&amp;#x27;t worry. In this blog, we present 4 highly effective options to enhance your invoicing and receive payments more promptly. Get ready to ensure your cash flow and ensure your business&amp;#x27;s success!Option 1: A head start for the right beginning!Imagine receiving a 50% advance for every job you undertake. Sounds good, right? By obtaining an upfront deposit, you&amp;#x27;ll shift your mindset from scarcity to abundance. Why? Because many jobs come with a gross profit margin of 50%, meaning you&amp;#x27;ll cover all your costs at the project&amp;#x27;s outset.‍Moreover, if you manage the job well, you won&amp;#x27;t have to worry about the next paycheck to pay your employees. Advances are designed to cover your costs and minimize risks.‍Remember, receiving an advance builds trust with the client and reduces non-payment risks. Establishing a trusting relationship with your prospects is vital to securing upfront money.‍Option 2: Invoice weekly for improved cash flow!How often do you send invoices to your clients each month? If you typically do it only at the end of the month, there&amp;#x27;s an issue. Invoicing weekly can significantly speed up payment receipts.‍If you have staff who can invoice weekly, you&amp;#x27;ll make a significant improvement in cash flow compared to monthly invoicing.‍In fact, if you issue invoices on the same day each week, data suggests that sending them on weekends can lead to quicker payments.‍Option 3: Invoice immediately upon project completion!Imagine you finish a job on the 5th day of the month, but you don&amp;#x27;t send the invoice until the end of the month, and the client pays you 30 days later. In total, it will take 55 days until you receive payment. During those 55 days, you&amp;#x27;ll likely have to cover payroll multiple times.‍The ideal approach is to invoice the client as soon as possible, either weekly, at milestones, or as soon as the job is finished. Once you complete a job, send the invoice promptly!‍If you want to receive your money faster, send the invoice on the same day or the next day. Focusing on quicker payment will put you on the path to improving your cash flow.‍Option 4: Invoice by milestones if weekly isn&amp;#x27;t feasible!If you can&amp;#x27;t invoice weekly or upfront, invoicing by milestones is another effective option to maintain a positive cash flow during a large project.‍The timing and amount of payments should be based on specific milestones or achievements you can pinpoint. The payment schedule should allow you to maintain a positive cash flow as you progress through each project stage. This is key to having enough working capital to invest in the next project phase (e.g., planning, design, development, and implementation).‍Keep in mind that you need to stay ahead of your direct expenses. This means getting 50% upfront and receiving the remaining 50% at significant project milestones.‍The goal is to leave the smaller percentage for the final payment when most issues arise.‍Ensure you receive the money before having to cover payroll related to a project.Achieving this can have a significant impact on your cash flow. Additionally, the larger and more successful your company becomes, the more important this strategy is, as larger companies require more funds to survive and face greater cash flow risks.‍Remember, whether you&amp;#x27;re a $500,000 or $5 million company, you must meet every payroll. One of the main reasons many small businesses fail is because they spend their time chasing money just to cover the next payroll.‍To improve your cash flow, consider strategies like cutting expenses, shortening collection days, and paying suppliers. Small changes can make a big impact on your cash flow.Tribal: Automation and optimization for efficient invoicingWith Tribal, you can access financing options that help you maintain your company&amp;#x27;s operational liquidity and cover necessary expenses to optimize your cash flow. Additionally, it offers a specialized platform for financial automation and optimization that can assist you in optimizing your payment process and enhancing your cash flow. How?‍Automation: With Tribal, you can pay all your invoices from our platform in just three steps—using your existing credit line. First, choose between national or international payment; then, select your preferred currency and the amount. Finally, enter the beneficiary&amp;#x27;s banking information. From there, you can track your payment and save information for future use.‍Reminders and Alerts: With Tribal, you no longer have to worry about payment follow-ups. The platform sends automated reminders to your clients about pending payments, reducing late payments and improving the likelihood of timely receipts.‍Financial Reports and Analysis: With Tribal, you get real-time financial reports and analysis. You&amp;#x27;ll have a complete view of your income and expenses, categorize them, and make informed decisions to enhance your business&amp;#x27;s financial health. Detailed information will help you identify patterns and trends, further optimizing your invoicing process.‍Security and Confidentiality: The Tribal platform ensures the security and confidentiality of your financial data and your clients&amp;#x27;. You can have peace of mind that your information is protected and complies with the highest security standards.‍Don&amp;#x27;t let financial limitations hinder you from optimizing your cash flow. With Tribal, you can obtain the financial support you need to implement best practices and technologies in your business, achieving a more efficient and profitable invoicing process.‍</content>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/651bc5e67ed7eae78184be52/651bc5e67ed7eae78184c09e_64e3d21d16dcc480ad53dd55_%255BHEADER%255D%2520Mejora%2520tu%2520proceso%2520de%2520facturacio%25CC%2581nOK.webp"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
