<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">UntangledFin - Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/untangledfin?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Funtangledfin&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Funtangledfin&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:11:10+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Untangled joins Celo’s Climate Collective and Alliance for Prosperity</title>
    <published>2022-12-12T17:43:59+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-12-12T17:43:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/untangledfin/untangled-joins-celos-climate-collective-and-alliance-for-prosperity-521138f4556?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/untangledfin/untangled-joins-celos-climate-collective-and-alliance-for-prosperity-521138f4556?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Quan Le</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">(unsplash)Climate CollectiveCelo AllianceTo mark Untangled’s upcoming launch on Celo’s mainnet (our contracts have been active on Celo testnet Alfajores since June 2022) we are happy to announce our recent memberships of:Climate Collective: A community-driven initiative, the Climate Collective fights climate change by aligning the demand for Celo stablecoins — currently cUSD, cEUR, cREAL — with efforts to protect the planet. As the demand for these stable assets increases, so will the percentage of nature-backed assets allocated in the Reserve. The aim of the Collective is to diversify and increase the allocation of natural assets to 40% by the end of 2025.Alliance for Properity: Alliance members work to help digital assets be shared in faster, less expensive, and more transparent ways, while expanding financial access and inclusion to digital currencies for the under-banked. Untangled joins many notable members such as a16z, Coinbase Ventures, Grameen Foundation and Deutsche Telekom as well as other RWA credit protocols such as Centrifuge and Goldfinch.Given Untangled’s focus on trade finance and green assets it is hard to find more suitable alliances within Web3 than the above initiatives:Trade finance eases working capital needs among participants in international trade. For example, after shipment, a rice exporter in Vietnam typically has to wait 3 months for payment (e.g. from a supermarket chain in Europe). Trade finance enables the exporter to get early payment, allowing them to pay their workers and to ramp up production for the next order. With trade finance gap widened to $1.7 trillion as a result of the pandemic, improving access to trade finance by SMEs could make a real difference to the prosperity of many families in emerging markets.Both trade finance and green assets can be in the reserve that backs Celo ecosystem’s stablecoins. Imagine a currency that is backed by solar home system financing in Africa or a battery swapping infrastructure for bus fleets in India, among many other ReFi instruments. Apart from being money, this can bring about the transition necessary to avert the looming climate crisis, while providing energy access to millions of home and clean mobility for the people. This underpins the vision of “Money can be beautiful” that the Alliance for Prosperity has.There are some technical issues to be resolved and Untangled has been working with Celo Foundation, Mento Protocol (Celo’s stablecoin protocol) and Climate Collective to make “Money can be beautiful” a reality.To learn more about Untangled, read our technical documentation. To discover the mission-aligned projects building collaboratively with Untangled and the Climate Collective’s and Alliance for Prosperity’s many members and partners, visit the Climate Collective and Celo.Untangled joins Celo’s Climate Collective and Alliance for Prosperity was originally published in UntangledFin on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Pool launch — Earn 10%+ APY on short-term trade finance assets</title>
    <published>2022-03-02T16:09:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-02T16:09:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/untangledfin/pool-launch-earn-10-apy-on-short-term-trade-finance-assets-7186cba54f29?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/untangledfin/pool-launch-earn-10-apy-on-short-term-trade-finance-assets-7186cba54f29?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Manrui Tang</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Pool launch — Earn 10%+ APY on short-term trade finance assetscredit: chuttersnap/unsplashUntangled Diversified Trade Finance FundWe are launching Untangled Diversified Trade Finance Fund — Our first asset pools are to be announced soon. You will be able to invest in a portfolio of diversified trade finance assets originated by our experienced originating partners. Here is the fund strategy at a glance:How it works: Investors supply liquidity in the form of stable coin (USDC or DAI) into a liquidity pool. This pool will in turn invest in senior tranches of originator’s asset pools. As a result, investors gain a diversified exposure to the underlying asset pools.Underlying assets: trade finance assets like invoices, inventories — these are short-term, self-liquidating assets. Already a very low risk asset class, estimated to be around 0.5% default rate by ICC, our originating partners have managed with even less defaults.Yields: We expect a blended yield of 10%+ APY for Untangled Diversified Trade Finance Fund including Liquidity IncentiveLiquidity Incentive: We will announce a liquidity provider program that awards early participation with a native token of Whale Protocol, our asset finance protocol.Want even higher yields? Become a Liquidity Backer: A selected number of our asset pools offer opportunity to invest in high yield junior tranche. You could earn up to 12–20% APY on these opportunities before liquidity incentives. Indicate your interest to become a Liquidity Backer and we will be in touch with further information.Protecting your investmentA bankruptcy-remote structure: our asset originators would sell assets to a series within our Delaware SPV. Therefore assets are separated from the possibility of originators’s bankruptcy.Onchain securitisation: end-to-end tracking of asset backing on a blockchain through our digital asset finance protocol.No lock-up: In addition to being short-term duration, investors have the ability to redeem at any time. The pool will make automatic redemption with available liquidity.Institutional grade: Before onboarding, originators and assets are subject to due diligence. All our originators have “skin in the game” through participating/retaining a junior tranche.Have your say: with the native token you will be able to participate in the governance of the protocol including risk parameters for the asset pools.Learn more Early Liquidity Provider ProgramConnect directly with the team on DiscordPool launch — Earn 10%+ APY on short-term trade finance assets was originally published in UntangledFin on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Untangled in 2022</title>
    <published>2022-01-25T13:42:23+00:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-25T13:42:23+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/untangledfin/untangled-in-2022-2e44e560aee8?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/untangledfin/untangled-in-2022-2e44e560aee8?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Quan Le</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">In praise of stabilityAs we write this, the global stock market has its worst week since 2020. Crypto market cap has halved (50%) from $3 trillion in November to around $1.5 trillion today. Cryptos are highly volatile and correlated within themselves and with the stock market. In fact, crypto suffers from the same problem of the stock market — pro-cyclicality. A lot of decentralised finance (DeFi) is over-collateralized lending. A decline of collateral prices could trigger an automatic liquidation which dampens the prices further in a downward spiral.Times like these remind us of the virtue of stability…Untangled bridges real world assets like green loans, trade finance and SME financing to decentralised capital pools.We expand the collateral universe of DeFi lending. Our collaterals are stable and uncorrelated to the rest of crypto. More importantly, we can bring DeFi innovations to benefit the real economy, keeping people employed in SMEs and help mitigate the impact of climate change. We combine blockchain’s power of coordination and capital allocation with the real world’s stability and meaning.Sourcing assetsWe have a pipeline of nearly $200m for 2022. To give you a flavour of what going on across different asset classes:Green assets: Transitioning to a greener world — financing smaller issuers with proven renewable energy technologyRenewable energy producer from tidal wave: a winner of numerous awards for its innovative technology, this company is looking to refinance its construction loan. Yield will be around 6–7% APYTrade finance: Lifeblood of global trade. A lot of SMEs depends on trade finance for working capital requirements (e.g. pay their employees)FCA regulated trade financier providing working capital finance to suppliers globally, many of them are SMEs. Yield will be around 6–9% APY.SME loans: High yield, uncollateralized loans to smaller companiesUK based, FCA regulated SME lender offering flexible financing. As the economy continues to recover, the lender has seen a great demand for its services. Yields are 10%+ APYDeveloping a liquidity baseWe develop Untangled so that any investors, especially those in developed markets can access credit opportunities from anywhere in the world, especially emerging markets. Our liquidity providers are both institutions and qualified individuals.To bootstrap liquidity, we have done a lot of work connecting our platform to DeFi lending protocols and other institutional DeFi liquidity providers. This is to ensure that our asset originators can refinance their collaterals. Individual investors can also leverage the due diligence done by institutional investors for each opportunity.Early accessWe are inviting a selected group of investors to a dataroom opened for each of the above opportunities. If you are interested in an early access to any of these, please let us know at contact@untangled.financeUntangled in 2022 was originally published in UntangledFin on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The new era of smart contract based supply chain financing</title>
    <published>2021-09-08T09:25:40+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T09:25:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/untangledfin/the-new-era-of-smart-contract-based-supply-chain-financing-d72e81935805?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/untangledfin/the-new-era-of-smart-contract-based-supply-chain-financing-d72e81935805?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Quan Le</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The future of trade and supply chain finance is tokenised_Part 3DeFi — A glimpse of the future of trade and supply chain financeThe tokenisation of assets coupled with innovation in payment tokens will usher a new era in trade and supply chain finance.For a glimpse of what the future might look like, just take a look at decentralised finance (DeFi). The value of tokens locked in various DeFi lending protocols has increased 30 folds over the last 12 months to $30 billion. Still a tiny fraction of, say, the global corporate bond market ($41 trillion), DeFi has the potential to become a big part of the global financial system.DeFi lending protocols use smart contracts (a computer program residing on a blockchain) to receive a token in exchange for another token. An user interacts with a smart contract via a decentralised application (dApp). If you are a lender, you will receive interest. If you are a borrower, you will pay interest. The interest rate (on protocols such as Compound) is set programmatically by supply and demand. For Dai, the interest is replaced by stability fee which is effectively the interest for borrowing Dai. Again, this is set automatically by market forces. There is also over-collateralisation to protect against falling collateral prices. The smart contract also tracks collateral price through an automated program (an oracle).So DeFi lending is similar to traditional collateralised lending in most respects. The main differences are that they are permissionless and decentralised — anyone can borrow or lend — and fully automated.Collaterals used in these lending protocols are native blockchain tokens like Eth or Dai, they are not exposed to counterparty risks but only market risks. Counterparty risk is one of the main obstacles to bridge traditional finance to DeFi. Invoices pledged as collateral may not be collected.DeFi lending protocols are working on overcome this obstacle or coming to a realisation that they either face the concentration risk of cryptos or the counterparty risk of real world assets — Either ways, diversification will help to sustain the system and make DeFi lending becoming mainstream.With assets being tokenised and payment tokens becoming increasingly available, trade and supply chain finance can benefit from smart contract technology to streamline and automate lending process. The difference is of course that it can not be permissionless due to regulations such as Know-Your-Customer. The advantage over DeFi, however, is that, if implemented on a permissioned blockchain, privacy can be preserved. This is particularly important as supply chain sourcing is a source of competitive advantage for many companies.In a recent report, the World Bank recognises the potential of smart contracts in supply chain finance and insurance, in enabling more SMEs to to access finance. Specifically, smart contract-based financing could lead to process improvement, fraud reduction and enhanced transparency.Let’s talk on how this could be done in trade and supply chain finance:Financing with tokens and smart contractsTrade and supply finance refers to financing activities relating to a cross border transaction or along the supply chain respectively. Traditionally a bank-originated asset class, increasingly non-bank financiers have entered this space.An exporter ships goods to an overseas buyer and issues an invoice. The invoice will then be settled by the buyer 30 days, 60 days or 90 days later. The exporter needs working capital therefore sells or pledges the invoice to a bank or a non-bank financier. The financier discounts the invoice and pays the balance to the exporter.With smart contract-based financing, a single or a batch of tokenised invoices is sold or pledged as collateral for a loan. The financier first advances an amount (typically 90% of the value of invoices) and collects payment directly from the buyer. Each stakeholder has a wallet which has been topped up with payment tokens. As a buyer pays an invoice (or the invoice can initiate automatic payment on due date as discussed earlier) it will set off the advance with the remaining amount being automatically transferred to the seller, after deducting a fee for the financier.Pre-shipment finance can also be obtained. A financier advances working capital to an exporter on the back of inventory they own. Typically, there is a tripartite relationship between the company, the financier and a collateral manager who provides safe custody of the inventory on behalf of the financier. The inventory in this case is collateral for the financing.As inventory is tokenised, it is used as collateral for a loan via a smart contract. The loan is disbursed to the SME’s wallet.Funders fund the Lender (warehouse facilities)SMEs supply to Buyers and issue an invoice. Once invoices are accepted by approved Buyers they are tokenisedLender buys/finance tokenised invoices. Approved Buyers pay Lender directly via wallet which automatically set off the financingInventory can also be used as collateral. In this case, the service of an external collateral manager or a commodity exchange is required for safe custody. Once the inventory is sold and an invoice is accepted, the invoice token replaces inventory token as collateral.Purchase Orders (PO) from approved Buyers are also accepted as collateral. Once PO has been accepted, SMEs can apply for financing. When goods have been produced and delivered, an invoice token will be issued in place of the PO token as collateral for the financingOnce asset tokens have been built up to certain threshold they will be sold to an SPV for securitisation. A bond token will be issued to investors and DeFiProceeds from securitisation is used to repay Funders or to originate more assetsCollections from assets/Buyers is used to fund redemption of principal and interest to investorsAs raw materials are processed into products, raw material tokens are replaced by finished product tokens under the same lending contract. Once the inventory is sold and an invoice is raised, the collateral token transforms into an invoice token, still within the same lending smart contract. Once the invoice is paid either by a financier or the buyer, the proceeds automatically trigger the repayment of the loan plus interest with the remainder being transferred to the borrower’s wallet. This process saves SMEs from having to obtain multiple facilities, incurring extra costs, but also affords lenders with better loan issuance and monitoring as the physical flow inventory synchronises with its financial and information flows.Financing can be obtained even earlier in the supply chain. Based on the strength of a purchase order, a financier can lend to the exporter so they can buy the inventory for export or for processing into products. Again, in this case, the purchase order will be tokenised, allowing the smart contract to release a loan. Once the inventory has been bought or further processed, the inventory token will replace the purchase order token as collateral. Once inventory is sold, the invoice token will again replace the inventory token all the way to payment of the invoice in the manner described above.The above funding use cases increase in riskiness to financiers which is reflected in funding costs and other conditions such as collateral ratios or advance rates. Also, as the value of collateral is derived from the price of inventory, it is important that there is a reliable price reporting mechanism (an oracle) to the smart contract. The smart contract can also set a liquidation ratio i.e when the value of collateral falls and the borrower fails to either top up more collateral or to repay part of the loan, the lender can step in to seize the collateral to recover the loan.Trade and supply chain finance distributionTokenisation will not just transform the origination of trade and supply chain finance but also its distribution.This asset class is generally low risk with little correlation to other asset classes. However, so far it is quite difficult for non-bank investors to get exposure to. At the same time, banks find it expensive, from a regulatory capital perspective, to lend to sector. Many banks have retreated from trade, particularly commodity trade finance. This has led a rise of specialist supply chain financiers such as Greensill and private credit funds. Unlike banks, these organisations can’t raise retail deposits so securitisation is one of the main funding sources. Even for banks, securitisation is attractive as a way to move assets off their balance sheets whilst still maintaining the customer relationship.Since supply chain loans are tokens themselves they can be pooled together according to some eligibility criteria before another token representing a bond/fractional interest in the asset pool being issued to investors. As each pool is a smart contract that holds asset tokens, bond investors can always track performance of underlying assets — there can never be a loss of nexus between the security and the assets backing it up. This was one of the major causes of the 2008 Global Financial Crisis.With the bond token being issued on a public blockchain like Ethereum, it will open up to opportunities in DeFi. In a near future, the consumers of chocolate made from Niche Cocoa’s materials can invest in a token backed up by a portfolio of Niche Cocoa’s invoices and inventory. They can further increase their investment through using the bond token as collateral in DeFi lending protocols to obtain more liquidity.Continue reading this series:Part 1_Trade/Logistics: Tokenising trade connections and assetsPart 2_ Payment: The race between stable coins and CBDCsPart 3_Financing: The new era of smart contract-based supply chain financingThe new era of smart contract based supply chain financing was originally published in UntangledFin on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Payment: The race between stable coins and CBDCs</title>
    <published>2021-09-08T09:24:19+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T09:24:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/untangledfin/payment-the-race-between-stable-coins-and-cbdcs-ef76f0992660?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/untangledfin/payment-the-race-between-stable-coins-and-cbdcs-ef76f0992660?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Quan Le</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The future of trade and supply chain finance is tokenised_Part 2Payment is one of the most impactful areas of blockchain technology. For the first time, payment can be made on a Peer-to-Peer basis, remotely, at a fraction of the costs of existing cross-border payment and as easy and fast as sending a text or email. Business to Business (B2B) payment is a large market that is bank-dominated. New B2B payment firms like TransferWise and AirWallex bring great customer experience and cost savings but still need to rely on bank’s payment rail.Regulatory landscapes for crypto payment vary among countries. However, banks and traditional financial firms are increasingly turning to cryptocurrencies for international payment:JPM Coin, a cryptocurrency run on private blockchain Quorum reportedly went live in late 2020 after 2 years in development. It is initially used to settle within the JP Morgan’s international network.Paypal announced that they would launch a service to allow customers to spend Bitcoin and other cryptos at 26 million merchants on its network in 2021. This is anticipated to bring crypto currencies to the mainstream.Visa has been working with blockchain technology for several years and filed a few patents. One of the most recent developments was the collaboration with the issuer of stablecoin USDC which enables B2B payment within the Visa network.Stable coinsIndeed stablecoins have been one of the most exciting developments in blockchain space. The last year has seen a huge increase in stablecoins in issuance and uses. Some of the most prominent and relevant for global trade are:USDC is a stable coin guaranteed by off-chain deposit of USD. The crypto currency is therefore fiat-backed. The deposit is regularly audited. Through a partnership with Visa (above) and Coinbase we expect it to become a major player in the B2B payment space.Dai, like USDC, pegs 1:1 to USD through an on-chain collateralised lending mechanism. Anyone can generate Dai by depositing Eth (which powers the Ethereum blockchain) and other acceptable collateral with a smart contract. It is expected that real-world assets such as invoices and loans could eventually be accepted as collateral, thus vastly increase the use of Dai in the real economy.Diem is a stablecoin to be issued by Diem Association which was set up by Facebook and 26 other organisations. It is pegged 1:1 against USD and targets specifically at the unbanked in emerging markets.CBDCsThese developments have partly prompted the Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC) efforts by many countries. China started Digital Yuan project many years ago and now piloting the digital currency in a number of cities.The Digital Yuan could challenge the USD hegemony as China is the largest economy in real terms and the largest trading nation. Other CBCD projects include e-krona (Sweden), Digital Euro and those from the likes of Japan, Thailand and Australia, albeit at different stages of development.In a few years, we are likely to see these digital tokens playing a major role in international trade. By that time, regulatory regimes will have evolved. Conversions back and forth to national currencies will become easier through services such as PayPal. It is also likely that other digital tokens like the above stable coins will widely be accepted, not just CBDCs.Visa estimates that $120 trillion in payments annually are made using checks and wire transfers, costing as much as $50 each, regardless of the size of the transaction. Since stable coins settle on a blockchain, transactions can close in a little as 20 seconds and, importantly, can be done for nearly free. Visa believes its vast array of merchants could choose to use this nearly instant alternative form of payment.Continue reading this series:Part 1_Trade/Logistics: Tokenising trade connections and assetsPart 2_ Payment: The race between stable coins and CBDCsPart 3_Financing: The new era of smart contract-based supply chain financingPayment: The race between stable coins and CBDCs was originally published in UntangledFin on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Trade and logistics: Tokenising trade connections and assets</title>
    <published>2021-09-08T09:16:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T09:16:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/untangledfin/trade-and-logistics-tokenising-trade-connections-and-assets-f2729fddac05?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/untangledfin/trade-and-logistics-tokenising-trade-connections-and-assets-f2729fddac05?source=rss----5734f4ec2c85---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Quan Le</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The future of trade and supply chain finance is tokenised_Part 1IntroductionNiche Cocoa is a Ghanaian cocoa processor that supplies semi-finished products such as powder, butter and liquor to buyers in Europe and Asia. The buyers will then process them into consumer products like chocolate. Niche Cocoa first needs to buy cocoa beans from farmers. As supplies of beans are generally available throughout the year, there is a short period from buying raw beans to processing them into products at their 60,000 ton/year facility in Free Zone, near the Tema port. Buyers from Europe and increasingly China approach the company, review samples and quotes before placing an order. Once products are ready, they are shipped to buyers.Niche Cocoa borrows from local banks to buy cocoa beans and to run the facility. Banks typically employ independent collateral managers to monitor the stock and flow of inventory. Once the products are shipped as evidenced by a Bill of Lading, Niche Cocoa issues an invoice to the buyer. Standard payment terms vary between 30 to 90 days. In need of working capital for a new production cycle, Niche Cocoa reaches out to a specialist financier who buys the invoices from Niche Cocoa and arranges for collection directly from the buyer. In the process, they charge 2.5% for a typical 3 month financing (10% APY). Niche Cocoa accepts the terms as the financing allows Niche Cocoa to deliver larger orders in the next cycle.Niche Cocoa is among millions of SMEs around the world who needs working capital in the form of trade and supply chain financing to carry and process inventory and to plug the gap between invoicing and payment.Let unpack what is happening here:Trade/logistics: Buyer and seller ‘meet’ and agree on trade terms such as goods, price, quality, quantity, delivery etc. Logistics transaction is about transforming goods either in time (storage) or in space (shipping). The lack of trust and heavy paperworks make it difficult for SMEs to access the global market.Payment: Buyer pays for goods when certain conditions are met such as proof of shipment (Bill of Lading), on receipt of the shipment or according to a payment term. This payment is made via the correspondent banking network. When finance is used, a financier transfers money to the borrower, also through the banking network. Payment is both slow and costly. Depending on corridors and amount, participant could pay up to 7–8%, according to the World Bank.Finance: Working capital finance is to bridge the timing mismatch between when an invoice is raised and when it is paid; when inventory can be converted to invoices once shipped; or between receiving a purchase order and its fulfilment, where raw materials are transformed in form (processing), time (storage) and space (shipping). Working capital financing could cost SMEs 15% — 40% depending on countries and instruments. For USD financing it could cost SMEs 10–12% in for invoice financing.We believe that blockchain/tokenization coupled with other technologies such as AI and IoT will have huge impact on trade and supply chain finance in terms of trust/transparency, speed and especially costs.. This paper focuses on the impact of tokenisation on trade and supply chain finance in each of three areas.Trade and logistics: Tokenising trade connections and assetsThe COVID-19 Pandemic has highlighted the importance of resilience supply chain. Visibility brings resilience. With a clear view of the conditions of suppliers along the supply chain, stakeholders are able to prepare for and deal with supply chain disruptions.There have been digitisation efforts of the global supply chains. Tradetech is a major development area in recent years. HSBC’s Serai started with connecting apparel suppliers in Bangladesh to global buyers. It allows users to set up profiles, showcasing their products and finding relevant partners through a search function. Serai is integrating with other technology solutions to provide enhanced services such as a 3D Visualisation tool that allows closer examination of products. All these help enhancing visibility and trust in the supply chain. Being set up by a bank, it is anticipated that trade and supply chain finance solutions will be integrated in the Serai platform eventually.Tracking and traceabilityA trade for physical goods requires a movement of the goods from A to B. This is logistics. Supply chain visibility means that stakeholders can track the goods during as it transits through the supply chain. It is also important for traceability as consumers increasingly want to know the source i.e to ensure that it is environmentally and socially sustainable (e.g. no child labour).Tracking shipment is a major issue. Financiers often lack up-to-date information of the cargo whereabouts let alone its conditions. Here Internet of Things (IoT) has a huge role to play. Monitoring micro climate conditions (e.g. temperature and humidity) of storage of fish or grains or tracking a container as it transits through different ports or choke points or tracking a vehicle as it moves from a warehouse to a distributor’s forecourt and eventually sold to a customer are just a few use cases of IoT within global trade.In the supply chain of commodities, when financing is involved, often banks engage independent collateral managers who provide safe custody of physical commodities. This is to ensure that inventory movement is controlled and the collateral is adequate for financing. Often this control is done by human who guards the inventory with a physical lock..Whether being digital or manual, the above efforts are about giving financiers more and better information to make lending decisions and manage risks after lending. In fact, lacking of information, whether financial, commercial or supply chain, is the main reason that trade and supply chain finance is only available to large companies. SMEs find it difficult to access finance due to a lack of information and acceptable security such as hard assets.We believe that the IoT, AI and blockchain will fundamentally change the way trade and supply chain finance is done. Whilst IoT transforms data acquisition (e.g. environment, locations), AI gives insights on data from many different sources. Blockchain ensures unknown parties to share data securely with its inherent qualities — immutability and a traceable chain of custody.Tokenisation of supply chain assetsThrough tokenisation, assets in supply chain such as stored inventory, goods in transit, invoices and even purchase orders can be used in collateralised lending. Asset backed tokens can synchronise financial flow with information flow, removing the need for reconciliation and lower fraud risks.Whilst a Bolivian cattle ranch has been tokenized, inventory can be tokenised, leveraging the existing collateral management practice. Collateral managers (CMA), trusted third parties (because of reputation and adequate insurance) monitor inventories in terms of movements and conditions. Blockchain tokens are issued by collateral managers once they have accepted the type, quality and quantity of each inventory deposit at an accredited storage. This digital token can be a security, like a tokenised electronic warehouse receipt, or simply a digital representation of inventory under custody that is recognised by parties under a contract (financier, borrower and CMA).Goods in transit can also be tokenised. CargoX, a blockchain document transfer platform, has been working on a tokenized electronic Bill of Lading solution. The solution replaces paper Bill of Lading, a key title document in international trade that needs to be couriered around, with a Non Fungible Token (NFT) on Ethereum blockchain. It is still early days as the token is yet to be generally accepted but, like the stored inventory case above, it is being recognised among parties involved under contract law.Tokenising invoices and purchase orders is far simpler as it doesn’t involve a third party vouching for physical existence as in the case of inventory. Once an invoice is accepted by a buyer it is tokenised. Tradeshift, a leader in supply chain payment and marketplace has been working on invoice tokenisation.Dubbed “Smart invoice” the tokenised invoice can trigger payment on due date, removing the need for time consuming follow-up and laying a foundation for many financial application (programmable money).Perhaps one of the major developments in tokensing supply chain assets is a project that Coca Cola has been working on. Coca Cola looks to tokenised invoices from its bottlers, making it secure to share data among them.Key blockchain conceptsBlockchain: A public, distributed, immutable database where transactions are validated not by a single centralised party but by many incentivised parties through a consensus mechanism (way to come to agreement).Tokenisation: Process of digitising an asset or a liability to digital representation on a blockchain.Fungible Token: Tokens that can be used interchangeably with other tokens within a particularly type e.g. a payment token.Non-Fungible Token: Tokens that are unique and can’t be used interchangeably with another token e.g. an invoice tokenStable coin: Tokens whose values are pegged against the value of a currency or a commodity.Smart contract: A piece of computer code residing on a blockchain that is capable of self execution when certain conditions are metOracle: Computer program or human report of real world events (such as commodity prices) to the blockchain. Oracles can be both centralised or decentralisedContinue reading this series:Part 1_Trade/Logistics: Tokenising trade connections and assetsPart 2_ Payment: The race between stable coins and CBDCsPart 3_Financing: The new era of smart contract-based supply chain financingTrade and logistics: Tokenising trade connections and assets was originally published in UntangledFin on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
