<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Ultra Stellar - Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ultra-stellar?source=rss----d59db8dd32d9---4"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fultra-stellar&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fultra-stellar&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:11:13+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Allbridge Launch Connects Stellar Network to Solana, Ethereum, Polygon and Celo</title>
    <published>2023-07-11T11:54:17+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-07-11T11:54:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ultra-stellar/allbridge-launch-connects-stellar-network-to-solana-ethereum-polygon-and-celo-e2862bcc2d4a?source=rss----d59db8dd32d9---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ultra-stellar/allbridge-launch-connects-stellar-network-to-solana-ethereum-polygon-and-celo-e2862bcc2d4a?source=rss----d59db8dd32d9---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ultra Stellar</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">New Cross-Chain Bridge Brings Newfound Interoperability and Simple Asset Transfer Between Prominent ChainsAs a long-time participant in the Stellar ecosystem, Ultra Stellar takes immense pride when strategic partnerships come together, helping combine technology to bring new usability to the Stellar network. Today we have the pleasure of revealing our work with Allbridge, an established cross-chain solutions provider, resulting in seamless interoperability between Stellar and a multitude of blockchains, such as Ethereum, Solana, Polygon, and Celo.Allbridge, renowned for their robust ability to expedite asset movements across blockchains, has designed a unique Stellar bridge that complements its existing system of validators. This pivotal development brings good news for Stellar developers, offering a reliable pathway to expose decentralized applications (dApps) to an expansive user base across various chains. In addition, all Stellar users benefit from the ability to bridge assets between Stellar and other networks, increasing the useability of Stellar as a place of exchange and on/off ramping.Our expertise at Ultra Stellar, with a rich history of over nine years in the ecosystem, helped this strategic initiative come to fruition. The team’s technical contributions towards Allbridge’s validators, and our ongoing hosting support for validators and transaction signing services, underpin our unwavering dedication to Stellar’s continued growth and cross-chain operability.“We are incredibly proud to be part of this landmark integration. Our collaboration with Allbridge perfectly complements our mission to expand financial services on the Stellar network,” said Dmitri Gmyza, representing Ultra Stellar. “By offering ongoing support for Allbridge’s validators, we’re helping bridge the gap between Stellar and other networks. We’re confident this integration, enabling seamless asset transfers, will enhance user experiences across our LOBSTR, StellarX, and StellarTerm products.”This integration underscores the spirit of cooperative innovation within the Stellar ecosystem, enabling users to leverage the potential of varied chains while enjoying the secure and transparent infrastructure that Stellar brings to the table. Importantly, users can now conveniently access Allbridge’s assets within Stellar applications, such as LOBSTR.The advent of Allbridge’s assets in the Stellar ecosystem elevates the Stellar experience, with LOBSTR, StellarX, and StellarTerm benefiting. Users now have the capacity to trade, swap, and send these new assets at near-zero cost. Today’s launch provides on/off ramps to each of the supported assets’ respective chains via allbridge.io, allowing assets to flow between networks and be traded on the Stellar Decentralized Exchange (DEX).Getting started with these new assets is a breeze, thanks to our comprehensive guides. If you’re new to LOBSTR, follow this guide on how to install and use your wallet. For a walkthrough on how to use Allbridge and effectively bridge assets, refer to this bridging guide or watch the video tutorial.About Ultra StellarUltra Stellar, established in 2014, is a software engineering company specializing in financial solutions for the Stellar network. The company’s main products include LOBSTR, StellarX, and StellarTerm — three leading Stellar wallets and interfaces. These secure and user-friendly products empower individuals and businesses alike, enabling anyone in the world to achieve financial freedom. Ultra Stellar also offers professional services, assisting businesses in their transition into blockchain technology, integrating with the Stellar network, and developing ready-to-launch solutions. For more information, visit ultrastellar.com.About AllbridgeAllbridge is a leading cross-chain provider, specializing in integrating EVM with non-EVM blockchains. Our mission is to make the blockchain world borderless by providing an infrastructure to freely move assets between various networks. For more information, visit allbridge.io.Allbridge Launch Connects Stellar Network to Solana, Ethereum, Polygon and Celo was originally published in Ultra Stellar on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Launching BTC &amp; ETH anchors on Stellar</title>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:01:19+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:01:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ultra-stellar/launching-btc-eth-anchors-on-stellar-c9625d118ed2?source=rss----d59db8dd32d9---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ultra-stellar/launching-btc-eth-anchors-on-stellar-c9625d118ed2?source=rss----d59db8dd32d9---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ultra Stellar</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Ultra Stellar expands the suite of tethered crypto assets by adding Bitcoin and Ethereum bridges on StellarIt’s an exciting day for us here on the Ultra Stellar team. After thorough preparation, we are ready to announce the launch of 4 new cryptocurrency assets: BTC, yBTC, ETH, and yETH. These assets are the newest addition to our anchor product line and join the widely popular yXLM and yUSDC products.⛓ Tethered BTC &amp;amp; ETH on StellarToday we are launching ETH:ultrastellar.com and BTC:ultrastellar.com assets on the Stellar network. These assets are connected to our ultrastellar.com domain to ensure authenticity and make it easy to discover them in Stellar wallets and apps.Ultra Stellar will act as an anchor for these assets, securely storing the deposited native Bitcoin and Ether while issuing BTC and ETH on Stellar. Every issued asset is strictly backed 1:1 by the reserves. This means you can hold wrapped Bitcoin &amp;amp; Ether assets on the network, making use of fast and inexpensive transactions on Stellar.At any time, you can withdraw BTC &amp;amp; ETH back to their respective networks. These assets support SEP-24 integration, which means you can deposit &amp;amp; withdraw to the Bitcoin or Ethereum networks directly from supported Stellar wallets.Tokenised BTC and ETH on Stellar allows anyone to make use of the efficiency of the Stellar network. This could save time and money for users if they need to make lots of transactions. You can use these assets for fast and low-cost payments, but they can also be traded on the SDEX or deposited in upcoming AMM liquidity pools, set to launch on Stellar in early November.There are two ways how you can get a hold of these wrapped assets on Stellar. Let’s take BTC as an example. You can mint new BTC on Stellar by depositing native Bitcoin through our Deposit bridge. Use these step-by-step guides (for LOBSTR, StellarTerm, StellarX, and Solar) to learn more about the deposit flow into each product. Another option is to buy BTC on SDEX from someone else. In both cases, you can be sure that the BTC asset is fully backed by Bitcoin in Ultra Stellar’s reserves, and you can exchange BTC:ultrastellar.com to native Bitcoin at a 1:1 rate (minus the network fee).If you would like to move these assets from the Stellar network, we recommend using our SEP-24 withdrawal bridge to get 1:1 for the assets you hold.📈 Trading BTC &amp;amp; ETH on StellarHaving these assets tethered on the Stellar network also means trading can be completed on the decentralized exchange (SDEX). We are taking steps to ensure there is liquidity in the SDEX order book and that the SDEX prices of BTC and ETH are up-to-date.We suggest using BTC/USDC and ETH/USDC markets on SDEX for the best liquidity and exchange rates. Alternatively, you can use Swap functionality available in most Stellar apps to ensure you get the best exchange rates.With Automated Market Makers coming at the beginning of November, we expect liquidity to continue to increase and spreads and slippage to become lower.🧑‍🌾 Yield Earning yBTC &amp;amp; yETHAs an addition to our asset lineup, we offer y-assets. These versions are called yBTC &amp;amp; yETH, which both generate a yearly APY, currently set at 5%.Upcoming Stellar AMMs will bring the option to earn fees on any Stellar asset for liquidity providers. The protocol upgrade introducing AMM is scheduled for November 3rd, so mark the date in your calendars.We mention AMMs because y-assets can be deposited into AMM pools too. And in addition to regular AMM fees, y-assets will continue to earn yield even while being locked in AMM pools. This unlocks very interesting opportunities.We are especially excited to see how pools such as XLM/yXLM or BTC/yBTC will perform. These pools have no impermanent loss risk because y-assets are fully backed and 1:1 redeemable. And every yield farmer in this pool will benefit from regular AMM exchange fees as well as receive a portion of yield generated by y-asset in the pool.You can use SEP-24 withdrawal &amp;amp; deposits for these assets as well, either depositing straight from the original blockchains or using our new BTC &amp;amp; ETH tethered assets.We hope all these assets combined will help create a better experience for you when using Stellar. We will be looking to integrate more assets as time progresses, so sign up for our Medium to keep up to date with the latest developments at Ultra Stellar.Also, we would like to welcome you to our new assets page, describing yXLM, yBTC, yETH and yUSDC in one place: https://ultrastellar.com/assets/.You can also find us over on our Twitter account here.Or visit us on our webpage at https://ultrastellar.com/.Launching BTC &amp;amp; ETH anchors on Stellar was originally published in Ultra Stellar on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">LOBSTR &amp; WalletConnect</title>
    <published>2021-10-22T14:59:37+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T14:59:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/ultra-stellar/lobstr-walletconnect-7807fb9c83ae?source=rss----d59db8dd32d9---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/ultra-stellar/lobstr-walletconnect-7807fb9c83ae?source=rss----d59db8dd32d9---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>LOBSTR Wallet</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Connect your favorite wallet to the best apps on StellarToday we are very excited to open a new chapter and transform how Ultra Stellar products work together. Furthermore, we propose a standard way for any products built on Stellar to interact with each other.LOBSTR is where Ultra Stellar started but over the years of building in crypto, our suite has expanded to also include StellarX &amp;amp; StellarTerm. The Stellar ecosystem has grown immensely too with more wallets, platforms, interfaces, and use-cases being created daily.All of these products need to be able to integrate. Users enjoy using multiple wallets to allow them to trade on the DEX, buy NFTs, provide liquidity into AMM pools, visualize their portfolio, and much more. Those wallets can reside on their mobile phones, browser extensions, or hardware devices like Ledger.The challenge for us was to allow users of LOBSTR, the most popular Stellar wallet, to seamlessly and securely interact with different products whilst also giving users of other mobile wallets a way to use StellarX &amp;amp; StellarTerm.🔗 About WalletConnectWalletConnect has previously created a protocol for Ethereum, allowing wallets like MetaMask or TrustWallet to connect with other platforms in the Ethereum ecosystem. Currently, there are over a hundred different apps and wallets that can interact through the WalletConnect protocol.WalletConnect acts as a secure bridge between your wallet and the app you are using in the browser. This technology allows you to simply scan a QR code with your wallet to establish the connection with the app.With the success of this solution, the WalletConnect development team has created a brand new version in the form of WalletConnect 2.0. This new upgraded version of the WalletConnect protocol is chain agnostic, meaning that it is no longer limited to a single blockchain and can be adapted to function with multiple networks.We are working with the WalletConnect team, as they make progress towards the release of v2. We defined standards for new WalletConnect protocol to support Stellar and added WalletConnect into all our products, leading the way for other apps in the Stellar ecosystem.🤝 LOBSTR adds WalletConnect 2.0We are pleased to announce that with our latest updates you can now use LOBSTR to connect to StellarX and StellarTerm, just by scanning a QR code. These updates are powered by our WalletConnect v2 integration and are already live. You can watch the video demo below to see how it works before checking it out for yourself.Please note that this is a beta release, so there might be some stability issues for the time being. Rest assured, security is top notch. Private keys never leave your LOBSTR wallet. Once the connected application sends the transaction request to LOBSTR, you can review all the transaction details before you sign and submit it to the network.Our team will continue using WalletConnect to give LOBSTR users access to upcoming products such as StellarX’s AMM interface. We are also in touch with several other teams building on Stellar who are currently adding WalletConnect support. Stay tuned for these upcoming updates.This new way of interacting with Stellar applications doesn’t stop at Ultra Stellar products, you can use this login option on any Stellar-based platform that supports WalletConnect v2. As more apps &amp;amp; platforms enable this log-in functionality, you will be able to travel through the Stellar ecosystem with your favourite Stellar wallet in hand.WalletConnect 2.0 provides developers with a simple way to onboard new users. No longer do they need to write custom code for each browser extension or mobile wallet to start gaining users. Instead, they can integrate WalletConnect and gain access to all the users of wallets with WalletConnect v2 enabled.With its open-source nature, anyone can adopt WalletConnect. Whether you’re a developer of a Stellar exchange interface, gaming app, margin trading service, or even an NFT platform. From now, developers can set up faster than ever whilst also gaining access to LOBSTR’s large user base. This user base will only grow as more wallets integrate WalletConnect.🧐 How it all worksIf you’ve never used WalletConnect solutions before you may not understand what this all means so far. Let us show you how this works and introduce you to this new log in feature.https://medium.com/media/609b8c54700779729f9b828ef6990549/hrefMake sure to update your LOBSTR app to the latest version (v.7.5.0 or later). If you haven’t used LOBSTR before, get the app from either the Apple or Google Play stores:🍎 Download on the App Store🤖 Grab it on Google PlayOnce you have a Stellar wallet set up in LOBSTR, you can start making use of the WalletConnect function.On the home screen, navigate to the Universal QR Code Scanner in the top right corner. Then scan the QR code given to you by the service you’re using. In this example we used StellarTerm.4. You will now see a Reject/Connect notification on the LOBSTR app. If you press Reject the connection will stop. If you press Connect then the service you’re using will login with your Stellar Wallet from LOBSTR. The app will get your wallet address, and will show you the content that is relevant to you.5. From here you can now safely use the service with your Stellar Wallet and sign transactions. Once you input a transaction on the service you will receive a request to sign it inside the LOBSTR app. You can review all the details inside of LOBSTR and choose to Reject or Confirm the transaction.If you click Confirm, the transaction will be submitted to the Stellar Network and will be processed in the next available ledger. If you press Reject the transaction will be aborted.If you exit the Active Connections screen and need to get back then simply Navigate to the ≡ icon in the top left corner, click Settings, then choose WalletConnect from the menu.That’s it! You can use LOBSTR with WalletConnect 2.0 to sign any transactions that you make, including trades, adding trustlines, and much more. This is an entirely new way of interacting with apps, which we think you will enjoy using.Over time as more developers integrate WalletConnect you will be able to use LOBSTR to interact with more products within the Stellar ecosystem.Follow our Medium to stay up to date with our product updates or follow us on our Twitter using this link @Lobstrco.To keep up to date with the WalletConnect team, follow them on Twitter @WalletConnect or visit their website at walletconnect.org.LOBSTR &amp;amp; WalletConnect was originally published in Ultra Stellar on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
