<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Stories by Vottun on Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40vottun&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*H2OSelkS_XtpiPrrrbw4Lg.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*H2OSelkS_XtpiPrrrbw4Lg.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2F%40vottun&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:11:22+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Moment You’ve All Been Waiting For: Airdrop Distribution Details Announced!</title>
    <published>2025-03-28T12:28:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-28T12:28:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/the-moment-youve-all-been-waiting-for-airdrop-distribution-details-announced-1ca43f8600a1?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/the-moment-youve-all-been-waiting-for-airdrop-distribution-details-announced-1ca43f8600a1?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The long-awaited moment for a significant part of the community is finally here! Today, we are thrilled to announce the official dates and distribution structure for the airdrops of Seasons 1, 2, and 3. Below, you’ll find everything you need to know about this highly anticipated milestone.How Will the Airdrop Tokens Be Distributed?The token distribution will follow this structured approach:25% unlocked on April 9, 2025, followed by a 6-month linear vesting period.This applies to all seasons.Distributions are carried out progressively throughout the specified day and may take up to 24 hours for the initial distribution to be completed.Where will the airdrop be distributed?The airdrop will be credited to your Vottun World account associated with your registered email. From there, you will be able to claim your tokens and transfer them to an external wallet if desired.How Often Can You Claim the Tokens From Linear Vesting?You can claim new tokens every 24 hours if you wish, or you can wait to accumulate several days or weeks/months worth of tokens and claim them all at once later.Deadline to claim the airdropAll users who have qualified for the airdrop have 3 months to make the first claim. After this date, users with unclaimed tokens on the platform will no longer be able to retrieve them, and all unclaimed tokens will be permanently burned.A Quick Note on Airdrop &amp;amp; Bonus Final AmountsThe airdrop amount you received is final and based on the latest review of completed tasks and contributions. This amount may differ slightly from any initial estimate that was previously shown in your wallet. The final allocation reflects the most accurate and up-to-date evaluation of your activity and impact during the campaign.Make sure to follow us on social media so you don’t miss the upcoming updates. The DEX listing, the first AI iterations, staking, and much more are just around the corner!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Welcoming Sergi Mias Martínez to Vottun as Product Manager</title>
    <published>2025-03-14T10:43:36+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-14T10:43:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/welcoming-sergi-mias-mart%C3%ADnez-to-vottun-as-product-manager-830eafc6cb36?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/welcoming-sergi-mias-mart%C3%ADnez-to-vottun-as-product-manager-830eafc6cb36?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We are thrilled to announce that Sergi Mias Martínez has joined the Vottun team as our new Product Manager. With a robust background in blockchain development and a deep passion for technological innovation, Sergi will play a crucial role in reinforcing our commitment to advancing the Web3 space.A Journey Rooted in Blockchain ExcellenceSergi’s foray into the Web3 world began nearly a decade ago when he first explored platforms like Coinbase and Binance. His early curiosity soon evolved into a profound technical pursuit, leading him to earn a Master’s in Blockchain Engineering while serving as a technical lead in London. During this time, he honed his expertise in Distributed Ledger Technologies (DLT), Hyperledger frameworks, smart contract development, and the creation of decentralized applications.Passion for Education and Community BuildingBeyond his professional and academic achievements, Sergi has dedicated the past several years to educating and onboarding new users into the blockchain ecosystem. Actively participating in various Web3 communities, he has contributed by guiding beginners through the complexities of blockchain technology, clarifying fundamental concepts, and providing critical security insights to help users navigate the space safely.Innovating Through Practical ExperienceSergi’s dedication to blockchain extends beyond theory. He has built an impressive portfolio of personal and academic projects, applying his Solidity development skills and exploring innovative solutions within the Web3 landscape. His hands-on approach to problem-solving and technical acumen will be invaluable as we continue to develop cutting-edge blockchain solutions at Vottun.Looking AheadAt Vottun, we are confident that Sergi’s expertise and vision will strengthen our team and further our mission of delivering accessible, efficient blockchain solutions. His leadership and technical proficiency will be instrumental in driving new initiatives, fostering innovation, and consolidating our position as a leader in the blockchain industry.Please join us in welcoming Sergi to the Vottun family! 🚀</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Next Steps Post-TGE: New Listings, Use Cases &amp; More</title>
    <published>2025-02-19T14:09:54+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-19T14:09:54+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/next-steps-post-tge-new-listings-use-cases-more-4c9369e15da7?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/next-steps-post-tge-new-listings-use-cases-more-4c9369e15da7?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The $VTN TGE took place on February 18, marking the first step toward the full integration of our token within the ecosystem. However, this is just the beginning — many plans are in motion for the utility token of the Vottun Ecosystem.Vottun has been in the market for over five years, building and developing a solid and reliable ecosystem for developers. The beginning is just the first chapter — the real magic is in how the story unfolds.These are the list of immediate things that are going to happen post TGE.Listings on Data AggregatorsTo enhance visibility and reach, we are preparing $VTN listings on CoinMarketCap, CoinGecko, and other essential but lesser-known data aggregators. Being featured on the most recognized aggregators will be instrumental in attracting new community members to discover Vottun and join us.Listing on Decentralized ExchangesFollowing our initial listing on MEXC, our next objective is to list $VTN on a well-known decentralized exchange. This will open the door to new liquidity and increased exposure for the project. While centralized exchanges work perfectly for most people, offering a decentralized alternative is key and aligns with our vision and Web3 values.$VTN StakingAs outlined in our tokenomics, we are actively developing a staking system to reward users who hold $VTN. This staking mechanism will not only provide passive income opportunities but also lay the foundation for our upcoming buyback model and governance participation within the Vottun ecosystem.We have allocated 14% of the total token supply to reward $VTN holders, demonstrating our commitment to building long-term value for our community. We’re also excited about future collaborations with other Web3 projects and partners, which could bring additional yield opportunities and amplify benefits for our token holders.Key Events: Vottun on the Global Stage!Vottun is present in Consensus HK, and next week will be heading to ETH Denver, one of the most significant blockchain and crypto events worldwide. This is a prime opportunity to forge new partnerships, explore innovative use cases, and gain greater exposure for our growing ecosystem.But that’s not all! We’re also gearing up TOKEN2049 in Dubai, and actively organizing hackathons to engage Web3 developers, drive innovation, and expand our community of builders.Token Page UpdateThe website vtncommunity.xyz will be updated to include all relevant information about vesting contracts and wallet addresses connected to Vottun and the main smart contract, which is already available on the site.This initiative reinforces our commitment to transparency and trust for all our investors and community members.The story of $VTN has just begun, and there is still so much to build and so much to tell.Follow us on our social media to stay updated on what’s coming next.Website | Twitter | Telegram | Discord</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Transparency and Community Commitment: Vottun Journey Airdrop Season 2</title>
    <published>2024-10-23T08:53:35+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-23T08:53:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/transparency-and-community-commitment-vottun-journey-airdrop-season-2-66b6c61c0317?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/transparency-and-community-commitment-vottun-journey-airdrop-season-2-66b6c61c0317?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">We’re excited to share the details for the second season of the Vottun Journey airdrop. Whether you qualify this time or not, there are always opportunities to engage and prepare for future rewards. Let’s dive into the details!In this distribution, we have deviated from the traditional tier-based model. Instead, we have increased the rewards proportionally based on users’ positions on the leaderboard.Those who ranked higher received more rewardsThis approach ensures a more equitable and motivating reward system.Total Airdrop of Vottun : 2,026,774 $VTN Tokens 🔥1. Community Points and RewardsIn this season, we distributed rewards based on the activity and engagement of our community members. A total of 400,000 $VTN was allocated. Here are the details:Total points accumulated: 3,607,200Tokens distributed: 400,000 $VTNCommunity StatisticsMaximum points: 30,000Minimum points: 2,500Average points: 8,568Median points: 5,850Token Rewards Based on PointsThe most active users received up to 3,327 $VTN (~$250 USD).Even users with the minimum of 2,500 points received 277 $VTN (~$21 USD).2. Developer Points and RewardsDevelopers in our community were also rewarded for their technical contributions. A total of 75,000 $VTN was set aside for this category.Total developers qualified: 136Total points accumulated: 595,400Tokens distributed: 75,000 $VTNDeveloper StatisticsMaximum points: 32,900Minimum points: 1,000Average points: 4,378Median points: 2,000In this category, developers with the highest points received up to 4,144 $VTN ($311 USD). Those meeting the minimum threshold of 1,000 points received 126 $VTN ($9 USD).3. NFT Holder RewardsNFT holders were also rewarded this season. A total of 67,267 $VTN was allocated.NFT Holder StatisticsMaximum NFTs per user: 27Minimum NFTs per user: 1Average NFTs per user: 3Tokens distributed per NFT: 67 $VTN (~$5 USD) per NFTIn this category, users with the most NFTs received up to 1,800 $VTN ($135 USD), while those with a single NFT received 67 $VTN ($5 USD).Get Ready for the Next Season 3!If you qualified this season, congratulations! If not, now is the perfect time to get involved and start earning points for upcoming seasons of airdrops in Vottun World. We will continue to build and reward our community for their loyalty and active participation. Stay tuned for more details about the next season!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Enhancing Web3 Core API: Technical Updates and Improvements</title>
    <published>2024-09-06T08:49:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-06T08:49:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/enhancing-web3-core-api-technical-updates-and-improvements-a385912f736f?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/enhancing-web3-core-api-technical-updates-and-improvements-a385912f736f?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Smart Contract development has traditionally (if we can say tradition in the Blockchain world) been full of challenges, from deployment complexities to managing interactions across various chains. To address these issues, We introduced the Web3 Core API, a tool designed to streamline these processes and provide developers with a straightforward tool for integrating Smart Contracts into their applications. In this article, we will explore the latest updates to the Web3 Core API, highlighting the new features and improvements that enhance its functionality and usability.Read the article on our blog: https://vottun.com/blog/how-we-achived-over-40000-users-in-2-weeks-with-vottundojo/</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How to obtain over 40,000 users in 2 weeks with #VottunDojo</title>
    <published>2024-08-01T10:30:16+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-08-01T10:30:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/how-to-obtain-over-40-000-users-in-2-weeks-with-vottundojo-98dcb317780c?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/how-to-obtain-over-40-000-users-in-2-weeks-with-vottundojo-98dcb317780c?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Recently, Telegram-based bot games have gained significant popularity. Leveraging this trend and aiming to expand our community within the Vottun Ecosystem and increase users for Vottun World, we have developed a game called Vottun Dojo.Vottun Dojo is a game on Telegram where the main goal is to increase your ‘Shuriken’ balance to level up. Users can boost their balance by improving their passive income of ‘Shurikens’ per hour through various activities, which are integrated with the multi-blockchain platform developed by Vottun. Through the game, users not only have fun but also get introduced to the Web3 world and the Vottun ecosystem subconsciously.Read the article on our blog: https://vottun.com/blog/how-we-achived-over-40000-users-in-2-weeks-with-vottundojo/</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Foundry for Beginners: A Smart Contract Testing Deep Dive</title>
    <published>2024-07-18T15:59:33+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-18T15:59:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/foundry-for-beginners-a-smart-contract-testing-deep-dive-6c8aed1c8d78?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/foundry-for-beginners-a-smart-contract-testing-deep-dive-6c8aed1c8d78?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">By Sergio Ruíz, Fullstack at Vottun.Web3 development has recently become a strong trend, capturing the attention of many Web2 developers. However, these new developers, especially those working at companies looking to integrate smart contracts into their products, may inadvertently introduce logic and security errors.One of the main reasons for these errors is a lack of thorough testing or reliance on tools that don’t fully leverage Solidity’s capabilities, like Hardhat. While Hardhat is a useful tool, it doesn’t always maximize Solidity’s potential for efficient and secure smart contract development.At Vottun, we’ve chosen Foundry for our smart contract testing. If you’re new to Web3 development, you might not be familiar with it, but Foundry is a crucial tool to consider.This article is aimed at newer Solidity developers, so I won’t dive too deep into the technicalities of Foundry. In a nutshell, Foundry is a tool that lets you write tests using Solidity itself — a huge advantage because you can use the same language for both development and testing. It also provides powerful features to simulate various environments, scenarios, and conditions, making your smart contracts more robust.Read the article on our blog: https://vottun.com/blog/how-to-start-using-vottun-apis-from-postman/</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Soroban integration into Stellar network</title>
    <published>2024-07-11T09:38:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-11T09:38:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/soroban-integration-into-stellar-network-2f8980a358a2?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/soroban-integration-into-stellar-network-2f8980a358a2?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">By Imanol Hernando, Lead Software Development Engineer at Vottun.In the ever-evolving landscape of blockchain technology, the Stellar network has consistently stood out as a beacon of innovation and efficiency. Known for its fast transaction times and low fees, Stellar has been a preferred choice for cross-border payments and decentralized finance applications.However, the introduction of Protocol 21 and the adoption of Soroban, Stellar’s new smart contract platform, mark a significant leap forward for the ecosystem. Protocol 21 brings a host of improvements, enhancing the network’s scalability, security, and functionality. Meanwhile, Soroban’s integration promises to revolutionize how developers build and deploy decentralized applications (dApps) on Stellar, unlocking new possibilities for financial services, asset tokenization, and beyond.This article delves into the transformative potential of Protocol 21 and Soroban, exploring how these advancements are set to redefine the future of decentralized finance on the Stellar network.But, to start with, what is Soroban? Soroban is not a new blockchain. Soroban is a smart contract platform integrated into the existing Stellar blockchain. It is an additive feature that lives alongside and doesn’t replace the existing set of Stellar operations. Based on WASM (web assembly) and Rust, the Stellar network supports Soroban’s Turing-complete smart contracts. When combined with the strength of the Stellar network, Soroban on Stellar will enable use cases focused on extending access to financial services.But, taking into consideration that Ethereum is by far the most popular blockchain for developers, why would we like to adopt Soroban? Let’s analyze whose are the main differences between them:Ethereum uses the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM) runtime environment, and contracts are built using the Solidity programming language (for the most part, you can also use Vyper or Yul), while Soroban uses the WebAssembly (WASM) runtime environment and supports contracts written in a broader range of languages such as Rust, C, C++, Go, AssemblyScript, and more.While EVM was developed specifically for the Ethereum blockchain (although other chains have decided to use it), WASM is designed for broader interoperability and can be used in various environments such as web browsers, server-side applications, and other blockchain platforms.The same interoperability distinction can be applied to Solidity versus Rust. Solidity was explicitly designed for writing smart contracts on the Ethereum blockchain, while Rust is a general-purpose programming language.Analyzing the differences between the two smart contract development technologies, predicting which will ultimately position itself as the more widespread among developers is as difficult as determining what the ultimate scope of use of blockchain technology in general will be. It is clear that Stellar has positioned itself strongly within the world of decentralized finance while EVM blockchains are focused on a more generalist scope.From Vottun, with the aim of being a tool to facilitate the development of applications that implement web3 functionalities for as many blockchain networks as possible, we do not want to miss all the possibilities that Stellar and Soroban offer, therefore, in the near future we will enable the possibility of implementing this network and this smart contract technology.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">How to Start Using Vottun APIs from Postman</title>
    <published>2024-06-27T09:00:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-27T09:00:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/how-to-start-using-vottun-apis-from-postman-c1728f03d7e6?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/how-to-start-using-vottun-apis-from-postman-c1728f03d7e6?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">By Martí Ras, product owner at Vottun.This article explains how to use Vottun APIs to create decentralized Web3 applications (dApps) using Postman. Postman is a tool that allows sending HTTP requests and analyzing API responses.To use Vottun APIs, it is necessary to authenticate with an API Key and an App ID, which are obtained by registering on the Vottun Web3 platform, generating a new token, and locating the App ID in the dApps section. With this information, Postman is configured by setting the authorization type to “Bearer Token” and adding the x-application-vkn header with the App ID.Once configured, calls can be made to the Vottun APIs. The article presents a simple example of obtaining information about blockchain networks using the endpoint, and a more complex example of uploading a file to IPFS with the endpoint.These steps allow developers to take advantage of Vottun’s API capabilities from Postman, facilitating the development of dApps in the blockchain environment.Read the article on our blog: https://vottun.com/blog/how-to-start-using-vottun-apis-from-postman/</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Revolutionizing Blockchain Interactions: The Power of Web3 Core API</title>
    <published>2024-06-06T10:00:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-06T10:00:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/@vottun/revolutionizing-blockchain-interactions-the-power-of-web3-core-api-1a88943bacb5?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/@vottun/revolutionizing-blockchain-interactions-the-power-of-web3-core-api-1a88943bacb5?source=rss-dcf00aa149cf------2"/>
    <author>
      <name>Vottun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">By Martí Ras, Product Owner at Vottun.In this continuously evolving world of blockchain technology, Smart Contracts have emerged as an amazing tool, automating and enhancing various processes across industries. Despite their immense potential, the development and deployment of Smart Contracts is limited, and there aren’t many use cases or applications taking off. This is because Smart Contract development presents significant challenges.There are not that many developers skilled in Smart Contract development, and those who do have the knowledge, often find themselves lacking the necessary tools to deploy and manage these contracts. Unlike deploying a conventional application on a server, Smart Contract deployment is a complex process with many obstacles.During many of our projects at Vottun, we experienced firsthand the pain of creating, deploying, interacting with every function of every Smart Contract and then making an application to run on top of each Contract.Each new project that we launched, required the creation of a new stack of APIs. This is why we decided to develop Web3 Core API — a feature that allows for the deployment and interaction with any contract and any function in it on any chain (currently supporting Solidity, with Solana and Soroban in progress).But What is it Web3 Core APISo, what exactly is Web3 Core API?It is an API that allows users to interact directly with the blockchain and with Smart Contract thanks to three main functions.Smart Contract DeploymentSending TransactionsQuery Smart Contract InformationIf you have created a dApp, wanted to create, deploy with a new Smart Contract, or interact with an existing one you will know the many stoppers and pains that appear during the process.For example, for a simple project like creating a digital art collection with NFTs, just the Smart Contract deployment can be tricky and tedious without using Web3 Core API.To deploy the contract you need to follow all this process:Develop a Smart Contract using Solidity language (or download the SC).Testing the Smart Contract with Ganache.Creating a wallet.Funding the wallet with the selected blockchain cryptocurrency.Configuring Truffle for RPC requests.Implementing scripts (in JavaScript) for deploying the Smart Contract using Truffle.Executing the deployment scripts.Checking the blockchain evidence.Developing custom code to automate this process, considering batch processes and blockchain evolution.This much effort just to deploy the contract!With Vottun’s Web3 Core API, this process is drastically simplified. Users only need to log in and deploy their contract — whether by uploading their contract, using an already deployed one, or selecting one from our library.For more detailed instructions on how to deploy a Smart Contract from the Web3 API Application, check out this tutorial on how to deploy a contract with Vottun’s Web3 Core API by Imanol Hernando.It means that developers and companies for the first time can create and run unique applications on the blockchain with their own Smart Contracts tailored to specific purposes just with an API that just has three endpoints. Three!Even developers who are just starting their journey in blockchain and have basic knowledge of Solidity can now make calls to Smart Contracts simply by knowing the name of the function and its parameters.Transforming Blockchain InteractionsThe difference Web3 Core API makes is astounding. By democratizing access to Smart Contract deployment and management, we are paving the way for broader adoption and innovation in the blockchain space. Developers and businesses can now focus on creating value and leveraging the full potential of blockchain technology without getting bogged down by the complexities traditionally associated with Smart Contracts.Start integrating Smart Contracts with ease today with Vottun Web3 Core API. Experience the difference in efficiency and simplicity that Vottun brings to the table.Start using Web3 Core API now!</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
