<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <title type="text">Zebec Network - Medium</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fzebec-protocol&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom"/>
  <icon>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</icon>
  <logo>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</logo>
  <id>http://10.0.0.124:3044/?action=display&amp;bridge=FeedFinderBridge&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmedium.com%2Fzebec-protocol&amp;strip=on&amp;_cache_timeout=3600&amp;format=Atom</id>
  <updated>2025-04-11T22:11:25+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RSS-Bridge</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Introducing Zebec Carbon</title>
    <published>2025-03-27T14:39:05+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-27T14:39:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/introducing-zebec-carbon-2225b942b1ce?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/introducing-zebec-carbon-2225b942b1ce?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>elena solovyov</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The world’s first reloadable, zero-fee, and privacy-first crypto debit card.Zebec brings to you a new card designed for seamless, everyday use — with quick activation, smooth funding, and total freedom to spend across the globe. The crypto card that’s as fast and seamless as the streams behind it.TL;DR:Reloadable: Load up to $10K daily ($1K per top up)Zero Fees: No sign-up, no monthly, no transaction feesFast Setup: Activate in seconds via email, wallet + U.S. addressPrivacy-First: No intrusive ID checksGlobal Access: Spend anywhere Mastercard is acceptedMultichain Power: 150+ tokens across 8 major chainsEarly Perk: First 500 users get completely fee-free cardsTo order Zebec Carbon visit card.zebec.ioCrypto was never meant to sit still.It was meant to move — across borders, between hands, through apps, and out into the real world. But until now, spending crypto in everyday life has felt like trying to fit a square peg in a round hole: delays, fees, and hoops that make the experience anything but seamless.That ends today.Meet Zebec Carbon, the latest offering from Zebec — a next-generation crypto debit card that’s reloadable, feeless, and fully private. Built for the way you actually live, it unlocks your tokens for everyday spending across the globe. Whether you’re grabbing a coffee in California or shopping in Singapore, Carbon makes your crypto as usable as cash — minus the friction.Fast. Flexible. Frictionless.With Zebec Carbon, there’s no paperwork, no waiting, and no drawn-out approval process. Just connect your wallet, load up your card, and start spending. It takes seconds — not days. Use a US address for expedited processing.✅ Instant Activation✅ Fully Reloadable — up to $10,000 daily spend✅ Apple Pay and Google Pay Compatible✅ Accepted Worldwide via MastercardWhether you’re using stablecoins or other tokens, your funds are ready to move when you are. Carbon supports over 150 tokens across 8 major chains, with conversion powered by USD and real-time settlement.Zero Fees. Seriously.Most crypto cards talk about being low-fee. We decided to go one step further: no fees at all.❌ No sign-up fees❌ No monthly charges❌ No transaction fees✅ 1 USDC = $1 USDThat’s not marketing spin — it’s how the card actually works. What you load up is what you get to spend. Every dollar stays yours, every time.Privacy Comes StandardZebec Carbon is built with privacy in mind. Your data stays in your hands, and your purchases stay your business. You can activate the card using just an email address, a wallet and a U.S. address — no ID uploads or further authentications or intrusive steps required.Because freedom isn’t just about where you spend — it’s about how.One Card. Infinite Possibilities.Whether you’re a degen trader, digital nomad, or just someone who wants to pay for dinner with your favorite meme token, the Carbon Card makes it happen. It’s not just about spending crypto — it’s about living crypto.With easy reloading, tap-to-pay convenience, and global acceptance, it’s the simplest bridge yet between Web3 and the real world.Ready to go borderless, fee-less, and limitless?Zebec Carbon is available now. For our first 500 users, it’s completely fee-free.Get Your Zebec Carbon card.zebec.ioA Quick “How to” order a Zebec CarbonCreate an account and password on card.zebec.io and select Carbon reloadable. Confirm with a code via email.Connect wallet and fund the card with crypto of your choiceComplete activation with a US address.Card details will arrive via emailAdd to Apple or Google Pay and start spending on-line or in storesZebec Carbon: Your crypto. Your card. Your way.Follow Zebec Network official channels:Twitter | Discord | Telegram | Website | Zebec CardsDisclaimer: The content of this article is for informational purposes only and is not intended as investment advice or to provide specific financial guidance. Readers are advised to conduct their own research and consult financial experts before making any investment decisions. Review card contract and documents for complete details.Introducing Zebec Carbon was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Zebec’s Smart Payment Layer (ZAI): Protecting Payment Flows within the Zebec Network Ecosystem</title>
    <published>2024-10-15T15:28:38+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-15T15:28:38+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/zai-zebecs-smart-payment-layer-fcadeeed3678?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/zai-zebecs-smart-payment-layer-fcadeeed3678?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>elena solovyov</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">​​In a payment ecosystem as dynamic as Zebec’s, securing every transaction while maintaining privacy and compliance is no small feat. That’s why we’ve introduced ZAI, an intelligent AI-powered payment layer that quietly powers the Zebec platform’s most critical security functions. From our real-world asset (RWA) flows and Web3 payroll to our ZePIN pilot, early field-testing for point-of-sale devices and software, Zebec’s decentralized physical infrastructure network, ZAI ensures that transactions flow securely, remain private, and meet regulatory requirements in the background.At the core of ZAI’s functionality is real-time transaction scanning, designed to detect anomalies or violations before they become a problem. It’s not just an added step — it’s an advanced monitoring layer seamlessly embedded within Zebec’s technology stack, facilitating secure payment flows and ensuring that each transaction is scrutinized for potential fraud or data breaches.ZAI also goes a step further by incorporating dark web monitoring, privacy safeguards, and fraud prevention mechanisms, ensuring that even the most sophisticated threats are identified and mitigated.The integration of ZAI across the entire Zebec product suite means that compliance with global financial regulations, such as Anti-Money Laundering (AML) standards, is up-to-date and managed automatically. This thorough approach to security and compliance instills confidence in our partners and enterprise clients, allowing them to focus on growth and innovation while their operations or services, reliant on Zebec’s infrastructure, are safeguarded by continuous, robust AI-driven monitoring and compliance protocols.ZAI acts as a protective layer across Zebec’s platform, operations, technology, and applications supporting ecosystem participants, ensuring that every transaction remains secure, compliant, and private. In a world where digital threats are rapidly evolving, ZAI is an essential part of Zebec’s infrastructure, offering a level of security that is both indispensable and adaptive, keeping the network one step ahead in an ever-changing financial landscape.Follow Zebec Network official channels:Twitter | Discord | Telegram | Website | Zebec CardsDisclaimer: The content of this article is for informational purposes only and is not intended as investment advice or to provide specific financial guidance. Readers are advised to conduct their own research and consult financial experts before making any investment decisions. Review card contract and documents for complete details.Zebec’s Smart Payment Layer (ZAI): Protecting Payment Flows within the Zebec Network Ecosystem was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Zebec DAO Governance Moves to Solana: A More Convenient and Logical Approach</title>
    <published>2024-09-30T14:10:49+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-30T14:10:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/zebec-dao-governance-moves-to-solana-a-more-convenient-and-logical-approach-cedb0b26b04f?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/zebec-dao-governance-moves-to-solana-a-more-convenient-and-logical-approach-cedb0b26b04f?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>elena solovyov</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">At Zebec, we believe in the power of decentralization and empowering our community to have an active role in shaping the future of our ecosystem. To streamline the experience for our community and to make governance as simple and efficient as possible, the team re-deployed Zebec DAO governance on Solana Governance Realms.Previously, $ZBCN DAO governance operated on Binance, which has served us well, but presents certain limitations in use and participation. As we continue to grow, it is critical to maintain a scalable, decentralized, and user-friendly governance framework and platform.​​Solana Realms now offers a robust and scalable framework for decentralized organizations, aligning perfectly with our vision for the growing decentralized Zebec ecosystem.This move from Binance is not only logical for our Solana-native token, but will also make the governance process more convenient and seamless for all ZBCN holders. As a project deeply rooted in the Solana ecosystem, moving our governance to Solana Realms eliminates unnecessary steps that were required when using Binance chain for governance activities.This move:Simplifies Governance for $ZBCN holders: By eliminating extra steps, ZBCN holders can now engage with governance directly within the Solana ecosystem, reducing friction and making participation faster and more intuitive.Is logical for a Solana-native token: Transitioning our DAO governance to Solana Realms is the natural evolution of our commitment to simplifying processes for our users.Details of the DAO move and $ZBCN governance process:With the ZBCN DAO governance move to Solana Governance Realms, a new Governance Realm for ZBCN will be created, and all ongoing and future proposals will be conducted exclusively on this platform.1.Governance Token: $ZBCN remains the governance token for the DAO. Proposal and Voting Process: Proposal Creation: ZBCN holders and community members will be able to create governance proposals within the Solana Realms system.To initiate DAO proposal — minimum requirement — must hold a minimum of 0.5% of $ZBCN2.Voting: All votes will occur via the Realms interface, with the ability to set quorum and participation thresholds to ensure fair representation.To vote: A stake of 5% of ZBCN token held is required.3.Quorum and Execution. Once a proposal passes, the execution will be automatically triggered on-chain where applicable, improving efficiency and transparency.4.Migration of existing governance structures: Existing governance records and decisions from Binance will be archived for transparency. All future governance activities will be exclusively conducted through the Realms platform.5. Transparency and Security: Realms provides on-chain transparency of governance activities, including voting histories and proposal details, ensuring full accountability. Solana’s secure and scalable infrastructure will support the DAO’s evolving needs.What Does This Mean for ZBCN Holders?ZBCN, the governance and utility token of the Zebec ecosystem, remains key to DAO governance. The principles of Zebec DAO governance remain the same. By moving the governance and vote process to Solana Realms, ZBCN holders will experience a simplified, more streamlined way to participate in decisions that shape the future of Zebec.All governance powers and voting rights will be transferred seamlessly to Solana, ensuring that there’s no interruption in the decision-making process.As a result, Zebec ecosystem participants and contributors will see:Improved Governance Efficiency: With faster transaction speeds and lower costs, proposals and votes will be processed more efficiently.Increased Transparency: Solana’s Governance Realms offers clear and transparent mechanisms for voting and proposal tracking, giving DAO participants more visibility into decision-making processes.Boost in Engagement: By leveraging the user-friendly Realms interface, we are making it easier for more ZBCN holders to actively participate in governance decisions.How Will the Transition Work?With technical Integration and testing completed, all DAO activities will take place to Solana Realms, with continued community participation at the heart of the governance process.Fast DeploymentThe availability of a new “plug-and-play” platform modules from Solana Labs, deployment and execution take days, not months. We are grateful to Solana’s community for building out and making available cutting-edge tools like Governance Realms, which provide robust, efficient, and transparent management for DAOs.By making this move, we’re ensuring that the Zebec community has access to the most convenient and logical governance process for a Solana-native project. We are confident that this transition further empowers and energize our community.Follow our progress onTwitter | Discord | Telegram | Website | Zebec CardsDisclaimer: The content of this article is for informational purposes only and is not intended as investment advice or to provide specific financial guidance. Readers are advised to conduct their own research and consult financial experts before making any investment decisions.Zebec DAO Governance Moves to Solana: A More Convenient and Logical Approach was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">$ZBCN: Buyback Program 2024</title>
    <published>2024-09-28T08:23:04+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-28T08:23:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/zbcn-buyback-program-2024-5d7783107b4e?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/zbcn-buyback-program-2024-5d7783107b4e?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>elena solovyov</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Zebec Network Announces Details of its Token Buyback ProgramTo maintain the deflationary model for $ZBCN and to support its long-term value, Zebec’s DAO plans to reinstate its token buyback program.Rationale$ZBCN — a Solana native token — is a central asset within the Zebec Network ecosystem, serving as the foundation for our governance, ZePIN (Zebec Decentralized Physical Infrastructure Network) incentives, Zebec card rewards, and other select uses and incentives within the ecosystem.While Zebec Network operates as a multi-chain ecosystem, we rely heavily on Solana — with its superior speed, cost efficiency, and high transaction throughput — to handle the bulk of our transaction processing for card products, rewards distribution, and other essential operations.With heavy use of the Solana blockchain, and its corresponding gas fees in Sol for transactions — the use cases for ZBCN within the ecosystem have decreased. To address this and reinforce ZBCN’s value as a deflationary asset, we are reinstating the ZBCN buyback program to reduce its circulating supply and increase scarcity.Schedule: Monthly cycleThe buyback program will operate on a monthly cycle, with buybacks conducted at the end of each month based on two main components.Buyback Parameters: Partner Integrations and Zebec Cards VolumeThe monthly buybacks are tied to the Zebec Cards transaction volumes and partnership contracts, based on the following metrics1.Partner Contributions: For partnerships where projects pay Zebec with their tokens to integrate on our cards, we will buy an equivalent amount of ZBCN from the open market. This ensures both community engagement and consistent reduction in circulating supply.2. Card Volume: As our card programs grow, we will burn an amount of ZBCN equivalent to the monthly total spend volume on Zebec cards, up to a limit of $500K This aligns with our broader strategy to increase the scarcity of ZBCN as the popularity of Zebec cards expands.Reporting and TransparencyTo ensure full transparency, we will provide a public dashboard that tracks all buyback events in real-time and add these numbers to the regular company results reporting to ensure accountability and clarity for the Zebec community.Potential ImpactWith Zebec cards volumes growing rapidly, up to $500K monthly ZBCN buyback would amount to approximately 1% of the $ZBCN circulating supply, adding up to 10–12% reduction in total circulating supply of $ZBCN on the market .The Zip-6 proposal outlining the details of the buyback program and its parameters is currently with the Zebec DAO for consultation, consideration and formal vote and is expected to start as early as October 2024.Follow Zebec Network official channels:Twitter | Discord | Telegram | Website | Zebec CardsDisclaimer: The content of this article is for informational purposes only and is not intended as investment advice or to provide specific financial guidance. Readers are advised to conduct their own research and consult financial experts before making any investment decisions. Review card contract and documents for complete details.$ZBCN: Buyback Program 2024 was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Zebec Instant is Back, As Zebec Silver Card!</title>
    <published>2024-09-03T21:35:14+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-03T21:35:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/the-zebec-instant-is-back-as-zebec-silver-card-ebe1cbf2af91?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/the-zebec-instant-is-back-as-zebec-silver-card-ebe1cbf2af91?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>elena solovyov</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Back by popular demand, meet our blockbuster card — Zebec Silver Card, formerly known as The Zebec Instant Card. With its re-launch, we are able to offer you enhanced features, broader compatibility, and a more refined user experience. The Zebec Silver Card builds on the strengths of the original Instant Card while introducing new capabilities that meet the needs of today’s dynamic crypto users.Zebec Silver: One of a KindGlobal Acceptance: The Zebec Silver Card is your passport to spending crypto anywhere. Supported by the Mastercard network, it’s accepted at millions of locations worldwide, both online and offline. Whether it’s a daily coffee or a cross-border shopping spree, your crypto is instantly convertible into spendable funds.No Fees: With the Zebec Silver Card, there are no hidden costs. You can enjoy the full range of benefits without worrying about sign-up fees or monthly maintenance charges. FX rates vary, but you can avoid even the FX fees, when you match the card denomination (UDS live now, EURO and GBP coming shortly, additional fiat to come)Private: Activate in seconds, confirm with e-mail and limited KYC based on your address.Non-Custodial Security: Retain full control of your digital assets. The Zebec Silver Card ensures that your funds remain in your possession until the moment you choose to spend them, providing the highest level of security.Multi-Chain Compatibility: The Zebec Silver Card supports a diverse range of blockchains, including Ethereum, Binance Smart Chain, Solana, BASE, and TRON. This multi-chain compatibility makes it easy to fund your card with the crypto assets you already hold.Use with Apple Pay and Google Pay: The Zebec SilverCard is compatible with Google Pay and Apple Pay, allowing you to add your card to your digital wallet and start spending instantly on-line and in stores and restaurants around the world.What’s New In addition to New Name?The Zebec Silver Card not only retains the beloved features of the Instant Card but also introduces new enhancements that make it even more versatile and valuable:Earn Yield on Your funds: With the Zebec Silver Card, when your funds are added to Silver dashboard, these don’t not just idle; they’re working for you. Funds not yet used for purchasing the cards you can earn yield on the tokens you hold, adding an extra layer of value to your crypto assets.Expanded Chain Support: We’ve expanded the range of supported blockchains to include BASE and TRON, in addition to the chains and wallets supported by Instant — Solana and Etherium. This ensures greater flexibility and expands your wallet choices in funding your card.Optimized User Experience: We’ve listened to user feedback and made improvements to the card’s user interface and dashboard to make it easier than ever to sign up, fund, and start spending.And, yes, we re-named it Silver to stay in the family, since our recent launch of the premium debit card — Zebec Black. So maybe there is a Titanium in the works next…Zebec Silver vs. Zebec Black: In Summarycard.zebec.ioZebec Silver:Ideal for users who want an instant, prepaid, non-reloadable card with no extra fees and wide global acceptance. (FX fees differ) The Zebec Silver Card is perfect for everyday spending, requires minimal KYC, with a one-time load option and the flexibility to purchase multiple cards as needed. ($1K per card, p to $10K per day limit)Zebec Black:A premium debit card designed for high spenders. The Zebec Black offers no spending limits, full reloadability, and a range of exclusive features, making it the “Black Amex” of the crypto world. Check out the side by side features guide for Silver and Black to help with selections.How to get Started with Silver Card: Fast &amp;amp; EasyGetting started with the Zebec Silver Card is straightforward:1. Visit card.zebec.io: Select the Zebec Silver Card and follow the easy sign-up steps. If you you wish to learn more, including the complete list of countries The Zebec Silver USD card is available today, start here.2. Connect Your Wallet: Fund your account, select the cryptocurrency and amount to load onto your card, and complete your purchase.3. Start Spending: Add your card to Apple Pay or Google Pay and begin using it for online and in-person purchases immediately.If you encounter any issues, our support team is available 24/7 via email at cardsupport@zebec.io or DM us on X @Zebec_HQ or via our Telegram.Looking to the FutureThe Zebec Silver Card is gaining popularity just one week post launch. We are adding new rewards, expanding other fiat currencies support, and growing list of tokens and projects we bring on-board, including some of the coolest new memes to fund the card, launching weekly airdrops for card users, and more.Stay tuned for more ways to maximize the value of your Zebec Silver Card.As all our products, The Zebec Silver Card is designed to make your crypto spending as seamless and rewarding as possible. Whether you’re a crypto novice or a seasoned pro, the Zebec Silver Card provides the tools you need to integrate your digital assets into your everyday life effortlessly.Follow Zebec Network via:Twitter | Discord | Telegram | Website | Zebec CardsDisclaimer: The content of this article is for informational purposes only and is not intended as investment advice or to provide specific financial guidance. Readers are advised to conduct their own research and consult financial experts before making any investment decisions. Review card contract and documents for complete details.The Zebec Instant is Back, As Zebec Silver Card! was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Lucrative Rewards Unlocked: Zebec Cards Airdrop Program Gains Momentum</title>
    <published>2024-09-03T20:50:45+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-03T20:50:45+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/lucrative-rewards-unlocked-zebec-cards-airdrop-program-gains-momentum-46c778f5bde0?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/lucrative-rewards-unlocked-zebec-cards-airdrop-program-gains-momentum-46c778f5bde0?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>elena solovyov</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Rewards in Hottest Memes and Blue-Chip GemsZebec Crypto Payment Cards offer more than just token rewards — they provide real-world value and global reach. Whether you choose the Zebec Black, a debit and reloadable card, or the newly released Zebec Silver Card, a prepaid card with immediate activation, both allow you to seamlessly spend your digital assets on everyday purchases, anywhere Mastercard is accepted globally. With support for multiple blockchains, wallets, and tokens, Zebec Cards offer unmatched flexibility. Plus, with a zero-to-low fee structure and weekly rewards featuring the hottest meme tokens and crypto alpha, Zebec Cards bring real value — and a whole lot of fun!The Only Cards That Reward in Hottest Memes and Blue-Chip GemsZebec Cards are the only crypto cards that reward you with the hottest tokens, almost weekly. Our Airdrop Program is renowned for integrating with and delivering a wide variety of high-quality tokens to cardholders and ecosystem participants. From the latest meme sensations like MOG, BRETT, established favorites like SILLY, BONK or MEW to the rising stars like MUMU and NEIRO, Zebec cardholders receive a mix of fresh, high-potential tokens direct to the wallets, Zebec rewards its clients for being part of the expanding Zebec Network ecosystem. By partnering with industry leaders and new projects, Zebec Cards not only add utility to tokens but also keep them at the forefront of the meme economy, allowing users to enjoy the best of both worlds. Have ideas for tokens to add to our cards? DM us on X @ZebecCard or via our TelegramReal Value, Real RewardsZebec Cards offer more than just token rewards — they provide significant real-world value. With Zebec Cards, you can spend your crypto directly at millions of merchants globally, thanks to broad acceptance and non-custodial access. You maintain control over your assets without the worry of third-party custody.The cards support multiple blockchains and wallets, ensuring that your digital finances are as versatile as they are secure. Plus, with the zero-fee structure of the Zebec Silver, you maximize the value of every spend.Most recently, post announcements and buzz partner token price action saw up to 60% potential yield. With average meme airdrop amounts ranged from $35 to $100 per cardholder in the last few weeks, with new Airdrops announced weekly! Such airdrop amounts per wallet, have put the Zebec Network in the ranks of one of the most lucrative projects and web3 service providers, making these rewards a meaningful boost to your crypto portfolio. New rewards and integrations announced weekly, you always have something to look forward to. Read more about our rewards program zebec.io/airdropsWhich Zebec Card Fits You Best?Choosing the right Zebec Card depends on your needs and goals. If you’re looking for immediate activation and straightforward usability of a prepaid card, the Zebec Silver Card might be for you. It offers immediate spending power, privacy and easy integration with your daily crypto activities. On the other hand, if you’re after premium purchases and no spending limits, Zebec Black Card is designed specifically to cater to those power users with enhanced features and re-loadability.No matter which card you choose, you’ll have access to a versatile tool that seamlessly connects your crypto with everyday life.Convinced? Visit card.zebec.io to learn more, explore your choices and get the Zebec Card that fits you best and start unlocking the rewards that are rightfully yours. Follow our official channels for new announcements.Happy Farming!card.zebec.ioTwitter | Discord | Telegram | Website | Zebec Instant CardRewards criteria and qualifications differ. Zebec Netowrk reserves the right to modify distribution, cancel, or suspend the airdrops — at any time and without prior notice — if economic conditions render these impractical, such as, but not limited to, in situations when gas fees surpass the value of the coins or the amount of partners’ allocation is exhausted. Review full T&amp;amp;C here.Disclaimer: The content of this article is for informational purposes only and is not intended as investment advice or to provide specific financial guidance. Readers are advised to conduct their own research and consult financial experts before making any investment decisions.Lucrative Rewards Unlocked: Zebec Cards Airdrop Program Gains Momentum was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">June with Zebec: Milestones, Partnerships and Plans</title>
    <published>2024-07-10T19:11:26+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-10T19:11:26+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/june-with-zebec-milestones-partnerships-and-plans-bb7d7f4fa169?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/june-with-zebec-milestones-partnerships-and-plans-bb7d7f4fa169?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>elena solovyov</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">H1 by the NumbersJune has been another transformative month for Zebec Network, marking significant milestones and setting the stage for an exciting second half of the year. Here’s a look at our accomplishments in June and what’s on the horizon.Zebec Black Goes LiveOne of the standout achievements this past month was the launch of the Zebec Black Card — our debit reloadable crypto card, supported by Mastercard and available globally. Zebec Black offers unparalleled benefits and access, adding choices for how our clients interact with their digital assets.Early feedback has been overwhelmingly positive, with users praising the added value the card brings to their financial toolkit.In the first few weeks since Zebec Black launch, we have seen load volumes and the number of cards issued consistently double week on week.We are also seeing card transaction volumes with Zebec Black being substantially greater compared with the Zebec Instant. If this trend continues, card spend volume with Black to exceed $5M (annualized).We are pleased to now offer card options that best fit the needs of different types of clients in our ecosystem. Zebec Black — with its no spend limit and reloadable features — has found its own following and is able to serve the needs of our high-end clients.View our short film: Zebec Black is not just a card, lt’s a Lifestyle!https://card.zebec.io/The all-time favorite among our offerings, Zebec Instant, is returning in Q3 to provide convenient crypto prepaid card option for smaller daily expenditures of up to $1000.We introduced the Black card after listening to the wishes of our clients and will continue to expand our offerings and features to better serve our community and the broader crypto ecosystem. We are grateful for the confidence our users place in us.Integrations and Partnerships Are Back!We are thrilled to announce the return of integrations and partnerships with our cards, a crucial component of our strategy to grow awareness about our products and offer utility and marketing opportunities to varied crypto projects, including popular memecoins.There are two priorities for our Black integrations:1. Add support for tokens incorporated into Zebec Instant: MOG, MUMU announced in June, with others (BONK, SILLY, BRETT, etc.) adding in the upcoming weeks.2. Add new supported tokens from various chains to the Zebec Black: June opened with some of the brightest stars of the meme season — PEIPEI, BIAO, SCRAT — with more announcements in the works.https://www.zebec.io/airdropAirdrops Program RelaunchMany integrations and partnerships come with Airdrop rewards, offering users more opportunities to benefit from their engagement with Zebec. Stay tuned for official airdrop announcements and participation details.More in the PipelineOur roadmap for the coming months is packed with exciting developments. Next on the horizon is the integration with Solana and the relaunch of our blockbuster Instant Zebec.“Future of Money” — Conversations with the ExpertsOur interview series “Future of Money” hosted in studio in June our peers and principals from some of the most respected crypto, financial, and fintech firms — ONDO Finance, FT Partners, ZeroHash, Propy, Helium, Hivemapper, Filecoin, Maple Finance among others.Our interviews and panels — some already released and others still in editing — cover the hottest topics in the space: bringing on-chain real-world assets (RWA), trends and progress in the decentralized physical infrastructure networks (DePIN), decentralized finance, and atomic payments on blockchain.These engagements underscore Zebec’s thought leadership and serve as our contribution to continued industry-wide dialogue and education, important for broader adoption and understanding.Tune in here and catch up on insights from the leading voices in our industry.DePin / PoS Launch On-trackIn June, the team made significant progress in preparation for the launch of our point-of-sale terminals. With pre-orders already in the hundreds for our two Phase I models exceeding expectations, we are in the testing stages, on track for the launch in Q3 2024.https://www.zebec.io/products/depinRead our DePin Thesis here which outlines the strategic approach and importance of this initiative for our company and our ecosystem.Circle Alliance DesignationWith USDC at the heart of all of our products, Zebec Network was honored to receive the Circle Alliance official designation this month. This recognition affirms our commitment to integrating stablecoins and enhancing financial inclusion through blockchain technology.M&amp;amp;A: Closing the Next Payroll DealIn line with our growth strategy, our M&amp;amp;A team is closing in on our next major acquisition deal. This move is expected not only to multiply the ranks of 50,000 monthly employees we serve, but also to expand our technology platform and integrations with UKG — another major HR tech platform.H1 2024 By the NumbersJune with Zebec: Milestones, Partnerships and Plans was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Zebec Network’s DePin Thesis: Decentralized Physical Infrastructure for Retail Payments</title>
    <published>2024-07-02T16:04:49+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-02T16:04:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/zebec-networks-depin-thesis-decentralized-physical-infrastructure-for-retail-payments-cad44b36fea9?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/zebec-networks-depin-thesis-decentralized-physical-infrastructure-for-retail-payments-cad44b36fea9?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>elena solovyov</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">IntroductionWe are living in transformational times. The unprecedented technological advancements and market demand give birth to new business models, where capital-intensive infrastructure projects and centralized networks can be replaced by crowd-sourcing and community-based solutions.Zebec Network’s interconnected multi-chain infrastructure is hyper-optimized for payments and financial transactions and already services web3 and web2 payroll, crypto cards, and payments, providing solutions to companies and individuals globally.The next logical step in Zebec’s growth is: enabling merchants in retail, hospitality, and other sectors to accept crypto payments via Zebec’s decentralized physical infrastructure network (DePin) managed and balanced via crypto-economic incentives for network contributors, users, and clients.Poised for early success:Several factors and recent developments pave the way to this next chapter in our business:Developments in blockchain technology and broader adoption of stablecoins and digital assets — and their continued regulatory codification around the world — enable new blockchain-based payments and DePin infrastructure models.The demand for seamless, efficient, integrated, and cost-effective transaction solutions in the retail environment is more pressing than ever. Immediacy is now a daily expectation, yet retail payments lag behind, hampered by high credit card fees, multiple intermediaries, and delays.Plus, the maturity of our own network with its interoperable and connected blockchain infrastructure is capable to seamlessly power financial transactions and is optimized to integrate with modern payment systems and point-of-sale physical devices.Zebec’s market advantage is bolstered by an existing pool of small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) already serviced through its payroll products. Client acquisition is further simplified by modular integrations with off-ramp rails for existing payment solutions and seamless integrations within current payment and card systems.This approach means that businesses can adopt the technology with minimal disruption, reaping the benefits of faster, cheaper transactions almost immediately. Amplifying certainty for Zebec Network to rise quickly to dominate the space.DePins: Physicality and GeographyImportant fundamentals for DePin projects are physicality (hardware) and geography (locations of services).Zebec’s Phase I deployment will use re-tooled and networked models of existing NFC and PoS devices from leading suppliers, deployed at retail locations in the US, Canada and several pilot locations in Asia, all networked into Zebec’s infrastructure.This is no small task: on the network architecture side multiple layers of connectivity must be upgraded and tied together. To enable existing web2 hardware devices and networks to speak the same language as next-gen blockchain ledgers with their added cryptographic software and security layers. In addition, building a layer where network data flows are incorporated, managed and settled onto a blockchain to reward participants and users with tokens.Strategic PartnershipsStrategic partnerships and investments are crucial. Early support from industry leaders like Lightspeed, with over 100,000 PoS terminals worldwide, and Verifone, market leader in the global retail payment market, positions Zebec for an impactful market entry.Drawing on the experience and counsel of leading DePin projects within the Solana ecosystem, such as Helium and Hivemapper, along with industry innovators like IoTex and Filecoin, we are confident in our ability to address the complexities of web2 and web3 interoperability challenges.PoS Models at Launch: portable and versatileOur Phase I PoS models include portable, wireless, and versatile devices designed to simplify the purchasing experience. These devices can be placed anywhere consumers are physically located.NFC Model: A portable wireless ‘smart box’, the size of a credit card, that integrates with existing merchant hardware, adding crypto payment options. A projected funds flow [subject to change]Z-PIN: A universally compatible, portable, Wi-Fi, and cellular- connected terminal, rechargeable and networked.Additional models, including exclusive, proprietary and manufactured by Zebec are on the roadmap.Benefits for MerchantsIn a day and age of instant everything, payments and financial transactions in retail are the last frontier. We are bringing to merchants what we delivered with our real-time payroll and instant payments products: an inclusive, open, and empowering change.Our terminals in shops and cafes, networked directly into our payments infrastructure, will eliminate high fees, endless intermediaries, and frustrating delays.Token Incentives StructureEach device and merchant will have a unique network identifier NFT, ensuring accurate rewards distribution. Zebec will reward participating merchants with its native token ZBCN during the setup and stream tokens regularly, aiming to offset the device costs within 36 months. Additional token tiers based on transaction volume will allow merchants to achieve profitability sooner. Incentives structure:Setup Rewards: Merchants receive ZBCN tokens during the initial setup.Ongoing Incentives: Regular token streams to offset device costs.Performance-Based Rewards: Higher transaction volumes yield additional token rewards, promoting faster ROI for merchants.We are also planning to expand the universe of rewards mechanisms and opportunities for ecosystem participants, contributors and clients.Looking ahead: Global Market OpportunityThe global retail payments market is projected to experience significant growth. In 2023, the digital payment market, a major component of the retail payments market, was valued at USD 9.03 trillion.The global PoS market alone grew from $29.02 billion in 2023 and expected $110.22 billion by 2032, with a CAGR of 16.1%.Concurrently, global crypto ownership is rising, with 580 million holders in 2023, up 34% from the previous year. Zebec Network’s interoperable blockchain infrastructure is optimized to power modern payment systems, positioning it to capture a substantial share of this expanding market.ConclusionZebec Network’s expansion into DePin with the launch of PoS terminals represents a significant step toward realizing our vision of seamless, inclusive, and empowering financial system.By leveraging strategic partnerships and innovative technology, Zebec is well-positioned for swift and successful entry into DePin space, offering a transformative solution for merchants and consumers alike.This initiative aligns with Zebec’s on-going commitment to fostering a more inclusive and accessible financial environment, driving forward the adoption of blockchain technology and crypto payments in everyday life.This thesis is a continuous work in progress. As our development advances and our network and ecosystem grow, the implementation of our vision will likely evolve and differ from what is represented in today’s thinking. We invite you to follow our channels for ongoing updates and insights into our plans.Twitter | Discord | Telegram | Website | Zebec CardsDisclaimer: The content of this article is for informational purposes only and is not intended as investment advice or to provide specific financial guidance. Readers are advised to conduct their own research and consult financial experts before making any investment decisions.Zebec Network’s DePin Thesis: Decentralized Physical Infrastructure for Retail Payments was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">New to Zebec Cards Program: All About Zebec Black Card</title>
    <published>2024-06-12T14:02:22+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-12T14:02:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/new-to-zebec-cards-program-all-about-zebec-black-card-302428096add?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/new-to-zebec-cards-program-all-about-zebec-black-card-302428096add?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>elena solovyov</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">https://card.zebec.io/Your Crypto, Your WayThe Zebec Black card is here to how you manage and spend your cryptocurrency. Designed with flexibility and user empowerment in mind, Zebec Black is a reloadable debit card that bridges the gap between your digital assets and everyday expenses. Powered by Mastercard, this card provides global acceptance and unparalleled convenience.Key Features and Uses of the Zebec BlackReloadable and LimitlessUnlike traditional prepaid cards, Zebec Black offers limitless reloads, allowing you to fund your card with as much cryptocurrency as you need. With no spending cap, it provides unmatched flexibility for both minor purchases and significant expenditures.Swift ActivationGetting started with Zebec Black is quick and straightforward. Once you submit your personal details, user verification and approval take under a minute. This means you can start using your card almost immediately after registration.Global AcceptanceAccepted at any merchant that supports Mastercard, Zebec Black ensures seamless spending whether you are shopping online, dining out, or traveling internationally. This feature makes it an ideal companion for those who frequently move across borders or shop from global retailers.Multiple Supported Tokens, New Tokens Coming SoonAt launch, Zebec Black supports all major tokens on BNB, Ethereum, Bitcoin, Polygon, Tron, and CoreDAO. This extensive support means you can fund your card with a wide variety of cryptocurrencies, making it versatile for different users’ needs.In the upcoming weeks the tokens integrated into Zebec Instant are coming to Black, in addition to new partnerships with projects and meme across various chainsCash WithdrawalsIn addition to online and in-store purchases, Zebec Black allows for cash withdrawals from ATMs. With competitive fees, it ensures you can access your funds in traditional currency whenever needed.Comparison with Zebec Instant and Other Crypto Payments CardsWith no annual or sign-up fees, a low load fee of just 1%, and global reach via the Mastercard network, the Zebec Black card stands out among the competition. Its comprehensive support for multiple cryptocurrencies and seamless integration with digital wallets ensure that your crypto spending and off-ramping needs are met with ease. Additionally, once Zebec Instant is back online, you’ll have an even broader array of options for managing and utilizing your digital assets effectively.To get started with Zebec Blackhttps://card.zebec.io/In Summary:Zebec Black is more than just a debit card; it’s a gateway to a new financial lifestyle. By combining the stability of traditional currencies with the flexibility and privacy of cryptocurrencies, Zebec Black offers a secure, versatile, and globally accepted solution for your everyday spending needs.Whether you are a seasoned crypto user or just starting, Zebec Black empowers you to make the most of your digital assets.Follow Zebec Network via:Twitter | Discord | Telegram | Website | Zebec CardsDisclaimer: The content of this article is for informational purposes only and is not intended as investment advice or to provide specific financial guidance. Readers are advised to conduct their own research and consult financial experts before making any investment decisions.New to Zebec Cards Program: All About Zebec Black Card was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Future of Money — How Web3 Innovations Eliminate Web2 Payment Risks</title>
    <published>2024-06-07T14:23:28+00:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-07T14:23:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/the-future-of-money-how-web3-innovations-eliminate-web2-payment-risks-5bfa40129b60?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://medium.com/zebec-protocol/the-future-of-money-how-web3-innovations-eliminate-web2-payment-risks-5bfa40129b60?source=rss----eeb280edc77b---4"/>
    <author>
      <name>Parth Shah</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">The Future of Money — How Web3 Innovations Eliminate Web2 Payment RisksBy Shivi Sharma (Lead, Fraud Analytics at Varo Bank) &amp;amp; Parth Shah (Associate at Zebec Network)June 7th, 2024 11:00am ETSection 1: Payments Risks in Web2Our credit card purchases are completed in seconds but under the surface lies an entire ecosystem of players. Let’s understand the role of each player in the payments ecosystem:Merchants: Merchants sell goods or services via physical or online storefronts.Payment Gateway: Software or API that accepts credit card transaction information from the card reader (either a POS terminal or online checkout page) and securely communicates to the credit card processor. Examples: Stripe, PayPal, Adyen, Braintree.Acquiring Bank: Acquiring bank onboards merchants to provide them with a merchant account. The merchant account is used to receive funds from settlement. Examples: Chase Paymentech, Bank of America Merchant Services.Acquirer Processor: Acquiring processor transmits data from the gateway to the card networks. Examples: First Data, Worldpay, Global Payments.Card Network: Card networks supply the electronic infrastructure that enables the processors and banks to communicate and process transactions in real-time. They also set the rules and standards for its network participants. Examples: Visa, Mastercard, AmEx, Discover.Issuing Bank: Issuing banks underwrite their cardholders and provide them with credit accounts. Examples: Chase, Citi, Capital One, Bank of AmericaIssuer Processor: They provide services like card approval authorizations and funds settlement. Examples: TSYS, Fiserv, Fidelity National Information Services (FIS).In this ecosystem, users rely on centralized payment gateways or processors to facilitate transactions and ensure that funds are transferred securely and efficiently.   There are some challenges and risks associated with this centralization and reliance on a central payment gateway or processor. Some of the risks are:  1. Settlement Processes: Even if the payment itself appears instant to the end-user, settlement between financial institutions or payment processors can take time. Settlement involves the transfer of funds between banks, which may not happen immediately due to batch processing or interbank transfer protocols.2. Technical Issues: Glitches in software, hardware failures, or issues with third-party payment processors can also cause delays in payment processing.3. High Fees: High transaction fees eat into profits for merchants and can discourage customers from making purchases. Fees can be high due to intermediary charges from banks, payment processors, or card networks.4. Hacking: Traditional payment systems, such as credit cards, debit cards, and bank transfers, often require users to provide sensitive financial information, including credit card numbers, bank account details, and personal identification information. This information is necessary to authenticate the user’s identity and authorize the transaction. Even though the payment gateways employ robust encryption and security measures to protect sensitive payment data from unauthorized access or interception, the disclosure of such sensitive data raises concerns about privacy and security breaches. It makes payment gateways lucrative targets for hackers. If a hacker successfully breaches the security of a payment gateway, they can potentially access and misuse the financial data of millions of users.5. Cross-Border Transactions: International payments often involve multiple banks, currency conversions, and compliance checks, which can introduce delays compared to domestic transactions.6. Fraud &amp;amp; Chargebacks: Fraudsters can exploit vulnerabilities in the payment process and conduct fraudulent transactions using stolen credit card information, fake identities, or other deceptive means. To mitigate the risks of fraud and chargebacks, platforms implement various security measures, fraud detection techniques, and payment verification protocols, such as multi-factor authentication, address verification, card security codes, and fraud scoring algorithms.Fraudulent chargeback transactions can result in significant financial losses for both issuers and merchants. When merchants are unable to prove the legitimacy of a transaction, they are obligated to refund the customer, leading to direct revenue losses with an added chargeback fee. To safeguard against such losses, large merchants often invest in chargeback protection services, incurring additional expenses. Alternatively, they may deploy specialized teams tasked with identifying the root causes of fraudulent chargebacks and implementing mitigation strategies. In some cases, merchants face coordinated fraud attacks orchestrated by groups with access to stolen credit card information. These attackers exploit vulnerabilities in online payment systems to conduct unauthorized transactions, posing a serious threat to merchants’ financial stability and reputationAdditionally, issuers are required to provide provisional credit to customers if an unauthorized transaction dispute investigation remains unresolved within 10 business days. However, fraudulent customers often exploit this provision by spending the provisional credits before the investigation concludes, resulting in negative balances for issuers and further financial strain on the payment ecosystem.Web 3.0 enables transparent, immutable, and tamper-proof record-keeping of transactions on a decentralized ledger. Each transaction is cryptographically secured and linked to previous transactions, making it extremely difficult for fraudsters to alter or manipulate transaction data without detection. By leveraging blockchain’s immutability, Web 3.0 platforms can significantly reduce the risk of fraudulent transactions and enhance the integrity and transparency of their payment systems.Section 2: How Web3 Eliminates those RisksThe current Web2 payment infrastructure, while facilitating global commerce, inherently possesses several risks such as hacking vulnerabilities and fraud. The introduction of Web3, decentralized finance (DeFi), and smart payments promises to mitigate these risks through the use of blockchain technology, which provides a fundamentally different approach to processing and securing transactions. Zebec Network, a decentralized infrastructure network, aims to eliminate issues that traditional payments and payroll companies face.Security through Decentralization:In Web2, payment gateways and processors form a centralized structure that, despite robust security measures, remains susceptible to hacking. These centralized entities manage and store vast amounts of sensitive financial data, making them attractive targets for cybercriminals. Web3 platforms, like Zebec Network, that manage payments flows across multiple blockchains rely on a decentralized model where transactions do not flow through a central authority. Instead, they are distributed across a network of computers and devices each maintaining a record of the entire transaction ledger. This dispersion significantly reduces the risk of data breaches because there is no single point of failure. Additionally, the cryptographic nature of blockchain ledgers ensures that each transaction is securely encrypted.Reduction of Fraud with Smart Contracts:Smart contracts automate transactions based on pre-set conditions and are executed on the blockchain, making them immutable and transparent. This transparency ensures that all parties can view transaction histories but cannot alter them after they have been confirmed. This notability helps in significantly reducing fraud and eliminating chargebacks, which are prevalent in Web2 due to the ease of disputing charges. In a Web3 environment, once the conditions of a smart contract are met, transactions are irreversible, thus providing a clear audit trail and reducing fraudulent claims. Zebec implements smart contracts through its various supported blockchains, Solana and Nautilus Chain. These blockchains power Zebec’s PoS system and other products in Zebec’s product suite. Having Zebec’s PoS network running on a blockchain mitigates fraud and reduces chargebacks. Transactions across blockchain networks are immediate, irreversible and secure, and by consequence, eliminate merchant frauds such as chargebacks and delayed or reversible payment settlements.Enhanced User Privacy and Control:Web3 and DeFi empower users by enabling more control over their financial transactions without the need for disclosing sensitive personal information. Unlike Web2 payment systems where personal and financial data are often required for processing transactions, Web3 systems can operate with pseudonymity. Users can transact securely and privately using blockchain addresses without revealing their identity. Zebec Network’s products, whether its payroll, PoS terminals or payment cards, rely on cryptographic ledgers, individual Web3 wallet connections and addresses to ensure users control their private data and add many layers of security to transactions and records.Elimination of Intermediaries:Traditional payment systems involve multiple intermediaries, each of which adds transaction costs and potential delays. Web3 utilizes DeFi to enable peer-to-peer transactions without the need for intermediaries like banks or payment gateways. This not only speeds up transactions but also significantly reduces transaction fees.In conclusion, Web3, with the support of DeFi and smart payments, addresses the fundamental flaws of the Web2 payment systems — such as security vulnerabilities, privacy concerns, and high costs — by leveraging decentralized, transparent, and efficient blockchain technology. This shift not only promises to enhance security and reduce fraud but also improves transaction efficiency and user control, heralding a new era in digital finance. Zebec’s product suite is providing peer to peer access through blockchains, connecting users securely and in a decentralized manner. This can eliminate the middleman such as: banks, interchanges, processors and credit card networks, all of which tag on additional time and fees throughout the entire payment process. In contrast, blockchains are able to settle transactions between merchant and customer instantaneously and at near-zero cost.Case Study of Web2 Inefficiencies and How Web3 Eliminates Them: Global RemittanceCurrent cross-border remittance solutions today are costly and slow. Even with new fintech services, such as digital wallets, neobanks etc., solutions still depend on legacy infrastructure and traditional banks — making cross border P2P remittances slow, expensive and often risky. In contrast, blockchain payment infrastructure can deliver fast and secure financial transfer, instant currency conversion, immediate funds availability and significant cost savings.Let’s look at an example (image below): Say an employee gets paid $250 during their normal pay cycle and they want to send $250 to Argentina. When they take the $250 to Western Union, they’d have to pay an 11% remittance transfer fee, which means Western Union would only remit $222.5. The recipient in Argentina would also pay a small fee depending on the pickup location to access the funds.Zebec Network, through their nvative payroll app, WageLink, harnesses the power to revolutionize the global remittance ecosystem. WageLink is a hybrid technology solution built inside existing HCM solutions that integrate blockchains rails to accommodate modern finance — instant, efficient, cryptographically secured, programmable payments. WageLink enables cross-border remittance capabilities at a near-zero cost alongside a suite of other sophisticated financial tools, including options for USDC pay, early wage access, budgeting and paycards.The Future of Money — How Web3 Innovations Eliminate Web2 Payment Risks was originally published in Zebec Network on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
